I thought what we might do today is to
like finish off where we were in this
Russman noteblock looking at
timeseriesforecasting and structured
data analysis and then we might do a
little mini review of like everything
we've learned because believe it or not
this is the end like there's nothing
more to know about machine learning
rather than everything that you're going
to learn next semester and for the rest
of your life there anyway I got nothing
else to teach ya so I'll do a little
review and and then we'll cover like the
most important part of the course which
is like thinking about like what are the
what what of how are ways to think about
how to use this kind of technology
appropriately and you know effectively
in a way that's a positive hopefully a
positive impact on society so last time
we got to the point where we talked a
bit about this site this idea that when
we were looking at like building this
competition months open derived variable
but we actually truncated it down to be
no more than 24 months and we talked
about the reason why being that we
actually wanted to use it as a
categorical variable because categorical
variables thanks to embeddings have more
flexibility in how the neural net can
can use them and so that was kind of
where we where we left off
so let's like keep working through this
because what's happening in this
notebook is stuff which is probably
going to apply to most time series data
sets that you work with right and as we
talked about like although we used the F
dot apply here this is something where
it's running a piece of Python code over
every row and it's that's terrifically
slow right so we only do that if we
can't find a vectorized pandas or numpy
function that can do it too the whole
column at once
but in this case I couldn't find a way
to convert a year and a week number into
a date without using arbitrary Python
also worth remembering this idea of a
lambda function anytime you're trying to
apply a function to every row of
something or every element of a tensor
or something like that
if there isn't a vectorized version
already you're going to have to call
something like data frame dot apply
which will run a function you pass to
every element so this is something like
you know kind of this is basically a map
in functional programming since very
often the function that you want to pass
to it is something you're just going to
use once and then throw it away it's
really common to use this lambda
approach so this lambda is creating a
function just for the purpose of telling
DF not apply what to use right so we
could we could also have written this in
a different way which would have been to
say define create from o2 since on some
value return
and then we put that in here okay so
that and that are the same thing okay so
one approach is to define the function
and then pass it by name or the other is
to define the function in place using
lambda all right and so if you're not
comfortable creating and using lambdas
you know good thing to practice and
playing around at the F dot apply as a
good way to good way to practice it okay
so let's talk about this durations
section which may at first seem a little
specific but actually it turns out not
to be what we're going to do is we're
going to look at three fields promot
state holiday and school holiday and so
basically what we have is a table of for
each store for each date
that's that store have a promo going on
at that date is there a school holiday
in that region of that store of that
date is there a state holiday in that
region for that store at that date okay
and so this kind of thing is you know
like their events and time series with
events are like very very common like if
you're looking at oil and gas drilling
data you're trying to say like the flow
through this pipe you know here's an
event representing when it set off some
alarm you know or here's an event where
the drill got stuck or or whatever right
and so like most time series at some
level will tend to represent some events
so the fact that an event happened at a
time is is interesting itself but very
often a time series will also show
some something happening before and
after the event so for example in this
case we're doing grocery sales
prediction if there's a holiday coming
up it's quite likely that sales will be
higher before and after the holiday and
lower during the holiday if this is a
City based store right because you know
you're gonna you've got to stock up
before you go away to bring things with
you then when you come back you've got a
refill the fridge for instance right so
it's alone like we don't necessarily
have to do this kind of feature
engineering to create features
specifically about like this is before
or after a holiday that the neural net
you know the more we can give the neuron
that like the kind of information it
needs the less it's going to have to
learn it the less that it's going to
have to learn it the more we can do with
the data or we already have the more we
can do with the you know the size
architecture we already have so future
engineering even even with stuff like
neural nets is still important because
it means that you know we'll be able to
do you know get better results with
whatever limited data we have whatever
limited computation we have so the basic
idea here therefore is when we have
events in our time series is we want to
create two new columns for each event
how long is it going to be until the
next time this event happens and how
long has it been since the last time
that event happened so in other words
how long until the next state holiday
how long since the previous state
holiday okay so that's not something
which I'm aware of as existing as a
library or anything like that so we I
wrote up here by hand right and so
importantly I need to do this by store
right so I want to say like because you
know for this store when was this stores
last promo so how long has it been since
the last time it had a promo how long it
will be until the next time it has a
promo for instance
all right so here's what I'm going to do
I'm gonna create a little function
that's going to take a field name and
I'm going to pass it a chive promo and
then state holiday and then school
holiday all right so let's do school
holiday for example so we'll say field
equals school holiday and then we'll say
get elapsed school holiday comma after
so let me show you what that's going to
do so we've got a first of all sort by
store and date right so now when we loop
through this we're going to be looping
through within a store so store number
one January the first journey the second
January third and so forth and as we
look through each store we're basically
going to say like is is this row a
school holiday or not and if it is a
school holiday then we'll keep track of
this variable called last date which
says this is the last date and which
where we saw a school holiday okay and
so then we're basically going to append
to our result the number of days since
the last school holiday that's the kind
of basic idea here so there's a few
interesting features one is the use of
zip right so I could actually write this
much more simply right I could say let's
go through well we could basically go
through like four row in DF get a rose
right and then grab the the fields we
want from each row it turns out this is
300 times slower than the version that I
have and basically like iterating
through a data frame and extracting
specific fields out of a row has a lot
of overhead what's much faster is to
iterate through a numpy array
so if you take a series like the F store
and add values after it that grabs a
numpy array of that series okay so here
are three numpy arrays one is the store
IDs one is whatever field is in this
case that's a school holiday and what is
the date so now what I want to want to
do is look through the first one of each
of those lists and then the second one
of each of those lists and then the
third one of each of those lists and
like this is a really really common
pattern I need to do something like this
in basically every notebook I write and
the way to do it is with zip all right
so zip means look through each of these
lists one at a time and then this here
is where we can grab that element out of
the first list the second list and the
third list okay so if you haven't played
around watch with zip that's a really
important function to practice with like
I say I use it in pretty much every
notebook I write all the time you have
to look through you know a bunch of
lists at the same time alright so we're
going to look through every store every
school holiday at every date yes so is
it living through like all the possible
combinations of each of those or for one
one one yeah exactly
thanks for the question so in this case
we basically want to say let's grab the
first store the first school holiday the
first date right so fast or one January
the first school holiday was true or
false right and so if the if it is a
school holiday I'll keep track of that
fact by saying the last time I saw a
school holiday was that day okay and
then append how long has it been since
the last school holiday right and if the
store ID is different to the last door
ID I saw then I've now got to a whole
new store in which case I have to
basically reset everything okay you pass
that to her what will happen to the
first points that we don't have a life
last holiday yeah so I just said I
basically set this to some arbitrary
starting point it's going to end up with
like I can't remember is either largest
or the smallest possible date and you
know you may need to replace this with a
missing value afterwards or some you
know the zero or or whatever you know
the nice thing is though thanks to
rallies it's very easy for a neural net
to kind of cut off extreme values so in
this case I didn't do anything special
with it I ended up with these like
negative a billion day time stamps and
it still worked fine okay so we can go
through and so the next thing to note is
there's a whole bunch of stuff that I
need to do to both the training set and
the test set right so in the previous
section I actually kind of added this
little loop where I go for each of the
training data frame and the test data
frame through these things right so I
kind of you know each cell I did for
each of the data frames I've now got a
whole coming up a whole series of cells
that I want to run first of all for the
training set and then for the test set
so in this case the way I did that was I
have two different cells here one which
set DF to be the training set one which
set to be the test set and so the way I
use this is I run just this cell right
and then I run all the cells underneath
right so it does it alter the training
set and then I come back and run just
this cell and then run all the cells
underneath okay so like this notebook is
not designed to be just run from top to
bottom but it's designed to be run in
this particular way and I mentioned that
because like this can be a handy trick
no like you could of course put all the
stuff underneath in a function that you
pass the data frame to and call it once
with a test set once with the training
set bill I kind of like to experiment a
bit more interactively look at each step
as I go so this way is an easy way to
kind of run something on two different
data frames without turning it into a
function okay so this is going to if if
I sort by store and by date then this is
keeping track of the last time something
happened and so this is therefore going
to end up telling me how many days was
it since the last school holiday okay so
now if I sort date descending and call
the exact same function then it's going
to say how long until the next school
holiday okay so that's a kind of a nice
little trick for adding these kind of
event time as arbitrary event timers
into your time series models right so if
you're doing for example the Ecuadorean
groceries competition right now you know
maybe this kind of approach would be
useful for various events in that as
well do it for state holiday do it for
promo there we go okay the next thing
that we look at here is rolling
functions so rolling functions is how we
rolling in pandas is how we what we call
create what we call windowing functions
so let's say I had some data
you know something like this right and
this is like date and I don't know this
is like sales or whatever what I could
do is I could say like okay let's create
a window around this point of like seven
days
all right so it'd be like okay this is a
seven day window say right and so then I
could take the average sales in that
seven-day window all right then I could
like do the same thing like I don't know
over here take the average sales over
that seven-day window all right and so
if we do that for every point and join
up those averages you're going to end up
with a moving average okay so the kind
of the the the more generic version of
the moving average is a window function
ie something where you apply to some
function to some window of data around
each point now very often that windows
that I've shown here are not actually
what you want if you're trying to build
a predictive model you can't include the
future as part of a moving average all
right so quite often you actually need a
window that's ends here so that would be
our window function right and so pandas
lets you create window func arbitrary
window functions using this rolling here
this here says how many time steps do I
want to apply the function to write this
here says if I'm at the edge so in other
words if I'm like out here should you
have should you make that a missing
value because I don't have seven days to
average over or you know what's the
minimum number of time periods to use
that's so here I said one okay and then
then optionally you can also say do you
want to say
the window at the start of a period or
the end of a period or the middle of the
period okay so and then within that you
can then apply whatever function you
like okay so here I've got my weekly buy
store sums okay
so there's a nice easy way of getting
kind of moving averages or or whatever
else and you know I should mention in
pandas if you go to the time series page
on pandas there's literally like look at
just the index here time series
functionality is all of this is this
like there's lots because like where's
bikini who created this he was
originally in hedge fund trading I
believe and you know his work was all
about time series and so I think like
pandas originally was very focused on
time series and still you know it's
perhaps the strongest part of pandas so
if you're playing like if you're playing
around with time-series computations you
definitely owe it to yourself to try to
learn this entire API and like it
there's a lot of kind of conceptual
pieces around like time stamps and date
offsets and resampling and stuff like
that
to kind of get your head around but it's
totally worth it because otherwise
you'll be writing this stuff as loops by
hand it's going to take you a lot longer
than leveraging what pandas already does
and of course pandas will do it in you
know highly optimized C code for you
vectorize the C code whereas your
version is going to loop in Python so
definitely worth you know if you're
doing stuff in x here is learning the
the full panda's time series API there's
about is about as strong as any time
series API out there okay so at the end
of all that you can see here's those
kind of starting point values I
mentioned slightly on the extreme side
and so you can see here the
17th of September store one was thirteen
days after the last school holiday the
16th was 12 11 10 so forth okay and
we're currently in a promotion right
here this is one day before a promotion
here we've got nine days after the last
promotion and so forth okay so that's
how we can add kind of event counters to
our time series and probably always a
good idea when you're doing work with
time series so now that we've done that
you know we've got lots of columns in
our data set and so we split them out
into categorical versus continuous
columns we'll talk more about that in a
moment in the review section but so
these are going to be all the things I'm
going to create an embedding for okay
and these are all of the things that I'm
going to feed directly into the into the
model so for example we've got like
competition distance so that's distance
to the nearest competitor maximum
temperature and here we've got day of
week right so so here we've got maximum
temperature maybe is like twenty two
point one because they use centigrade in
Germany we've got distance two nearest
competitor might be 321 kilometres 0.7
all right and then we've got day of week
which might be I don't know maybe
Saturday is a six okay so these numbers
here are going to go straight into
[Music]
now vector right the vector that we're
going to be feeding into our neural net
right 22 1-3 21.7 okay well see in a
moment we'll actually will normalize
them but more or less but this
categorical variable we're not we need
to put it through an embedding right so
we'll have some embedding matrix right
of if there are seven days by I don't
know maybe dimension for embedding okay
and so this will look up the sixth row
to get back the four items right and so
this is going to turn into length four
vector which will then add here okay
so that's how our continuous and
categorical variables they're going to
work so then all of our categorical
variables will turn them into pandas
categorical variables in the same way
that we've done before and then we're
going to apply the same mappings to the
test set right so if Saturday is a six
in the training set this apply cats
makes sure that Saturday is also a six
and the test set for the continuous
variables
make sure they're all floats because pay
torch expects everything to be a float
so then this is another little trick
that I use both of these cells to find
something called joined sent one of them
defines them as the whole training set
one of them defines them as a random
subset all right and so the idea is that
I do all of my work on the sample make
sure it all works well
play around with different hyper
parameters and architectures and then
unlike okay I'm very happy with this I
then go back and run this line of code
to say okay now make that make the whole
dataset be the sample and then rerun it
okay so this is a good way again similar
to that what I showed you before it lets
you use the same cells in your notebook
to run first of all on the sample and
then go back later and run it on the
full data set okay so now that we've got
that join samp we can then pass it to
proc DF as we've done before to grab the
dependent variable to deal with missing
values and in this case we pass one more
thing which is du scale equals true de
scale equals true we'll subtract the
mean and divide by the standard
deviation and so the reason for that is
that if our first layer you know it's
just a matrix model play right so here's
our set of weights and our input is like
I don't know it's got something with
just like 0.001 and then it's got
something like which is like 10 to the 6
right and then our weight matrix has
been initialized to be like random
numbers between 0 &amp; 1
right so got like 0.6 0.1 etc then
basically this thing here is going to
have gradients that are nine orders of
magnitude bigger than this thing here
which is not going to be good for
optimization okay so by normalizing
everything to be mean of 0 standard
deviation of 1 to start with then that
means that all of the gradients are
going to be you know on the same kind of
scale we didn't have to do that in
random forests because in random forests
we only cared about the sort order
we didn't care about the values at all
right but in that with linear models and
things that are built out of layers of
lynnium
like ie neural nets we care very much
about the scale okay so do scale equals
true normalizes our data for us now
since it normalizes our data for us it
returns one extra object which is a
mapper which is an object that contains
for each continuous variable what was
the mean and standard deviation it was
normalized with the reason being that
we're going to have to use the same know
mean and standard deviation on the test
set correct because we need our test set
in our training set to be scaled in the
exact same way otherwise they're going
to have different meanings okay and so
these details about making sure that
your tests and training set have the
same categorical codings the same
missing value replacement and the same
scaling normalization are really
important to get right because if you
don't get it right then your test set is
you know not gonna work at all okay but
if you follow these steps you know it'll
work fine we also take the log of the
dependent variable and that's because in
this capital competition the evaluation
metric was root mean squared percent
error so root mean squared percent error
means we're being penalized based on the
ratio between our answer and the correct
answer we don't have a loss function in
pie chart called root mean square
percent error we could write 1 but
easier is just to take the log of the
dependent because the difference between
logs is the same as the ratio okay so by
taking the log we kind of get that for
free you'll notice like the vast
majority of regression competitions on
Kaggle use either root mean squared
percent error or a root mean squared
error of the log as their evaluation
metric and that's because in real world
problems most of the time we care more
about ratios than about raw differences
right so if you're designing your own
project it's quite likely that you'll
want to think about using log of your
dependent variable so then we create a
validation set and as we've learned
before most of the time if you've got a
problem involving a time component your
validation set probably wants to be the
most recent time period rather than a
random subset okay so that's what I do
here when I finished modeling and I
found an architecture and a set of hyper
parameters and a number of epochs and
all that stuff that works really well if
I want to make my model as good as
possible
I'll retrain on the whole thing right
including the validation set right now
currently at least past AI assumes that
you do have a validation set so my kind
of hacky workaround is to set my
validation set to just be one index
which is the first row okay and that way
like all the code keeps working but
there's no real validation set so
obviously if you do this you need to
make sure that your final training is
like the exact same hyperparameters the
exact same number of epochs exactly the
same as the thing that worked because
you don't actually have a proper
validation set now to check against I
have a question regarding get elapsed
function which we discussed before
so in get elapsed function we are trying
to find when is the next holiday like
when will the next one ready come how
many how many days away
so every year the holidays are more or
less fixed like there will be holiday on
4th of July 21st assemble and there is
hardly any change so can't we just look
from previous years and just get a list
of all the holidays that are going to
occur this year maybe I mean in this
case I guess like that's not sure of
promo right and some holidays change
like Easter you know so like this this
this way I get to write one piece of
code that works for all of them
you know and it doesn't take very long
to run so yeah so there might be ways if
you're if your data set was so big that
this took too long you could maybe do it
on one year and then kind of somehow
copy it but yeah in this case so those
no need to and I don't you know I always
value my time over my computer's time so
I try to keep things as simple as I can
okay so now we can create our model and
so to create our model we have to create
a model data object as we always do with
fast AI so a columnar model data object
is just a data a model data object that
represents a training set a validation
set and an optional test set of standard
columnar you know structured data okay
and we just have to tell it which of the
variables should we treat as categorical
okay and then pass in our data friends
so for each of our categorical variables
here is the number of categories it has
okay so for each of our embedding
matrices this tells us the number of
rows and that embedding matrix and so
then we define what embedding
dimensionality we want if you're doing
like natural language processing then
the number of dimensions you need to
capture all the nuance of what a word
means and how it's used
has been found empirically to be about
600 it turns out that when you do NLP
models with embedding matrices that are
that are smaller than 600 you don't get
as good a results as you do if you do if
there's the size 600 beyond 600 it
doesn't seem to improve much I would say
that human language is one of the most
complex things that we model so I
wouldn't expect you to come across
many if any categorical variables that
need embedding matrices with more than
600 dimensions at the other end you know
some things may have pretty simple kind
of causality right so for example let's
have a look state holiday you know maybe
if something's a holiday then it's just
a case of like ok at stores that are in
the city there's some behavior there's
doors that are in the country there's
some other behavior and that's about it
you know like maybe it's a pretty pretty
simple relationship so like ideally when
you decide what imbedding size to use
you would kind of use your knowledge
about the domain to decide like how
complex is the relationship and so how
big embedding do I need right in
practice you almost never know that
right like you only know that because
maybe somebody else has previously done
that research and figured it out like in
NLP so in practice you probably need to
use some rule of thumb okay and then
having tried to a rule of thumb you
could then maybe try a little bit higher
and a little bit lower and see what
helps so it's kind of experimental so
here's my rule of thumb my rule of thumb
is look at how how many discrete values
the category has ie the number of rows
in the embedding matrix and make the
dimensionality of the embedding half of
that alright so if a day of week which
is the second one eight rows and four
colors so here it is there right the
number of categories divided by two but
then I say don't go more than 50 right
so here you can see for store there's a
thousand stores only have a
dimensionality of 50 why 50 I don't know
it seems to work - okay so far like you
may find you need something a little
different actually
for the ecuadorian groceries competition
you know I haven't really tried playing
with this but I think we may need some
larger embedding sizes but it's
something to feel a bit princess can you
pass that left social variables the
cardinality size becomes larger and
larger you're creating more and more
like I think we collide in very much
seas on you therefore massively risking
overfitting which is just using so many
parameters of the model can never
possibly capture all that variation less
your data is actually huge that's a
great question and so let me remind you
about my kind of like golden rule with
the difference between modern machine
learning and old machine learning an old
machine learning we control complexity
by reducing the number of parameters in
modern machine learning we control
complexity by regularization so short
answer is not I'm not concerned about
overfitting because the way I avoid
overfitting is not by reducing the
number of parameters but by increasing
my dropout or increasing my weight okay
okay now having said that like there's
no point using more parameters for a
particular embedding than I need like
because regularization like is
penalizing a model by giving it like
more random data or by actually
penalizing weights so we like we'd
rather not use more than we have to but
they're kind of my general rule of thumb
for designing an architecture is to you
know be generous on the side of the
number of parameters but yeah in this
case if after doing some work we kind of
felt like you know what the store
doesn't actually seem to be that
important then I might manually go and
make change this to make it smaller but
you know or if I was really finding
there's not enough data here I'm either
overfitting or I'm using more
regularization uncomfortable with again
you know then you might go back but I
would always start with like being
generous with parameters and yeah in
this case this model turned out pretty
good
okay so now we've got a list of tuples
containing the number of rows and
columns of each bar embedding matrices
and so when we call get learner to
create our neural net that's the first
thing we pass in right is how big is
each of our embeddings okay and then we
tell it how many continuous variables we
have we tell it how many activations to
create for each layer and we tell it
what dropout to use page layer okay and
so then we can go ahead and call fit
okay so then we fit for awhile and we're
kind of getting something around the the
point one mark all right so I tried
running this on the test set and I
submitted it to kaggle during the week
actually last week and here it is okay
private score 107 public score 103 okay
so let's have a look and see how that
would go so when I was seven private 103
public's let's start on public which is
103 not there out of 3000 I've got to go
back a long way here it is 103 okay
three hundred and fortieth yeah that's
not good so on the public leaderboard
three hundred and fortieth let's try the
private leader board which is 107 oh
fifth
so like hopefully you are now thinking
oh there are some chemical competitions
finishing soon which I entered and I
spent a lot of time trying to get good
results on the public leaderboard I
wonder if that was a good idea and the
answer is no I want write the cavil
public leaderboard is not meant to be a
replacement for your carefully developed
validation set okay so for example if
you're doing the iceburg competition
right which ones are ships which ones
icebergs then they've actually put
something like 4,000 synthetic images
into the public leaderboard and money
into the private leaderboard okay so
this is one of the really good kind of
things that tests you out on Kegel is
like are you creating a good validation
set and are you trusting it right
because if you're trusting your
leaderboard feedback more than your
validation feedback then you may find
yourself in three hundred and fiftieth
place when you thought you're in fifth
right so in this case we actually had a
pretty good validation set right because
as you can see it's saying like
somewhere around 0.1 and we actually did
get somewhere around 0.1 okay and so in
this case the validation set that's re
that publicly the board in this
competition was entirely useless
yeah can you place the box please
so in regards to that how much does the
top of the public leaderboard actually
correspond to the top of a privately
reward because in the in the churn
prediction challenge there's like for
people who are just completely above
everyone else that's it it totally
depends you know like if they randomly
sample the public and private
leaderboard then it should be extremely
indicative right but it might not be
right so in this case
okay let's crushed oh here comes so in
this case the person who was second on
the public leader
what did end up winning s dnt came
seventh right so in fact you can see the
little green thing here right where else
this guy jumped 96 places if we had
entered with the neural net we just
looked at we would have jumped 250
places so it yeah it just depends and so
often like you can figure out where the
the public leaderboard like sometimes
they'll tell you the public leaderboard
was randomly sampled sometimes they'll
tell you it's not generally you have to
figure it out by looking at the
correlation between your validation set
results and the public leaderboard
results to see how well they're
correlated sometimes if like 2 or 3
people are way ahead of everybody else
they may have found some kind of leakage
or something like that like that's often
a sign that there's some trick okay so
that's Russman and that brings us to the
end of all of our material so let's come
back after the break and do a quick
review and then we will talk about
ethics and machine level so let's come
back in five minutes
so we've learnt two ways to train a
model one is by building a tree and one
is with SGD okay and so the SGD approach
is a way we can train a model which is a
linear model or a stack of linear layers
with nonlinearities between them whereas
tree building specifically will give us
a tree
okay and then tree building we can
combine with bagging to create a random
forest or with boosting to create a GBM
or various other slight variations such
as extremely randomize trees so it's
worth like reminding ourselves of like
what these things do so let's let's look
at some data so if we've got some data
like so actually let's look specifically
let's look specifically a categorical
data right
okay so categorical data there's a
couple of possibilities of what
categorical data might look like it
could be like okay so let's say we got
zip code like so we've got line for
double O three here's our zip code right
and then we've got like sales right and
it's like 50 and like nine four one
three one sales or twenty two and so
forth all right so we've got some
categorical variable so there's a couple
of ways we could represent that
categorical variable one would be just
to use the number right and like maybe
it wasn't a number to start you know
maybe it wasn't a number at all maybe a
categorical variable is like San
Francisco New York
Mumbai and Sydney right but we can turn
it into a number just by like
arbitrarily deciding to give them
numbers right so like it ends up in your
number so we could just use that kind of
arbitrary number so if if it turns out
that zip codes that are numerically next
to each other have somewhat similar
behavior then the zip code versus sales
chart might look something like this for
example right or alternatively if the
zip code versus sales like sorry if the
two zip codes next to each other didn't
have any ways similar similar sales
behavior you would expect to see
something that looked more like this
like kind of just all over the place
right okay so there are kind of two
possibilities so what a random forest
would do if we had just encoded zip in
this way is it's gonna say alright I
need to find my single best split point
okay the split point that's going to
make the two sides have as smaller
standard deviation as possible or
mathematically equivalently have the
lowest root mean squared error so in
this case it might pick here as our
first bit point because on this side
there's one average and on the other
side there's the other average okay and
then for its second split point it's
going to say okay how do I split this
and it's probably going to say I would
split here right because now we've got
this average versus this average right
and then finally it's going to say okay
how do we split here and it's going to
say okay I'll spit there right so now
I've got that average and
average okay so you can see that it's
able to kind of hone in on the set of
spits it needs even though it kind of
doesn't greatly top down one at a time
right the only reason it wouldn't be
able to do this as if like it was just
such bad luck that the two halves were
kind of always exactly balanced right
but even if that happens it's not going
to be the end of the world it'll spit on
something else some other variable and
next time around you know it's very
unlikely that it's still going to be
exactly balanced in both parts of the
tree all right so in practice this works
just fine in the second case right it
can do exactly the same thing right
it'll say like okay which is my best
first split right even as though there's
no relationship between one zip code and
its neighboring zip code numerically we
can still see here if it if it's bits
here right there's the average on one
side and the average on the other side
is probably about here okay and then
where would it split next probably here
all right because here's the average on
one side here's the average on the other
side
all right so again can do the same thing
right it's going to need more splits
because it's going to end up having to
kind of narrow down on each individual
large that code in each individual small
zip code but it's still going to be fine
okay so when we're dealing with building
decision trees for random forests or
gbm's or whatever we tend to encode our
variables just as ordinals okay on the
other hand if we are doing a a neural
network or like a simplest version like
a linear regression or logistic
regression the best it could do is that
right which is no good at all and did
over this one it's going to mean like
that okay so an ordinal is not going to
be a useful encoding for a linear model
or something that stacks linear and
nonlinear models together so instead
what we do is we create a one hot
encoding right so we'll say like you
know he is zero one zero zero zero here
zero 100
he is Oh 100 one okay and so with that
encoding that can effectively create
like a little histogram right where it's
going to have a different coefficient
for each level okay and so that way it
can do exactly what it needs to do can
you pass that back please
at what point does that become like too
tedious for your system or does it not
pretty much never yeah
because remember in real life we don't
actually actually we don't actually have
to create that matrix instead we can
just you know have the four coefficients
right and just do an index lookup to
grab the second one which is
mathematically equivalent to x on the
one pot encoding okay so so that's no
problem one thing to mention you know I
know you guys have kind of been taught
quite a bit of more like analytical
solutions to things and in analytical
solutions to like a linear regression
you get you can't solve something with
this amount of collinearity in other
words
Sydnee something you know something is
certainly if it's not Mumbai or New York
or San Francisco so in other words
there's a hundred percent collinearity
between the forth of these classes
versus the other three and so if you try
to solve a linear aggression
analytically that way the whole thing
falls apart now note with SGD we have no
such problem okay
like SGD why would it care right we're
just taking one step along the
derivative here cares a little right
because like in the end the main problem
with collinearity is that there's an
infinite number of equally good solution
right so in other words we could
increase all of these and decrease this
or decrease all of these and increase
this and they're going to balance out
right and when there's an infinitely
large number of good solutions it means
there's a lot of kind of flat spots in
the Loess surface and it can be harder
to optimize all right so that's a really
easy way to get rid of all of those flat
spots which is to add a little bit of
regularization so if we added a little
bit of a little bit of weight decay like
one enix seven even then that basically
says these are not all equally good
anymore the one which is the best is the
one where the parameters are the
smallest and the most similar to each
other and so that'll again move it back
to being a nice loss function yes could
you just clarify that point you made
about why what hard coding wouldn't be
that sure if we have a one hot encoded
vector right and we are multiplying it
by a set of coefficients right then
that's exactly the same thing as simply
saying let's grab the thing where the
one is right so in other words if we had
stored this as a zero you know and this
one has a one and this one is a two
right then it's exactly the same as just
saying hey look up that thing in the
array okay and so we call that version
and imbedding right so an embedding is a
model clica is a weight matrix you can
multiply by a one-pot encoding and it's
just a computational shortcut okay but
it's mathematically the same so there's
a key difference so the first you know
key difference between like solving
linear type models analytically versus
with SGD with SGD we don't have to worry
about : the arity and stuff or at least
not nearly to the same degree and then
the difference between solving a linear
or single layer or multi-layer model
with SGD versus a trinny
a tree is going to be like it's going to
complain about less things right so in
particular you can just use ordinals
as your categorical variables and as we
learnt just before we also don't have to
worry about normalizing continuous
variables for a tree but we do have to
worry about it
for these SGD change models so then we
also learnt a lot about interpreting
random forests in particular and if
you're interested you may be interested
in trying to use those same techniques
to interpret neural nets right so if you
want to know which of my features are
important in a neural net you could try
the same thing try shuffling each column
in turn and see how much it changes your
accuracy okay and that's going to be
your feature importance for your neural
net and then if you really want to have
fun recognize then that shuffling that
column is just a way of calculating how
sensitive the output is to that input
which in other words is the derivative
of the output with respect to that input
and so therefore maybe you could just
ask pipe torch to give you the
derivatives with respect to the input
directly and see if that gives you the
same kind of answers okay you could do
the same kind of thing for partial
dependence plot you could try
you know doing the exact same thing with
your neural net replace everything in
the column with the same value do it for
1960 1961 1962 plot that that I don't
know if anybody who's done these things
before
not because it's rocket science but just
because I don't know maybe no one
thought of it or it's not in our library
I don't know but if somebody tried it I
think you should find it useful it would
make a great blog post maybe even the
paper if you wanted to take it a bit
further so there's a thought that
something you can do
so those most of those interpretation
techniques are not particularly specific
to random forests things like the tree
interpreter certainly are because
they're all about like what's inside the
tree can you pass it occur
we're applying for interpreter for
neuron that's how are we going to make
inference out of activations that the
path follows for example so how are we
going to like in three interpreter we
are like when looking at we are looking
at the parts and their contributions of
the features in this case it will be
same with activations I guess the
contributions of each activation on
their path yeah baby no I haven't
thought about it how can we like make in
front of the activations so I'd be
careful to say the word inference
because no people normally is the word
inference specifically domain the same
is like a test a test time okay
prediction you make like make some kind
of interrogate the model yes yeah I'm
not sure we should think about that
actually Hinton and one of his students
just published a paper on how to
approximate a neural net with a tree for
this exact reason which I haven't read
the paper yet could you pass that so in
linear regression and traditional
statistics like one of the things that
we focused on was statistical
significance of like the changes and
things like that and so when thinking
about a tree interpreter or even like
the waterfall chart which I guess is
just a visualization
um I guess where does that fit in like
because we can see like oh now this
looks important in the sense that it
causes large changes but how do we know
that it's like traditionally
statistically significant or anything
about yeah so most of the time I don't
care about the traditional statistical
significance and the reason why is that
nowadays the main driver of statistical
significance is data volume not kind of
practical importance and nowadays most
of the models you build will have so
much data that like every tiny thing
will be statistically significant but
most of them won't be practically
significant so my main focus therefore
is practical significance which is does
the size of this influence impact your
business you know statistical
significance only you know like it was
much more important when we had a lot
less data
to work with if you do need to know
statistical significance because for
example you have a very small data set
because it's like really expensive to
label or hard to collect or whatever or
it's a medical data set for a rare
disease you can always get statistical
significance by bootstrapping which is
to say that you can randomly resample
your data set a number of times
train your model a number of times and
you can then see the actual variation in
predictions ok so that's that's with
bootstrapping
you can turn any model into something
that gives you confidence intervals
there's a paper by Michael Jordan which
has a technique called the bag of little
bootstraps which actually kind of takes
takes this a little bit further and well
worth reading if you're interested
actually positive prints so you say we
don't need one hold encoding matrix in
if you're doing random forests or if you
are doing any cleavage models what will
happen if we do that and how bad can a
model be if you trigger a one horn
coding yeah we actually did do it
remember we had that like maximum
category size and we did create one-hot
encodings and the reason why we did it
was that then our feature importance
would tell us the importance of the
individual levels and our partial
dependence plot we could include the
individual levels so it doesn't
necessarily make the model worse it may
make it better but it probably won't
change it much at all in this case it
hardly changed it this is something that
we have noticed on real data also that
if cardinality is higher let's say 50
levels and if you do one hot encoding
the random forest performs very badly
yeah yeah that's right if the cab now
that's why we have that in that's why in
fast I we have that like maximum
categorical size you know because at
some point you're one hot encoded
variables become too sparse right so I
generally like cut it off at six or
seven also because like when you get
past that it kind of becomes less useful
because the feature importance there's
going to be too many levels to really
look at
so can it not just not look at those
levels which are not important and just
gives those significant features as
important yeah yeah I mean it's it's
it's it'll be okay you know it's just
like once the cardinality increases to
high you're just you're just splitting
your data up you know too much basically
and so in practice your ordinal version
is likely to be it's likely to be better
okay so yeah so little there's no time
to you're kind of review everything but
I think that's the kind of key concepts
and then of course remembering that you
know the embedding matrix that we can
use is likely to have more than just one
coefficient will actually have a
dimensionality of a few coefficients
which isn't going to be useful for most
linear models but once you've got
multi-layer models that's now creating a
representation of your category which is
kind of quite a lot richer and you can
do a lot more with it let's now talk
about the most important bit we started
off early in this course talking about
how actually a lot of machine learning
is kind of misplaced people focus on
predictive accuracy like Amazon has a
collaborative filtering algorithm for
recommending books and they end up
recommending the book which it thinks
you're most likely to write highly and
so what they end up doing is probably
recommending a book that you already
have or that you already know about and
would have bought anyway right which
isn't very valuable what they should
instead have done is to figure out like
which book can I recommend that would
cause you to change your behavior right
and so that way we actually maximize our
lift in sales due to recommendations and
so this idea of like the difference
between optimizing influencing your
actions were suggest of improving
predictive accuracy improving predictive
accuracy is a really important
distinction which
like very rarely discussed in academia
or industry kind of crazy enough it's
more discussed in industry it's
particularly ignored in most of academia
right so it's a really important idea
which is that in the end that our idea
the goal of your model presumably is to
influence behavior okay and so and
remember I actually mentioned a whole
paper right have about this where I
introduced this thing called the
drivetrain approach where I talk about
like ways to think about how to
incorporate machine learning into like
how do we actually influence behavior so
you know that's a starting point but
then the next question is like okay if
we're trying to influence behavior what
kind of behavior should we be
influencing and how and what might it
mean when we start influencing behavior
okay because like nowadays like a lot of
the companies that you're going to end
up working at are bigger as companies
and you'll be building stuff that can
influence millions of people right so
what does that mean
so I'm actually I'm not going to tell
you what it means because like I don't
know all I'm going to try and do is make
you aware of some of the issues right
and and make you believe two things
about them first that you should care
right and second that they're big
current issues right the main reason I
want you to care is because I want you
to want to be a good person and show you
that like not thinking about these
things will make you a bad person
but if you don't find that convincing I
will tell you this Volkswagen were found
to be cheating on their emissions tests
the person who was sent to jail for it
was the programmer that implemented that
piece of code they did exactly what they
were told to do right and so if you're
coming in here thinking hey I'm just a
techie you know I'll just do what I'm
told
right that's that's my job is to do what
I'm told
I'm
if you do that you can be sent to jail
for doing what you're told okay so so a
don't just do what you're told because
you can be a bad person and B you can go
to jail okay
second thing to realize is in the heat
of the moment you're in a meeting with
twenty people at work and you're all
talking about how you're going to
implement you know this new feature and
everybody's discussing it and there's
some cut you know and everybody's like
we could do this and here's a way of
modeling it and then we can implement it
and here's these constraints and there's
some part of you that's thinking I'm not
sure we should be doing this right
that's not the right time to be thinking
about that because it's really hard
so like step up there and say excuse me
I'm not sure this is a good idea you
actually need to think about how you
would handle that situation ahead of
time okay so I want you to like think
about about these issues now right and
realize that by the time you're in the
middle of it right you might not even
realize it's happening you know like
they'll just it'll just be a meeting
like every other meeting and a bunch of
people will be talking about how to
solve this technical question okay and
you need to be able to recognize like oh
this is actually something with ethical
implications so Rachel actually wrote
all of these slides I'm sorry she can't
be here to present this because like
she's studied this in depth and you know
she's actually being in in in difficult
environments herself where she's kind of
seen these things happening you know and
we know how hard it is right but let me
give you a sense of like what happens
right so so engineers trying to solve
engineering problems is you know and
causing problems is not a new thing
right so in Nazi Germany IBM that the
group known as Hollerith right Hollerith
was the original name of IBM and it
comes from the guy who actually invented
the use of punch cards for tracking the
US Census the first mass wide-scale use
of punch cards for data collection in
the world
right and that turned into IBM and so at
this point if this this unit at least
was still called Hollerith so Hollerith
sold a punch card system to Nazi Germany
and so each punch card would like code
you know this is a Jew eight gypsy
twelve general execution for death by
gas chamber six and so here's one of
these cards describing the right way to
kill these various people right and so a
Swiss judge ruled that IBM's technical
assistance facilitated the tasks of the
Nazis and Commission of their crimes
against humanity this led through the
death of something like twenty million
civilians so according to the Jewish
virtual library where I got these
pictures and quotes from their view is
that the destruction of the Jewish
people became even less important
because of the invigorating nature of
IBM's technical achievement only fightin
by the fantastical profits to be made
right so this was a long time ago and
you know hopefully you won't end up
working at companies that facilitate
genocide
Ryan but perhaps you will right because
perhaps you'll go to Facebook who are
facilitating genocide right now and and
I know people at Facebook who are doing
this and they had no idea they were
doing this right so right now in
facebook the rahega in the middle of a
genocide a Muslim population of Myanmar
babies are being grabbed out of their
mother's arms and thrown into fires
people are being killed hundreds of
thousands of refugees when interviewed
the Myanmar generals doing this say we
are so grateful to Facebook for letting
us know about the ringing of fake news
that the words they use their finger
fake news that these people are actually
not human that they're actually animals
right now Facebook did not set out to
enable the genocide of their hinga
people in Myanmar no instead what
happened is they wanted to maximize
impression
in place right and so it turns out that
for the data scientists at Facebook's
their algorithms kind of learned that if
you take the kinds of stuff people are
interested in and think them slightly
more extreme versions of that you're
actually going to get a lot more
impressions and the project managers are
saying maximize these impressions and
people are clicking and like it creates
this this thing right and so the the the
potential implications are extraordinary
and global right and this is something
that like is literally happening you
know this is October 2017 is it's
happening now okay could you pass that
back there
so I just want to clarify what was
happening here so it was the
facilitation it's like fake news or like
inaccurate media yeah so what happened
was let me go into it in more detail so
what happened was in mid-2016 Facebook
fired its human editors right so it was
humans that decided how to order things
on your homepage those people got fired
and replaced with machine learning
algorithms and so the machine learning
algorithms written by data scientists
like you you know they had nice clear
metrics and they were trying to maximize
their predictive accuracy and be like
okay
we think if we put this thing higher up
than this thing will get more place okay
and so it turned out that these
algorithms for putting things on the
facebook newsfeed had a tendency to say
like Oh human nature is that we tend to
click on things which like stimulate our
views and are therefore like more
extreme versions of things we already
see okay so so this is great for the
kind of Facebook revenue model of
maximizing engagement it looked good on
all of their KPIs and so at the time you
know there was some negative press about
like you know I'm not sure that the
staff that Facebook's now putting on
their trending section is actually that
accurate
that from the point of view of the
metrics that people are optimizing at
Facebook it looked terrific and so way
back to October 2016 people started
noticing some serious problems for
example it is illegal to target housing
to people of certain races in America
that is illegal and yet a news
organization discovered that Facebook
was doing exactly that right in October
ok not because somebody in that data
science team said like let's make sure
black people can't live in nice
neighborhoods right but instead you know
they found that their automatic
clustering and segmentation algorithm
found there was a cluster of people who
didn't like african-americans and that
if you targeted them with these kinds of
ads then they would be more likely to
select this kind of housing or whatever
right but the interesting thing is that
even after being told about this three
times Facebook still hasn't fixed it
right and that is to say these are not
just technical issues they're also
economic issues right when you start
saying like the thing that you get paid
for that is ads you have to change the
way that you structure those so that you
know you either use more people that
cost money or you like a less aggressive
on your algorithms to target people you
know based on like minority group status
or whatever you know that can impact
revenues and so the reason I mention
this is you will at likely at some point
in your career find yourself in a
conversation where you're thinking I'm
not confident that this is like morally
ok the person you're talking to is
thinking in their head this is going to
make us a lot of money that and you just
you don't quite ever manage to have a
successful conversation because you're
talking about difficult different things
you know and so when you're talking to
somebody who may be more experienced and
more senior than you and they may sound
like they know what they're talking
about right just realized that their
incentives are not necessarily going to
be focused on like how do I be a good
person you
like they're not thinking how it might
be a bad person but you know the more
time you spend an industry in my
experience the more desensitized you
kind of get to this stuff of like okay
maybe getting promotions and making
money isn't the most important thing
right so for example I've got a lot of
friends who are very good at computer
vision and some of them have gone on to
create startups that seem like they're
almost handmade to help authoritarian
governments surveil their you know their
citizens and when I ask my friends like
have you thought about how this could be
used in that way you know they're
generally kind of offended that I asked
you know but but I'm asking you to think
about this like you know wherever you
end up working if you end up creating a
start-up like tools can be used for good
or for evil right and so I'm not saying
like don't create excellent object
tracking and detection tools from
computer vision because yeah you could
go on and use that to create like a much
better surgical intervention robot tool
kit right
I've just seen like be aware of it think
about it talk about it you know so
here's what I'd find like fascinating
and there's this really cool thing
actually that made up calm did this is
from a made-up contour kits online they
they think about this they actually
thought about this they actually thought
you know what if we built a
collaborative filtering system like we
learned about in class to help people
decide what meetup to go to it might
notice that on the whole in San
Francisco a few more men and women tend
to go to techie meetups and so it might
then start to decide to recommend techie
meetups to more men than women as a
result of which more men will go to
techie meet us as a result of which when
women go to techie meet ups they'll be
like oh this is all men I don't really
want to go to tech he made ups as a
result of which the algorithm will get
new data saying that men like taking
meetups that
right and so it continues Matt and so
like a little a little bit of kind of
that initial push from the algorithm can
create this runaway
feedback loop and you end up with like
almost all my old tech meetups for
instance right and so this kind of
feedback loop is a kind of subtle issue
that you really want to think about when
you're thinking about like what is the
behavior that I'm changing with this
algorithm that I'm building so another
example which is kind of terrifying is
in this paper where the authors describe
how a lot of the partment s-- in the US
are now using predictive policing
algorithms right so where can we go to
find somebody who's about to commit a
crime and so you know that the algorithm
simply feeds back to you basically the
data that you've given it right
so if your Police Department has engaged
in racial profiling at all in the past
then it might suggest slightly more
often maybe you should go to the black
neighborhoods to check for people
committing crimes right as a result of
which more of your police officers go to
the black neighborhoods as a result of
which they arrest more black people as a
result of which the data says that the
black neighborhoods are less safe as a
result of which the algorithm says to
policeman maybe you should go to the
black neighborhoods more often and so
forth right and this is not like you
know vague possibilities of something
that might happen in the future this is
like documented work from top academics
who have carefully studied the data and
the theory right this is like serious
scholarly work is like no this is this
is happening right now and so you know
again like I'm sure all the people that
started creating this predictive
policing algorithm didn't think like how
do we arrest more black people right you
know hopefully they were actually
thinking gosh I'd like my children to be
safer on the street
it's how do I create you know a safer
society right but they didn't think
about this this nasty runaway feedback
loop so actually this this one about
social network algorithms is actually a
article in The New York Times recently
that one of my friends Renee direst her
and she did something that was kind of
amazing she set up a second Facebook
account all right like a fake facebook
account and she was very interested in
the anti vex movement at the time so she
started following a couple of
anti-vaxxers and visited a couple of
anti-vaxxer links and so suddenly her
newsfeed starts getting full of
anti-vaxxer news along with other stuff
like chemtrails and deep state
conspiracy theories and all this stuff
and so she's like starts clicking on
those right and the more she clicked the
more hardcore far-out conspiracy stuff
facebook recommended so now when Renee
goes to that Facebook account the whole
thing is just full of angry crazy
far-out conspiracy stuff like that's all
she sees and so if that was your world
right then as far as you're concerned is
just like this continuous reminder and
proof of of all this stuff right and so
again it's like this this is to answer
your question this is the kind of ran
away feedback loop that ends up telling
me and my generals you know throughout
their Facebook homepage that reinga
animals and fake news and whatever else
all right so you know it's it's a lot of
this comes from also from bias right and
so like let's talk about bias
specifically so bias in image software
comes from bias in data and so most of
the folks
I know at Google brain building computer
vision algorithms very few of them are
people of color and so when they're
training the algorithms with you know
photos of their families and friends
they are training them with very few
people of color and so when face up then
decided we're gonna try looking at lots
of Instagram photos to see which ones
are like you know I've voted the most
without them necessarily realizing it
the answer was like you know light
colored faces so then they built a
generative model to make you more hot
and so this is the actual photo and here
is the hotter version right so the
harder version is like more white less
nostrils you know more european-looking
right and so like this did not go down
well to say the least so like that so
again you know I don't think anybody at
face app said like let's create
something that makes people look more
white right
they just trained it on a bunch of
images of the people that they had
around them okay and this has kind of
you know serious commercial implications
as well they had to pull this feature
right and they had a huge amount of
negative pushback like ads a short right
here's another example Google photos
created this photo classifier airplane
skyscrapers cars graduation and no
guerrillas right so like think about how
this looks to like most people like most
- most people they look at this they
don't know about machine learning they
say what the somebody at Google
wrote some code to take black people and
call them gorillas like that's what it
looks like right now we know that's not
what happened right we know what
happened is you know they're a team you
know of folks at Google computer vision
experts who have none if a few people of
color working in the team built a
classifier using all the photos they had
available to them
and so when the system came along came
across you know a person with dark skin
it was like oh I've only mainly seen
that before amongst gorillas so I'll put
it in that category right so again it's
the bias and the data creates a bias in
the software and again the commercial
implications were very significant like
Google really got a lot of bad PR - as
they should this this was a photo that
some you know somebody put in their
Twitter feed they said like look what
look what Google photos just decided to
do you can imagine what happened with
the first international beauty contest
judged by artificial intelligence and
basically it turns out all the beautiful
people of what okay right so like you
could kind of see this bias in image
software thanks to bias in the data
thanks to by lack of diversity and the
team's building it you see the same
thing in natural language processing
alright so here is Turkish oh is the the
pronoun in Turkish which has no gender
right there is no he or versus she right
cut him no okay no he visit she but of
course in English we don't really have a
widely used and gendered singular
pronoun so Google Translate converts it
to this okay now there are plenty of
people who saw this online and said like
literally so what you know it is
correctly feeding back the usual usage
in English like this is you know it's it
I know how this is trained this is like
word to Vic vectors I was trained on
Google News corpus Google books corpus
it's just telling us how things are and
like from a point of view that's
entirely true right like the biased data
to create this biased algorithm is the
actual data of how people are written
books and newspaper articles for decades
but does that mean that this is the
product that you want to create
you know does this mean this is the
product you have to create but just
because the particular way you've
trained the model means it ends up doing
this you know is this actually the
design you want and can you think of
potential negative implications and
feedback loops this could create no and
you know if any of these things bother
you there now you're lucky you you have
a new cool engineering problem to work
on like how do I create unbiased and RP
solutions and now there are some
startups starting to do that and
starting to make some money right so
like opera these are opportunities for
you it's like hey here's some stuff
where people are creating screwed up
societal outcomes because of their
shitty models like okay well you can go
and build something better right
so like another example of the bias in
word lvesque word vectors is
restaurant reviews ranked Mexican
restaurants worse because Mexico the
Mexican words tend to be associated with
criminal words in the u.s. press and
books more often again this is like a
real problem that is happening right now
so you know Rachel actually did some
interesting analysis of just the plain
word for backward vectors where she
basically pulled them out and you know
looked at these analogies based on some
research that had been done elsewhere
and so you can see like where to Vic
like the the vector directions show that
father is the doctor is the mother is
too nervous man is too computer
programmer as women is the homemaker and
so forth right so like it's it's really
easy to see what's in these word vectors
and you know they're kind of fundamental
to much of the NLP you're probably just
about all the NLP software we use today
so like here's a great example so a pro
public has actually done a lot of good
work in this area
judges many judges now have access to
sentencing guideline software and so
Sentencing Guidelines software says to
the judge
for this individual we would recommend
this kind of sentence right and now of
course a judge doesn't understand
machine learning so like they have two
choices which is either do what it says
or ignore it entirely right and some
people fall into each category right and
so for the ones that fall into the like
do what it says category here's what
happens for those that were labeled
higher risk right the subset of those
that label high risk but actually turned
out not to rear fender quarter of whites
and about 1/2 of african-americans okay
so like nearly twice as often right
people who didn't really marked as
higher risk if they're african-american
and vice versa amongst those labeled
lower risk but actually did reoffended
to be about half of the whites and only
28% of the african-americans like so
like this is data which I I would like
to think nobody is setting out to create
something that does this right but when
you start with bias data right and you
know the data says that whites and
blacks smoke marijuana at about the same
rate that blacks are jailed at I think
it's something like five times more
often than whites like you know the
nature of the justice system in America
or at least at the moment is that it's
not it's not equal it's not fair and
therefore the data that's fed into the
machine learning model is going to
basically support that status quo and
then because of the negative feedback
loop it's just going to get worse and
worse right now I'll tell you something
else interesting about this one which
research court erred Gong has pointed
out is here are some of the questions
that are being asked right so let's
let's take one was your father ever
arrested right so your answer to that
question it's going to decide whether
you're locked up and for how long now as
a machine learning researcher do you
think that might improve the
active accuracy of your algorithm and
get you a better r-squared it could well
but I don't know you know maybe it does
you try it out so oh I've got a bit of R
squared so does that mean you should use
it like well there's another question
like do you think it's reasonable to
lock somebody up for longer because of
who their dad was that and yet these are
actually the examples of questions that
we are asking right now to offenders and
then putting into a machine learning
system to decide what happens to them
okay so again like whoever designed this
presumably they were like laser focused
on technical excellence getting the
maximum area under the ROC curve and I
found these great predictors that give
me another 0.02 right and I guess didn't
stop to think like well is that a
reasonable way to decide who goes to
jail for longer so like putting this
together you can kind of see how this
can that you know more and more scary we
take a company like taser right and
tasers are these devices that kind of
give you a big electric shock basically
and tasers manage to do a great job of
creating strong relationships with some
academic researchers who seem to say
whatever they tell them to say to the
extent where now if you look at the data
it turns out that there's a much higher
problem you know there's a pretty high
probability that if you get tased that
you all die it happens you know not
unusually and yet you know the
researchers who they've paid to look
into this have consistently come back
and said oh no it was nothing to do with
the Taser the fact that they died
immediately afterwards was totally
unrelated it was just a random you know
things things happen so this company now
owns 80% of the market for body cameras
and they've started buying computer
vision AI companies and they're going to
try and now use these police body camera
videos to anticipate criminal activity
okay and so like what does that mean
right so is that like okay I now have
some augmented reality display saying
like pays this person because they're
about to do something bad you know so
it's like it's kind of like a whirring
direction and so you know I'm sure
nobody who's a data scientist at taser
or at the companies that they bought out
is thinking like you know this is the
world I want to help create that they
could find themselves in you know or you
could find yourself in the middle of
this kind of discussion where it's not
explicitly about that topic but there's
part of you that's just like wow I
wonder if this is how this could be used
right and and you know I don't know
exactly what the right thing to do in
that situation is because like you can
ask and of course people gonna be like
no no no no so it's like you know are
you gonna you know what what could you
do know you could like ask for some kind
of written promise you could decide to
leave you could you know start doing
some research into the legality of
things to say like oh I would at least
protect my own you know legal situation
I don't know like have a think about how
you would respond to that so these are
some questions that reaction Rachel
created as being things to think about
right so if you're looking at building a
data product or you know using a model
like if you're building machine learning
model is your a reason okay if you're
trying to do something right
so what bias may be in that data right
because whatever bias is in that data
ends up being a bias in your predictions
potentially then biases the actions
you're influencing potentially then
biases the data that you come back and
you may get a feedback loop if the team
that built it isn't diverse you know
what might you be missing yeah so for
example one senior executive at Twitter
called the alarm about major Russian bot
problems at Twitter way back well before
the election that was the one black
person in the exact team a Twitter the
one and shortly afterwards they lost
their job right and so like it
definitely having a more diverse team
that means having a more diverse set of
opinions and beliefs and ideas and
things to look for and so forth so non
diverse teams seem to make more of these
bad mistakes can we order a code as an
open-source check for the different
error rates amongst different groups
it's there like a simple rule we could
use instead that's like extremely
interpretive all and easy to communicate
and like you know if something goes
wrong do we have a good way to deal with
it okay so when when we've talked to
people about this and a lot of people
like have come to Rachel and said like
I'm I'm concerned about something my
organization's doing you know what do I
do
or I'm just concerned about my toxic
workplace what do I do and very often
you know
Rachel will say like well have you
considered leaving and they will say all
I I don't want to lose my job
but actually if you can code you're in
like 0.3 percent of the population if
you can code and do machine learning
you're in probably like 0.01 percent of
the population you are massively
massively in demand so like
realistically
you know obviously it's an organization
does not want you to feel like you're
somebody who could just leave and get
another job that's not in your interest
in their interest but that is absolutely
true right and so one of the things I
hope you'll leave this course with is is
enough self-confidence to recognize that
you have the skills you know to get to
get a job and particularly once you've
got your first job your second job is an
order of magnitude easier right and so
you know this is important not just so
that you feel like you actually have the
ability to act
ethically but it's also important to
realize like if you find yourself in a
toxic environment right which is which
is pretty damn common unfortunately like
there's a lot of shitty tech cultures
environments particularly in the Bay
Area right you find yourself in one of
those environments the best thing to do
is to get the hell out right and and if
you don't have the self-confidence to
think you can get another job you can
get trapped right so you know it's
really important you're really important
to know that you are leaving this
program with very in demand skills and
particularly after you have that first
job you'll nail somebody with in-demand
skills and a track record of being
employed in that area okay okay great so
yes this is kind of just a broad
question but what are some things that
you know of that people are doing to
treat bias in data you know it's kind of
like a bit of a controversial subject at
the moment and there are there are like
people are trying to use some people try
to use an algorithmic approach you know
where they're basically trying to say
how can we identify the bias and kind of
like subtract it out but like that the
most effective ways I know of the ones
that are trying to treat it at the data
level so like start with a more diverse
team particularly a team involved it you
know and concludes people from the
humanities like sociologists
psychologists economists people that
understand feedback loops and
implications for human behavior and they
tend to be equipped with you know good
tools for kind of identifying and
tracking these kinds of problems and so
and then kind of trying to incorporate
the solutions into the process itself
let's say there isn't kind of like a you
know some standard process I can point
you to and say here's how to solve it
you know if there is such a thing we
haven't found it yet
you know it requires a diverse team of
smart people
aware of the problems and what had of
them it's the short answer how can you
pass that back please
this is just kind of a general thing I
guess for the whole class if you're
interested in the stuff that I read a
pretty cool book Jeremy you've probably
heard of it weapons of mass destruction
by Cathy O'Neil it covers a lot of the
same stuff yeah
just more topics yeah thanks the
recommendation so Kathy's great she's
also got a TED talk I didn't manage to
finish the books it's so damn depressing
I was just like yeah no more but yeah
it's it's it's very good all right well
that's it thank you everybody
you know this has been this has been
really intense for me you know obviously
this was meant to be something that I
was sharing with Rachel
so I've you know ended up doing one of
the hardest things in my life which is
to take two peoples worth of course on
my own and also look after a sick wife
and have a toddler and also do a deep
learning course and also do all this
with a new library that I just wrote so
I'm looking forward to getting some
sleep but it's been it's been totally
worth it because you've been amazing
like I'm thrilled with how you've you
know reacted to that kind of you know
the opportunities I've given you and
also to the feedback that I've given you
so congratulations