last lesson we looked at what random
forests are and we looked at some of the
tweaks that we could use to make them
work better so in order to actually
practice this we needed to have a
Jupiter notebook environment running so
we can either install anaconda on our
own computers we can use AWS or we can
use cress or comb that has everything up
and running straight away or else paper
space comm also works really well so
assuming that you've got all that going
hopefully you had a chance to practice
running some random forests this week I
think one of the things to point out
though is that before we did any tweets
of any type of parameters or any tuning
at all the broad defaults already gave
us a very good answer for an actual data
set that we want to Carol so like the
tweets are always you know the main
piece there they're just sometimes
they're totally necessary but quite
often you can go a long way without
doing any food store
so today we're going to look at
something I think may be even more
important than building a predictive
model that's good at predicting which is
to learn how to interpret that model to
find out what it says about your data to
actually understand your data better by
using machine learning and this is kind
of contrary to this the common refrain
that things like random forests are
black boxes that hide
meaning from us and you'll see today
that the truth is quite the opposite the
truth is that random forests allow us to
understand our data deeper and more
quickly than traditional approaches the
other thing we got to learn today is how
to look at larger data sets than those
which you can import with just the
defaults and specifically we're going to
look at a data set with over 100 million
rows which is the current kaggle
competition for groceries there anybody
had any questions outside of those two
areas since we're talking about today or
comments Emily yeah it is this kind of
like basic just to make sure I'm
understanding the concept I'm talking
here sorry um
can you just talk a little about like in
general I understand the details more
now random florists but like when do you
know this is an applicable model to use
in general be like oh I should try
random forests here because that's the
part that I'm still like yeah if I'm
told to I can yeah so the short answer
is
I can't really think of anything offhand
that it's definitely not going to be at
least somewhat useful for so it's always
worth trying I think really the question
is in what situations should I try other
things as well and the short answer to
that question is for unstructured data
what I call unstructured data so where
are all the different data points
represent the same kind of thing like a
wave form in a sound or speech or the
words and piece of text or the pixels in
an image are you almost certainly you're
going to want to try deep learning and
then outside of those two there's a
particular type of model we're going to
look at today called a collaborative
filtering model where which it so
happens that the groceries competition
is at that kind where neither of those
approaches are quite what you want
without some tweaks to them so that
would be the other main one so you're
saying neither using deep learning and
neither deep learning or random forests
is exactly what you're wanting in to
kind of do some quests yes yeah if
anybody thinks of other places where
maybe neither of those techniques is the
right thing to use
yeah mention it on the forums even if
you're not sure you know so we can talk
about it because I think this is one of
the more interesting questions and to
some extent it is a case of
practice and experience but I do think
there are you know true main classes no
no so last week we at the point where we
had kind of done some of the key steps
you know like over CSV reading in
particular which door you know a minute
or two at the end of that we saved it to
a feather format file and just to remind
you that's because this is basically
almost the same format that it lives in
in RAM so it's like ridiculously fast to
read it and write stuff from from
feather point so what we're going to do
today is we're going to look at lesson 2
RF interpretation and the first thing
we're going to do is read that feather
format file now one thing to mention is
a couple of you pointed out during the
week a really interesting little little
bug or little issue which is in the proc
DF function the proc DF function
remember finds the numeric columns which
have missing values and creates an
additional boolean column as well as
replacing the messing with medians and
also turns the categorical objects you
know into into the integer codes the
main things it does and coming you
pointed out some key points about the
missing value handler the first one is
that your test set may have missing
values in some columns that weren't in
your training set or vice versa and if
that happens you're going to get an
error when you try to do the random
forest because it's going to say you
know if that is missing field appeared
in your training set but not in your
test set that ended up in the model it's
going to say you can't use that data set
with this model because you're missing
one of the columns it requires
that's problem number one problem number
two is that the median of the missing
belt are the median of the numeric
values in the test set may be different
for the training set and so it may
actually process it into something which
has different semantics so I thought
that was a really interesting point so
what I did was I changed property air so
it returns a third thing na s and the na
s thing it returns it doesn't matter in
detail what it is but I'll tell you to
say you know that's a dictionary that
where the keys are the names of the
columns that had missing values and the
values of the dictionary are the medians
and so then optionally you can pass n
A's as an additional argument to prop D
F and it will make sure that it adds
those specific columns and it uses those
specific medians okay so it kind of it's
it's giving you the ability to say
process this test set in exactly the
same way as we process this training
center can you pass that
is a did it features we just yeah so I
just did that like it's just a good pool
yeah in fact that's a good point
before you start doing work any day I
would start doing it get pull and it
something's not working today that was
was working yesterday check the forum
where they'll be an explanation of why
you know this this library in particular
is moving fast but pretty much all the
libraries that we use including pi torch
and particular move fast and so one of
the things to do if you're watching this
on through the MOOC is to make sure that
you go to course doc bastard AI and
check the links there because they'll be
links saying oh these are the
differences from the course so they're
kind of kept up to date so that you're
never gonna because I can't edit what
I'm saying yeah but yeah do it get Paul
before you start each day so I haven't
actually updated all of the notebooks to
add the extra return value i will over
the next couple of days but if you're
using them you'll just need to put next
to a comma and it is yeah otherwise
we're going to error them its return
through things and you only have room
for two things okay
what I want to do I think what I want to
do before I talk about interpretation is
to show you what the exact same process
looks like when you're working with a
really large data set so and you'll see
it's kind of almost the same thing but
there's going to be a few cases where we
can't use the defaults because the
default kind of flag just run a little
bit too slowly right
so specifically I'm going to look at the
travel groceries competition specific
lady
what's a call here it is compress your
favorite grocery sales forecasting so
this competition Oh who's who who was
entering this competition okay lot of
you who would like to have a go at
explaining what this competition
involves what what the data is when
family
okay trying to predict the items on the
shelf depending on lots of factors like
oil prices let me say predicting the
items on the show what do you mean what
are you actually predicting how much
change to help me stop to maximize their
I guess it's not quite what we're
predicting but not trying to fix that
yeah and then there's a bunch of
different data sets that you can use to
do that there's oil prices there's a
stores there's locations and each of
those can be used to try to predicted
okay does anybody want to have a go at
expanding on that all right so we have a
bunch of information on different
products so we have so forth all right
so far every stool for every item for
every day we have a lot of related
information available like the location
where the school was located the class
of the product and units soared and then
based on this we are supposed to
forecast in a much shorter timeframe
compared to the training data for every
item number how much we think it's going
to sell so only the units and nothing
else so um so your ability to explain
the problem you're working on is really
really important okay so if you don't
currently feel confident of your ability
to do that practice right with someone
who is not in this competition tell them
all about it so in this case but or in
any case really the key things to
understand a machine learning problem
would be to say what are the independent
variables and what is the dependent
variable so the dependent variable is
the theme that you're trying to predict
the thing you're trying to predict is
how many units of each kind of product
were sold in each store on each day
during the two-week period so that's the
thing that you're trying to predict and
the information you have to predict it
is how many units of each product at
each store on each day were sold in the
last few years and for each store
it's a metadata about it like where is
it located and what classes or is it for
each type of product you have some
metadata about it such as what category
of product is it and so forth for each
date we have some metadata about it such
as what was the oil price on that date
so this is what we would call a
relational data set so a relational data
set is one where we have a number of
different pieces information that we can
join together specifically this kind of
relational database data set is what we
would refer to as a star schema a star
schema is a kind of data warehousing
schema where we basically say there's
some central transactions table then
this place the central transactions
table we go in the data section here is
train dot CSV and it contains the event
number of units that were sold by date
by store ID by item ID okay so that's
the central transaction state where it's
more very simple and then from that we
can join various bits of metadata and
it's called a standard schema
because you can kind of imagine the
transactions take on the middle and then
all these different metadata tables
join onto it giving you more information
about the date the item ID and the store
already okay sometimes you'll also see a
snowflake schema which means they might
then be additional information joined on
to maybe the the items table that tells
you about different item categories and
store to the store table coming about
the stage that the stores in and so for
wholesomely okay so that's the basic
information about this problem
the independent variables the dependent
variable and you probably also wanting
about like things like the time frame
okay now we start in exactly the same
way as we did before loading in exactly
the same spot setting the path but when
we go to read CSV if you say limit
memory equals false right then you're
basically saying use as much memory as
you like to figure out what kinds of
data is here it's going to run out of
memory pretty much regardless of how
much memory you have so what we do in
order to limit the amount of space that
it takes up and read it in is we create
a dictionary for each column name
through the data type of that column
right and so for you to create this it's
basically up to you to you know run less
or head or whatever on the data set to
see what the types are and to figure
that out and pass them in so then you
can just pass in D type equals with that
dictionary and so check this out right
we can read in the whole CSV file in one
minute and 48 seconds
and there are
one hundred and twenty five point five
million roads so like whence people say
like pythons slow now pythons not slow I
think can be slow if you don't use it
right but we can actually cause a
hundred and twenty-five million CSV
records in less than two minutes
my language had on for just a moment
actually if it's fast almost certainly
it's going to see yeah so Python is a
wrapper around a bunch of C code usually
yeah so yeah so Python itself isn't
actually very fast yeah so that was
Terrence paw who writes things for
writing programming languages for a
living so and he's right
- itself is not fast but almost
everything we want to do in Python and
data science has been written for us in
C or actually more often in scythe on
which is a - like language which
compiles to C and so most of the stuff
we run in Python is actually running not
just the C code but actually in pandas a
lot of it's written in like assembly
language it's heavily optimized behind
the scenes a lot of that is going back
to actually calling for train back
libraries for linear algebra so there's
layers one layer of speeds that actually
allow us to spend less than two minutes
reading that much data yeah if we wrote
our own CSV reader in pure Python it
would take it takes thousands of times
at least thousands of times longer than
the optimized versions yeah so for us
what we care about is the speed we can
get in practice and so this is pretty
cool we as well as telling it what the
different data types were we also have
to tell it as before which things do you
want to pass as as dense
that's - I've noticed searching this
dictionary of specifying 60 1433 ending
date I was wondering in practice is it
like faster if you all specify them to
endure slower or like any performance
consideration so the key performance
consideration here was to use the
smallest number of bits that I could to
fully represent the column so if I had
used in 8 for item number there are more
than 255 biomass and but the I mean who
was specifically the maximum item number
is bigger than 255 so on the other hand
if I'd used in 64 the score number it's
using more it's necessary given that the
whole purpose here was to avoid running
out of RAM we don't want to be using up
eight times more memory than necessary
so the key thing was really about memory
and in fact when you're working with
large data sets very often you'll find
the slope piece is the actually reading
and writing program not the actual CPU
operations so very often that's the key
performance consideration also however
as a rule of thumb smaller data types
often will run faster and particularly
if you can use Cindy so there's a single
instruction multiple data a vectorized
code it can pack more more numbers into
a single vector to run at once think
that was all definitely simplified
exactly right but once you do this the
shuffle thing beforehand I need anymore
they made assigned a random substitution
yeah so
so although here I've read in the whole
thing when I start I never start by
reading in the whole thing so if you
search the forum fish fish off shuf
you'll find some tips about how to use
this UNIX command to get a random sample
of data at the command prompt and then
you can just read that and the nice
thing is that that way like that's a
good way for example to find out what
data types to use it is to read in a
random sample and let pandas figure it
out for you
yeah and in general I do as much work as
possible on a sample until I feel
confident that I understand the sample
before I move on so yeah having said
that what we're about to learn is some
techniques for running models on this
full data set that I'm actually going to
work on arbitrarily large data sets but
also I specifically wanted to talk about
how to really invite analysis one thing
to mention
unpromoted object objects are like like
saying create a general-purpose Python
data type which is slow and memory heavy
and the reason for that is that this is
a boolean which also has missing values
and so we need to deal with this before
we can turn it into a boolean so you can
see after that I then go ahead and I say
fill in the missing values with false
now you wouldn't just do this without
doing some checking ahead of time but
some exploratory data analysis shows
that it seems that this is probably an
appropriate thing to do it seems that
missing doesn't mean most it objects
generally reading the string so replace
for Strings true and false with actual
volumes and then finally convert it to
an actual boolean flag so at this point
when I save this this file now over 123
million records takes up something under
two and a half gigabytes of memory so
like that you can do like run you know
look at pretty large data sets even on
pretty small computers which is
interests
so at that point now that it's in a nice
fast four-minute look how fast it is I
can save it to feather format in under
five seconds okay so that's nice and
then because pandas is generally pretty
fast you can do stuff like summarize
every column of all 125 million records
in 20 seconds
okay so the first thing I looked at here
actually is the dates right generally
speaking dates are just going to be
really important and one of the stuff
you do particularly because any model
that you put in in in practice you're
going to be putting it in at some note
that is later than the date that you
trained it by definition right and so if
anything in the world changes you need
to know how your predictive accuracy
changes as well and so what you'll see
on cable and what you should always do
in your own projects is make sure that
your plates don't overlap so in this
case the dates that we have in the
training set go from 2013 to mid August
2017 okay there's our first and last and
then in our test set they go from one
day later right August the 16th until
the end of the month so this is a key
thing that like you can't really do any
useful machine learning until you
understand this basic piece here which
is you've got four years of data and
you're trying to predict the next two
weeks okay so that's just a fundamental
thing that you're going to need to
understand before you can go and do a
good job at this and so as soon as I see
that what does that say to you if you
want it to now use a smaller data set
should you use a random sample or is
there something better you do probably
from the bottom more recent yeah okay
the most recent
right and and if you ever have trouble
answering questions like this just try
to make it as physical as possible so
it's like okay I'm going to go to a shop
next week
and I am I've got a $5 bet with my
brother as to whether I can guess how
many cans of coke are going to be on the
shelf
all right well probably the best way to
do that would be to go to the shop same
day of the previous week and see how
many cans of coke are on the shelf and
guess it's going to be the same you
wouldn't go and look at family were
there four years ago
but couldn't four years ago that same
time frame of the year be important I
mean like for example how much coke they
have in the shop at Christmas time is
gonna be way more than so exactly so
it's not that there's no useful
information from four years ago and so
we don't want to entirely throw it away
but as a as a first step
like what was this what's the simplest
possible thing it's kind of like
submitting the means I wouldn't submit
the mean of 2012 sales I would want to
probably submit the mean of last month's
cents so yeah we just want to think
about like how might we want to kind of
create some initial easy models and how
and later on like we might want to
weight it so for example we might want
to wait for recent dates more highly
they're probably more relevant but we
should do a whole bunch of exploratory
data analysis to check that so here's
what the bottom of that data set looks
like okay and you can see literally it's
got a date a store number and item
number and give it sales and tells you
whether or not that particular item was
on sale at that particular store on that
particular day and then there's some
Terry ID right so that's it so now that
we have read that in we can do stuff
like this is interesting again we have
to take the log of the sales and it's
the same reason as we looked at last
week right because we're trying to
predict something that kind of varies
according to ratios they told us in this
in this competition that the root mean
squared log error is something they care
about so we take a look
they mentioned also if you check the
competition details which should always
should read carefully the definition of
any project you do it's they say that
there are some negative sales that
represent returns and they tell us that
we should consider them to be zero for
the purpose of this competition so I
clip the sales so that they fall between
zero and
no particular maximum it's a clip just
means cuddle after that point truncate
it and then take the log of that plus
one why do I do plus one because again
if you check the details of the cable
competition that's what they tell you
they're going to use is they're not
actually just taking the root mean
squared log error but the root mean
squared log plus one there okay
because log of zero doesn't make sense
we can add the date part as usual and
you know again it's taking a couple of
minutes right so I would run through all
this on a sample first so everything
takes ten seconds to make sure it works
just to check everything that's
reasonable before I go back so I don't
want to wait two minutes or something I
don't know what's going to work but as
you can see all this all these lines of
code are identical to what we saw for
the bulldozers competition in this case
and all I'm bringing in is a training
set I didn't need to run trained cats
because all of my data types are already
numeric okay if they weren't I would
need to call trained cast and then I
would need to call the ply cats to apply
the same categorical codes that I down
from the training set to the validation
set I call prop D F as before to check
the missing values and so forth so all
of those lines of code are identical
these lines of code again are identical
because root mean square errors store we
care about and then I've got two changes
the first is sent our F samples which we
learnt about last week so we've got 120
something million records we probably
don't want to create a tree from our
hundred twenty million something
reckless I don't even know how long
that's going to take I haven't been
I haven't at the time and patience for
wagon see so you know you can start with
ten thousand or a hundred thousand you
know maybe runs in a few seconds make
sure it works and you can kind of figure
out how much you can run and so I found
getting it to a million
it runs in under a minute alright and so
the point here is there's no
relationship between the size of the
data set and how long it takes to build
the random forests their relationship is
between the number of estimators
multiplied by the sample size okay I'm
just curious what Angela's cousin has
always been negative one yeah so the
number of jobs is the number of cause
thursdaya news and I was running this on
a computer that has about 60 cause and I
just found if you try to use all of them
had spent so much time spending I've
drops it was doing slower so if you've
got like lots and lots of cores on your
computer sometimes you want less than
negative one means use every single core
and there's one more change I made which
is that I converted the data frame into
an array of floats and then I fit it on
that why did I do that because
internally inside the random forest code
they do that anyway right
and so given that I want to run a few
different random forests with a few
different hyper crepitus by doing it
once myself I save that minute 37
seconds right so if you run a line of
code at a text like quite a long time so
the first time I ran this random first
regressor a kind of took two or three
minutes and I thought I don't really
want to wait to a few minutes you can
always add in front of the line of code
hey run a percent P right and what
percent p run does is it runs something
called a profile and what a profiler
does is it'll tell you which lines of
code behind the teens took the most time
right and in this case I noticed that
there was a line of code inside
scikit-learn
that was this line of code
and it was taking all the time the other
day and so I thought oh I'll do that
first and then I'll pass you the result
and I won't do it again okay so this
thing of looking to see which things is
taking up the time is called profiling
and in software engineering is one of
the most important tools you have data
scientists really under appreciate this
tool that you'll find like amongst
conversations on issues or on Twitter or
whatever I'm at the top data scientists
they're sharing and talking about
profilers all the time and that's how
easy it is to get a profile so for fun
you know try running peer on from time
to time on stuff that's taking 10 20
seconds and see if you can learn to
interpret and use profile outputs you
know even though in this case I didn't
write this scikit-learn plus I was still
able to use the profile to figure out
how to make it run over twice as fast by
avoiding recalculating this each time so
in this case I build my regressor I
decided to use 20 estimators something
else that I noticed in the profiler is
that I can't use our base for when I do
is set our f samples because if I do
it's going to use the other 124 million
rows to calculate the oeob score which
is like again it's still going to take
forever so I may as well have a proper
validation set anyway besides which I
want the validation set that's the most
recent dates rather than is random so if
you use set RF samples on a large data
set
don't put the low B score parameter in
because it takes forever so that got me
a point seven six validation root mean
squared log error and then I tried like
fiddling around a different min samples
so if I decrease the min sample say from
100 to 10 it took a little bit more time
to run as we'd expect
and the arrow went down from 76 to 71 so
that looks pretty good so I kept
decreasing it down to 3 and that brought
this arrow down to 0.7 oh and when I
decrease it down to 1 we didn't really
know so I kind of had like a reasonable
random forest yeah
when I say reasonable though it's not
reasonable in the sense that it's it's
does not give a good result on the way
to one and so this is a very interesting
question about why is that and the
reason is really coming back to
Savannah's question earlier like where
my random forests not work as well let's
go back and look at the data okay here's
the entire data set that we won at the
whole data set here's all the columns
that we used so the columns that we have
to predict with are they the date the
store number the item number and weather
is unpredictable
day of week day of month day of year is
corner start etc etc so if you think
about it most of the insight you know
around like how much of something you
expect to sell tomorrow it's likely to
be very wrapped up in the details about
like what where is that store what kind
of things do they tend to sell at that
store for that item what category of
item is is it you know if it's like
fresh bread they might not sell much of
it on Sundays because on Sundays you
know and fresh bread doesn't get made
we're obvious it's gasoline maybe
they're gonna sell a lot of gasoline
because on Sundays people go and go up
there half with a wick ahead right now a
random forest has no ability to do
anything other than create a bunch of
binary splits on things like they have
week store number item number it doesn't
know which one represents gasoline it
doesn't know which stores are in the
center of the city versus which ones are
out in the
it doesn't know any of these things so
its ability to really understand what's
going on is somewhat limited so we're
probably going to need to use the entire
four years of data to even get some
useful insights but then the students
beside using the whole four years of
data and one of the data we're using is
really old so interestingly there's a
cable kernel that points out that what
you could do is just take the last two
weeks and take the average sales the
average sales by date by store number by
item number and just submit that and if
you just submit that you come about 30th
all right so for those of you in the
groceries kind of Terrace as I come into
a question I think this may have tripped
me up actually I think you said dates
store item I think it's actually store
item sales and then you mean across date
oh yeah you're right it's a store item
at one promotion
I know promotion is you know if you do
it if you do it like date as well you
end up so these each row represents
basically like a cross tabulation of all
of the sales on that date in that store
for the item so if you put date in there
as well there's only going to be one or
two items being averaged in each of
those cells which is you know too much
variation basically two spots it doesn't
give you a terrible result but it's it's
not xxx so
so your job if you are looking at this
competition and we'll talk about this in
the in the next class is how do you
start with that model and make it a
little bit better all right because if
you can then by the time we made up next
hopefully you'll be above the top 30
because you know CAG will be in Kaggle
lots of people have now taken this
kernel and submitted it and they all
have about the same score and the scores
are ordered not just by score but by
date submitted so if you now submit this
kernel you're not going to be 30th
because you're way down the list when it
was submitted all right but if you could
retire a bit better you're going to be
better than all of those people so try
and think of how can you make this a
tiny bit better I could you try to
capture seasonality and trend effects by
creating new columns like these are the
average sales in the month of August
these are the average sales for this
year yeah I think that's a great idea so
the thing for you to think about is how
to do that right and so like see if you
can see if you can make it work because
there are details to get right which I
know Terrance has been working on this
for the last week and he's got almost
crazy like the details Prez here the
details are are difficult they're not
difficult like intellectually difficult
they're kind of difficult in the way
that makes you like when I head back
your desk at to any air and like this is
something to mention in general is the
coding you do the machine learning is
like it's incredibly frustrating and
incredibly difficult not difficult like
technically but difficult like there if
you get a detail wrong
much of the time it's not going to give
you an exception it will just silently
be slightly less good than it otherwise
would have been right and if your own
peril at least you know okay well I'm
not doing as well as other people won't
haggle right but if you're not on cattle
you just don't know like you don't know
if your company's model is like half as
good as it could be because you made a
little mistake right so that's why one
of the reasons why practicing on tackle
now is great right because you're going
to get practice in finding all of the
ways in which you can infuriatingly
screw things up and you'll be amazed
like for me there's extraordinary array
array of them but as you get to know
what they are you'll start to know how
to check for them as you go right and so
the only way like you should assume
every button you press you're going to
press the wrong button right and that's
fine as long as you have a way to find
out
okay so we'll talk about that more
during the course but unfortunately
there isn't like a set of specific
things I can tell you to always do you
just always have to think like okay what
do I know about the results of this
thing I'm about to do I'll give you a
really simple example a really simple
example if you've actually created that
that basic entry entry where you do take
the mean by date by store number by own
promotion right and you've like
submitted it and you've got a reasonable
score and then you think you've got
something that's a little bit better and
you do predictions for that how about
you don't create a scatter plot showing
the predictions of your average model on
one axis versus the predictions of your
new model on the other axis you should
see that they just about form a line
right and if they don't then that's a
very strong suggestion that you screwed
something up alright so like that be an
example okay can you pass that one to
the end of that room possible instance
once those
yes so your so for a problem like this
unlike the car insurance problem on
taggle where we don't wear columns are
unnamed we know we know what the columns
representing what they are do you
how often do you pull in data from other
sources to supplement that I mean you
could maybe like weather data or you
know for example or how often is that
used very often right and so the whole
point of this star schema is that you
break the second table and then you've
got these other tables coming on third
that provide metadata about it so for
example whether it's meditating about a
date yeah on cattle specifically most
competitions have the rule that you can
use external data as long as you post on
the forum that you're using it and then
it's publicly available but you have to
check on a competition by competition
basis they will tell you outside of
cattle you should always be looking or
like what external data could I possible
leverage here okay so are we still
talking about how to tweak this data set
if you wish well I'm not familiar with
the countries here so maybe he's Ecuador
Ecuador so maybe I would Ecuador largest
grocery chain Ecuador is largest first
chain maybe I would start looking for
Ecuador's holidays and shopping holidays
maybe when they have a three-day weekend
or you know I've actually that
information is provided
in this case and so in general one way
of tackling this kind of problem is to
create lots and lots of new columns
containing things like you know average
number of sales on holidays average
percent change in sale or between
January and February and so on and so
forth and so if you have a look at
there's been a previous competition on
cattle Rossman store sales that was
almost identical it was in Germany in
this case for a major grocery chain how
many items are sold by day by item type
by store and the this case the person
who won quite unusually actually was
something of a domain expert in this
space they're actually a specialist in
doing logistics predictions and this is
basically what they did was professional
sales forecast consultant ping
he created just lots and lots and lots
of columns based on his experience of
what kinds of things can be useful for
making predictions to that but that's an
approach that can work the third-place
team did almost no feature engineering
however and also they had one big
oversight which I think they would have
won so you don't necessarily have to use
this approach so we're learning anyway
we'll be learning a lot more about how
to win this competition and ones like as
we go
they did it to you the third question so
if you google for among cattle rustlin
you'll see it the short answer is there
is a big blow so what are the things and
these are a couple of charts that so
Terrence is actually my teammate on this
competition so parents drew a couple of
these charts for us and I want to talk
about this which is if you don't have a
good validation set it's it's hard if
not impossible to create a good model so
in other words like if you're trying to
predict next month's sales and you build
a bunch you know you try to build a
model and you have no way of really
knowing whether the models you've built
are good at predicting sales a month
ahead of time then you have no way of
knowing when you put your model in
production whether it's actually going
to be any good okay so so you need a
validation set that you know is reliable
and telling you whether or not your
model is likely to work well when you
like put it into production or use it on
the test set so in this case what
Terrance has plotted here is and so
normally you should not use your test
set for anything other than using it
right at the end of the competition all
right end of the project to find out how
you've got but there's one thing I'm
going to let you use the test set for an
addition and that is to calibrate your
validation set so what Terrance did here
was he built four different models right
some which he thought would be better
than others and he submitted each of the
four models to cattle to find out its
score and so the x-axis is the score the
cattle produce on the leaderboard okay
and then on the y-axis he plotted the
score on a particular validation set he
was trying out to see whether this
validation said look like it was going
to be any good so if your validation set
is good then the relationship between
the leaderboards for by the testing
score and your validation set score
should lie in a straight line ideally
it'll actually lie on the y equals x
line but honestly that doesn't matter
too much as long as relatively speaking
it tells you which models are better
than which other models then you know
which model is the best right and you
know how it's going to perform on the
test set because you know the linear
relationship between two things okay so
in this case Terrence has managed to
come up with a validation set which is
looking like it's going to predict our
tab or leaderboards for pretty well and
that's really cool right because don't
even go away and try a hundred different
types of models feature engineering
waiting twigs paper parameters whatever
else see how they go on the validation
set and not have to submit to tackle
right so we're going to get a lot more
iterations one more feedback this is not
just true of cattle but every machine
learning project you do yeah and so if
you find so here's a different one he
tried back where it wasn't as good right
it's like oh these ones that were quite
close to each other it's showing us the
opposite direction that's a really bad
sign
it's like okay this validation set idea
didn't seem like a good idea this
validation set idea did number one good
idea so in general if your validation
set it's not showing a nice straight
line you need to think carefully like
okay how is the test set constructor why
how is my validation set different in
some way you're constructing images
which is different but I have to draw
lots of charts and so forth so one
question is and I modified two to guess
how how you did it so how they actually
tried to construct this validation set
us close today so I would try to do is
to try to sample points from the
training set that are very closer
possible to some of the points in the
test set first in what sense and I don't
know I will have to find any lectures
but in this case for this first room
4030 scrotus the last points was trying
variations off someplace right so the
most recent you know and what I noticed
was so first I looked at the date range
of the test set and then I looked at the
the kernel that described how he or she
here's the date range of the last two
weeks of August 26 that's right and then
the person who submitted the kernel that
said how to get the 0.58 leaderboard
position or whatever sport everything I
looked at the date range of that and
that was well there was actually 14 days
and the test set is 16 days but the
interesting thing is the test set begins
on the day after pay day and ends on the
pay day and so these are things I also
paid attention to but and I think that's
one of the bits of better data that they
told us you know so these are the kinds
of things you just put a like try and
like I said trick plot lots of pictures
and like even if you didn't know it was
pay day you know you would want to like
draw the time series part of sales and
you would hopefully see that like every
two weeks so it'd be a spike or whatever
you'd be like oh I want to make sure
that mine I have the same number of
spikes in my validation set that I've
had in my test day okay let's take a
five-minute break and let's come back at
2:30 to
okay so um this is my favorite bit of
interpreting machine learning models by
the way if you're looking for my
notebook about the groceries competition
you won't find it in github because I'm
not allowed to share code for running
competitions with you unless you're on
the same team as me after the
competition is finished it'll be on
github so if you're doing this for the
video you should be able to find it
so let's start by reading in our feather
file so after the file is exactly the
same as our CSV file this Israel Blue
Book for bulldozers competition so we're
trying to predict the sale price of
every industrial equipment adoption and
so reading the feather format by all
means that we've already read in the CSV
and processed it into categories and so
the next thing we do is to run property
F in order to turn the categories into
integers deal with the missing values
and pull out the hidden variable okay
this is exactly the same thing as we
used last time to create a validation
set where the validation set represents
the last couple of weeks the last twelve
thousand records by date and I
discovered thanks to one of your
excellent questions on the forum last
week I had a bug here which is that proc
Pierre was shuffling the order sorry
so doc Proctor yes and last week we saw
a particular version of property earth
where we passed in a subset and when I
passed in a subset it was randomly
shuffling and so then i said split
bowels it wasn't getting the last rose
by date but it was getting a random set
of roads so I've now fixed that so if
you really run the lesson 1rf code
you'll see slightly different results
specifically you'll see in that section
that my validation set results look less
good but that's only for this tiny
little bit where I had subset equals yes
I'm a little bit confused about the
notation here so only as is most a input
variable and this associate variable
dysfunction and yeah
why is thatis the proc DF returns a
dictionary telling you which things were
missing which columns are missing and
for each of those columns what the
median was so when you call it on like
the larger data set the non subset you
want to take that return value and you
don't pass in an energy to that weight
you just want to get back a result later
on when he planted into a subset you
want to use to have the same missing
columns and the same medians and so you
pass it in and if like this different
subsets like if it was a whole different
data set turned out had some different
missing columns it would update that
dictionary with some with additional key
values as well so it kind of you can you
don't have to pass it in if you don't
pass it in but it just gives you gives
you the information about what was
missing and the medians if you do a sit
in it uses that information for any
missing columns that that are there and
if there are some new missing columns
that will update that dictionary with
that
so it's like keeping our datasets common
information yeah it's got a keep track
of all any any missing columns that you
came across in any of anything you pass
the property yeah thank you okay so we
split it into the training and test set
just like we did last week and so to
remind you once we've done crop DF this
is what it looks like this is the log of
sale price okay so the first thing to
think about is we already know how to
get the predictions right which is we
take the average we take the average
value in each leaf node in each tree
after running a particular road through
each tree that's how we get them the
prediction but normally we don't just
want a prediction we also want to know
how confident we are of that prediction
and so we would be less confident of a
prediction if we haven't seen many
examples of roads like this one and if
we haven't seen many examples of roads
like this one then we wouldn't expect
any of the trees kind of have a path
through which which is really designed
to help us predict that road and so
conceptually you would expect then that
as you pass this unusual row through
different trees it's going to going to
end up in very different places so in
other words rather than just taking the
mean of the predictions of the trees and
saying that's a prediction what if we
took the standard deviation of the
predictions of the trees so the standard
deviation of the predictions of the
trees if that's high that means each
tree is giving us a very different
estimate of this rose prediction so if
this was a really common kind of row
right
then the trees follow forward to make
good predictions for it because it's
same lots of opportunities to split
based on those kinds of roads right so
the standard deviation of the
predictions across the trees gives us
some kind of at least relative
understanding of how confident we are of
this prediction so that is not something
which exists in scikit-learn or in any
library I know of so we have to create
it but we already have almost the exact
code we need because remember last
lesson we actually manually calculated
the averages across different sets of
trees so we can do exactly the same
thing there calculate the standard
deviations so we know I'm doing random
forest interpretation I pretty much
never use the full data set I always
call set our samples because like we
don't need a massively accurate random
forest we just need one which indicates
the nature of relationships involved
right and so I just make sure this
number is high enough that if I call the
same interpretation commands multiple
times I don't get different results back
each time that's like the rule of thumb
about how big does it need to be right
but in practice like 50,000 is an odd
number and most of the time you know it
would be surprising if that wasn't
enough and it runs in seconds so I
generally start with 50,000 so with my
50,000 samples per tree set I create 40
estimators I know from last time that
min samples we people three max features
it cost point five isn't bad and again
we're not trying to create the world's
most predictive tree anyway so that all
sounds fine we get an r-squared on the
validation set of 0.89 again we don't
particularly care but it's long as it's
good enough which it certainly is and so
here's where we can do that exact same
list comprehension as last time remember
go through each estimator at each tree
call drop predict on it with our
validation set make that a list
comprehension and pass that to NP stack
which in catenate s-- everything in that
list across a new axis okay so now our
rows are the results of each tree and
their columns are the result of each row
in the original data set and then we
remember we can calculate the mean right
so here's the prediction for a data set
row number one and here's our standard
deviation
okay so here's kind of do it for just
one observation right at the end here
we've calculated for all of them just
pretty nipple one here now this this can
take quite a while and specifically it's
not taking advantage of the fact that my
computer has lots of cause in it list
comprehensions this is this is like the
list comprehension itself is Python code
that it's my Python code and python code
unless you're doing special stuff runs
in serial which means it runs on a
single CPU doesn't take advantage of
your multi CPU hardware and so if I
wanted to run this you know on more
trees and more data you know this one
second is going to go out and you see
here the wall time the amount of actual
climate talk is roughly equal to the CPU
time where else if it was running on
lots of cause the CPU time would be
higher than the war time so it turns out
that scikit-learn provides a handy
national circuit load fast AI provides a
handy function called parallel trees
which pulls some stuff inside cyclone
and parallel trees takes two things it
takes a random forest model that I train
the here it is and
and some function to call and it calls
that function on every tree in parallel
so in other words rather than calling T
I predict X ballad let's create a
function that calls T dot predict X
salad let's use parallel trees to call
it on our model to every tree okay and
it will return a list of the result of
applying that function to every tree and
so then we can NP Don stack that so
hopefully you can see that that code and
that code are basically the same thing
right but this one is doing it in
parallel and so you can see here now our
wall time has gone down to 500
milliseconds and it's now giving this
exactly the same answer okay so a little
bit faster time committing we'll talk
about more general ways of writing code
that runs in parallel that turns out to
be super useful for data science but
here's one that we can use it's very
specific to random forests okay so what
we can now do is we can always call this
to get our predictions for each tree and
then we can call standard deviation to
then get them for every row and so let's
try using that so what I could do is
let's carried a copy of our data and
let's add an additional column to it
which is the standard deviation of the
predictions across the first axis okay
and let's also add in the name so
they're the predictions themselves so we
you might remember from last lesson that
one of the predictors we have is called
enclosure and we'll see later on but
this is an important predictor and so
let's start by just doing a histogram so
one of the nice things and panders is
it's got built in body and capabilities
it's well worth googling for pandas
plotting to see how
yes Terrence Jeremy can you remind me
what enclosure is so we don't know what
means and it doesn't matter you know
like that's the whole purpose of this
process is that we're going to pick it
out we're going to learn about what
things are or at least what things are
important and what later on figure out
what they are and how they're important
so we're going to start out knowing
nothing about this data set all right so
there's something so I'm just going to
look at something called enclosure that
has something called erupts and
something called robots and I don't even
know what this is yet
all I know is that the only three that
really appear at any great quantity are
over ops erupts whe and eros and this is
like really common as a data scientist
you know you often find yourself looking
at data that you're not that familiar
with and you've got to figure out at
baseline which fits to study more
carefully and which gets into matter and
so forth so in this case at least know
that these three groups I really don't
care about because they basically don't
exist so given that we're going to
ignore those three so we're going to
focus on this one here this one here and
this one here and so here you can see
what I've done is I've taken my data
frame and I've grouped by enclosure and
I am taking the average of these three
fields so here you can see here's the
average sale price the average
prediction and the standard deviation of
prediction for each of my three groups
so I can already start to learn a bit
here as you would expect the prediction
and the sale price are close to each
other on average so that's a good sign
and then the standard deviation varies a
little bit it's a little hard to see in
a table so what we could do is we could
try to start like printing these things
out so here we've got the sale price
or each little of enclosure and here
we've got the prediction peach level of
enclosure and for the error bars I'm
using the standard deviation of
perdition alright so here you can see
the actual and here's the prediction and
here's my confidence in the world okay
or at least it's the average of the
standard deviation of the random forests
so this tells us it'll tell us if
there's some groups or some rows that
we're not very confident of it all so we
could do something similar for product
size right so here's different product
sizes we can do exactly the same thing
of looking at our predictions under
standard deviations okay we could sort
by and what we could say is like well
what's the ratio of the standard
deviation of the predictions to the
predictions and selves right so you kind
of expect on average that when you're
predicting something that's a bigger
number that your standard deviation
would be higher all right so you can
like sort by that ratio and what that
tells us is that the product size large
and product size compact our predictions
are less accurate you know as relatively
speaking as a ratio of the total price
and so then if we go back and have a
look
well there you go that's why for the
histogram those are the smallest groups
okay so as you would expect in small
groups we're doing the less good job
right
so this confidence interval you can
really use for two main purposes one is
that you can group it up like this and
look at the average confidence interval
by group to find out are there some
groups that you just don't seem to have
confidence about about those groups but
perhaps more importantly you can look at
them for specific roads and so when you
put it in production you might always
want to see the confidence interval so
if you're doing say credit scoring so
deciding whether to give somebody alone
you probably want to see not only what's
their level of risk but how confident
are we and if they want to borrow lots
of money and we're not at all confident
or about our ability to predict whether
they'll pay it back we might want to
give them a small amount okay so those
are the two ways in which you reduce
this okay let me go to the next one
which is the most important the most
important is feature importance and the
only reason I didn't do this first is
because I think the intuitive
understanding of how to calculate
confidence interval is the easiest one
to understand entry in fact it's almost
identical to something we've already
happened right but in terms of which one
do I look at first in practice I always
look at this in Baptist so when I'm
working on whether it be a candle
competition or a real world project I
build a random forest as fast as I can
try and get it to the point that it's
led you know significantly better than
Brandon but doesn't actually much better
than that and then the next thing I do
is to plot the future importance and the
future importance tells us in this
random forest which columns mattered
right so we had like dozens and dozens
but of columns originally in this data
set and here I'm just picking out the
top ten so you can just call our F
feature importance again this is part of
the faster and ivory it's leveraging
stuff that's in scikit-learn parse in
the model pass in the data frame is
getting to know the names of columns
right and it'll tell you it author I'll
give you back a panda's data frame
showing you in order of importance how
important was each column and here on
this note pick out the top ten so we can
then plot that right so fi because it's
a data frame we can use data frame
plotting mints so here I've plotted all
of the future importances right and so
you can see here like and I haven't been
able to write all of the names of the
columns at the bottom which that's not
the important thing the important thing
is to see that some columns are really
really important and most columns don't
really matter at all and like in nearly
every data set you use in real life this
is what your feature importance is going
to look like it's going to say there's
like a handful of columns that you care
about and this is why I always start
here right because at this point in
terms of like looking into learning
about this domain heavy industrial
equipment options I only got to care
about learning about the columns which
matter right so are we going to bother
learning about enclosure depends whether
enclosure is important and
there it is it's in the top ten so we
are going to have to learn about
enclosure okay so then we could also
plot this as a bar plot all right so you
can hear I've just created a little
little tiny little function here that's
going to just plot my bars and I'm just
going to do it for the top 30 and so you
can see the same basic shape here and I
can see there's my enclosure okay
so we're going to learn about how this
is calculated in just a moment but
before you worry about how it's
calculated much more important is to
know what to do with it so the most
important thing to do with it is to now
sit down with your client or your data
dictionary or whatever your source of
information is and say to them okay tell
me about you made what does that mean
where does it come from
plot lots of things like histogram
Devere made and scatter plots of here
made against price and learn everything
you can because you're made and cupola
system they're the things that matter
right and what will often happen in
real-world projects is that you'll sit
with the client and you'll say oh it
turns out the capital system is the
second most important thing and then
they might say that makes no sense now
that doesn't mean that there's a problem
with your model it means there's a
problem with their understanding of the
data that they gave you okay so let me
give you an example I entered a cattle
competition where the goal was to
predict which applications for grants at
a university would be successful and I
used this exact approach and I
discovered a number of columns which
were almost entirely predictive of the
dependent variable and specifically when
I then looked to see in what way their
predictive it turned out whether they
were missing or not was basically the
only thing that mattered in his data set
and so later on so I ended up winning
that competition and I think a lot of it
was thanks to this insight right and so
later on
what had happened it turns out that at
that University there's you know there's
an administrative burden to fill any
other database and so for a lot of the
grant applications they don't fill in
the database for the folks whose
applications weren't accepted right so
in other words these missing values in
the data set were saying okay this grant
wasn't accepted because if it was
accepted then you know the admin folks
are going to go in and type in that
information so this is what we call data
leakage and data leakage means there's
information in the data set that I was
modeling with which the university
wouldn't have had in real life at the
point in time they were making a
decision right so when they're deciding
you know which grant applications should
I like prioritize they don't actually
know which ones the admin staff or later
I'm going to add information to because
it turns out that they've got accepted I
mean right so one of the key things
you'll find here is is data leakage
problems and that's a serious problem
you need to deal with the other thing
that will happen is you'll often find
it's signs of collinearity and I think
that's what's happened here with kapwa
system I think Kapler system tells you
whether or not a particular kind of
heavy industrial equipment has a
particular feature on it but if it's not
that kind of industrial equipment at all
it will be empty they'll be missing and
so capitalist system is really telling
you whether or not it's a certain class
of heavy industrial equipment now this
is not linkage this is actual
information you actually have at the
right time it's just that like
interpreting it you have to be careful
okay
so I would go through at least the top
10 or like kind of look for where the
natural breakpoints are and really study
these things carefully to make life
easier for myself what I tend to do is I
try to throw some data away and see if
that matters so in this case I had a
random forest which let's go and see how
accurate it was point eight nine point
eight eight nine what I did was I said
here okay let's go through our feature
importance data frame and filter out
those where the importance is greater
than 0.005 thanks 0.025 two point zero
five is about here right it's kind of
like where they really flattened off all
right so let's just keep those and so
that gives us a list of 25 column names
and so then I say okay let's now create
a new data frame view which just
contains those 25 columns
Coles flipped bowels on it again
decision to test and training set and
create a new random forest and let's see
what happens and you can see here the a
square basically didn't change eight
nine one versus eight eight nine so it's
actually increased a tiny bit right I
mean generally speaking removing
redundant columns well you know it
shouldn't
obviously it shouldn't make it worse if
it makes it worse they weren't redundant
after all it might make it a little
better because if you think about how we
built these trees when it's deciding
what to split on you know it's it's got
less things to have to worry about
trying it's less often going to like
accidentally find a crappy poem so it's
you know I've got a slightly better
opportunity to create a slightly better
tree with slightly less data
but it's still it's not going to change
it by much but it's going to make it a
bit faster and it's going to let us
focus on what matters so if I rerun
feature importance now I've now got
twenty five now the key thing that's
happened is that when you remove
redundant columns is that you're also
removing sources of collinearity right
in other words two columns that might be
related to each other
now Collini arity doesn't make your
random forests less predictive but if
you have two columns that are related to
each other you know
this column is a little bit related to
this column and this column is a strong
driver of the dependent variable now
what's going to happen is that the
importance is going to end up like kind
of split between the two collinear
columns it's going to say like well both
of those columns matter so kind of a
split between the two so by removing
some of those columns with very little
impact it makes your feature importance
block clearer and so you can see here
actually year made was pretty close to
couple system before but there must have
been a bunch of things that are
collinear with year made which makes
perfect sense right like old industrial
equipment wouldn't have had a bunch of
kind of technical features that new ones
would for example so it's actually
saying like okay you made really really
matters all right so I trust this
feature importance better you know the
predictive accuracy of the model is a
tiny bit better but this feature
importance says a lot less familiarity
to confuse us
so let's talk about how this works
it is actually really simple and not
only is it really simple it's a
technique you can use not just for
random forests but for basically any
kind of machine learning model and
interestingly almost no one knows that
like many people will tell you all this
particular kind of model there's no way
of like interpreting it and the most
important interpretation of a model is
knowing like which things are important
and that's almost certainly not going to
be true because there's technique
another teacher she actually works to
any kind of model so here's what we're
going to do we're going to take our data
set the bulldozers right and we've got
this column we're trying to predict
right which is price
and then we've got all of our
independent variables okay
so here's an independent variable here
year made right plus a whole bunch of
other variables and remember we had
after we did a bit of hemming we have 25
independent variables okay
how do we figure out how important year
made is well we've got our whole random
first but and we can find out our
predictive accuracy where so we're going
to put all of these rows through our
random forest and we're going to spit
out some predictions right and we're
going to compare them to the actual
price you get in this case for example
our root mean squared error and our R
squared and we're going to call that
like it's a starting point right so now
let's do exactly the same thing but
let's take the year made column and
randomly shuffle it so randomly permute
just that column so now you made has
exactly the same like distribution is to
follow same mean standard deviation but
it's going to have no relationship as a
dependent variable at all because we
totally randomly reorder them so before
we might have found our R squared with
point eight nine right and then after we
shuffle ear made we check again and now
it's like point eight oh that's poor got
much worse when we destroyed that
variable and it's like okay let's try
again let's put your made back to how it
was and this time let's take enclosure
and shuttle that right and we find this
time an enclosure it's point at four and
we can say okay so the amount of
decrease in our score for year made was
0.09 and the amount of decrease in our
score for enclosure was 0.05 right and
this is going to
and I'll feature importances for each
one of our columns yes wouldn't just
excluding let's say each column I'm
running running the random forests and
checking the decay in the perform yes so
you could remove the column and train a
whole new random forest but that's going
to be really slow where else this way we
can keep our random forest and just test
the predictive accuracy of it again
alright so this is nice and fast by
comparison in this case we just have to
rerun every row forward through the
forest for each shuffle column Jason
we're just basically doing predictions
of exactly okay question so if you want
to do like multi clone area would you do
two of them and random shuffle and then
three of them ran in trouble yes so I
don't think you need multicollinearity I
think you mean looking for interaction
effects yeah so if you want to say which
pairs of variables are most important
you could do exactly the same thing each
pair in in turn in practice there are
better ways to do that because that's
obviously computationally pretty
expensive and so we're trying to find
time to do that again
okay so we now have a model which is a
little bit more accurate and is we've
learned a lot more about it
[Music]
so we're out of time and so what I would
suggest you try doing now before the
next class for this bulldozes data set
it's like go through the top I don't
know five or ten predictors and try and
learn what you can about how to draw
plots and pandas and try to come back
with like some insights about like
what's the relationship between a year
made and the dependent variable what's
the histogram of year made you know try
and find you know some possible or like
now that you know you inmates really
important is there some noise in that
column which we could fix there's some
weird encodings in that column that
we've fixed this idea I had that maybe a
couple system is there entirely because
it's collinear with something else
johner we might try and figure out
whether that's true or so how would you
do it
fi product class desk that brings alarm
bells for me it sounds like it might be
a high cardinality categorical variable
it might be something with lots and lots
with levels because it sounds like it's
like a model name so like go and have a
look at that model name does it have
some order into it could you make it an
ordinal variable to make it better
it doesn't have some kind of
hierarchical structure in the stream
that we can split it on like - to create
more sub columns you don't ever think
about this you know and and so try and
make it so that you know by Tuesday when
you come back you've got some new
ideally you've got a better accuracy
than what I just showed because we found
some new insights or at least that you
can tell the class about some things
you've learnt about how heavy industrial
equipment options work in practice okay
right so your Tuesday