welcome back we're going to be talking
today about random forests we're going
to finish building our own random forest
from scratch but before we do I wanted
to tackle a few things that have come up
during the week a few questions that
I've had and I want to start with kind
of the position of random forests in
general so we spent about half of his
course doing random forests and then
after today the second half of this
course will be neural networks broadly
defined
this is because these these to represent
like the tea the two key classes of
techniques which cover nearly everything
that you're likely to need to do random
forests belong to the class of
techniques of decision tree ensembles
along with gradient boosting machines
being the other key type and some
variants like extremely randomized trees
they have the benefit that they're
highly interpretive all scalable
flexible work well for most kinds of
data they have the downside that they
don't extrapolate at all to like data
that's outside the range that you've
seen as we looked at at the end of last
week's session but you know they're
there they're a great starting point and
so
I think you know there's a huge
catalogue of machine learning tools out
there and I got lot of courses and books
don't attempt to kind of curate that
down and say like for these kinds of
problems use this for these kinds of
problems is that finished you know but
they're rather like here's a description
of 100 different algorithms and you just
don't need them you know like I don't
see why you would ever use in support
vector machine today for instance like
not know no reason at all I could think
of doing that
people love studying them in the 90s
because they are like very theoretically
elegant and like you can really write a
lot of math about support vector
machines and people did but you know in
practice I don't see them as having any
place
there's like a lot of techniques that
you could include in an exhaustive list
of every way that people adopt machine
learning problems but I would rather
tell you like how to actually solve
machine learning problems in practice I
think they you know we've we've about to
finish today the first class which is
you know one type of decision tree
ensembles in in part to you net will
tell you about the other key type there
being gradient boosting and we're about
to launch next lesson into neural nets
which includes all kinds of GLM Ridge
regression elastic net lasso logistic
regression etc or all variants of neural
nets you know interestingly
leo breiman who created random forests
did so very late in his life and
unfortunately passed away not many years
later so partly because of that very
little has been written about them in
the academic literature partly because
SVM's were just taken over at that point
you know other people didn't look at
them and also like just because they're
like quite hard to grasp at a
theoretical level like analyze them
theoretically it's quite hard to write
conference papers about them or academic
papers about them so there hasn't been
that much written about them
but there's been a real resurgence or
not resurgence a new wave in recent
years of empirical machine learning like
what actually works
kegels been part of that but also just
in part of it has just been like
companies using machine learning to make
loads of money like Amazon and
Google and so nowadays a lot of people
are writing about decision tree
ensembles in creating better software
for decision tree ensembles like like
GBM and x3 boost and Ranger 4r and
scikit-learn and so forth but a lot of
this is being done in industry rather
than academia but you know it's it's
encouraging to see there's certainly
more work being done in deep learning
than in decision tree ensembles
particularly in in academia but but
there's a lot of progress being made in
both you know if you look at like of the
packages being used today for decision
tree ensembles like all the best ones
the top five or six I don't know that
any of them really existed
five years ago you know maybe other than
like SK learn or even three years ago so
yet so that's that's been good but I
think there's a lot of work still to be
done we talked about for example
figuring out what interactions are the
most important last week and some of you
pointed out in the forum's that actually
there is such a project already for a
gradient boosting machine
which is great but it doesn't seem that
there's anything like that yet for
random forests and you know random
forests do have a nice benefit over gbms
that they're kind of harder to screw up
you know and easier to scale so
hopefully that's something that you know
this community might help fix another
question I had during the week was about
the size of your validations that how
big should it be so like to answer this
question about how big does your
validation set need to be you first need
to answer the question how how accurate
do I need help recite to know the
accuracy of this algorithm right so like
if the validation set that you have is
saying like this is 70% accurate and if
somebody said well is it 75% or 65% or
70% and the answer was I don't know
anything in that range is close enough
like that would be one answer where else
if it's like is that 70 percent or 70
point oh one percent or sixty nine point
nine nine percent like then that's
something else again
right so you need to kind of start out
by saying like how how accurate do I
need this so like for example in the
deep learning course we've been looking
at dogs versus cats images and the
models that we're looking at had about a
ninety nine point four ninety nine point
five percent accuracy on the validation
set and a validation set size was 2000
okay in fact let's do this in Excel
that'll be a bit easier so our
validation set size was 2000 and was
99.4% right so the number of incorrect
is something around one - accuracy times
and so we were getting about 12 wrong
right and the number of cats we had is
1/2 and so the number of wrong cats is
about 6 ok so then like we we run a new
model and we find instead that the
accuracy has gone to 99.2% right and
then it's like okay is this less good at
finding cats that's like well it got 2
more cats wrong
so it's like probably not right so but
then it's like well does this matter
there's ninety nine point four versus
ninety nine point two matter and if this
was like it wasn't about cats and dogs
but it was about finding fraud right
then the difference between a point six
percent error rate and a point eight
percent error rate is like twenty five
percent of your cost of fraud
so like that can be huge like it's
really interesting like when imagenet
came out earlier this year the new
competition results came out and the
accuracy had gone down from three
percent so the error went down from
three percent to two percent and I saw a
lot of people on the internet like
famous machine learning researchers
being like yeah some Chinese guys got it
better from like 97% to one ninety eight
percent it's like statistically not even
significant who cares kind of a thing
but actually I thought like holy crap
this Chinese team just blew away the
state-of-the-art an image recognition
like the old one was fifty percent less
accurate than the new one like that's
that's actually the right way to think
about it isn't it because it's like you
know we were trying to recognize you
know like which tomatoes were ripe and
which ones weren't and like our new
approach you know the old approach like
fifty percent of the time more was like
letting in the unripe Tomatoes or you
know 50 percent more of the time we were
like accepting fraudulent customers like
that's a really big difference so just
because like this particular validation
set we can't really see six versus eight
doesn't mean the 0.2% different isn't
important it could be so my kind of rule
of thumb is that this like this number
of like how many observations you
actually looking at I want that
generally to be somewhere higher than
twenty-two why 22 because 22 is the
magic number where the t-distribution
roughly turns into the normal
distribution right so as you may have
learned the T distribution is is the
normal distribution for small data sets
right and so in other words once we have
twenty-two of
thing or more it kind of starts to
behave kind of normally in both sense of
the words like it's kind of more stable
and you can kind of understand it better
so that's my magic number when somebody
says do I have enough of something I
kind of start out by saying like do you
have 22 observations of the thing of
interest so if you were looking at like
Lyme cancer you know and you had a data
set that had like a thousand people
without lung cancer and 20 people with
lung cancer I'd be like I very much
doubt we're going to make much progress
you know because we haven't even got 20
of the thing you want so ditto with a
validation set if you don't have twenty
of the thing you want that is very
unlikely to be useful or if like the at
the level of accuracy we need it's not
plus or minus 20 it's just it's that
that's the point where I'm thinking like
be a bit careful so just to be clear you
want 22 to be the number of samples in
each set like in the validation the test
and the Train
so what I'm saying is like if there's if
there's less than 22 of a class in any
of the sets then it's it's going to get
it's getting pretty unstable at that
point right and so like that's just like
the first rule of thumb but then what I
would actually do is like start
practicing what we learned about the
binomial distribution or actually very
weak distribution so what's the what is
the mean of the binomial distribution of
n samples and probability P n times P
okay thank you and times P is that mean
all right so if you've got a 50% chance
of getting ahead and you toss it a
hundred times on average you get 50
heads okay and then what's the standard
deviation and P 1 minus B okay so these
are like two numbers
the first number you don't have to
remember it's intuitively obvious the
second one is one that try to remember
forevermore because not only does it
come up all the time the people that you
work with we'll all have forgotten it so
you'll be like the one person in the
conversation who could immediately go we
don't have to run this 100 times I can
tell you straight away
it's binomial it's going to be NP q NP 1
minus B then there's the standard error
the standard error is if you run a bunch
of trials each time getting a mean what
is the standard deviation of the mean I
don't think you guys are covered this
yet is that right No
so this is really important because this
means like if you train a hundred models
right each time the validation set
accuracy is like the meaning of a
distribution and so therefore the
standard deviation of that validation
set accuracy it can be calculated with
the standard error and this is equal to
the standard deviation divided by square
root n all right so this tells you so
like one approach to figuring out like
is my validation set big enough is train
your model five times with exactly the
same hyper parameters each time and look
at the validation set accuracy each time
and give you know there's like a mean
and a standard deviation of five numbers
you could use or a maximum and a minimum
you can choose but to save yourself some
time you can figure out straight away
that like okay well I I have a point
nine nine accuracy as to you know
whether I get the cat correct or not
correct
so therefore the standard deviation is
equal to 0.99 times 0.01 okay and then I
can get the standard error of that right
so so basically the size of the
validation set you need
it's like however big it has to be such
that your insights about
accuracy good enough for your particular
business problem and so like I say like
the simple way to do it is to pick a
validation set of like a size of
thousand trained five models and see how
much the validation set accuracy varies
and if it's like if they're if it's
they're all close enough for what you
need then you're fine if it's not maybe
you should make it bigger or maybe you
should consider using cross-validation
instead okay so like as you can see it
really depends on what it is you're
trying to do how common you're less
common class is and how accurate your
model is could you pass that back to
Melissa please thank you I have a
question about the less common classes
if you have less than 22 let's say you
have one sample of something let's say
it's a face and I only have one
representation from that particular
country do I toss that into the training
set and it adds variety to I pull it out
completely out of the data set or do I
put it in a test set instead of the
validation set so he certainly couldn't
put it in the test of the validation set
because you're asking kind of I mean in
general because you're asking can I
recognize something I've never seen
before but actually this this question
of like can I recognize something I've
not seen before there's actually a whole
class of models specifically for that
purpose it's called either one-shot
learning which is you get to see
something once and you have to recognize
it again or zero shot learning which is
where you have to recognize something
you've never seen before we're not going
to cover them in this course but they
can be useful for things like face
recognition you know like is this the
same person I've seen before and so
generally speaking obviously for
something like that to work it's not
that you've never seen a face before
it's that you've never seen Melissa's
face before you know and so you see
Melissa's face once and you have to
recognize it again
yeah so in general you know your
validation set and test set need to have
the same mix or frequency observations
that you're going to see in production
in the real world and then your training
set should have an equal number in each
class and if you don't just replicate
the less common one until it is equal so
this is I think we've mentioned this
paper before a very recent paper that
came out they tried lots of different
approaches to training with unbalanced
datasets and found consistently that
over sampling the less common class
until that is the same size as the more
common class is always the right thing
to do so you could literally copy you
know so like I've only got a thousand
you know ten examples of people with
cancer and 100 without so I could just
copy those 10 and other you know 90
times that's kind of a little memory and
efficient so a lot of things including I
think SK learns random forests have a
class weights parameter that says each
time your boot strapping or resampling I
want you to sample the less common class
with a higher probability or did or if
you do and doing deep learning you know
make sure in your mini batch it's not
randomly sampled but it's a stratified
sample so the less common class is
picked more often okay okay so let's get
back to finishing off our random forests
and so what we're going to do today is
we're going to finish off writing our
random forests and then after day you're
after today your homework will be to
take this class and to add to it all of
the random forest interpretation
algorithms that we've learned ok so
obviously to be able to do that you're
going to need to totally understand how
this class works so please you know ask
lots of questions
as necessary as we go along so just to
remind you
we're doing the the bulldozers tackle
competition data set again we split it
as before into 12,000 validation the
last 12,000 records and then just to
make it easier for us to keep track of
what we're doing we're going to just
pick two columns out to start with year
made and Machine hours on the meter okay
and so what we did last time was we
started out by creating a tree ensemble
and the tree ensemble had a bunch of
trees which was literally a list of
entries trees where each time we just
called create tree and create tree
contained a sample size number of random
indexes okay this one is drawn without
replacement
so remember bootstrapping means sampling
with replacement so normally with
scikit-learn if you've got n rows we
grab n rows with replacement which means
many of them will appear more than once
so each time we get a different sample
but it's always the same size as the
original data set and then we have our
set our F samples a function that we can
use which does with replacement sampling
of less than n rows this is doing
something again which is its sampling
without replacement sample size rows
okay because we're permuting the numbers
from naught to self dot y -1 and then
grabbing the first self dot sample size
of them actually there's a faster way to
do this you can just use NPR and embrace
which is a slightly more direct way but
this way it works as well alright so
this is our random sample for this one
of our entries trees add so then we're
going to create a decision tree and our
decision tree we don't pass it all of X
we pass it these specific indexes and
remember X is a panda's data frame so if
we want to index into it with a bunch of
integers we
to use iLok integer locations and that
makes it behave indexing wise just like
numpy now why vector is numpy so we can
just index into it directly and then
we're going to keep track about minimum
of each size and so then the only other
thing we really need an ensemble is
somewhere to make a prediction and so we
were just going to do the mean of the
tree prediction for each tree all right
so that was that and so then in order to
be able to run that we need a decision
tree class because it's being called
here and so there we go okay so that's
the starting point so the next thing we
need to do is to flesh out our decision
tree so the important thing to remember
is all of our randomness happened back
here in the tree ensemble the decision
tree class we're going to create doesn't
have randomness in it okay so all right
now we are building a random B regressor
right so that's why we're taking the
mean of the tree the outputs if we were
to work with classification do we take
the max like the classifier will give
you either zeros or ones no I would
still take the mean so the so each tree
is going to tell you what percentage of
that leaf node contains cats and what
percentage to take contains dogs so then
I would average all those percentages
and say across the trees on average
there is 19% cats and 81 percent dogs
good question so you know random tree
classifiers are almost identical or can
be almost identical the random tree
regresses the technique we're going to
use to build this today will basically
exactly work for a classification it's
certainly for binary classification you
can do with exactly the same code for
multi-class classification you just need
to change your data structure but so
that like you have like a one hot
encoded matrix or a list of integers
that you treat as a one hot encoded
matrix okay so our decision tree so
remember our idea here is that we're
going to like try to avoid thinking so
we're going to basically write it as if
everything we need already exists okay
so we know from when we created the
decision tree we're kind of pass in the
X the Y and the minimum leaf size so
here we need to make sure we've got the
X and the y and the minimum left sides
okay so then there's one other thing
which is as we split our tree into sub
trees we're going to need to keep track
of which of the row indexes went into
the left-hand side of the tree which
went into the right-hand side of the
tree
okay so we're going to have this thing
called indexes as well right so at first
we just didn't bother passing and
indexes at all so if indexes is not
passed in if it's none then we're just
going to set it to everything the entire
length of Y right so NP dot a range is
the same as just range in Python but it
returns an umpire rate right so that the
root of a decision tree contains all the
roads that's the definition really of
the root of a decision tree so all the
rows is Rho naught Rho 1 Rho 2 etc up to
row y -1 okay
is going to store away all that
information that we were given we're
going to keep track of how many rows are
there and how many columns are there
okay
so then the every leaf and every node in
a tree has a value it has a prediction
that prediction is just equal to the
average of the dependent variable okay
so every node in the tree Y indexed with
the indexes is the values of the
dependent variable that are in this
branch of the tree and so here is the
main some nodes in a tree also have a
score which is like how effective was
the split here right but that's only
going to be true if it's not a leaf node
right a leaf node has no further splits
and at this point when we create a tree
we haven't done any splits yet so it's
score starts out as being infinity okay
so having built that the root of the
tree our next job is to find out which
variable should we split on and what
level of that variable should we split
on so let's pretend that there's
something that does them find bass bit
so then we're done okay
so how do we find a variable to split on
so well we could just go through each
potential variable so C contains the
number of columns we have so go through
each one and see if we can find a better
split than we have so far on that column
okay now notice this is like not the
full random forest definition this is
assuming that max features they're set
to all right remember we could set max
features too like 0.5 in which case we
wouldn't check all the numbers should
not to see we would check half the
numbers at random from not to see so if
you want to turn this into like a random
forest that has the max features support
we could easily like add one line of
code to do that but we're not going to
do it in our implementation today so
then we just need to find better split
and since we're not interested in
thinking at the moment for now we're
just going to leave that empty alright
so there one other thing I like to do
with my kind of word start writing a
class is I'd like to have some way to
print out what's in that class all right
and so if you type print followed by an
object or if it Jupiter notebook you
just type the name of the object at the
moment it's just printing out underscore
underscore main underscore underscore
got decision tree at blah blah blah
which is not very helpful right so if we
want to replace this with something
helpful we have to define the special
Python method named dan direct crack to
get a representation of this object so
when we type when we see please just
write the name like this behind the
scenes that calls that function and the
default implementation of that method is
just to print out this unhelpful stuff
so we can replace it by instead saying
let's create a format string where we're
going to print out N and then show N and
then print vowel and then show Val okay
so how many how many rows are in this
node and what's the average of the
dependent variable
okay then if it's not a leaf node so if
it has a split then we should also be
able to print out the score the value we
split out and the variable that we split
on now you'll notice here self dot is
leaf is leaf is defined as a method but
I don't have any parentheses after it
this is a special kind of method code of
property and so a property is something
that kind of looks like a regular
variable but it's actually calculated on
the fly so when I call is leaf it
actually calls this function right but
I've got this special decorator property
okay
and what this says is basically you
don't have to include the parentheses
when you call it okay and so it's going
to say all right is this a leaf or not
so a leaf is something that we don't
spit on if we haven't split on it then
it's score is still set to infinity so
that's my logic that makes sense
so this uh this at notation is called a
decorator it's basically a way of
telling Python more information about
your method does anybody here remember
where you have seen decorators before
we pass it over you
yeah where have you seen that where have
you seen decorators tell us more about
flask and Wow
yeah what is that - that no words
so flasks so anybody who's done any web
programming before with something like
flask or a similar framework would have
had to have said like this method is
going to respond to this bit of the URL
and either to post or to get and you put
it in a special decorator so
behind-the-scenes that's telling Python
to treat this method in a special way so
here's another decorator okay and so you
know if you get more advanced with
Python you can actually learn how to
write your own decorators which as was
mentioned you know basically insert some
additional code but for now just know
there's a bunch of predefined decorators
we can use to change how our methods
behave and one of them is a property
which basically means you don't have to
put parentheses anymore which of course
means you can't add any more parameters
beyond self.y if it's not belief why is
this for infinity because infinity mean
you're at the root why no infinity means
that you're not at the root it means
you're at a leaf so the root will have a
split assuming we find one but
everything will have a split till we get
all the way to the bottom and leaf and
so the leaves will have a score of
infinity because they won't split great
all right so that's our decision tree it
doesn't do very much but at least we can
like create an ensemble right ten trees
sample size a thousand right and we can
make print out so now when I go M trees
zero
it doesn't say blah blah blah blah blah
it says what we asked it to say n called
the thousand now : 10.8 oh wait okay and
this is the leaf because we haven't spit
on it yet so we've got nothing more to
say
okay so then the indexes are all the
numbers from nought to a thousand okay
because the base of the tree has
everything this is like everything in
the random sample that was passed to it
because remember by the time we get to
the point where it's a decision tree
where we don't have to worry about any
of the randomness in the random forest
anymore okay all right so let's try to
write the thing which finds a split okay
so we need to implement find better
split okay and so it's going to take the
index of a variable variable number one
variable number three whatever and it's
going to figure out what's the best blit
point is that better than any split we
have so far and for the first variable
the answer will always be yes because
the best one so far is none at all which
is infinity bad okay so let's start by
making sure we've got something to
compare to so the thing we're going to
compare two will be scikit-learn x'
random forest and so we need to make
sure that psychic learns random forest
gets exactly the same data that we have
so we start out by creating ensemble
grab a tree out of it and then find out
which particular random sample of x and
y did this tree use okay and we're going
to store them away so that we can pass
them to scikit-learn so we have exactly
the same information so let's go ahead
and now create a random forest using
scikit-learn
so one tree one decision
no bootstrapping so the whole the whole
data set that's oh this should be
exactly the same as the thing that we're
going to create this tree okay so let's
try so we need to define find better
split okay so fine better split takes a
variable okay so let's define our x
independent variables and say okay well
it's everything inside our tree but only
those indexes that are
in this node right which at the top of
the tree is everything all right and
just this one variable okay and then for
our Y's it's just whatever a dependent
variable is at the indexes in this node
okay so there's our X&amp;Y so let's now go
through every single value in our
independent variable and so I'll show
you what's going to happen so let's say
our independent variable is um ade
and not going to be an order right and
so we're going to go to the very first
row and we're going to say okay yeah
mate here is three right and so what I'm
going to do is I'm going to try and
calculate the score if we decided to
branch on the number three alright so I
need to know which rows are greater than
three which rows are less than equal to
three and they're going to become my
left-hand side my right hand side but
and then we need a score right so
there's lots of schools we could use so
in random forests we call this the
information gain right the information
gain is like how much better does our
score get because we split it into these
two groups of data there's lots of ways
we could calculate it Jinni
cross-entropy root mean squared error
whatever if you think about it there is
an alternative formulation of root mean
squared error which is mathematically
the same to within a constant scale but
it's a little bit easier to deal with
which is we're gonna try and find a
split which the causes the two groups to
each have as lower standard deviation as
possible right so like I want to find a
spirit that puts all the cats over here
and all the dogs over here right so if
these are all cats and these are all
dogs then this has a standard deviation
of zero and this has a standard
deviation of zero or else this is like a
total around a mix of cats and dogs this
is a totally random mix of cats and dogs
they're going to have a much higher
standard deviation
make sense and so it turns out if you
find a split that minimizes those group
standard deviations or specifically the
weighted average of the true standard
deviations it's mathematically the same
as minimizing the root mean square error
that's something you can prove to
yourself after class if you want to okay
so we're going to need to find first of
all split this into two groups so
where's all the stuff that is greater
than three so greater than three is this
one this one and this one so we need the
standard deviation of that so let's go
ahead and say standard deviation of
greater than three that one that one and
that one okay and then the next will be
the standard deviation of less than or
equal to three so that would be that one
that one that one and then we just take
the weighted average of those two and
that's our score that would be our score
if we split on three that make sense and
so then the next step would be try to
spit on four try spitting on one try
spitting on six redundantly try
splitting on four again redundantly try
spitting on one again and find out which
one works best so that's our code here
is we're going to go through every row
and so let's say okay left hand side is
any values in X that are less than or
equal to this particular value our right
hand side is every value in X that are
greater than this particular value
okay so what's the data type that's
going to be in LHS and RHS what are they
actually going to contain
they're going to be arrays arrays of
what
rays of erosive audience yeah which we
can treat a zero and one okay so LHS
will be an array of false every time
it's not less than or equal to and true
otherwise and RHS will be a boolean
array of the opposite okay and now we
can't take a standard deviation of an
empty set right so if there's nothing
that's greater than this number then
these will all be false which means the
sum will be zero okay and in that case
let's not go any further with this step
because there's nothing to take the
standard deviation of and it's obviously
not a useful split okay so assuming
we've got this far we can now calculate
the standard deviation of the left-hand
side and of the right-hand side and take
the weighted average or the sums the
same thing to us to a scaler right and
so there's a score and so we can then
check is this better than our best score
so far and our best score so far we
initially initialized it to infinity
right so initially this is this is
better so if it's better let's store
away
well as the information we need which
variable has found this better split
what was the score we found and what was
the value that we spit on okay so there
it is so if we run that and I'm using
time it so what time it does is that
sees how long this command takes to run
and it tries to give you a kind of
statistically valid measure of that so
you can see here it's run run at ten
times to get an average and then it's
done that seven times to get a mean and
standard deviation across runs and so
it's taking me 75 milliseconds plus or
minus ten okay so let's check that this
works find bladder split tree zero so
zero is year made one is machine hours
current meter so I with one we got back
machine hours current meter thirty seven
four four with this score and then we
ran it again with zero that's year made
and we've got a better score 658 and
split 1974 and so 1974 let's compare
yeah that was what this treated as well
okay so we've got we've confirmed that
this method is doing is giving the same
result that as K loans random forests
did okay and you can also see here the
value 10 point oh eight and again
matching here the value ten point oh
eight okay
so we've got something that can find
once bit could you pass that to your net
please
so Jeremy why don't we put a unique on
the eggs there because I'm not trying to
optimize the performance yet but do you
see that no like he is doing more yeah
so it's like and you can see in the
excel I like checked this one twice I
check this four twice unnecessarily yeah
okay so and so you're not already
thinking about performance which is good
so tell me what is the computational
complexity of this section of the code
and and like ever think about it but
also like feel free to talk us through
it if you want to kind of think and talk
at the same time what's the
computational complexity of this piece
of code
can I pass it over there yes all right
Jay take us through your thought process
I think you have to take each different
values through the column to calculate
it once to see those splits so and then
compare
oh the cup like all the possible
combinations between these different
values so that can be expensive like
this yours
huh can you do somebody else would have
tell us the actual computational
complexity so like yeah quite high
Jayde's thinking how high
I think it's great okay so tell me why
is it N squared Oh because for the full
loop it is in yes and I think I guess
the standard deviation well ticket in so
it's in square okay
or um this one maybe is even is yet to
know like this is like which ones are
less than X I I'm gonna have to check
every value to see if it's less than X I
okay and so so it's useful to know like
how do I quickly calculate computational
complexity I can guarantee most of the
interviews you do are going to ask you
to calculate computational complexity on
the fly and it's also like when you're
coding you want it to be second nature
so the technique is basically is there a
loop okay with then we're obviously
doing this end times
okay so there's an N involved it's there
a loop inside the loop if there is then
you need to multiply those two together
in this case there's not is there
anything inside the loop that's not a
constant time thing so you might see a
sort in there and you just need to know
that sort is n log n like that should be
second nature if you see a matrix
multiply you need to know what that is
in this case there are some things that
are doing element wise array operations
right so keep an eye out for anything
where lump I is doing something to every
value of an array in this case is
checking every value of x against a
constant so it's going to have to do
that n times so to flesh this out into a
computational complexity you just take
the number of things in the loop and you
multiply it by the highest computational
complexity inside the loop n times n is
N squared and you pass them in this case
couldn't we just pre sort the list and
then do like 1 + log n computation
there's lots of things we can do to
speed this up so at this stage is just
like what is the computational
complexity we have and but absolutely
it's certainly not as good as it can be
okay
so and that's where we're going to go
next just like alright N squared is not
is not great so let's try and make it
better
so here's my attempt at making it better
and the idea is this ok who wants to
first of all tell me
what's the equation for standard
deviation Masha can you grab the pose so
for the standard deviation it's the
difference between the value and its
mean it's we take a square root of that
so that we take the the power of two
then we sum up all of these situations
and we take the square root out of all
this sum yeah you have to fight divided
by M yep yep great
good okay now in practice we don't
normally use that formulation because it
kind of requires us calculating you know
X minus the mean lots of times does
anybody know the formulation that just
requires X and x squared anybody happen
to know that one yes at the back can I
pass that back there
square root of a mean of squares -
squared off mean yeah great mean of
squares minus the square of the means
right so that's a really good 1/8 that's
a really good one to know because like
you can now calculate variances or
standard deviations of anything you just
have to first of all grab the column as
it is the column squared right and as
long as you've got those stored away
somewhere you can immediately calculate
the standard deviation so the reason
this is handy for us is that if we first
of all sort our data right let's go
ahead and sort our data then if you
think about it as we kind of start going
down one step at a time right then each
group it's exactly the same as the
previous group on the left hand side
with one more thing in it and on the
right hand side with one less thing in
it so given that we just have to keep
track of some of X and some of x squared
we can just add one more thing to X one
more thing - x squared on the left and
remove one thing on the right okay so we
don't have to go through the whole lot
each time and so we can turn this into a
order n algorithm so that's all I do
here is I sort the data right and
they're going to keep track of the count
of things on the right the sum of things
on the right and the sum of squares on
the right and initially everything's on
the right hand side
okay so initially n is the count Y sum
is the sum on the right and Y squared
sum is the sum of squares on the right
and then nothing is initially on the
left so it's zeros okay and then we just
have to loop through each observation
right and
add one to the left hand count subtract
one from the left right hand count add
the value to the left hand count
subtract it from the right hand count
add the value squared to the left hand
subtract it from the right hand okay now
we do need to be careful though because
if we're saying less than or equal to
one say we're not stopping here we're
stopping here like we have to have
everything in that group so the other
thing I'm going to do is I'm just going
to make sure that the next value is not
the same as this value if it is I'm
going to skip over it
right so I'm just going to double check
that this value and the next one aren't
the same okay so as long as they're not
the same I can keep going ahead and
calculate my standard deviation now
passing in the count the sum and the sum
squared right and there's that formula
okay the sum is squared divided by the
square of the sum so i minus the square
of the sum i do that's the right hand
side and so now we can calculate the
weighted average score just like before
and all of these lames are now the same
okay
so we've turned our order and square an
algorithm into an order n algorithm and
in general stuff like this is going to
get you a lot more value than like
pushing something onto a spark cluster
or ordering faster ram or using more
cores and your cpu or whatever right
this is the way you want to be you know
improving your code and specifically
write your code right without thinking
too much about performance run it is it
fast enough for what you need then
you're done if not profile it right so
in Jupiter instead of seeing percent
time at you say % p run and it will tell
you exactly where the time was spent in
your algorithm and then you can go to
the bit that's actually taking the time
and think about like okay is this this
is algorithmically as efficient as a
can be okay so in this case we run it
and we've gone down from 76 milliseconds
to less than 2 milliseconds and now some
people that are new to programming think
like oh great I've saved 60 something
milliseconds but the point is this is
going to get run like tens of millions
of clients okay so the 76 millisecond
version is so slow that it's got to be
impractical for any random forest you
using in practice right where else the
one millisecond version I found is
actually quite quite acceptable and then
check the numbers should be exactly the
same as before and oh yeah okay
so now that we have a function find
better split that does what we want I
want to insert it into my decision tree
class and this is a really cool Python
trick Python does everything dynamically
right so we can actually say the method
called find better split in decision
tree is that function I just created and
that might sticks it inside that class
now I'll tell you what's slightly
confusing about this is that this thing
this word here and this word here they
actually have no relationship to each
other
they just happen to have the same
letters in the same order right so like
I could call this find better split
underscore foo right and then I could
like call that right and call that right
so now my function is actually called
fine better split underscore foo but my
method I'm expecting to call something
called decision tree dot fine better
split all right so here I could say
decision tree dot fine better split
equals find better split underscore foo
okay
you see that's the same thing okay so
like it's important to understand how
namespaces
work like in in every language that you
use one of the most important things is
kind of understanding how how it figures
out what a name refers to so this here
means find better split as to find
inside this class right and nowhere else
right well I mean there's a parent class
but never mind about that
this one here means find better split
fou in the global namespace a lot of
languages don't have a global namespace
that Python does okay and so the two are
like even if they happen to have the
same letters in the same order they're
not referring in any way to the same
thing that makes sense it's like this
family over here may have somebody
called Jeremy and my family has somebody
called Jeremy and our names happen to be
the same but we're not the same person
okay great so now that we've stuck the
decision tree sorry I did a fine Bettis
flip method inside the decision tree
with his new definition when I now call
the tree ensemble constructor all right
the decision tree ensemble instructor
called create tree create tree
instantiated decision tree decision tree
called find vas whit which went through
every column to see if it could find a
better split and we've now defined find
better split
and therefore tree ensemble when we
create it has gone ahead and done this
wet
that makes sense don't have any anybody
have any questions uncertainties about
that like we're only creating one single
split so far
all right so this is pretty pretty neat
right we kind of just do a little bit at
a time
testing everything as we go and so it's
as as as you all implement the random
forest interpretation techniques you may
want to try programming this way too
like every step check that you know what
you're doing matches up with what
scikit-learn does or with a test that
you've built or whatever so at this
point we should try to go deeper very
inception right so let's go now max
depth is two and so here is what
scikit-learn did after breaking it in
made 74 it then broke at Machine hours
later
29:56 so we had this thing called find
violet right which just went through
every column and try to see if there's a
better split there
all right but actually we need to go a
bit further than that not only do we
have to go through every column and see
if there's a better split in this node
but then we also have to see whether
there's a better split in the left and
the right sides that we just created
right in other words the left right side
and the right-hand side should become
decision trees themselves right so
there's no difference at all between
what we do here to create this tree and
what we do here to create this tree
other than this one contains 159 samples
and this one contains a thousand so this
row of codes exactly the same as we had
before
right and then we check it actually we
could do this a little bit easier we
could say if self dot is leaf right
would be the same thing hey don't leave
it here for now
so it's self dot score so if the score
is infinite still let's write it
properly
yes wait so let's go back up and just
remind ourselves is leaf is self that's
poor equals in okay so since it's there
we mostly use it so if it's a leaf node
then we have nothing further to do right
so that means we're right at the bottom
there's no split that's been made okay
so we don't have to do anything further
on the other hand if it's not a leaf
node so it's somewhere back earlier on
then we need to split it into the left
hand side and the right hand side now
earlier on we created a left hand side
in the right hand side array of
bullying's
right now better would be to have here
we have an array of indexes and that's
because we don't want to have a full
array of all the volumes in every single
node right because remember although it
doesn't look like there are many nodes
when you see a tree of this size when
it's fully expanded the bottom level if
there's a minimum leaf size of one
contains the same number of nodes as the
entire data set and so if every one of
those contained a full boolean array of
size of the whole data set you've got
squared memory requirements which would
be bad right on the other hand if we
just store the indexes there for things
in this node and that's going to get
smaller and smaller
okay so NP non zero is exactly the same
as just this thing which gets the
boolean array but it turns it into the
indexes of the truths okay so this is
now a list of indexes for the left-hand
side and indexes to the right-hand side
alright so now that we have the indexes
the left-hand side and the right-hand
side we can now just go ahead and create
a decision tree okay so there's a
decision tree for the left and there's
our decision tree for the right okay and
we don't have to do anything else we've
already written these we already have a
function of a constructor that can
create a decision tree
so like when you really think about what
this is doing it kind of hurts your head
right because the reason the whole
reason that fine vast bit got called is
because find vasp lit is called by the
decision tree constructor but then the
decision tree that then find vast bit
itself then causes the decision tree
constructor so we actually have circular
recursion and I'm not nearly smart
enough to be able to think through
recursion so I just choose not to write
like I just write what I mean and then I
don't think about it anymore right like
what do I want well to find a
variable-speed I've got to go through a
few column see if there's something
better
it had managed to do a split figure out
left-hand side of the right-hand side
and make them into decision trees okay
but now try to think through how these
two methods call each other would just
drive me crazy but I don't need to write
I know I have a decision tree
constructor that works no no no I have a
vine up find basket that works so that's
it right that's how I do recursive
programming is by pretending I don't I
just just ignore it that's my advice
a lot of you are probably smart enough
to be able to think through it better
than I can so that's fine if you can all
right so now that I've written that
again I can patch it into the decision
tree class and as soon as I do the tree
ensemble constructor will now use that
right because pythons dynamic right
that's just happens automatically so now
I can check my left-hand side
should have 159 samples right and a
value of nine point six six
there it is 159 samples nine point six
six right hand side huh 841 10.15 the
left hand side of the left hand side 150
samples nine point six to 150 samples
nine point six - okay so you can see
like I'm because I'm not nearly clever
enough to write machine learning
algorithms like not only can I not write
them correctly the first time
often like every single line I write
will be wrong right so I always start
from the assumption that the the line of
code I just typed is almost certainly
wrong and I just have to see why and how
right and so like I just make sure and
so eventually I get to the point where
like much to my surprise it's not broken
anymore you know
so here I can feel like okay this it
would be surprising if all of these
things accidentally happen to be exactly
the same as scikit-learn so this is
looking pretty good okay so now that we
have something that can build a whole
tree where you want to have something
that can calculate predictions right and
so remind you we already have something
that calculates predictions for a tree
ensemble by calling trade-up predict but
there is nothing called treetop predict
so we're gonna have to write that
to make this more interesting let's
start bringing up the number of columns
that we use let's create our tree
ensemble again and this time let's go to
a maximum depth of three okay so now our
tree is getting more interesting
and let's now define how do we create a
set of predictions for a tree and so a
set of predictions for a tree is simply
the prediction for a row for every row
that's it all right that's our
predictions so the predictions for a
tree are every rows predictions in an
array okay so again we're like skipping
thinking thinking's hard you know
so let's just like keep pushing it back
this is kind of Handy right notice that
you can do four
in array with an umpire array regardless
of the rank of the array regardless of
the number of axes in the array and what
it does is it will look through the
leading axis at least these concepts are
going to be very very important as we
get into more and more neural networks
because we're going to be all doing
tensor computations all the time so the
leading axis that the vector is the
vector itself the leading axis of a
matrix are the rows the leading access
axis of a three dimensional tensor the
matrices that represent the slices and
so forth right so in this case because X
is a matrix this is going to look
through the rows and if you write your
kind of tensor code this way then it'll
kind of tend to generalize nicely to
higher dimensions like it doesn't really
mention matter how many dimensions are
in X this is going to loop through each
of the leading axis okay so we can now
call that decision tree do I predict
alright so all I need to do is write
predict row right and I've delayed
thinking so much which is great that the
actual point where I actually have to do
the work it's now basically trivial so
if we're at a leaf no then the
prediction is just equal to whatever
that value was which we calculated right
back in the original tree constructor is
to assist the average of the Y's right
if it's not a leaf node then we have to
figure out whether to go down the
left-hand path or the right-hand path to
get the prediction right so if this
variable in this row is less than or
equal to that thing we decided the
amount we decided to split on then we go
down the left path otherwise we go down
the right path okay and then having
figured out what path we want which tree
we want then we can just call predict
row on that right and again we've
accidentally created something recursive
again I don't want to think about how
that works control flow wise or whatever
but I don't need to because like I just
it just does like I just told it what I
wanted so I'll trust it to work right if
it's a leaf return the value otherwise
return the prediction for the left hand
side or the right hand side as
appropriate there notice this here this
if has nothing to do with this if all
right this if is a control flow
statement that tells Python to go down
on that path or that path to do some
calculation this if is an operator that
returns a value so those of you that
have done C or C++ will recognize it as
being identical to that it's called the
ternary operator all right if you
haven't that's fine basically what we're
doing is we're going to get a value
where we're going to say it's this value
if this thing is true and that value
otherwise and so you could write it
this way right but that would require
writing four lines of code to do one
thing and also require you to code that
if you read it to yourself or to
somebody else is not at all naturally
the way you would express it right I
want to say the tree I going to go down
is the left-hand side if the variables
less than the split or the right-hand
side otherwise right so I want to write
my code the way I would think about all
the way I would say my code okay so this
kind of ternary operator can be quite
helpful for that alright so now that
I've got a prediction for a row I can
dump that into my class and now I can
create calculate predictions and I can
now plot my actuals against my
predictions when you do a scatter plot
you'll often have a lot of dots sitting
on top of each other so a good trick is
to use alpha alpha means how transparent
the things not just a map plot lib but
like in every graphics package in the
world pretty much and so if you set
alpha to less than 1 then this is saying
you would need 20 dots on top of each
other for it to be fully blue and so
this is a good way to kind of see how
much things are sitting on top of each
other so it's a good trick but trick the
scatter plots
there's my R squared not bad
and so let's now go ahead and do a
random forest with no max mana spitting
and our tree ensemble had no max amount
of spitting we can compare our R squared
- there are squared and so they're not
the same but actually ours is a little
better so I don't know what we did
differently but we'll take it
okay so we have now something which for
a forest with a single tree in is giving
as good accuracy on a validation set
using an actual real-world data set you
know books for pluto's is compared to
scikit-learn so let's go ahead and round
this out so what I would want to do now
is to create a package that has this
coding and I created it by like creating
a method here a method here a method
here and catching them together so what
I did with now is I went back through in
my notebook and collected up all the
cells had implemented methods and pasted
them all together right and I've just
pasted them down here so here's this is
my original tree ensemble and here is
all the cells and the decision tree I
just dumped them all into one place
without any change so that was it that
was the code we wrote together so now I
can go ahead and I can create a tree
ensemble I can calculate my predictions
I can do my scatter plot I can get my
r-squared right and this is now with
five trees right and here we are we have
a model of blue dog for bulldozers with
a 71% a squid with a random forest we
wrote entirely from scratch that's
pretty cool
any questions about that and I know
there's like quite a lot to get through
so I during the week feel free to ask on
the forum about any bits of code you
come across can somebody pass the box to
Mercia others
can we get back to the probably to the
top maybe a decision tree when we said
the score equal to infinity right yes I
do a calculator Scott the score for the
I mean like I lost track of that and
specifically I wonder when we implement
when we implement find VAR split we
check for self score equal to whether
it's equal to infinity or not it says to
me it seems like I'm clear whether we
fall out of this I mean like if we ever
implement the method if if our initial
value is infinity so okay let's talk
sure the logic so so the decision tree
starts out with a score at infinity so
in other words at this point when we've
created the mode there is no split so
it's infinitely bad okay that's why the
score is infinity and then we try to
find a variable and a split that is
better and do that we look through each
column and say hey column do you have a
split which is better than the best one
we have so far and so then we implement
that let's do the slow way since it's a
bit simpler find better split
we do that by looping through each row
and finding out this is the current
score if we split here is it better than
the current score the current score is
infinitely bad so yes it is and so now
we set the new score equal to what we
just calculated and we keep track of
which variable we chose and the split we
spit on okay no worries
okay great let's take a five-minute
break and I'll see you back here at 22
so when I tried comparing the
performance of this against scikit-learn
this is quite a lot slower and the
reason why is that although like a lot
of the works being done by numpy which
is nicely optimized c-code think about
like the very bottom level of a tree if
we've got a million data points and the
bottom level of the tree has something
like 500 thousand decision points with a
million leaves underneath right and so
that's like five hundred thousand split
methods being called each one of
contained which contains multiple calls
to numpy which only have like one item
that's actually being calculated on and
so it's like that's like very
inefficient and it's the kind of thing
that Python is particularly not good at
performance wise right like calling lots
of functions lots of times I mean we can
see it's it's not bad right you know for
a kind of a random forest which 15 years
ago would have been considered pretty
big this would be considered pretty good
performance right but nowadays this is
some hundreds of times at least slower
than than it should be so what the
scikit-learn folks did to avoid this
problem was that they wrote their
implementation in something called
siphon and siphon is a superset of
Python so any Python you've written
pretty much you can use as siphon right
but then what happens is siphon runs it
in a very different way rather than
passing it to the kind of the Python
interpreter it instead converts it to C
can
Kyle's that and then runs that C code
right which means the first time you run
it it takes a little long work so it has
to go through the kind of translation
and compilation but then after that it
can be quite a bit faster and so I want
to just to quickly show you what that
looks like because you are absolutely
going to be in a position where siphons
going to help you with your work and
most of the people you're working with
will have never used it may not even
know it exists and so this is like a
great superpower to have so to use
siphon in a notebook you say load next
load extension siphon right and so
here's a Python function bit one here is
the same as a siphon function is exactly
the same thing with percent % at the top
this actually runs about twice as fast
as this right just because it does their
compilation here is the same version
again where I've used a special siphon
extension called C death which defines
the C data type of the return value and
of each variable right and so basically
that's the trick that you can use to
start making things run quickly right
and at that point now it knows it's not
just some Python object called T in fact
I probably should put one here as well
let's try that so we've got fib 2 we
call that 53 so 453 yeah so it's exactly
the same as before but we say what the
data type of the thing we passed to it
was is and then define the data types of
each of the variables and so then if we
call that
okay we've now got something that's 10
times faster right so yeah it doesn't
really take that much extra and it's
just it's just Python with a few little
bits of markup so that's like it's it's
good to know that that exists because if
there's something custom you're trying
to do it's actually a find it kind of
painful having to go out and you know
going to see and compile it and whip it
back and all that where else doing it
here is pretty easy can you pass that
just your right please not sure so when
you're doing like for the second version
of it so in the case an array for an NP
array this is a specific C type of yeah
so there's like a lot of um specific
stuff for integrating scythe on with
numpy and there's a whole page about it
yeah so we won't worry about going over
it but you can read that and you can
basically see the basic ideas there's
this C import which basically imports a
certain types of Python library into the
kind of the C bit of the code and you
can then use it in your siphon yeah it's
it's pretty straightforward well good
question
thank you all right so your your mission
now is to implement confidence based on
tree variance feature importance partial
dependence in tree interpreter for that
random first removing redundant features
doesn't use a random forest at all so
you don't have to worry about that the
extrapolation is not an interpretation
technique so you don't have to worry
about that so it's just the other ones
so confidence based on tree variance
we've already written that code so I
suspect that the exact same code we
would have in the notebook should
continue to work so you can try and make
sure it get that working feature
importance is with the variable
shuffling technique and once you have
that working partial dependence it will
just be a couple of lines of code away
rather than you know rather than
shuffling a column you're just replacing
it with a constant value that it's
nearly the same code and then tree
interpreter it's going to require you
writing some code and thinking about
that well ince you've written tree
interpreter you're very close if you
want to to creating the second approach
to feature importance the one where you
add up the importance across all of the
rows which means you would then be very
close to doing interaction importance so
it turns out that that there are
actually there's actually a very good
library for interaction importance for
extra boost but there doesn't seem to be
one for random forests so you could like
start by getting it working on our
version and if you want to do
interaction importance and then you
could like get it working on the
original site SK learn version and that
would be a cool contribution all right
like sometimes writing it against your
own implementation is kind of nicer
because you can see exactly what's going
on all right so that's that's your job
now you don't have to rewrite the random
forest feel free to if you want to you
know practice so if you get stuck at any
point you know ask on the forum right
there is a whole page here on wiki dot
fast play I about how to ask for help so
when you ask your co-workers on slack
for help when you ask people in a
technical community on github or
discourse for help or whatever
asking for help the right way will go a
long way towards you know having people
want to help you and be able to help
here right so so like search for your
aunt's like search for the arrow you're
getting see if somebody's already asked
about it you know how have you tried to
fix it already what do you think's going
wrong what kind of computer are you on
how is it set up what are the software
versions exactly what did you type at
exactly what happened right now you
could do that by taking a screenshot so
you know make sure you've got some
screenshot software that's really easy
to use so if I were to take a screenshot
I just hit a button select the area copy
to clipboard
go to my forum paste it in and there we
go right that looks a little bit too big
so let's make it a little smaller all
right and so now I've got a screenshot
people can see exactly what happened
better still if there's a few lines of
code and error messages to look at and
create a gist it just is a handy little
github thing which basically lets you
share code so if I wanted to create a
gist of this I actually have a extension
area that little extension so if I click
on here
give it a name say make public okay and
that takes my Jupiter notebook shares it
publicly
I can then grab that URL copy link
location right and paste it into my
forum post right and then when people
click on it then they'll immediately see
my notebook when it renders
okay so that's a really good way now
that particular button is an extension
so on Jupiter you need to click end the
extensions and click on just it right
while you're there you should also click
on collapsible headiness that's this
really handy thing I use that lets me
collapse things and open them up if you
go to your Jupiter and don't see this MB
extensions button then just Google for
Jupiter and B extensions it'll show you
how to pip install it and and get it set
up right where those two extensions are
SuperDuper handy
alright so other than that assignment
where we're done with random forests and
until the next course when you look at
gPMs we're done with decision tree
ensembles and so we're going to move on
to neural networks broadly defined and
so Dero networks are going to allow us
to to go beyond just you know the kind
of nearest neighbors approach of random
forests you know all around and forests
can do is to average data that it's
already seen it can't extrapolate it
can't they can't calculate right linear
regression can calculate and can
extrapolate but only in very limited
ways neural nets give us the best of
both worlds we're going to start by
applying them to unstructured data all
right so unstructured data means like
pixels or the amplitudes of sound waves
or words you know data where everything
in all the columns are all the same type
you know as opposed to like a database
table where you've got like a revenue
and a cost and a zip code and a state it
should be structured data we're going to
use it for structured data as well but
we're going to do that a little bit
later so structured data is a little
easier and
it's also the area which more people
have been applying deep learning to for
longer
the if you're doing the deep learning
course as well you know you'll see that
we're going to be approaching kind of
the same conclusion from two different
directions so the deep learning course
is starting out with big complicated
convolutional neural networks being
solved with you know sophisticated
optimization schemes and we're going to
kind of gradually drill down into like
exactly how they work where else with
the machine learning course we're going
to be starting out more with like how
does stochastic gradient descent
actually work what do we do what can we
do is like one single layer which would
allow us to create things like logistic
regression when we add regularization to
that how does that give us things like
Ridge regression elastic net lasso and
then as we add additional layers to that
how does that let us handle more complex
problems and so we're not going to we're
only going to be looking at fully
connected layers in this machine
learning course and then I think next
semester with your net you're probably
going to be looking at some more
sophisticated approaches and so yeah so
this machine learning we're going to be
looking much more at like what's
actually happening with the matrices and
how they actually calculated and the
deep learning it's much more like what
are the best practices for actually
solving you know at a world-class level
real-world deep learning problems right
so next week we're going to be looking
at like the classic Emnes problem which
is like how do we recognize digits now
if you're interested you can like skip
ahead and like try and do this with a
random forest and you'll find it's not
bad but it given that a random forest is
basically a type of nearest neighbors
right it's finding like what are the
nearest neighbors in entry space then a
random forest could absolutely recognize
that this nine those pixels you know are
similar to pixels we've seen in these
other ones and on average they were
nines as well right
so like it can absolutely solve these
kinds of problems to an extent using
random forests but we end up being
rather data limited because every time
we put in another decision point you
know we're having our data roughly and
so this is this limitation and the
amount of calculation that we can do
where else with neural nets we're going
to be able to use lots and lots and lots
of parameters using these tricks we
don't learn about with regularization
and so we're going to be able to do lots
of computation and there's got to be
very little limitation on really what we
can actually end up calculating as a
result great good luck with your random
forest interpretation and I will see you
next time