so from here the next two or three
lessons we're going to be really diving
deep into random forests so so far all
we've learned is there's a thing called
random forests for some particular
datasets they seem to work really really
well without too much trouble
but we don't really know yet like well
how do they actually work what do we do
if they don't work properly what are
their pros and cons what are the can we
tune and so forth so we're gonna look at
all that and then after that we're going
to look at how do we interpret the
results of random forests to get not
just predictions but to actually deeply
understand our data in a model driven
way so that's where we're going to go
from here
so let's just review where we're up to
so we learned that there's this library
called fast AI and the fast AI library
is basically it's a highly opinionated
library which is to say we've spent a
lot of time researching what are the
best techniques to get like
state-of-the-art results and then we
take those techniques and package them
into pieces of code so that you can use
the state-of-the-art results yourself
and so where possible we wrap or provide
things on top of existing code and so in
particular for the kind of structured
data analysis we're doing scikit-learn
has a lot of really great code so most
of the stuff that we're showing you from
fast AI is stuff to help us get stuff
into scikit-learn and then interpret
stuff out from scikit-learn the fast AI
library
the way it works in our environment here
is that we've got out our notebooks are
inside fast AI repo / courses and in /
ml 1 + dl 1 and then inside there
there's a symlink to the parent of the
parent fast AI so this is a sim link to
a directory containing a bunch of
modules so if you want to use the fast
AI library in your own code there's a
number of things you can do one is to
put your notebooks or scripts in the
same directory as ml 1 or 0 1 whether
it's already this simile and just import
it just like I do
you could copy this directory dot dot
slash dot dot slash birthday I into
somewhere else and use it or you could
sim link it just like I have from here
to wherever you want to use it so notice
it's mildly confusing there's a github
repo called fast AI and inside the
github repo caught fast AI which looks
like this there is a folder called fast
AI okay and so the FASTA a folder in the
FASTA a repo contains the FASTA a
library and it's that library when we go
from fast AI dot imports to import star
then that's looking inside the farsi a
folder for a file called inputs imports
py and importing everything from that
okay yes Danielle
okay and just like as a clarifying
question for this Bentley
it's just that anything
that's just the Ellen thing that you
talked about yeah so a symlink is
something you can create by typing Ln
minus s and then the path to the source
which in this case would be dot dot dot
first AI could be relative or it could
be absolute and then the name of the
destination if you just put the current
directory at the destination
it'll use the same name as it comes from
like a alias on the Mac or a shortcut on
Windows
and when you do the important system yep
got it imports this and then append that
relative link that also creates the same
link and I don't think I've created the
same link anywhere in the workbooks the
symlink actually lives inside the github
repo okay I created some symlinks in the
deep learning notebook to some data that
was different at the top of Tim Lee's
workbook from the last class there was
important
oh yeah don't do that probably I mean
you you can but I think this is I think
this is better like this way you can go
from fast AI imports and regardless of
kind of how you got it there it's it's
going to work you know okay okay so then
we had all of our data for blue books
for bulldozers competition in data slash
bulldozers and here it is right so we
were able to read that CSV file the only
thing we really had to do was to say
which columns were dates and having done
that we were able to take a look at a
few earth examples of the rows of the
data and so we also noted that it's very
important to deeply understand the
evaluation metric for this project and
so if a cattle they tell you what the
evaluation metric is and in this case it
was the root mean squared log error so
that is
some of the actuals - the predictions
now but it's the log of the actuals -
the log the predictions squared right so
if we replace actuals with log actuals
and replace predictions with log
predictions then it's just the same as
root mean squared error so that's what
we did was we replaced sale price with
log of sale price and so now if if we
optimize for root mean squared error
we're actually optimizing for the root
mean squared error of the logs
okay so then we learnt that we need all
of our columns to be numbers and so the
first way we did that was to take the
date column and remove it and instead
replace it with a whole bunch of
different columns such as is that date
the start of a quarter is at the end of
a year how many days are elapsed since
generally the first 1970 what's a year
what's the month or the day of weeks and
so forth okay so they're all numbers
then we learnt that we can use train
underscore katz to replace all of the
strings with categories now when you do
that it doesn't look like you've done
anything different they still look like
strings all right but if you actually
take a deeper look you'll see that the
datatype now is not string but category
and category is a panda's class where
you can then go dark cat dot and find a
whole bunch of different attributes such
as cat categories to find a list of all
of the possible categories and this says
hi is going to be 0 low will become 1
medium will become 2 so we can then get
codes
to actually get the numbers so then what
we need to do to actually use this data
set to turn it into numbers is take
every categorical column and replace it
with cap codes and so we did that using
proc DF okay
so how do I get the source code for proc
DF question question mark okay all right
so if I scroll down I go through each
column and I numerical eyes it okay
that's actually the one I want so I'm
going to now have to look up numerical
eyes so tab to complete it if it's not
numeric then replace the data frames
filled with that columns cat codes last
one because otherwise unknown is minus
one we went unknown to be zero okay so
that's how we turn the strings into
numbers right they get replaced with a
unique basically arbitrary index it's
actually based on the alphabetical order
of the feature names
the other thing property f did remember
was continuous columns that had missing
values the missing got replaced with the
median and we added an additional column
called column name underscore na which
is a boolean column told you if that
particular item was missing or not
so once we did that we were able to call
random forest regressor dot fit and get
the dots poor and turns out we have an
r-squared of 0.98 can anybody tell me
what an r-squared is listen um can we
you
so r-squared essentially shows how much
variance is explained by the modal this
is the yeah this is the relation of this
is ssro which is like trying to trying
to remember the exact formal but I don't
roughly a curative way
yeah intuitively it's how much the model
explains the how much it accounts for
the variance in the data okay good so
let's talk about the formula and so with
formulas the idea is not to learn the
formula and remember it but to learn
what the formula does and understand it
right so here's the formula it's 1 minus
something divided by something else so
what's this something else from the
bottom SS taught okay so what this is
saying is we've got some actual data
so my eyes right we've got some actual
data 3e two-for-one okay and then we've
got some average okay so our top bit
this SS tot is the sum of each of these
- that
so in other words it's telling us how
much does this data bury perhaps more
interestingly is I remember when we
talked about like last week what's the
simplest non stupid model you could come
up with and I think the simplest non
stupid model we came up with was create
a column of the mean just copy the mean
a bunch of times and submit that to
cable if you did that then your root
mean squared error would be this so this
is the root mean squared error of the
most naive non stupid model where the
model is just predict mean on the top we
have SS res which is here which is that
we're now going to add a column of
predictions
okay and so then what we do is rather
than taking the why I - why mean we're
going to take why I - Fi right and so
now instead of saying what's the root
mean squared error of our naive model
we're saying what's the root mean
squared error of the actual model that
we're interested in and then we take the
ratio
so in other words if we actually were
exactly as effective as just predicting
the mean then this would be top and
bottom would be the same that would be 1
1 minus 1 will be 0 if we were perfect
so fi minus y I was always zero then
that's zero divided by something one
minus that is 1 ok so what is the
possible range of values of R squared
okay I heard a lot of 0 to 1 does
anybody want to give me an alternative
negative 1 to 1
anything less than one there's the right
answer let's find out way through the
boss
okay
so why is it any number less than one
which you can make a model basically as
crappy as you want and just I guess like
the arrows as you want you're just
subtracting from one in the formula
exactly so interestingly I was talking
to our computer science professor
Terrence this morning who was talking to
where a statistics professor told him
that the possible range of values was
asked where it was zero to one I said
that is totally not true if you predict
infinity for every column sorry for
every row then you're going to have
infinity for every residue and so you're
going to have one minus infinity okay so
the possible range of values is less
than one that's all we know and this
will happen you will get negative values
sometimes in your r-squared and when
that happens it's not a mistake it's not
it's not like a bug it means your moral
is worse than predicting the main okay
which is suggest it's not great so
that's R squared it's not
it's not necessarily what you're
actually trying to optimize right but
it's it's it's the nice thing about it
is that it's a number that you can use
kind of for every model and so you can
kind of start try to get a feel of like
what does point-eight look like what
does point-9 look like so like something
I find interesting is to like create
some different synthetic data sets just
to two dimensions with kind of different
amounts of random noise and like see
what they look like on a scatterplot and
see what they are squared are just gonna
get a feel for like what does it ask for
it you know is it a spur to point line
close or not about 0.7 closed or not
okay so I think r-squared is a useful
number to have a familiarity with and
you don't need to remember the formula
if you remember the meaning which is
what's the ratio between how good your
model is it means bit error versus how
good is the naive mean model for it
squared error okay and LK is 0.98 it's
saying it's a very good model however it
might be a very good model because it
looks like this all right this would be
called overfitting so we may well have
created a model which is very good at
running through the points that we gave
it but it's not going to be very good at
running through points that we didn't
give it so that's why we always want to
have a validation set creating your
validation set is the most important
thing that I think you need to do when
you're doing a machine learning project
at least in terms of in the actual
modeling because what you need to do is
come up with a data set where the
scroller of your model on that data set
is going to be representative of how
well your model is going to do in the
real world like in cattle on the
leaderboard or off Kaggle like when you
actually use it in production
I very very very often hear people in
industries they I don't trust machine
loading I tried modeling once it looked
great we put it in production it didn't
work now whose fault is that right that
means their validation set was not
representative right so here's a very
simple thing which generally speaking
cattle is pretty good about doing if
your data has a time piece in it right
as happens in Blue Book for bulldozers
in Blue Book for bulldozers we're
talking about the sale price of a piece
of industrial equipment on a particular
date so the start up during this
competition wanted to create a model
that wouldn't predict last February's
prices that would predict next month's
prices so what they did was they gave us
data representing a particular date
range in the training set and then the
test set represented a future set of
dates that wasn't represented in the
training set right so that's pretty good
right that means that if we're doing
well on this model we've built something
which can actually predict the future or
at least it could predict the future
then assuming things haven't changed
dramatically so that's the test set we
have so we need to create a validation
set that has the same properties so the
test set had 12,000 rows in so let's
create a validation set that has 12,000
rows right and then let's split the data
set into the first n minus 12 thousand
rows for the training set and the last
12,000 rows for the validation set and
so we've now got something which
hopefully looks like cackles test set
plus enough that when we actually try
and use this validation set we're going
to get some reasonably accurate scores
and the reason we want this is because
on cattle you can only submit so many
times and if you submit too often you'll
end up fitting to the leaderboard anyway
and in real life you actually want to
build a model that's going to work in
why did you have a question can we help
the green box can you explain the
difference between a validation set and
a test set absolutely so what we're
going to learn today is how to set what
other things alone it's how to set high
parameters hyper parameters are like
tuning parameters that are going to
change how your model behaves now if you
just have one holdout set so one set of
data that you're not using to train with
and we use that to decide which set of
hyper parameters to use if we try a
thousand different sets of hyper
parameters we may end up overfitting to
that holdout set that is to say well
find something which only accidentally
worked so what we actually want to do is
we want to have a second holdout set
where we can say okay I'm finished
okay I've done the best I can and now
just once right at the end I'm gonna see
whether it works and so this is
something which almost nobody in
industry does correctly you really
actually need to remove that holdout set
that's called the test set remove it
from the data give it to somebody else
and tell them do not let me look at this
data until I promise you I'm finished
like it's so hard otherwise not to look
at it and for example in the world of
psychology and sociology you might have
heard about this replication crisis this
is basically because people in these
fields have accidentally or
intentionally maybe been peed hacking
which means they've been basically
trying lots of different variations
until they find something that works and
then it turns out and they try to
replicate it in other words it's like
somebody creates a test set somebody
says okay this study which shows you
know the impact of whether you eat
marshmallows on your tenacity later in
life I'm going to rerun it and like over
half the time they're finding the effect
turns out not to exist so that's why we
want to have a test set
get that next door yeah so for handling
categorical data you can market those to
numerix two numbers order numbers I've
seen a lot of models where we convert
categorical data into different columns
using one for encoding yes
so which approach to use in which model
yeah we're kind of track for that today
yeah it's a great question okay so so
I'm splitting my my data into validation
and training sets and so you can see now
that my validation set is twelve
thousand about 66 where else my training
set is three hundred ninety nine
thousand sixty-six okay so we're going
to use this set of data to train a model
and this set of data to see how well
it's working so when we then tried that
last week we found out just a moment we
found out that our model which had point
nine eight two R squared on the training
set only had point eight eight seven on
the validation set which makes us think
that we're overfitting quite badly but
it turned out it wasn't too badly
because the root mean squared error on
the logs of the prices actually would
have caught us in the top 25 percent of
the competition anyway so even although
we're overfitting it wasn't the end of
the world could you pass the microphone
to Marsha please ah in terms of you
dividing the set into training and
validation it seems like you simply take
the first and train observations of the
data status and set them aside why don't
you like why don't you randomly pick up
the observations because if I did that I
wouldn't be replicating the test set so
cattle has a test set that when you
actually look at the dates in the test
set they are a set of dates that are
more recent than any date in the
training set so if we used a validation
set that was a random sample that is
much easier because we're predicting
options like what's the value of this
piece of industrial equipment on this
day when we add
we already have some observations from
that day so in general anytime you're
building a model that has a time element
you want your test set to be a separate
time period and therefore you really
need your validation set to be observer
time period as well and in this case the
data was already sorted that's why this
works so let's say we have our test the
training set by which we in the data and
then we have the validation set against
which we are trying to find the r-square
in in case of r-squared turns out to be
really bad we would want to cheer to not
parameters and run it again yes so
wouldn't that be eventually overfitting
on the overall training set yeah so
actually that's that's the issue so that
would eventually have the possibility of
overfitting on the validation set and
then when you try it on the test set or
we submit it to kaggle it turns out not
to be very good and this happens in
careful competitions all the time
careful actually has a fourth data set
which is called the private leader board
set and every time you submit to Kaggle
you actually only get feedback on how
well it does on something called the
public leader board set and you don't
know which rows they are and at the end
of the competition you actually get
judged on a different data set entirely
called the private leader board set so
the only way to avoid this is to
actually be a good machine learning
practitioner and know how to set these
parameters as effectively as possible
which we're going to be doing gladly
today and over the next few weeks
can you get that actually watching
is it too early or late to ask what's
the difference between a paper parameter
and a parameter okay so let's start
tracking things on written in spread era
so here is root mean square error in a
line of code and you can see here like
this is one of these examples where I'm
not writing this the way a proper
software engineer would write this right
so a proper software engineer would be a
number of things differently they would
have it on a different line they would
use longer variable names they would
have documentation blah blah blah right
but
I really think like for me I really
think that being able to look at
something in one go with your eyes and
like over time learn to immediately see
what's going on has a lot of value and
also to like consistently use like
particular letters to have many
particular things or abbreviations I
think works really well in data science
if you're doing it like a take-home
interview test or something you should
write your code according to pet eight
standards right so pep eight is the the
style guide for python code and you
should know it and use it because a lot
of software engineers are super anal
about this kind of thing but for your
own work you know I think this is I
think this works well for me you know so
I just wanted to make you aware a that
you shouldn't necessarily use this as a
role model for dealing with software
engineers but B that I actually think
this is not this is a reasonable
approach okay so there's a root mean
squared error and then from time to time
we're just going to print out the score
which will give us the RMS C of the
predictions on the training versus the
actual there are predictions on the
valid versus the actual RMS see the R
squared for the training and the R
squared of the Bell and we'll come back
to over in a moment so when we ran that
we found that this rmse was in the top
25% and it's like okay there's a good
start now this took eight seconds of
wall time so eight actual seconds if you
put percent time it'll tell you how long
things talk and luckily I've got quite a
few calls quite a few CPUs in this
computer because it actually took over a
minute a compute time so I paralyzed
that across cause if your dataset was
bigger or you had less cause you know
you could well find that this took a few
minutes to run or even a few hours and
my rule of thumb is that if something
takes more
10 seconds to run it's too long for me
to do like interactive analysis with it
right I want to be able to like run
something wait a moment
and then continue so what we do is we
try to make sure that things can run in
a reasonable time and then when we're
when we're finished at the end of the
day we can then say ok this feature
engineering these hyper parameters
whatever these are all working well and
I'll now rerun it you know that's the
big slow precise way so one way to speed
things up is to pass in the subset
parameter to proc DF and that will
randomly sample my data right and so
here I'm got a randomly sample 30,000
rows now when I do that I still need to
be careful to make sure that my
validation set doesn't change and that
my training set doesn't overlap with the
dates otherwise I'm cheating
so I call split bells again to again do
this split by dates and you'll also see
I'm using rather than putting it into a
validation set I'm putting it into a
variable called underscore this is kind
of a standard approach in Python is to
use a variable called underscore if you
want to throw something away because I
don't want to change my validation set
like no matter what different models I
build I want to be able to compare them
all to each other so I want to keep my
validation set the same all the time
okay so all I'm doing here is I'm
resampling my training set into a 20 the
first 20,000 out of a 30,000 subsets so
I now could run that and it runs it 621
milliseconds so I can like really zip
through things now try things out okay
so with that let's use this subset to
build a model that is so simple that we
can actually take a look at it and so
we're going to build a forest is made of
trees and so before we look at the
forest we look at the trees in
scikit-learn they don't call them trees
they call them estimators
so we're going to pass in the parameter
number of estimators equals one the
Creator forest with just one tree and
then we're going to make a small tree
so we pass in maximum depth equals three
and a random forest as we're going to
learn randomizes a whole bunch of things
we want to turn that off so to turn that
off you say bootstrap equals false so if
I pass you in these parameters that
creates a small deterministic tree okay
so if I fit it and say print score my a
squared has gone down from point eight
five two point four so this is not a
good model it's better than the mean
model this is better than zero right
it's not a good model but it's a model
that we can draw all right so let's
learn about what it's built so a tree
consists of a sequence of binary
decisions of binary splits so at first
of all decided to split on coupla system
greater than or less than point five
that's boolean variable so it's actually
true or false and then within the group
we're a couple system was true we
decided to split into year made greater
than or less than 1987 and then we're a
couple system was true and year made was
less than or equal to 1986
it used fi product class desk is less
than or equal to 0.75 and so forth right
so right at the top we have 20,000
samples 20,000 rows right and the reason
for that is because that's what we asked
for here when we split our data in the
sample
I just want to double-check that for
your decision tree that you had there
that the coloration was whether it's
true or false not so like it it gets
darker it's true for the next one not
the darker is a higher value we'll get
to that in a moment okay
so let's look at these numbers here so
in the whole data set
well our sample that we're using there
are 20,000 rows
the meter the average of the log of
Christ is 10.1 and if we built a model
where we just used that average all the
time then the mean squared error would
be 0.477 okay so this is in other words
the denominator of an R squared all
right this is like the most basic model
is a tree with zero splits right which
is just predict the average so the best
single binary split we can make it turns
out to be splitting by where the coupler
system is greater than or equal to sorry
less than or equal to or greater than
0.5 know whether it's true or false and
turns out if we do that the mean squared
error of couple system is less than 0.5
so it's false goes down from 0.477 to
0.1 one right so it's really improved
the error a lot in the other group it's
only improved at a bit so I'm from 0.47
2.41
and so we can see that the coupler
system equals false group has a pretty
small percentage it's only got twenty
two hundred of the twenty thousand all
right where else this other group has a
much larger percentage but it hasn't
improved it as much so let's say you
wanted to create a tree with just one
split so you're just trying to find like
what is the very best single binary
decision you can make for your data how
might you be able to do that how could
you do it
I'm gonna give it to foot
specify the max depth of one but I mean
your writing you don't have a random
first write how are you going to how are
you going to like write what's an
algorithm a simple algorithm which you
could use sure so we want to start
building a random forest from scratch so
the first step is to create a tree the
first step to create a tree is to create
the first binary decision how are you
gonna do it I'm gonna give it to Chris
maybe in two steps
so isn't this simply trying to find the
best predictor based on maybe a linear
regression you could use a linear
regression but could you do something
much simpler and more complete we're
trying not to use any statistical
assumptions here I can't see your name
sorry
and of course your friends anything can
we just do like take just one variable
if it is true give it like the true
thing and if it is false so which
variable are we gonna choose so at each
binary point we have to choose a
variable and something to split on how
are we going to do that then I pass it
over there how do I pronounce your name
chicken so the variability tools could
be like which divides population into
two groups which kind of heterogeneous
to each other and homogeneous within
themselves like having the same quality
within themselves and they are very
different
could you be more specific like in terms
of the target variable maybe yeah right
let's say we have two groups of tested
so one has a different price altogether
from the second group yes internally
they have similar prices okay that's
good
so like to simplify things a little bit
when we're saying find a variable that
we could split into such that the two
groups are as different to each other as
possible and okay how do you how would
you pick which variable and which split
point that's the question
yeah what's your first cut which
variable and which split point
we don't like we're making the trade
from scratch we want to create our own
tree that makes sense we've got somebody
amazing
can we test all of the possible split
and see which one has this ah small and
rmse that sounds good okay so let's dig
into this
so when you say test all of the possible
splits what does that mean how do we
enumerate all the possible splits
oh and think of that but
if you want for each variable you could
put one aside and then put a second
aside and compare the two and if it was
better good okay so for each variable
for each possible value of that variable
see whether it's better now coming back
to Maslak so I want to dig into the
better when you said see if the RMS see
is better what does that mean though
because after a split you've got two
rmse so you've got two two groups so you
just gonna fit what that one variable
comparing to the other it's not so so
what I mean here is that before we
decided to speed on coupler system we
had a root mean square root of 0.477 and
after we've got two groups one were the
mean square error point one another with
a mean squared error of 0.4 so you treat
each individual model separately so for
the first player you're just gonna
compare between each variable in himself
and then you move on to the next node
with the remaining but but even the
first node like so the model with zero
splits has a single root mean squared
error the model with one split so the
very first thing we tried we've now got
two groups with two mean square errors
you don't give it to Daniel do you pick
the one that gets them as different as
they can be well we're truck well okay
that would be one idea get the two mean
squared errors as different as possible
but why might that not work what might
be a problem with that sample size come
on because you could just literally
leave one point out yeah so we could
have like year made is less than 1950
and it might have a single sample with a
low price and like that's not a great
split is it you know because the other
group is actually not going to be very
interesting at all can you improve it a
bit can Jason improve it a bit
could you take a weighted average yeah a
weighted average so we could take point
four one times 17,000 plus 0.1 times
2,000 that's good right and that would
be the same as actually saying I've got
a model the model is a single binary
decision and I'm going to say for
everybody with year made less than
ninety six point five I'm going to fill
in point ten point two for everybody
else are going to fill in nine point two
and then I'm going to calculate the root
mean squared error of this crappy model
and that would give exactly the same
right as the weighted average that
you're suggesting okay good so we now
have a single number that represents how
good a split is which is the weighted
average of the mean squared errors of
the two groups that creates okay and
thanks to I think it was was it Jake we
have a way to find the best split which
is to try every variable and to try
every possible value of that variable
and see which variable and which value
gives us a split with the best score
that makes sense
okay what's your name sir okay and
somebody give Natalie the box when you
see every possible number for every
possible variable link are you saying
like here we have 0.5 as like our
criteria to split the tree so are you
are you saying we're trying out a
reasonable number for every possible
value right so cupola system only has
two values true and false so there's
only one way of splitting which is trues
and falses ear made is an integer which
varies between like O'Donnell 1960 and
2010 so we can just say what are all the
possible unique values of year made and
and try them all so we're trying all the
possible spec points can you pass a
better annual pass to me and I so I just
want to clarify again for the first
split why did we split on Cutler system
true or false sister because what we did
was we used Jake's technique we tried
every variable for every variable we
tried every possible split so each one
we noted down I think it was Jason's
idea which was the weighted average mean
squared error of the two groups are
created we found which one had the best
means grid error and we picked it and it
turned out it was cutlass system true or
false
does that make sense I guess my question
is more like so coupler system is like
one of them like best indicators I guess
it's the best we tried every variable
and every possible level everything else
at try it wasn't as good okay and then
you do that right so now that we've done
that we now take this group here
everybody who's got coupler system
equals true and we do it again for every
possible variable for every possible
level for people where coupler system
equals true what's the best possible
split and then are there circumstances
when it's not just like binaries like
you split it into like three groups for
like example you're made so I'm gonna
make a claim and then I'm gonna see if
you can justify it I'm gonna claim that
it's never necessary to do more than one
split at a level because you can just
cuz you can just split them again
exactly so you can get exactly the same
result by submitting twice okay good so
that is the entirety of creating a
decision tree you stop either when you
hit some limit that was requested so we
had a limit where we said max depth
equals three so that's one one way to
stop would be you ask to stop at some
point and so we stopped otherwise you
stop when you're your leaf nodes these
things at the end of court leaf nodes
when your leaf nodes only have one thing
in them okay that's a decision tree that
is how we grow a decision tree and this
decision tree is not very good because
it's got a validation r-squared of 0.4
so we could try to make it better by
removing next steps equals three right
and creating a deeper tree so it's going
to go all the way down they're going to
keep splitting these things further
until every leaf node only has one thing
in it and if we do that the training
r-squared is of course one
because we can exactly predict every
training element because it's in a leaf
node or on its own but the validation
r-squared is not one it's actually
better than our really really shallow
tree but it's not as good as we'd like
okay so we want to find some other way
of making these trees better and the way
we're going to do it is to create a
forest so what's the forest to create a
forest we're going to use a statistical
technique called bagging and you can bag
any kind of model in fact Michael Jordan
who is one of the speakers at the recent
recent data Institute conference here at
university of san francisco developed a
technique called the bag of little
bootstraps and which he shows how to use
bagging for absolutely any kind of model
to make it more robust and also to give
you confidence intervals the random
forest is simply a way of bagging trees
so what is bagging managing is a really
interesting idea which is what if we
created five different models each of
which was only somewhat predictive but
the models weren't at all correlated
with each other they gave predictions
that weren't correlated with each other
that would mean that the five models
would have profound different insights
into the relationships in the data and
so if you took the average of those five
models right then you're effectively
bringing in the insights from each of
them and so this idea of averaging
models is a is is a technique for
ensemble right which is really important
now let's come up with a more specific
idea of how to do this ensemble what if
we created a whole lot of these trees
big deep massively overfit trees right
but each one let's say we only pick a
random
one-tenth of the data so we pick one out
of every 10 rows at random build a deep
tree right which is perfect on that
subset and kind of crappy on the rest
all right let's say we do that a hundred
times so different random sample every
time so all of the trees are going to be
better than nothing right because they
do actually have a real random subset of
the data and so they found some insight
but they're also overfitting terribly
but they're all using different random
samples so they all over fit in
different ways on different things so in
other words they all have errors but the
errors are random what is the average of
a bunch of random errors zero so in
other words if we take the average of
these trees each of which have been
trained on a different random subset the
errors will average out to zero and
what's left is the true relationship and
that's the random forest right so
there's the technique right we've got a
whole bunch of rows of data we grab a
few at random all right put them into a
smaller data set and build a tree based
on that okay and then we put that tree
aside and do it again with a different
random subset and do it again with a
different random subset do that a whole
bunch of times and then for each one we
can then make predictions by running our
test data through the tree to get to the
leaf mode take the average in that leaf
node for all the trees and average them
all together so to do that we simply
call random forests regressor and by
default it creates n what scikit-learn
cords estimators an estimator is a tree
right so this is going to create ten
treats
and so we go ahead and train it I can't
remember if I remember to split okay
so create our ten trees and we're just
doing this on our little random subset
of 20,000 and so let's take a look at
one example can you pass the box to
Devin so just to make sure I understand
this so you're saying like we take ten
kind of crappy models we average ten
crappy models and we get a good model
exactly because the crappy models are
based on different random subsets and so
their errors are not correlated with
each other if the error errors work are
they with other this isn't going to work
okay so the key insight here is to
construct multiple models which are
better than nothing and where the errors
are as much as possible not correlated
with each other so is there like a
certain number of trees that like we
need that in order to be this sort of
the things like valid or invalid there's
like has a good validation set our MSC
or not you know and so that's what we're
going to look at is how to make that
metric higher and so this is the first
of our hyper parameters then we're going
to learn about how to tune hyper
parameters and the first one is going to
be the number of trees and we're about
to us look at that now yes mostly you're
selecting aren't they exclusive yes so I
mentioned you know one approach would be
pick out like attempt at random but
actually what scikit-learn does by
default is for n rows it picks out n
rows with replacement okay and that's
called bootstrapping and if memory
serves me correctly that gets you on
average 63.2% of the rows will be
represented and you know a bunch of them
will be represented multiple times yeah
it sure so rather than just picking out
like a tenth of the rows at random
instead we're going to pick out of an n
row data set we're going to pick out n
rows with replacement which on average
gets about 63 I think 63.2% of the rows
will be represented many of those rows
will appear multiple times I think
there's a question behind you in essence
what this model is doing is if I
understand Craig is just picking out
data points that look very similar to
the one you're looking at yeah that's a
great insight so what a tree is kind of
doing there's no quite complicated way
of doing about doing that I mean there
would be other ways of assessing
similarity there are other ways of
assessing similarity but what's
interesting about this way is it's doing
it in in tree space right so we're
basically saying what are in this case
like for this little tree what are the
593 samples you know closest to this one
and what's their average closest in tree
space so other ways of doing that would
be like and we'll learn later on in this
course about K nearest neighbors you
could use like Euclidean distance C
right but here's a thing the whole point
of machine learning is to identify which
variables actually matter the most and
how do they relate to each other and to
your dependent variable together right
so if you've like imagine a synthetic
data set where you create five variables
that add together to create your
independent to create your dependent
variable and ninety five variables which
are entirely random and don't impact
your dependent variable and then if you
do like a K nearest neighbors in
Euclidean space you're going to get
meaningless nearest neighbors because
most of your columns are actually
meaningless or imagine your actual
relationship is that your dependent
variable equals x1 times x2 then you'll
actually need to find this interaction
right so you don't actually care about
how close it is to x1 and how close to
x2 but how close to the product so the
entire purpose of modeling in machine
learning is
to find a model which tells you which
variables are important and how do they
interact together to drive your
dependent variable and so you'll find in
practice the difference between using
like tree space or random forest space
to find your nearest neighbors versus
like Euclidean space is the difference
between a model that makes good
predictions in the model that makes many
most predictions elicit here
I did but I feel like we've got only 35
minutes so yeah great so so in general a
machine learning model which is
effective is one which is accurate when
you look at the training data it's it's
accurate at predicting at actually
finding the relationships in that
training data and then it generalizes
well to new data and so in bagging that
means that each of your individual
estimators at your individual trees you
want to be as predictive as possible but
for the predictions of your individual
trees to be as uncorrelated as possible
and so the inventor of random forests
talks about this at length in his
original paper that introduced this in
the late 90s this idea of trying to come
up with predictive but poorly correlated
trees the the research community in
recent years has generally found that
the more important thing seems to be
creating uncorrelated trees rather than
more accurate trees so more recent
advances tend to create trees which are
less predictive on their own but also
less correlated with each other so for
example in scikit-learn there's another
class you can use called extra trees
regress on your extra trees classifier
with exactly the same API you can try it
tonight just replace my random prose
regressor with that
that's called an extremely randomized
trees model and what that does is
the same as what we just discussed but
rather than trying every speck of every
variable it randomly tries a few splits
of a few variables right so it's much
faster the Train it has more randomness
okay but then you've got time you can
build more trees and therefore get
better generalization so in practice if
you've got crappy individual models you
just need more trees to get a good end
up model Melissa could you pass that
over to Devin could you talk a little
bit more about what you mean by like
uncorrelated trees yeah if I build a
thousand trees h1 on just ten data
points then it's quite likely that the
ten data points for every tree are going
to be totally different and so it's
quite likely that those ten trees are
going to trees are going to give totally
different answers to each other so the
correlation between the predictions of
tree one and three two is going to be
very small between tree one and three
three very small and so forth on the
other hand if I create a thousand trees
where each time I use the entire data
set with just one element removed all
those trees are going to be nearly
identical ie their predictions will be
highly correlated and so in the latter
case it's probably not going to
generalize very well where else in the
former case the individual trees we're
not going to be very predictive so I
need to find some nice in-between so yes
Danielle and is there a case where you
want to use one over the other like any
particular times yeah so again hyper
parameter tuning so driven in terms of
like random random forests versus
extremely randomized phase yeah so again
a hyper parameter walk tree architecture
do we use so we're going to talk about
that now can you pass that through do
you know
you know I was just trying to understand
how this random forest actually makes
sense for continuous variables I mean
I'm assuming that you build a tree
structure and the last final notes you'd
be seeing like maybe the small node
represents maybe a category a or a
category B but how does it make sense
for your continuous storage so this is
actually what we have here and so the
value here is the average so this is the
average log of price for this subgroup
and that's what we do the prediction is
the average of the value of the
dependent variable in that leaf node
means finally if you have just like
dengue nodes you just have 10 values yes
that's right well if it was only one
tree right so a couple things to
remember the first is that by default
we're actually going to train the tree
all the way down until the leaf nodes
were size 1 which means for a data set
with n rows we're gonna have n leaf
nodes and then we're going to have
multiple trees which we average together
right so in practice we're gonna have a
you know lots of different possible
values it's a question behind you so far
the continuous variable how do we decide
like which value to split out because
there could be many values we try every
possible value of that in the training
set one did be computationally
computational expensive and this is
where it's very good to remember that
your CPUs performance is measured in
gigahertz which is billions of clock
cycles per second and it has multiple
cores and each core has something called
Simbi single instruction multiple data
where it can direct up to eight
computations per core at once and then
if you do it on the GPU the performance
is measured in teraflops
so trillions of floating-point
operations per second and so this is
where when it comes to designing
algorithms it's very difficult for us
mere humans to realize how stupid
algorithms should be given how fast
today's computers are so yeah it's quite
a few operations
but that trillions per second you hardly
notice it Russia I have a question so
essentially at each remote we make a
decision like which category T or which
variable to use and which pinpoint yes
so we have MSE a calculated for each
node so this is kind of our one of the
decision criteria but please MSE it is
calculated for which model like which
model underlies the model is the model
is for the initial root mode is what if
we just predicted the average right
which is here is ten point oh nine eight
and just the average and then the next
model is what if we predicted the
average of those people with capitalist
system equals false and for those people
with couple of system is true and then
the next is what if we predicted the
average of couple systems equals true
yeah made less than 1986 is it always
average sure we can use median or we can
even run linear regression there's all
kinds of things we could do and practice
the average works really well there are
there are types of they're not called
random forests but there are kinds of
trees where the leaf nodes are
independent linear regressions they're
not terribly widely used but there are
certainly researchers who I have worked
on them okay thank you and pass it back
over that afford and then to check
so this tree has a depth of three yeah
and then I on one of the next commands
we get rid of the max depth yeah the
tree without the max depth does that
contain the tree with with the depth of
three yeah so that is that like by
definition it's yeah well except in this
case we've added randomness but if you
turned bootstrapping off then yeah the
the deeper tree will you know the the
the the less deep tree would be how it
start and then it goes keep spitting
okay so you have many trees you're gonna
have different leaf nodes across streets
hopefully so we want um so how do you
average leaf nodes across different
trees so we just take the first row in
the validation set we run it through the
first tree we find its average nine
point two eight then do it through the
next tree find its average in the second
tree nine point nine five and so forth
and we're about to do that so you'll see
it okay so let's try it right so after
you've built a random forest each tree
is stored in this attribute called
estimators underscore okay
so one of the things that you guys need
to be very very comfortable with is
using list comprehensions okay so I hope
you've all been practicing okay so here
I'm using a list comprehension to go
through each tree in my model I'm going
to call predict on it with my validation
set and so that's going to give me a
list of arrays of predictions so H array
will be all of the predictions for that
tree and I have ten trees MP dot stack
concatenates them together on a new axis
so after I run this and called shape you
can see I now have the first axis ten
means I have my ten different sets of
predictions and for each one my
validation set as a side of twelve
thousand so here are my twelve thousand
predictions for each of the ten trees
alright so let's take the first row of
that and print it out and so here are
what weirdest thing here are ten
predictions one from each tree okay and
so then if we say take the mean of that
here is the mean of those ten
predictions and then what was the actual
the actual was nine point one our
prediction was nine point O seven so you
see how like none of our individual
trees had very good predictions but the
mean of them was actually pretty good
and so
when I talk about experimenting like
Jupiter notebook is great for
experimenting this is the kind of stuff
I mean dig inside these objects and like
look at them and plot them take your own
averages cross check to make sure that
they work the way you thought they did
write your own implementation of
r-squared make sure it's the same as a
psychic learn version plot it like
here's an interesting plot I did let's
go through each Taffet entries right and
then take the mean of all of the
predictions up to the ithe tree right so
let's start by predicting just based on
the first tree than the first two trees
and the first three trees and let's then
plot the r-squared so here's the
r-squared of just the first tree is the
r-squared of the first two trees three
trees four trees blah blah blah blah up
to ten trees and so not surprisingly a
script keeps improving right because the
more estimators we have the more bagging
that we're doing the more it's well it's
going to generalize all right and you
should find that that number there bit
under point eight six should match this
number here okay
let's rerun that yeah okay so they're
actually slightly above what it says all
right so again these are all like the
cross checks you can do the things you
can visualize to deepen your
understanding okay so as we add more
trees our r-squared improves it seems to
flatten out after a while so we might
guess that if we increase the number of
estimators to twenty right it's maybe
not going to be that much better
so let's see we've got point eight six
two first is point eight six oh yeah so
doubling the number of trees didn't help
very much but double it again eight six
seven double it again eight six nine so
you can see like there's some point at
which you're going to you know not want
to add more trees not because it's never
going to get worse because every tree is
you know giving you more semi-random
models to bag together
right but it's going to stop improving
things much okay and so this is like the
first hyper parameter if you learn to
set is number of estimators and the
method for setting is as many as you
have time to fit and that actually
seemed to be hopping okay now in
practice we're going to learn to set a
few more hyper parameters adding more
trees slows it down but with less trees
you can still get the same insights so
I've build most of my models in practice
with like 20 to 30 trees and it's only
like then at the end of the project or
maybe at the end of the day's work I'll
then try doing like I don't know a
thousand trees and run it overnight was
there a question yes can we pass that
Prince
so each tree might have different
estimators different combination of
estimators HQ is an estimator so this is
a synonym so in scikit-learn when I say
estimator they name three so I mean each
tree would have different break points
on differently on different columns but
if at the end we want to locate the
important features and we'll get to that
yeah so I'm after we finished with kind
of setting hyper parameters the next
stage of the course will be learning
about what it tells us about the data if
you need to know it now you know for
your projects feel free to look ahead
there's a lesson to our F interpretation
them is where we can see it okay so
that's our first type of parameter um I
want to talk next about out-of-bag score
sometimes your data set will be kind of
small and you won't want to pull out a
validation set because doing so means
you now don't have enough data to build
a good model what do you do there's a
cool trick which is pretty much unique
to random forests and it's this what we
could do is recognize that some of our
in our first tree some of our columns
sorry some of our rows didn't get used
so what we could do would be to pass
those rows through the first tree and
treat it as a validation set
and then for the second tree we could
pass through the rows that weren't used
for the second tree through it to create
a validation set for that and so
effectively we would have a different
validation set for each tree and so now
to calculate our prediction we would
average all of the trees where that row
is not used for training right so for
tree number one we would have the ones
I've marked in blue here and then maybe
for tree number two it turned out it was
like this one this one this one and this
one and so forth right so as long as
you've got enough trees every rows going
to appear in the out of bag sample from
one of them at least so you'll be
averaging you know hopefully a few trees
so if you've got a hundred trees it's
very likely that all of the rows are
going to appear many times in these
other bag samples so what you can do is
you can create an out of bag prediction
by averaging all of the trees you didn't
use to train each individual row and
then you can calculate your root mean
square error R squared etc on that if
you pass low B score equals true to
scikit-learn it will do that for you and
it will create an attribute called oob
score underscore and so my little print
score function here if that attribute
exists it it adds it to the print so if
you take a look here hoby square equals
true we've now got one extra number and
it's R squared that is the R squared for
the oeob sample it's a square it is very
similar the R squared and the validation
set which is what we hoped for can we
plus it
is it the case that the prediction for
the obese core has to be must be
mathematically lower than the one for
our entire forest um certainly it's not
true that the prediction is lower it's
possible for accuracy yeah um it's not
mathematically necessary that it's true
but it's gonna be true on average
because your average for each row
appears in less trees in the oeob
samples and it does in the full set of
trees so as you see here it's a little
less good so I'm in general it's a great
insight Chris in general the OOBE
r-squared will slightly underestimate
how generalizable the model is the more
trees you add the less serious that
underestimation is and for me in
practice I I find it's totally good
enough you know in practice okay so this
our B score is is is super handy and one
of the things that super handy for is
you're gonna see there's quite a few
hyper parameters that were going to set
and we would like to find some automated
way to set them and one way to do that
is to do what's called a grid search a
grid search is where if there's a
scikit-learn function called grid search
and you pass in the list of all of the
parameters all of the hyper parameters
that you want to tune you pass in for
each one a list of all of the values of
that hyper parameter you want to try and
it runs your model on every possible
combination of all of those hyper
parameters and tells you which one is
the best and our B score is a great like
choice for to forgetting it to Tory
which one is best in terms of our V
score like that's an example of
something you can do with a which works
well
now
if you think about it I kind of did
something pretty dumb earlier which is I
took a subset of 30,000 rows of the data
and it built all my models of that which
means every tree in my random forest is
a different subset of that subset of
30,000 why do that why not take a
different I like a totally different
subset of 30,000 each time so in other
words let's leave the entire 300
thousand records as is right and if I
want to make things faster right pick a
different subset of 30,000 each time so
rather than bootstrapping the entire set
of rows that's just randomly sample a
subset of the data and so we can do that
so let's go back and recall property yet
without the subset parameter to get all
of our data again and so to remind you
that is okay 400,000 I in the whole data
frame of which we have three 89,000 in
our training set and instead we're going
to go set our F samples 20,000 remember
that was the site that off the 30,000 we
use 20,000 of them in our training set
if I do this there now when I run a
random forest it's not going to
bootstrap an entire set of 391 thousand
rows it's going to just grab a subset of
20,000 rows all right and so now if I
run this it will still run just as
quickly as if I had like originally done
a random sample of 20,000 but now every
tree can have access to the whole data
set right so if I do enough estimators
enough trees eventually it's going to
see everything right so in this case
with 10 trees which is the default I get
an R squared of 0.8 6 which is actually
about the same as my R squared with the
with the 20,000 subsets
and that's because I haven't used many
estimators yet right but if I increase
the number of estimators it's got to
make more of a difference right so if I
increase the number of estimators
two-forty alright it's going to take a
little bit longer to run but it's going
to be able to see a larger subset of the
data set and so as you can see the
r-squared is gone up from point eight
six two point eight seven six okay so
this is actually a great approach and
for those of you who would doing the
groceries competition that's got
something like 120 million roads but
there's no way you would want to create
a random forest using 128 million roads
in every tree like it's going to take
forever so what you could do is use this
set area of samples to do like I don't
know a hundred thousand or a million
I'll play around with it so the trick
here is that with a random forest using
this technique no data set is too big I
don't care if it's got a hundred billion
rows right you can create a bunch of
trees each one of the different random
subsets can somebody pass the actual
accuracy
so my question was for the albey scores
and these ones does it take the only
like for the ones from the sample or
take from all the that's a great
question
so unfortunately scikit-learn does not
support this functionality out of the
box so I had to write this and it's kind
of a horrible hack right because we're
much rather be passing in like a sample
size parameter rather than doing this
kind of setting up here so what I
actually do is if you look at the source
code is I'm actually this is a internal
this is the internal function I looked
at their source code that they call and
I've replaced it with a with a lambda
function that has the behavior we want
unfortunately the current version is not
changing how our B is calculated so yeah
so currently low B scores and set our F
samples are not compatible with each
other so you need to turn our B equals
false if you use this approach which I
hope to fix but at this stage it's it's
not fixed so if you want to turn it off
you just call reset our F samples okay
and that returns it back to what it was
okay so in practice when I'm like
doing interactive machine learning using
random forests in order to like explore
my model explore hyper parameters the
stuff we're going to learn in the future
lesson where we actually analyze like
feature importance and partial
dependence and so forth I generally use
subsets and reasonably small forests
because all the insights that I'm going
to get are exactly the same as the big
ones but I can run it in like you know
three or four seconds rather than hours
alright so this is one of the biggest
tips I can give you and very very few
people in industry or academia actually
do this most people run all of their
models on all of the data all of the
time using their best possible
parameters which is just pointless right
if you're trying to find out like which
features are important and how are they
related to each other and so forth
having that fourth decimal place of
accuracy isn't going to change any of
your insights at all okay so I would say
like do most of your models on you know
a large enough sample size that your
accuracy is you know reasonable when I
say reasonable it's like within a
reasonable distance of the best accuracy
you can get and it's taking you know a
small number of seconds to train so that
you can interactively do your analysis
so there's a couple more parameters I
wanted to talk about so I'm going to
call reset RF samples to get back to our
full data set because in this case at
least on this computer it's actually
running in less than 10 seconds so
here's our baseline we're going to do a
baseline with 40 estimators okay and so
each of those 40 estimators is going to
Train all the way down to all the leaf
nodes just have one sample in them
so that's going to take a few seconds to
run here we go so that gets us a point
eight nine eight a sweat on the
validation set or 0.90 eight on the oeob
now this case the OB is better why is it
better
well that's because remember our
validation set is not a random sample
our validation set is a different time
period okay so it's actually much harder
to predict a different time period than
this one which is just predicting random
okay so that's why this is not the way
around we expected so the next the first
parameter we can try fiddling with is
min samples leaf and so min samples leaf
says stop training the tree further when
your leaf node has three or less samples
in there are going all the way down
until there's one we're going to go down
until there's three so in practice this
means there's going to be like one or
two less levels of decision being made
which means we've got like half the
number of actual decision criteria we
have to do is it's going to train more
quickly it means that when we look at an
individual tree rather than just taking
one point we're taking the average of at
least three points
that's who would expect the trees to
generalize each one to generalize a
little bit better okay but each tree is
probably going to be slightly less
powerful on its own so let's try
training that so possible values of min
samples leaf I find ones which work well
are kind of 1 3 5 10 25 you know like I
find that kind of range seems to work
well but like sometimes if you've got a
really big data set and you're not using
the small samples you know you might
need a mint samples leaf of hundreds or
thousands so it's you kind of got to
think about like
how bigger your sub-samples going
through and try things out now in this
case going from the default of one to
three has increased our validation set
our squared from 898 to 902 so it's a
slight improvement okay and it's going
to train a little faster as well as
something else you can try which is and
since this worked I'm going to leave
that in I'm going to add in max features
equals point five
why does max features do well the idea
is that the less correlated your trees
are with each other the better now
imagine you had one column that was so
much better than all of the other
columns of being predictive that every
single tree you built regardless of like
which subset of rows always started with
that column so the trees are all going
to be pretty similar right but you can
imagine there might be some interaction
of variables where that interaction is
more important than that individual
column so if every tree always fits on
the first thing the same thing the first
time you're not going to get much
variation in those trees so what we do
is in addition to just taking a subset
of rows we then at every single split
point take a different subset of columns
so it's slightly different to the row
sampling for the row sampling H nu tree
is based on a random set of rows or
columns sampling every individual binary
split we choose from a different subset
of columns so in other words rather than
looking at every possible level of every
possible column we look at every
possible level of a random subset of
columns okay
and each time each decision point each
binary split we use a different random
subset how many well you get to pick 0.5
means randomly choose half of them
the default is to use all of them
there's also a couple of special values
you can use here as you can see in max
features you can also pass in square
root to get square root of features or
log two to get log two in features so in
practice good values I found our range
from 1.5 log to or square root that's
going to give you a nice bit of
variation right can somebody positive
Danielle and so just to clarify does
that just like break it up smaller each
time it goes through the tree or is it
just taking half of what's left over or
like hasn't been touched each time
there's no such thing as what's left
over after you've split on year made
less than or greater than 1984 you made
still there right so later on you might
then spit on your maid left Center
greater than 1989 so so it's just each
time rather than checking every variable
to see where it's best fit is you just
check half of them and so the next time
you check a different hops the next time
you took a different path but I mean
like terms is as you got like further to
like the leaf you're gonna have less
options no you're not you'd never remove
the variables okay you can use them
again and again and again because you've
got lots of different spit points
so imagine for example that the
relationship was just entirely linear
between year made and price right then
in practice to actually model that you
know your real relationship is year made
versus price right but the best we could
do would be this kind of first of all
split here right and then just split
here and here right and like spitting
spitting split so yeah even if the
binary most random forest libraries
don't do anything special about that
they just kind of go okay we'll try this
variable oh it turns out there's only
one level left you know so yeah that
didn't they don't do any kind of clever
bookkeeping okay okay so if we add next
features equals 0.5 it goes up from 901
the 906 so that's better still and so as
we've been doing this we've also
hopefully have noticed that our root
mean squared error log price has been
dropping on a validation set as well and
so it's now down to 0.2 to 86 so how
good is that right so like our totally
untrue and random florists got us in
about the top 25 percent now remember
our validation set isn't identical to
the Kaggle test set right and this
competition unfortunately is old enough
that you can't even put in a kind of
after this after the time entry to find
out how you would have gone so we can
only approximate how we could have gone
but you know generally speaking is going
to be a pretty good approximation so
2:286
here is the competition here's the
public leaderboard
two two eight six here we go
14th or 15th place so you know roughly
speaking
looks like we would be about in the top
20 of this competition with basically
totally brainless random forest with
some totally brainless minor hyper
parameter tuning and so this is kind of
why the random forest is such an
important not just first step but often
only step from the Xin learning because
it's kind of hard to screw it up like
even when we didn't tune the hyper
parameters we still got a good result
and then a small amount of type of
parameter tuning got us a much better
result and so any kind of model so and
I'm particularly thinking of like linear
type models which have a whole bunch of
statistical assumptions and you have to
get a whole bunch of things right before
they start to work at all can really
throw you off track right because they
give you like totally wrong answers
about how accurate the predictions can
be but also the random forest you know
generally speaking they tend to work on
most data sets most of the time with
most sets of hyper parameters so for
example we did this thing with it with
our categorical variables in fact let's
take a look at our tree a single tree
look at this right
fi product class desc less than 7.5 what
does that mean so f I product plus desc
here's some examples of that column all
right so what does it mean to be less
than or equal to 7
well we'd have to look at dark cat dark
categories to find out okay and so it's
0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 so what it's done is its
created a split where all of the backhoe
loaders and these three types of
hydraulics
enter in one group and everything else
is in the other group so like that's
like weird you know like like these
aren't even in order we could have made
them in order if we had you know bother
to say the categories have this order
but we hadn't right so how come this
even works like because when we turn it
into codes it's actually this is
actually what the random forest sees and
so imagine to think about this imagine
like the only thing that mattered was
whether as a hydraulic excavator at zero
to two metric tons and nothing else
mattered imagine that right so it has to
pick out this this single level well it
can do that because first of all it
could say okay let's pick out everything
less than seven versus greater than
seven to create you know this is one
group and this is another group right
and then within this group they could
then pick out everything less than six
versus greater than six we're just going
to pick out this one item right so with
two split points we can pull out a
single category so this is why it works
right is because the tree is like
infinitely flexible even with a
categorical variable if there's
particular categories which have
different levels of price it can like
gradually zoom in on those groups by
using multiple splits right now you can
help it by telling it the order of your
categorical variable but even if you
don't it's okay it's just going to take
a few more decisions to get there and so
you can see here it's actually using
this product class desk quite a few
times right and and as you go deeper
down the tree you'll see it used more
and more right where else in a linear
model or almost any kind of other model
certainly any any non tree model pretty
much encoding a categorical variable
like this won't work at all because
there's no linear relationship to train
totally arbitrary
identifiers and anything right so so
these are the kinds of things that make
Brennan forests very easy to use and and
very resilient and so by using that you
know we've gotten ourselves a model
which is clearly you know world class at
this point already it's like you know
probably will in the top 20 of this
cackle competition and then in our next
lesson we're going to learn about how to
analyze that model to learn more about
the data to make it even better right so
this week try and like really experiment
right have a look inside look try and
draw the trees try and plot the
different errors try maybe using
different data sets to see how they work
really experiment to try to get a sense
and maybe try to like replicate things
like write your own r-squared you know
write your own versions or some of these
functions see if ya see how much you can
really learn about your data set about
the random person great see you on
Thursday
[Music]