all right welcome back something to
mention somebody asked on the forums
really good question
was like how do I deal with version
control and notebooks the question was
something like every time I change the
notebook Jeremy goes and changes it on
git and then I do a git pull and I end
up with a conflict and I love that and
that's that happens a lot with notebooks
because notebooks behind the scenes at
JSON files which like every time you run
even a cell without changing it it
updates that little number saying like
what numbered cell this is and so now
suddenly there's a change and so trying
to merge notebook changes is a nightmare
so my suggestion I'd like a simple way
to do it is is when you're looking at
some notebook like less than 200 if
interpretation you want to start playing
around with this the first thing I would
do would be to go file make a copy and
then in the copy say file rename and
give it a name that starts with TMP that
will hide it from get right and so now
you've got your own version of that
workbook that you can that you can play
with okay and so if you now do a git
pull and see that the original changed
it won't conflict with yours and you can
now see there are two different versions
there are different ways of kind of
dealing with this Jupiter notebook get
problem like everybody has it one one is
there are some hooks you can use it like
remove all of the cell outputs before
you commit to get but in this case I
actually want the outputs to be in the
repo so you can read it on github and
see it so it's a minor issue but it's a
it's something which catches everybody
ah yes before we move on to
interpretation of the random forest
model I wonder if we could summarize the
relationship between the hyper
parameters on the random forest and its
effect on you know overfitting and
dealing with collinearity and yeah that
sounds like a question born from
experience absolutely so I gotta go back
to lesson 1 RF if you're ever unsure
about where I am you can always see my
top here courses mly and lesson 1 on
earth in terms of the hyper parameters
that are interesting and I'm ignoring
I'm ignoring like pre-processing but
just the actual hyper parameters the
first one of interest I would say is the
set RF samples command which determines
how many rows are in each sample so in
each tree you're created from how many
rows n each tree so before we start a
new tree we either bootstrap a sample so
sampling with replacement from the whole
thing or we pull out a subsample of a
smaller number of rows and then we build
a tree from there so so step one is
we've got our whole big data set and we
grab a few rows at random from it and we
turn them into a smaller data set and
then from that we build a tree right so
that's the size of that is set our F
samples so when we change that size
let's say this originally had like a
million rows and we said set our F
samples twenty thousand right and then
we're going to grow a tree from there
assuming that the tree remains kind of
balanced as we grow it can somebody tell
me how many layers deep with this tree
be and assuming we're growing it until
every leaf is of size one
yes log base 2 of 20,000
right okay so the the depth of the tree
doesn't actually vary that much
depending on the month samples right
because it's it's related to the log of
the size can somebody tell me at the
very bottom so once we go all the way
down to the bottom
how many leaf nodes would there be speak
up what what do you think right because
every single leaf node has a single
thing in it so we've got obviously a
linear relationship between the number
of leaf nodes in the size of the sample
so when you decrease the sample size it
means that there are less kind of final
decisions that can be made right so
therefore the tree is is going to be
less rich in terms of what it can
predict because it's just making less
different individual decisions and it
also is making less binary choices to
get to those decisions so therefore
setting RS samples lower is going to
mean that you over fit less but it also
means that you're going to have a less
accurate individual tree model right and
so remember the way Braman the inventor
of random first described this is that
you're trying to do two things when you
build a model when you build a model
with bagging one is that each individual
tree or as SQL you say each individual
estimator is as accurate as possible
right on the training set so it's like
each model is a strong predictive model
but then the across the estimators
relation between them is as low as
possible so that when you average them
out together you end up with something
that generalizes so by decreasing the
set RF samples number we are actually
decreasing the power of the estimator
and increasing the correlation and so is
that going to result in a better or a
worse validation set result for you
it depends right this is the kind of
compromise which you have to figure out
when you do machine learning models can
you pass that back there
if I wait if I put the Bovie value equal
to so it is basically dividing every 30
it ensures that the data won't be there
in each three right now our page second
probably if I put all the equal to two
yeah random voice yeah so is it that
make sure that out of my entire data 37
personal data would be there in every
tree so all our P equals true does is it
says whatever your sub sample is it
might be a bootstrap sample or it might
be a subsample take all with the other
rows right and put them into a tree tree
and put them into a different data set
and calculate the the error on those so
it doesn't actually impact training at
all it just gives you an additional
metric which is the oob error so if you
don't have a validation set then this
allows you to get kind of a quasi
validation set for free if you want to
set out a sample
Aref sample so that the default is
actually if you say reset our F samples
and that causes it to bootstrap so it
all sample our new data set as big as
the original one but with replacement
okay so obviously the second benefit of
set our samples is that you can run more
quickly and particularly if you're
running on a really large data set like
a hundred million rows you know it won't
be possible to run it on the full data
set so you would either have to pick a
subsample if yourself before you start
or you set our examples
the second key parameter that we learnt
about was min samples leaf okay so if I
changed min samples leaf
for we assumed that men samples leaf was
equal to 1 all right if I set it equal
to 2 then what would be my new depth how
deep would it be
yes
log base to 20,000 minus one okay so
each time we double the min samples leaf
we're removing one layer from the tree
and fine I'll come back to you again
since you're doing so well
how many leaf nodes would there be in
that case
but how many leaf nodes would there be
in that case
10,000 okay so we're gonna be again
dividing the number of leaf nodes by
that number so the result of increasing
min samples leaf is that now each of our
leaf nodes has more than one thing in so
we're going to get a more stable average
that we're calculating in each tree okay
we've got a little bit less depth okay
we've got less decisions to make and
we've got a smaller number of leaf nodes
so again we would expect the result of
that would be that each estimator would
be less predictive but the estimators
would be also less correlated so again
this might help us to avoid overfitting
could you pass the microphone over here
please oh hi Jimmy I'm not sure if in
that case every node will have exactly
two no it won't necessarily have exactly
two and I thank you for mentioning that
so it might try to do a split and so one
reason well what would be an example
Chen XI that you wouldn't split even if
you had a hundred nodes what might be a
reason for that sorry 100 items in a
leaf node they're all the same they're
all the same in terms of the independent
to saw the dependent and it has the
dependent right now I mean I guess
either but much more likely would be the
dependent so if you get to a leaf node
where every single one of them has the
same option price or in classification
like every single one of them is a dog
then there is no split that you can do
that's going to improve your information
all right and remember information is
the term we use in a kind of a general
sense in random for us to describe the
amount of difference about at that
additional information we create from a
split is like how much are we improving
the model so you'll often see this word
information gain which means like how
much better did the model get by adding
an additional split point and it could
be based on our MSC or it could be based
on cross-entropy or it could be based on
how different to the standard deviations
or whatever so that's just a general
term okay so that's the second thing
that we can do
again it's going to speed up our
training because it's like one less set
of decisions to make remember even
though there's one less set of decisions
those decisions like have as much data
again as the previous set so like each
layer of the tree can take like twice as
long as the previous layer so it could
definitely speed up training and it
could definitely make it generalize
better so then the third one that we had
was max features who wants to tell me
what max features does
I want to pass that back over there okay
Vinay we just leave their minds
how many features you're going to use in
HP in this case it's a fraction up so
you're going to use up other be just for
each three nearly right what kind of
right can you be more specific or can
somebody else be more specific it's not
exactly for each tree can she
that is that for each tree randomly
simple healthy so not quite it's not for
each tree so the the set don't possibly
care them so the scent are of samples
picks a picks a subset of samples subset
of rows for each tree but min samples
leaf sorry that max features doesn't
quite do that it's not something
different at each set smell ant will
yeah right so it kind of sounds like a
small difference but it's actually quite
a different way of thinking about it
which is we do our set our samples so we
pull out our sub sample or a bootstrap
sample and that's kept for the whole
tree and we have all of the columns in
there right and then with max features
equals 0.5 at each point we then at each
split we'd pick a different half of the
features and then here what you could
pick a different half of the features
and here we'll pick a different half of
the features and so the reason we do
that is because we want the trees to be
as as rich as possible right so
particularly like if you if you were
only doing a small number of trees like
you had only ten trees and you picked
the same column set all the way through
the tree you're not really getting much
variety and what kind of things are
confined okay so this this way at least
in theory seems to be something which is
going to give us a better set of trees
picking a different random subset of
features at every decision point so the
overall effective max features again
it's the same it's going to mean that
the traits individual tree is probably
going to be less accurate but the trees
are going to be more buried and in
particular here this can be critical
because like imagine that you've got one
feature that's just super predictive
it's so predictive that like every
random subsample you look at always
starts out by splitting on that same
feature then the trees are going to be
very similar in the sense like they all
have the same initial split right but
there may be some other are interesting
initial splits because they create
different interactions of variables so
by like half the time that feature won't
even be available at the top of the tree
so half at least half the trees are
going to have a different initial split
so it definitely can give us more
variation and therefore again it can
help us to create more generalized trees
that have less correlation with each
other even though the individual trees
probably won't be as predictive
in practice we actually looked at have a
little picture of this that as as you
add more trees right if you have max
features equals none that's going to use
all the features every time right then
with like very very few trees that can
still give you a pretty good error but
as you create more trees it's not going
to help as much because they're all
pretty similar because they're all
trying every single variable where else
if you say max features equal square
root or max pictures equals log two then
as we add more estimators we see
improvements okay so there's an
interesting interaction between those
two and this is from the SK loan Docs
this cool little chat okay
so then things which don't impact out
our training at all and jobs simply says
how many cpu how many cause do we run on
okay so it'll make it faster up to a
point
generally speaking making this more than
like eight or so they may have
diminishing returns -1 says use all of
your cause
so there's wrote there's I don't know
why the default is to only use one core
that's seems weird to me you'll
definitely get more performance by using
more cause because all of you have
computers with more than one core
nowadays and then our base core equals
true simply allows us to see the low B
score if you don't say that it doesn't
calculate it and particularly if you had
set RF samples pretty small compared to
a big data set or B is going to take
forever to calculate hopefully at some
point we'll be able to fix the library
so that doesn't happen there's no reason
that need be that way but right now
that's that's how the Bible place okay
our base Kuhn okay basic parameters that
we can change there are more that you
can see in the docs or shift tab to have
a look at them but the ones you've seen
are the ones that I've found useful to
play with so feel free to play with
others as well and generally speaking
you know max features as I said max
features are like either non means all
of them about 0.5 or square root or log
you know kind of those trees seem to
work pretty well and then some in
samples leaf you know I would generally
try kind of 1 3 5 10 25 you know 100 and
like as you start doing that if you
notice by the time you get to 10 it's
already getting worse then there's no
point going further if you get to 100
it's still going better then you can
keep trying right but they're the kind
of general amounts that most things in
to sit in all right
so random forest interpretation is
something which you could use to create
some really cool cattle kernels now
obviously one issue is the faster I
library is not available in Cabell
kernels but if you look inside fast AI
dot structured right remember you can
just use double question mark to look at
the source code for something or you can
go into the editor to have a look at it
you'll see that most of the methods
we're using or a small number of lines
of code in this library and have no
dependencies on anything so you could
just copy that little if you need to use
one of those functions just copy it into
your kernel and and if you do to say
this is from the first day a library you
can link to it on github because it's
available on github as open-source but
you don't need to import the whole thing
right so this is a cool trick is that
because you're the first people to learn
how to use these tools you couldn't
start to show things that other people
haven't seen right so
for example this confidence based on
tree variance is something which doesn't
exist anywhere else feature importance
definitely does and that's already in
quite a lot of cable kernels if you're
looking at a competition or a data set
that where nobody's done feature
importance being the first person to do
that is always going to win lots of
votes because it's like the most
important thing is like which features
are important so last time we let's just
make sure we put our tree data so we
need to change this to add one extra
thing all right so that's no load no
data yet there's that data okay so as I
mentioned when we do mobile
interpretation I tend to set our of
samples to some subset something small
enough that I can ran a model in under
10 seconds or so because there's just no
point run running a super accurate model
fifty thousand is more than enough to
see you'll basically see each time you
run an interpretation you'll get the
same results back and so as long as
that's true then you you're already
using enough data okay
so feature importance we learnt it works
by randomly shuffling a column each
column one at a time and then seeing how
accurate the model the pre trained model
the model we've already built is when
you pass it in all the data as before
but with one column shuffled so some of
the questions I got after class kind of
reminded me that it's very easy to under
appreciated and kind of magic this
approach is and so to explain I'll
mention a couple of the questions that I
heard and so one question was like why
don't we or what if we just um
we took one column at a time and created
a tree on just each one column at a time
so we've got our data set it's got a
bunch of columns so why don't we just
like we have that column and just build
a tree from that right and then like
we'll see which which columns tree is
the most predictive can anybody tell me
why what why that may give misleading
results about feature importance okay
we're going to lose the interactions
between the features yeah if we just
shuffle them it will be a bad randomness
and we were able to both capture the
interactions and the importance of the
future it's great yeah and and so this
issue of interactions is not a minor
detail it's like it's massively
important so like think about this
bulldozes data set where for example
where there's one field called year made
and there's one field called sale date
and like if we think about it it's
pretty obvious that what matters is the
combination of these two which in other
words is like how old is the piece of
equipment when it got sold so if we only
included one of these we're going to
massively underestimate how important
that feature is now here's a really
important point though if you
it's pretty much always possible to
create a simple like logistic regression
which is as good as pretty much any
random first if you know ahead of time
exactly what variables you need exactly
how they interact exactly how they need
to be transformed and so forth right so
in this case for example we could have
created a new field which was equal to
year made as a sale date or sale year -
year made and we could have fed that to
a model and got you know got that
interaction for us but the point is we
never know that like you never like you
might have a guess of it I think some of
these things are interacted in this way
and I think this thing we need to take
the log and so forth but you know the
truth is that the way the world works
the causal structures you know they've
got many many things interacting in many
many subtle ways right and so that's why
using trees whether it be gradient
boosting machines or random forests
works so well so can you pass that to
Terrance please one thing that bit me
years ago was also I tried that doing
one variable at a time thinking oh well
I'll figure out which one's most
correlated with the dependent variable
but what it doesn't pull apart is that
what if all variables are basically
copied the same variable then they're
all going to seem equally important but
in fact it's really just one factor yeah
and that's also true here so if we had
like a column appeared twice right then
shuffling that column isn't going to
make the model much worse right there'll
be if you think about like how it was
built
some of the times particularly if we had
like max features is 0.5 and some of the
times we're going to get version a of
the column some of the time to get going
to get version B of the column so like
half the time shuffling version a of the
column is going to make a tree a bit
worse half the time it's going to make
you know column B you'll make it a bit
worse and so it'll show that both of
those features are somewhat important
and it'll kind of like share the
importance between the two features and
so this is why a reco linearity but
collinearity literally means that
they're linearly related so this isn't
quite right but this is why having two
variables that are related closely
related to each other or more variables
that are closely related to each other
means that you will often underestimate
their importance using this this random
first technique um yes
Terrence and so once we've shuffled and
we get a new model what exactly are the
units of these importances is this a
change in the R squared yeah I mean it
depends on the library we're using so
the units are kind of like
I never think about them I kind of know
that like in this particular library
you know 0.005 is often kind of a cutoff
I would tend to use but all I actually
care about is is this picture right
which is the feature importance ordered
for each variable and then kind of
zooming in turning into a bar plot and
I'm kind of like okay you know here
they're all pretty flat and I can see
okay that's about 0.05 and so I removed
them at that point and just see like the
model hopefully the validation score
didn't get worse and if it did get worse
I'll just increase this a little bit so
I decrease this a little bit until it it
doesn't get worse so yeah the units of
measure of this don't matter too much
and we'll learn later about a second way
of doing variable importance by the way
can you pass that over there
is one of the goals here to remove
variables that I guess your state your
score will not get worse if you remove
them so you might as well get rid of
them yeah so that's what we're going to
do next so so what having looked at our
feature importance plot we said okay it
looks like the ones like less than 0.005
you know that kind of this long tail of
boringness so I said let's try removing
them right so let's just try grabbing
the columns where it's greater than
0.005 and I said let's create a new data
frame called DF keep which is DF train
with just those cap columns create a new
training and validation set with just
those columns created a new random
forest and I looked see how the
validation set score and the validation
set our MSC changed and I found they got
a tiny bit better so if they're about
the same or a tiny bit better than the
thinking my thinking is well this is
just as good a model but it's now
simpler and so now when I redo the
feature importance there's less
collinearity right and so in this case I
saw that year maid went from being like
quite a bit better than the next best
thing which was couple system - way
better than the next best thing okay and
coupler system went from being like
quite a bit more important than the next
two - equally important to the next two
so it did seem to definitely change
these feature importances and hopefully
give me some more insight there
so how did that help our model in
general look what does it mean that your
maid is no way yeah so we're going to
dig into that kind of now but basically
it tells us that for example if we're
looking for like how we're dealing with
missing values is there noise and the
data you know it's a high cardinality
categorical variable they're all
different steps we would take so for
example if it was a high cardinality
categorical variable that was originally
a string right like for example I think
like maybe fi product class description
I remember one of the ones we looked at
the other day he had like first of all
was the type of vehicle and then a
hyphen and then like the size of the
vehicle we might look at that and be
like okay well that was an important
column let's try like splitting it into
two on - and then take that bit which is
like a size of it and trying you know
posit and convert convert it into an
integer you know we can try and do some
feature engineering and basically until
you know which ones are important you
don't know where to focus that feature
engineering time you can talk to your
client you know and say you know or you
know and if you're doing this inside
your workplace you go and talk to the
folks that like we're responsible for
creating this data so in this if you
were actually working at a bulldozer
auction company you might now go to the
actual auctioneers and say I'm really
surprised that couply system seems to be
driving people's pricing decisions so
much why do you think that might be and
they can say to you oh it's actually
because only these classes of vehicles
have capital systems or only this
manufacturer has couple of systems and
so frankly this is actually not telling
you about couple of systems but about
something else and oh hey that reminds
me that's that that's something else we
actually have measured that it's in this
different CSV file I'll go get it for
you but kind of helps you focus your
attention
so I hello
little problem this weekend as you know
I introduced a couple of crazy
computations in into my random forest
and all of a sudden they're like oh my
god these are the most important
variables ever squashing all of the
others but then I got a terrible score
and then is that because now that I
think I have my scores computed
correctly what I noticed is that the
importance went through the roof but the
validation set was still bad or got
worse is that because somehow that
computation allow the training to almost
like an identifier map exactly what the
answer was going to be for training but
of course that doesn't generalize to the
validation set is that what is that what
I observed okay so this there's two
reasons why your validation score might
not be very good um let's go up here
okay so we got these five numbers right
the rmse of the training validation
r-squared of the training validation and
the r-squared of the oeob okay so
there's two reasons and really in the
end what we care about like for this
Cargill competition is the rmse of the
validation set assuming we've created a
good validation set
so an Terrance's case he's saying this
number is this thing I care about got
worse when I did some feature
engineering why is that
okay there's two possible reasons reason
one is that you're overfitting if you're
overfeeding
then your mobiie will also get worse if
you're doing a huge data set with a
small set RF sample so you can't use a
know a B then instead create a second
validation set which is a random sample
okay and and do that right so in other
words if your OB or your random sample
validation set is has got much worse
then you must be overfitting
I think in your case Terrence it's
unlikely that's the problem because
random forests
don't over fit that badly like it's very
hard to get them to overfit that badly
unless you use some really weird
parameters like only one estimator for
example like once we've got ten trees in
there there should be enough variation
that you're you know you can definitely
over fit but not so much that you're
going to destroy your validation score
by adding a variable so I'd think you'll
find that's probably not the case but
it's easy to check and if it's not the
case
then you'll see that your oob score or
your random sample validation score
hasn't got worse okay so the second
reason your validation score can get
worse if your mobiie score hasn't got
worse you're not overfitting but your
validation score is got worse that means
you're you're doing something that is
true in the training set but not true in
the validation set so this can only
happen when your validation set is not a
random sample so for example in this
bulldozes competition or in the grocery
shopping competition we've intentionally
made a validation set that's for a
different date range it's for the most
recent two weeks right and so if
something different happened in the last
two weeks to the previous weeks then you
could totally break your validation set
so for example if there was some kind of
unique identifier which is like
different in the to date periods then
you could learn to identify things using
that identifier in the training set but
then like the last two weeks may have a
totally different set of ID's or the
different set of behavior could get a
lot worse yeah what you're describing is
not common though and so I'm a bit
skeptical it might be a bug but
hopefully there's enough things you can
now use to figure out if it is about
will be interested to hear what you
learned
okay so that's that's feature importance
and so I'd like to compare that to how
feature importance is normally done in
industry and in academic communities
outside of machine learning like in
psychology and economics and so forth
and generally speaking people in those
kind of environments tend to use some
kind of linear regression logistic
regression general linear models so they
start with their data set and they
basically say that was weird
oh okay so they start with their data
set and they say I'm going to assume
that I know the kind of parametric
relationship between my independent
variables and my dependent variable so
I'm going to assume that it's a linear
relationship say or it's a linear
relationship with a link function like a
sigmoid to create logistic regression
say and so assuming that I already know
that I can now write this as an equation
so if I've got like x1 x2 so forth right
I can say all right my Y values are
equal to ax 1 plus BX 2 equals y and
therefore I can find out the feature
importance easily enough by just looking
at these coefficients and saying like
which one's the highest particularly if
you've normalized the data first right
so there's this kind of trope out there
it's it's very common which is that like
this is somehow more accurate or more
pure or in some way better way of doing
feature importance but that couldn't be
further from the truth right if you
think about it if you were like if you
were missing an interaction right or if
you were missing a transformation you
needed or if you have any way being
anything less than a hundred percent
perfect in all of your pre-processing so
that your model is the absolute correct
truth of this situation right unless
you've got all of that correct then your
coefficients are wrong right your
coefficients are telling you in you're
totally wrong model this is how
important those things are right which
is basically meaningless so where else
do the random forest feature importance
it's telling you in this extremely high
parameter highly flexible functional
form with few if any statistical
assumptions this is your future
importance right so I would be very
cautious you know and and again I can't
stress this enough when you when you
leave ence and when you leave this
program you are much more often going
see people talk about logistic
regression coefficients then you're
going to see them talk about random
first variable importance and every time
you see that happen you should be very
very very skeptical of what you're
seeing anytime you read a paper in
economics or in psychology or the
marketing department tells you that this
regression or whatever every single time
those coefficients are going to be
massively biased by any issues in the
model furthermore if they've done so
much pre-processing that actually the
model is pretty accurate then now you're
looking at coefficients that are going
to be of like a coefficient of some
principal component from a CA or a
coefficient of some distance from some
cluster or something
at which point they're very very hard to
interpret anyway they're not actual
variables right so they're kind of the
two options I've seen when people try to
use classic statistical techniques to do
recover a variable importance equivalent
I think things are starting to change
slowly you know there there are some
fields that are starting to realize that
this is totally the wrong way to do
things but it's been you know nearly 20
years since random forests appeared so
it takes a long time you know people say
that the only way that knowledge really
advances is when the previous generation
dies and that's kind of true right like
particularly academics you know they
make a career of being good at a
particular sub thing and you know often
don't if you know it's not until the
next generation comes along that that
people notice that oh that's actually
longer no good way to do things and I
think that's what's happened here okay
so we've got now a model which isn't
really any better as a predictive
accuracy wise but it's kind of we're
getting a good sense that there seems to
be like four main important things when
it was made the capital system its size
and its product classification okay so
that's cool there is something else that
we can do however which is we can do
something called one
hot encoding so this is going to where
we're talking about categorical
variables so remember a categorical
variable let's say we had like a string
high and remember the order we got was
kind of back weird it was high low
medium so it was in alphabetical order
by default right was their original
category for like usage banned or
something
and so we mapped it to 0 1 2 right and
so by the time it gets into our data
frame it's now a number so the random
forest doesn't know that it was
originally a category it's just a number
right so when the random forest is built
it basically says oh is it greater than
1 or not or is it greater than naught or
not you know basically the two possible
decisions it could have made for for
something with like five or six bands
you know it could be that just one of
the levels of a category is actually
interesting right so like if it was like
very high very low or unknown right then
we know that like six levels and maybe
the only thing that mattered was whether
it was like unknown maybe like not
nothing it's sighs somehow impacts the
price and so if we wanted to be able to
recognize that and particularly if like
it just so happened that the way that
the numbers were coded was it unknown
ended up in the middle right then what
it's going to do is it's going to say
okay there is a difference between these
two groups you know less than or equal
to two versus greater than two and then
when it gets into this this leaf here
it's going to say oh there's a
difference between these two between
less than four and greater than or equal
to four and since going to take two
splits to get to the point where we can
see that it's actually unknown that
matters so this is a little inefficient
and we're kind of like wasting tree
computation and like wasting tree
computation
because every time we do a split we're
having the amount of data at least that
we have to do more analysis so it's
going to make our tree less rich less
effective if we're not giving the data
in a way that's kind of convenient for
it to do the work it needs to do so what
we could do instead is create six
columns we could create a column cord is
very high is very low is high is unknown
is low is medium and h1 would be ones
and zeros right so the one or a zero so
we had six columns this one moment
so having added six additional columns
to our data set the random first now has
the ability to pick one of these and say
like oh let's have a look at is unknown
there's one possible fit I can do which
is one versus zero let's see if that's
any good right so it actually now has
the ability in a single step to pull out
a single category level and so this this
kind of coding is called one-hot
encoding and for many many types of
machine learning model this is like
necessary something like this is
necessary like if you are doing logistic
regression
you can't possibly put in a categorical
variable that goes not through five
because there's obviously no written
linear relationship between that and
anything right so one part encoding a
lot of people incorrectly assume that
all machine learning requires one pod
encoding but in this case I'm going to
show you how we could use it optionally
and see whether it might improve things
sometimes yeah
hi Jeremy so we have six categories like
in this case would there would be any
problems with adding a column for each
of the categories Oh Chris in linear
regression we saw we had to do it like
if there's six categories we should only
do it for five of them yeah so um
it you certainly can say oh let's not
worry about adding is medium because we
can infer it from the other five I would
say include it anyway because like
rather than otherwise the random forest
would have to say is very high know is
very low know is high know is unknown
mode is low know okay and finally on
there right so it's like five decisions
to get to that point so the reason in
linear models that you need to not
include one is because linear models
hate collinearity but we don't care
about about that here so we can do one
hot encoding easily enough and the way
we do it is we pass one extra parameter
to proc DF which is what's the max
number of categories right so if we say
it's seven then anything with less than
seven levels is going to be turned into
a one hot encoded bunch of columns right
so in this case this has got six levels
so this would be one hot encoded where
else like zip code has more than six
levels and so that would be left as a
number and so generally speaking you
obviously probably wouldn't want a one
hot in code zip code right because
that's just going to create masses of
data memory problems computation
problems and so forth right so so this
is like another parameter that you can
play around with so if I do that try it
out run the random forest as per usual
you can see what happens to the
r-squared of the validation set and to
the rmse of the validation set and in
this case I found it got a little bit
worse this isn't always the case and
it's going to depend on your data set
you know do you have a data set where
you know single categories tend to be
quite important or not in this
particular case it didn't make it more
predictive how
what it did do is that we now have
different features right so proc TF puts
the name of the variable and then an
underscore and then the level name and
so interestingly it turns out that where
else before it said that enclosure was
somewhat important when we do it as one
hot encoded it actually says enclosure
erupts with AC is the most important
thing so for at least the purpose of
like interpreting your model you should
always try one hot encoding you know
quite a few of your variables and so I
often find somewhere around six or seven
is pretty good you can try like making
that number as high as you can so that
it doesn't take forever to compute and
the feature importance doesn't include
like really tiny levels that aren't
interesting so that's kind of up to you
to play it play around with but in this
case like this is actually I found this
very interesting it clearly tells me I
need to find out what enclosure erupts
with AC is why is it important because
like means nothing to me right and but
it's the most important thing so I
should go figure that out so then I had
a question you plus it
so can you explain how changing the max
number of categories worse because for
me it just seems like there's five
categories or site categories oh yeah
sorry so it's it's just like all it's
doing is saying like okay here's a
column called zip code here's a column
called usage band and here's a column
sex right I don't know whatever right
and so like zip code has whatever five
thousand levels the number of levels in
a category we call its cardinality okay
so it has a cardinality of five thousand
usage banned maybe has a cardinality of
six sex has maybe a cardinality of - so
when proc TF goes through and it says
okay this is a categorical variable
should i one-hot encode it it checks the
cardinality against max and hats and
says all five thousand is bigger than
seven so I don't one hot encoder and
then it goes to usage band 6 is less
than 7 I do one hot encode it goes to
sex 2 is less than 7 I do want to encode
it so it just says for each variable how
do I decide whether the one hot encoded
or not we are keeping legal in cause no
once we decide to one hot in code it
does not keep the original variable
maybe the best will be an interval well
you don't need a labeling code if the if
so if the best is an interval it can
approximate that with multiple one hot
encoding levels yeah so like you know
it's a the the truth is that each column
is going to have some you know different
you know should it be label encoded or
not you know which you could make on a
case-by-case basis I find in practice
it's just not that sensitive to this and
so I find like just using a single
number for the whole data set gives me
what I need but you know if you were
building a model that really had to be
as awesome as possible and you had lots
and lots of time to do it you can go
through men you know don't use property
if you can go through manually and
decide which things to use dummies or
not your you'll see in the code if you
look at the code for property F Rock D F
right like I never want you to feel like
the code that happens to be in the fast
AI library is the code that you're
limited to right so where is that done
you can see that the max n cat gets
passed to numerical eyes and numerical
eyes simply checks okay is that a
numeric type and it's the number of
categories either not in pass to us at
all or we've got more unique values than
there are categories and if so we're
going to use the categorical codes so
for any column where that's where it's
skipped over that right so it's remained
as a category then at the very end we
just go pandas get dummies we pass in
the whole data frame and so a pandas get
that means you pass in a whole data
frame it checks for anything that's
still a categorical variable and it
turns it into a dummy variable which is
another way of saying a one-pot encoding
so you know with that kind of approach
you can easily override it into your own
dummy verification variable ization did
you have a question so some data has a
quite obvious order like if you have
like a grading system like food bad or
whatever things like that there's an
order to that and showing that order by
doing the dummy variable thing probably
will your benefit so is there a way to
just force it to leave alone one
variable just like invert it or
yourself not not in the library and to
remind you like unless we explicitly do
something about it we're not going to
get that order so when we when we import
the data so this is in Lesson one RF we
showed how by default the categories are
ordered alphabetically and we have the
ability to order them properly so yeah
if you've actually made an effort to
turn your ordinal variables into proper
ordinals using prop D F can destroy that
if you have max MCATs
so the simple thing the simple way to
avoid that is if we know that we always
want to use the codes for usage banned
rather than the you know like never one
hot encoder you could just go ahead and
replace it right you could just say okay
let's just go D F dot u s-- taband
equals DF q suspend cat codes and it's
now an integer and so it'll never get
page all right so
we kind of already seen how
variables which are basically measuring
the same thing can kind of confuse our
variable importance and there can also
make our random forest slightly less
good because it requires like more
computation to do the same thing there's
more columns to check so I'm going to do
some more work to try and remove
redundant features and the way I do that
is to do something called a dendrogram
and it's a kind of hierarchical
clustering so cluster analysis is
something where you're trying to look at
objects they can be either rows in the
data set or columns and find which ones
are similar to each other so often
you'll see people particularly talking
about cluster analysis they normally
refer to rows of data and they'll say
like oh let's plot it right and like oh
there's a cluster and there's a cluster
right a common type of cluster analysis
time - permitting we may get around to
talking about this in some detail is
called k-means which is basically where
you assume that you don't have any
labels at all and you take basically a
couple of data points at random and you
gradually find the ones that are near to
it and move them closer and closer to
centroids and you kind of repeat it
again and again and it's an iterative
approach that you basically tell how
many clusters you want and it'll tell
you where it thinks that classes are I
really I don't know why but I really
under use technique 20 30 years ago it
was much more popular than it is today
is hierarchical clustering
hierarchical also known as agglomerated
clustering and in hierarchical order
agglomerative clustering we basically
look at every pair of option up every
pair of objects and say okay which two
objects are the closest alright so in
this case we might go okay those two
objects are the closest and so we've
kind of like delete them and replace it
with the midpoint of the two and then
okay here the next two closest if we
delete them and replace them with the
midpoint of the two and you keep doing
that again
again right since we're kind of removing
points and replacing them with their
averages you're gradually reducing a
number of points by pairwise combining
and the cool thing is you can plot that
like so right
so if rather than looking at points you
look at variables we can say okay which
two variables are the most similar it
says okay say year and sale elapsed
they're very similar so the kind of
horizontal axis here is how similar are
the two points that are being compared
right so if they're closer to the right
that means they're very similar so sale
year and sale elapsed have been combined
and they were very similar again it's
like okay as you know it'll be like
correlation coefficient or something
like that you know in this particular
case what I actually did so you get to
tell it so in this case I actually used
Spearman's R so you guys familiar with
correlation coefficients already all
right so correlation is cut as almost
exactly the same as the r-squared right
but it's between two variables rather
than a variable and it's prediction the
problem with a normal correlation is
that if the I create a new workbook here
if you have data that looks like this
then you can do a correlation and you'll
get a good result right but if you've
got data which looks like this right and
you try and do a correlation it assumes
linearity that's not very good right so
there's a thing called a rank
correlation a really simple idea
it's replace every point by its rank
right so instead of like so we basically
say okay this is the smallest so we'll
call that one - there's the next one
three is next one four five right so you
just replace every number by its rank
and then you do the same for the y-axis
so
that 1 2 3 and so forth right and so
then you do it like a new plot where you
don't plot the data but you plot the
rank of the data and if you think about
it the rank of this data set is going to
look an exact line because every time
something was greater on the x-axis
it was also greater on the y-axis so if
we do a correlation on the rank that's
called a rank correlation okay and so
because I want to find the columns that
are similar in a way that the random
forest would find them similar random
forests don't care about linearity they
just care about ordering so a rank
correlation is the the right way to
think about that so Spearman's are is is
the name of the most common rank
correlation but you can literally
replace the data with its rank and chuck
it at the regular correlation and you'll
get basically the same answer the only
difference is in how ties are handled
it's a pretty minor issue if you had
like a full parabola in that rank
correlation you'll will not write right
it has to be has to be monotonic yeah
yeah
okay so once I've got a correlation
matrix there's basically a couple of
standard steps you do to turn that into
a dendogram which I have to look up on
stackoverflow each time I do it you
basically turn it into a distance matrix
and then you create something that tells
you you know which things are connected
to which other things hierarchically so
this kind of these two and this step
here like just three standard steps that
you always have to do to create a
dendogram and so then you can plot it
and so alright so say your and sell a
lot soon to be measuring basically the
same thing at least in terms of rank
which is not surprising because they
elapsed is the number of days since the
first day in my data set so obviously
these two are nearly entirely correlated
with some ties browser tracks and
hydraulics flow and coupla system all
seem to be measuring the same thing and
this is interesting because remember
coupla system it said was super
important right and so this rather
supports our hypothesis there's nothing
to do with whether it's a coupler system
but whether it's whatever kind of
vehicle it is it has these kind of
features product group and product
groups desk seem to be measuring the
same thing if I base model on fi model
desk seem to be measuring the same thing
and so once we get past that everything
else like suddenly the things are
further away so I'm probably going to
not worry about those so we're going to
look into these one two three four
groups that are very similar could you
pass that over there
the citizen that grabbed that the
similarity between stick glint and
enclosure is higher than with stick lens
and anything that's higher yeah pretty
much I mean it it's a little hard to
interpret but given that stick length
and enclosure don't join up until way
over here yeah it would strongly suggest
that then that they're a long way away
from each other otherwise you would
expect them we were joined up earlier I
mean it's it's possible to construct
like a synthetic data set where you kind
of end up joining things that were close
to each other through different paths so
you've got to be a bit careful but I
think it's fair to is probably assume
that stick length or enclosure are
probably very different so they are very
different but would they be more similar
than for example stick length and sale
day of year no which is in a very top no
there's nothing to suggest that here
because like the key point is to notice
where they sit in this tree right and
they both that they sit in totally
different halves of the tree thank you
but really to actually know that the
best way would be to actually look at
this p.m. and our correlation matrix and
if you just want to know how similar is
this thing or this thing
the Spearman our correlation matrix
tells you that can you plus that over
there
so today's we are passing the leader
cream right second we are passing the
cream this is just a data frame so we're
passing in DF Cape so that's the data
frame containing the whatever it was 30
or so features that our random forest
thought was interesting
so there's no random first being used
here the measure the distance measure is
being done entirely on rent correlation
so what I then do is I take these these
groups right and I create a little
function that I call get out of fans
score right which is it does a random
forest for some data frame I make sure
that I've taken that data frame and
split it into a training and validation
set and then I call fit and return the
oeob score right so basically what I'm
going to do is I'm going to try removing
each one of these one two three four
five six seven and eight nine or so
variables one at a time and see which
ones I can remove and it doesn't make
the oob score get worse and each time I
run this I get slightly different
results so actually it looks like last
time I had seven things not not eight
things so you can see I just do a loop
through each of the things that I'm
thinking like maybe I could get rid of
this because it's redundant and I print
out the column name and the oeob score
of a model that is trained after
dropping that one column okay so the
oeob score on my whole data frame is
point eight nine and then after dropping
each one of these things
they're basically none of them get much
worse sale elapsed is getting quite a
bit worse than say all year but like it
looks like pretty much everything else I
can drop with like only like a third
decimal place problem so obviously
though you've got to remember the
dendogram let's take fi model discs and
Fi based model right they're very
similar to each other right so what this
says isn't that I can get rid of both of
them right I can get rid of one of them
because they're basically measuring the
same thing okay so so then I try it I
say okay let's try getting rid of one
from each group say oh yeah F by based
model and grouse attracts okay and like
let's now have a look it's like okay
I've gone from point eight nine oh two
point eight eight eight it's like again
so close as to be meaningless so that
sounds good simpler is better so I'm now
going to drop those columns from my data
frame and then I can try running the
full model again and I can see you know
so reset our air samples means I'm using
my whole data frame my whole bootstrap
sample used for tea estimators and I've
got 0.90 seven okay
so I've now got a model which is smaller
and simpler and I'm getting a good score
for so at this point I've now got rid of
as many columns as I feel I comfortably
can ones that either didn't have a good
feature importance or were highly
related to other variables and the model
didn't get worse significantly whenever
when I removed them so now I'm at the
point where I want to try and really
understand my data better by taking
advantage of the model and we're going
to use something called partial
dependence and again this is something
that you could like using the Carroll
kernel and lots of people are going to
appreciate this because almost nobody
knows about partial dependence and it's
a very very powerful technique what
we're going to do is we're going to find
out for the features that are important
how do they relate to the dependent
variable right so let's have a look
right so let's again since we're doing
interpretation we'll set set our samples
to 50,000 to run things quickly we'll
take our data frame we'll get our
feature importance and notice that we're
using Max and Kat because I'm actually
pretty interested in terms of
interpretation and seeing the individual
levels and so here's the top 10 and so
let's try and learn more about those top
10 so year made is the second most
important so one obvious thing we could
do would be to plot year made against
sale elapsed because as we've talked
about already like it just seems to make
sense that both important but it seems
very likely that they kind of combine
together to find like how old was the
product when it was sold so we could try
plotting year made against sale elapsed
to see how they relate to each other and
when we do we get this very ugly graph
and it shows us that year made actually
has a whole bunch that are a thousand
right so clearly you know this is where
I would tend to go back to the client or
whatever and say ok I'm guessing that
these bulldozers weren't actually made
in the Year 1000 and they would
presumably say to me oh yes they're ones
where we don't know where it was made
you know maybe before 1986 we didn't
track that or maybe the things that are
sold in Illinois we don't have that data
provided or or whatever they tell us
some reason so in order to understand
this plot better I'm just going to
remove them from this interpretation
section of the analysis so I'm just
going to say ok let's just grab things
where year made is greater than 1930
ok so let's now look at the relationship
between year made and sale press and
there's a really great package called GG
plot GG plot originally was an
package G G stands for the grammar of
graphics and the grammar of graphics is
like this very powerful way of thinking
about how to produce charts in a very
flexible way I'm not going to be talking
about it much in this class there's lots
of information available online but I
definitely recommend it as a great
package to use ggplot which you can pip
install it's part of the first AI
environment already ggplot in python has
basically the same parameters and API as
the R version the R version is much
better documented so you should read
it's documentation to learn how to use
it but basically you say okay I want to
create a plot of this data frame now
when you create plots most of the
datasets you're using are going to be
too big to plot as in like if you do a
scatter plot it'll create so many dots
that it's just a big mess it'll take
forever
and remember when you're plotting things
you just you're you're looking at it
right so there's no point putting
something with a hundred million samples
when if you're only used a hundred
thousand samples it's going to be pixel
identical right so that's why I call get
sample first so get sample just grabs a
random sample okay so I'm just going to
grab five hundred points for now okay so
I've got a grab five at a point from my
data frame I got a plot a year made
against sale price a EES stands for
aesthetic this is the basic way that you
set up your columns in ggplot okay so
this says to plot these columns from
this data frame and then there's this
weird thing and GG plot where plus means
basically add chart elements okay so I'm
going to add a smoother so most of the
very very often you'll find that a
scatter plot is very hard to see what's
going on because there's too much
randomness or else a smoother basically
creates a little linear regression for
every little subset of the graph and so
it kind of joins it up and allows you to
see a nice smooth curve okay
so this is like the main way that I tend
to look at univariate relationships and
by adding standard error equals true it
also shows me the confidence interval of
this smoother right so low S stands for
locally weighted regression which is
this idea of like doing kind of out
doing lots of little mini regressions so
we can see here the relationship between
year made and sale price is kind of all
over the place right which is like not
really what I would expect
I would I would have expected that more
recent stuff it sold more recently would
probably be like more expensive because
of inflation and because there like more
current models and so forth and the
problem is that when you look at a
univariate relationship like this
there's a whole lot of collinearity
going on a whole lot of interactions
that are being lost so for example why
did the price drop yeah is it actually
because like things made between 1991
and 1997 are less valuable or is
actually because most of them were also
sold during that time and actually there
was like maybe a recession then or maybe
it was like products sold during that
time a lot more people but buying types
of vehicle that were less expensive like
there's all kinds of reasons for that
and so again as data scientists one of
the things are going to keep seeing is
that at the companies that you join
people will come to you with with these
kind of univariate charts where they'll
say like oh my god our sales in Chicago
have disappeared that got really bad or
people aren't clicking on this add
anymore and they'll show you a chart
that looks like this and they'll be like
what happened and most of the time
you'll find the answer to the question
what happened is that there's something
else going on right so I actually are in
Chicago last week actually we were doing
a new promotion and that's why you know
revenue went down it's not because
people are buying stuff in Chicago
anymore it's because the prices were
lower for instance so what we really
want to be able to do is say well what's
the relationship between sale price and
year made
all other things being equal so all
other things being equal basically means
if we sold something in 1990 versus 1980
and it was exactly the same thing -
exactly the same person in exactly the
same option so on and so forth what
would have been the difference in price
and so to do that we do something called
a partial dependence plot and this is a
partial dependence plot there's a really
nice library which nobody's heard of
called PDP which does these partial
dependence plots and what happens is
this we've got our sample of 500 data
points right and we're going to do
something really interesting we're going
to take each one of those hundred
randomly chosen options and we're going
to make a little data set out of it
right so like here's our
here's elf come on here's our data set
of like 500 options and here's our
columns one of which is the thing that
we're interested in which is year made
so here's year made okay and what we're
going to do is we're now going to try
and create a chart where we're going to
try and say all other things being equal
in 1960
how much did bulldozers cost how much
did things cost in options and so the
way we're going to do that is we're
going to replace the year made column
with 1960 we're going to copy in the
value 1960 again and again and again all
the way down right so now every row the
year made is 1960 and all of the other
data is going to be exactly the same and
we're going to take our random forest
we're going to pass all this through our
random forest to predict the sale price
so that will tell us for everything that
was auctioned how much do we think it
would have been sold for if that thing
was made in 1960 and that's what we're
going to plot here all right that's the
price we're going to put here and then
we're going to do the same thing for
1961 alright we're going to replace all
these and do 1961 yeah so to be clear
we've already fit the random forest yes
and then we're just passing a new year
and seeing what it determines the price
should be yeah so this is a lot like the
way we did feature importance but rather
than randomly shuffling the column we're
going to replace the column with a
constant value all right so randomly
shuffle in the column tells us how
accurate it is when you don't use that
column anymore
replacing the whole column with a
constant tells us or estimates for us
how much we would have sold that product
for in that auction on that day in that
place if that product had been made in
right so we basically then take the
average of all of the sale prices that
we calculate from that random first and
so we drew it in 1961 and we get this
value right so what the partial
dependence plot here shows us is each of
these light blue lines actually is
showing us all 500 lions so it says for
row number 1 in our data set if we sold
it in 1960 we're going to index that to
0 right so call that zero right if we
sold it in 1970 that particular auction
would have been here if we sold it in
1980 I would have been here if he sold
in 1990 would have been here so we
actually plot all 500 predictions of how
much every one of those 500 auctions
would have gone for if we replace it
before replacing a year made with each
of these different values and then then
this dark line here is the average right
so this tells us how much would we have
sold on average all of those options for
if all of those products were actually
made in 1985 1990 1993 1994 and so forth
and so you can see what's happened here
is at least in the period where we have
a reasonable out of data which is since
1990 this is basically a totally
straight line which is what you would
expect right because if it was sold on
the same date and it was the same kind
of tractor it sold to the same person in
the same option house then you would
expect more recent vehicles to be more
expensive because of inflation and
because they're they're newer right
they're not they're not as secondhand
and you would expect that relationship
to be roughly linear and that's exactly
what we're finding ok so by removing all
of these externalities it often allows
us to see the truth much more clearly as
a question the back can you pass that
back there you're done ok so um
this this partial dependents plot
concept is something which is using a
random forest to get us a more clear
interpretation of what's going on in our
data and so the steps were to first of
all look at the feature importance to
tell us like which things do we think we
care about and then to use the partial
dependence plot to tell us what's going
on on average right there's another cool
thing we can do with PDP as we can use
clusters and what clusters does is it
uses cluster analysis to look at all of
these each one of the 500 rows and say
to some of those 500 roads kind of move
in the same way and like we could kind
of see it seems like there's a whole lot
of rows that kind of go down and then up
and there seems to be a bunch of rows
that kind of go up and then go flat like
it does seem like there's some kind of
different types of behaviors being
hidden and so here is the result of
doing that cluster analysis right is we
still get the same average but it says
here kind of the five most common shapes
that we see and this is where you could
then go in and say all right it looks
like some kinds of vehicle actually
after 1990 their prices are pretty flat
and before that they were pretty linear
some kinds of vehicle and of exactly the
opposite and so like different kinds of
vehicle have these different shapes
right and so this is something you could
dig into I think it was one at the back
oh you could okay so what we're going to
do with this information well the
purpose of interpretation is to learn
about a data set and so why do you want
to learn about a data set it's because
you it's because you want to do
something with it right so in this case
it's not so much something if you're
trying to win a cogwheel competition I
mean it can be a little bit like some of
these insights might make you realize
all I could transform this variable or
create this interaction or whatever
obviously feature importance is super
important for cowgirl competitions but
this one
much more for like real life you know so
this is when you're talking to somebody
and you say to them like okay those
plots you've been showing me which
actually say that like there was this
kind of dip in prices you know based on
like things made between 1990 and 1997
there wasn't really you know actually it
was they were increasing there was
actually something else going on at that
time
no it's basically the thing that allows
you to say like so whatever this outcome
I'm trying to drive in my business is
this is how something's driving it all
right so if it's like I'm looking at you
know kind of advertising technology
what's driving clicks that I'm actually
digging into say okay this is actually
how clicks are being driven this is
actually the variable that's driving it
this is how it's related so therefore we
should change our behavior in this way
that's really the goal of any model I
guess there's two possible goals 1 goal
of a model is just to get the
predictions like if you're doing hedge
fund trading you probably want to know
what the price of that equity is going
to be if you're doing insurance you
probably just want to know how much
claims that guy's going to have but
probably most of the time you're
actually trying to change something
about how you do business how you do
marketing how you do just sticks so the
thing you actually care about is how the
things are related to each other all
right I'm sorry can you explain again
when you scroll up and you were looking
at the sale pricier may looking at the
entire model and you saw that dip and
you said something about that dip didn't
signify what we thought it did can you
explain why yeah so this is like a
classic boring univariate plot right so
this is basically just taking all of the
dots all of the options plotting year
made against sale price and we're gonna
just fitting a rough average through
them and so
true that products made between 1992 and
1997 on average in our data set are
being sold for less so like very often
in business you'll hear somebody look at
something like this and they'll be like
oh we should we should stop auctioning
equipment that is made in that year in
those years because like we're getting
less money for example but if the truth
actually is that during those years it's
just that people were making more small
industrial equipment where you would
expect it to be sold for less and
actually our profit on it is just as
high for instance or during those years
it's not that it's not things made
during those years now would have repeat
cheaper it's that during those years
when we were selling things in those
years they were cheaper because like
there was a recession going on so if
you're trying to like actually take some
action based on this you probably don't
just care about the fact that things
made in those years are cheaper on
average but how does that impact today
you know so so this this approach where
we actually say let's try and remove all
of these externalities so if something
is sold on the same day to the same
person of the same kind of vehicle then
actually have as year made impact price
and so this basically says for example
if I am deciding what to buy at an
option then this is kind of saying to me
okay like getting a more recent vehicle
on average really does on average give
you more money which is not what the
kind of the naive univariate plot said
that because it's Tyler
[Music]
for like this bulldozer bulldozers made
in 2010 probably are not close to the
type of bulldozers that were made in
1960 right and if you're taking
something that would be so very
different like a 2010 bulldozer and then
trying to just drop it to say oh if it
was made in 1960 that may cause poor
prediction at a point because it's so
you're outside absolutely rainy
absolutely so you know I think that's a
good point it's you know it's a
limitation however random forest is if
you're got a kind of data point that's
like over client you know which is kind
of like in a part of the space that it's
not seen before like maybe people didn't
put air conditioning really in
bulldozers in 1960 and you're saying how
much would this bulldoze over their
conditioning have gone for 1960 you
don't really have any information to
know that so you know you it's a it's
it's this is still the best technique I
know of but it's it's not perfect and
you know you kind of hope that the trees
are still going to find some useful
truth even if though it hasn't seen that
combination of features before but yeah
it's something to be aware of so you can
also do the same thing in a PDP
interaction plot and a PDP interaction
plot which is really what I'm trying to
get to here is like how to sail elapsed
and year made together impact price and
so if I do a PDP interaction plot it
shows me sail elapsed versus price it
shows me year made versus price and it
shows me the combination versus price
remember this is always log of price
that's why these prices look weird right
and so you can see that the combination
of sale elapsed and year made is as you
would expect later dates so more or less
time is giving me I'm sorry it's the
other way around isn't it so the higher
crisis those where there's the least
elapsed and the most recent year made so
you can see here there's the univariate
relationship between sale elapsed and
price and here is the univariate
relationship between year made and price
and then here is the combination of the
two it's enough to see like clearly that
these two things are driving christs
together you can also see these are not
like simple diagonal lines so it's kind
of some interesting interaction going on
and so based on looking at these plots
it's enough to make me think oh we
should maybe put in some kind of
interaction term and see what happens
so let's come back to that in a moment
but let's just look at a couple more
remember in this case I did one hot
encoding way back at the top here I said
max and cat equals seven so I've got
like enclosure erupts with AC so if
you've got one hot encoded variables you
can pass an array of them to pit plot
PDP and it'll treat them as a category
right and so in this case I'm going to
create a PDP plot of these three
categories I'm going to call it
enclosure and I can see here that
enclosure erupts with AC on average are
more expensive than enclosure erupts and
enclosure arose it actually looks like
enclosure erupts from closure erupts are
pretty similar
or else erupts with AC is higher so this
is you know at this point you know I
probably being fine to hop into Google
and like type erupts and erupts and find
out what the hell these things are and
here we go
so it turns out that erupts is enclosed
rollover protective structure and so it
turns out that if your your bulldozer is
fully enclosed then optionally you can
also get air conditioning so it turns
out that actually this thing is telling
us whether it's got air conditioning if
it's an open structure then obviously
you don't have air conditioning at all
so that's what these three levels are
and so we've now learnt all other things
being equal the same bulldozer sold at
the same time built at the same time
sold to the same person is going to be
quite a bit more expensive is if it has
air conditioning than if it doesn't ok
so again we're kind of getting this nice
interpretation ability and you know now
that I spent some time with this data
set I'd certainly noticed that this you
know knowing this is the most important
thing you do notice that there's a lot
more air conditioned bulldozers nowadays
and they used to be and so there's
definitely an interaction between kind
of date and that so based on the earlier
interaction analysis I've tried
first of all setting everything before
1950 to 1950s it seems to be some kind
of missing value I've been set age to be
equal to sale year - year made and so
then I try running a random forest on
that and indeed page is now the single
biggest thing sale elapsed is way back
down here year made is back down here so
we've kind of used this to find an
interaction but remember of course a
random forest can create or it can
create an interaction through having
multiple split points so we shouldn't
assume that this is actually going to be
a better result and in practice I
actually found when I looked at my score
and my rmse adding age was actually a
little worse and we'll see about that
later probably in the next lesson ok
so one last thing is tree interpreter so
this is also in the category of things
that most people don't know exists but
it's super important almost pointless
for like cattle competitions but super
important for real life and here's the
idea let's say you're an insurance
company and somebody rings up and you
give them a quote and they say oh that's
five hundred dollars more than last year
why okay so in general you've made a
prediction from some model and somebody
asks why and so this is where we use
this method called tree interpreter and
what tree interpreter does is it allows
us to take a particular row so in this
case we're going to pick row number zero
right so here here is row zero right uh
presumably this is like year made I
don't know what all the codes stand for
but like his is all of the columns in
row 0 what I can do with a tree
interpreter is I can go t i dot predict
pass in my random forest pass in my row
so this would be like this particular
customers insurance information or this
in this case this particular option
right and it'll give me back three
things the first is the prediction from
the random forest the second is the bias
the bias is basically the average sale
price across the whole original data set
right so like remember you know random
forest we started with single trees oh
we haven't got to draw in there anymore
but remember we started with a single
tree in our random forest
and we split it once and then we spit
that once and then we split that one
straight we said like oh what's the
average value for the whole data set
then what's the average value for those
where the first split was true and then
what's the average value where the next
that was also true until eventually you
get down to the leaf nodes where you've
got the average value you predict right
so you can kind of think of it this way
if this for a single tree if this is our
final leaf node right maybe we're
predicting like nine point one right and
then maybe the average log sale price
for the whole the whole lot is like ten
point two right that's the average
through all the options and so you could
kind of like work your way down here so
let's go and create this that's actually
go and run this so I can see it okay so
let's go back and redraw this single
tree you'll find like in Jupiter
notebooks often a lot of the things we
create like videos progress bars and
stuff they don't know how to like save
themselves to the file so you'll see
just like a little string here and so
you actually have to rerun it to create
the string so this was the single tree
that we created
so the whole dataset had an average log
sale price of 10.2 the data set for
those with capital system equals true
had an average of ten point three the
data set for capital system equals true
enclosure less than point lesson two was
nine point nine and then eventually we
get all the way up here and also a model
ID less than forty five seventy three
it's ten point two so you could kind of
like say okay why did this particular
row let's say we had a row that ended up
over in this leaf node why did we
predict him point two well it's because
we start with ten point one nine and
then because the capitalist system was
was was less than point five so it was
actually false
we added about point two to that so we
went from ten point one to ten point
three right so ten point two to ten
point three so we added a little bit
because if this one is true and then to
go from ten point three to nine point
nine so because enclosure is less than
two we subtracted about 0.4 and then
because model ID was less than
45-hundred we added about point seven
right so you can see like with a single
tree you could like break down like why
is it that we predicted ten point two
retinas like and each one of these
decision points we're adding or
subtracting a little bit from the value
so what we could then do is we could do
that for all the treats
and then we could take the average so
every time we see enclosure did we
increase or decrease the value and how
much by every time we see model ID did
we increase what decrease the value and
how much by and so we could take the
average of all of those and that's what
ends up in this thing called
contributions so here is all of our
predictors and here is the value of each
and so this is telling us and I've
sorted them here that the fact that this
thing was made in 1999 was the thing
that most negatively impacted our
prediction and the fact that the age of
the vehicle was 11 years was more most
positively impacted
um I think you actually needs a sort
after you zip them together they seem to
be sort of negative point five well my
bunions are sorted but then they're just
reassigned to the columns in the
original order which is what's thank you
thank you that makes perfect sense
yes we need to do an index sort okay
thank you we will make sure we fix that
by next week so we need to sort columns
by the index from contributions so then
there's this thing called bias and so
the bias is just the average but before
we start doing any splits right so if
you basically start with the average log
of value and then we went down each tree
and each time we saw a year made we had
some impact couple systems some impact
product size some impact and so forth
right
[Music]
okay so I think what we might do is we
might come back to because we could have
out of time we might come back to tree
interpreter next time
but the basic idea this is the last this
is the last of our key interpretation
points and the basic idea is that we
want some ability to not only tell us
about the model as a whole and how it
works on average but to look at how the
model makes predictions for an
individual row and that's what we're
doing here okay great next everybody see
you on this way