so let's just yeah let's start by
reviewing kind of what we've learnt
about optimizing multi-layer functions
with SGD and so the idea is that we've
got some data and then we do something
to that data for example we multiply it
by a weight matrix and then we do
something to that for example we put it
through a softmax or a sigmoid and then
we do something to that such as do a
cross entropy loss or a root mean
squared error loss okay and that's gonna
like give us some scalar so this is
gonna have no hidden layers this has got
a linear layer a nonlinear activation
being a soft Max and a loss function
being a root mean squared error or a
cross entropy all right and then we've
got our input data port linear nonlinear
bus so for example if this was sigmoid
or softmax and this was cross entropy
then that would be logistic regression
so it's still ya cross entropy yeah
let's do that next short for now think
of it like think of RIT means great
error same thing some loss function okay
now we'll look at cross entropy again in
the moment so how do we calculate the
derivative of that with with respect to
our weights right so really it would
probably be better if we said X comma W
yeah because it's really a function of
the weights as well and so we want the
derivative of this with respect to our
weights sorry I put it in the wrong spot
Oh G f of X comma W that's why that
didn't make sense all right so to do
that we just basically we do the chain
rule so we just say that this is equal
to H of U and u equals G well G du
equals G of V and V equals f of X so we
can just rewrite it like that right and
then we can do the chain rule so we can
say that's equal to H - the derivative
is H - u by G dash V by F dash X hacker
with all that so far okay so in order to
take the derivative with respect to the
weights therefore we just have to
calculate that derivative with respect
to W using that exact formula so if we
had in there yeah yeah so so d of all
that DW would be yep
so then if if we you know went further
here and had like another linear layer
right that's going to be more room now
that linear layer I cover
w2 okay so we have another Lydia lair
there's no difference to now calculate
the derivative with respect to all of
the parameters we can still use the
exact same chain rule right so so don't
think of the multi-layer network as
being like things that occur at
different times it's just a composition
of functions and so we just use the
chain rule to calculate all the
derivatives at once you know there's
that there just a set of parameters that
happen to appear in different parts of
the function but look at that the
calculus is no no different so to
calculate this with respect to w1 and w2
you know it's it's just you just
increase you know W you can just now
just call it W and say w1 is all of
those weights so the result ah that's a
great question
so what you're going to have then is a
list of parameters right so here's w1
and like it's it's it's probably some
kind of higher rank tensor you know like
if it's a convolutional layer it'll you
don't be like a wreck three tensor or
whatever but we can flatten it out that
would just make it a list of parameters
there's w1 here's w2 okay it's just
another list of parameters right and
here's our loss which is a single you
know a single number so therefore our
derivative is just a vector of that same
length right it's how much does changing
that value of W affect the loss
how much does changing that value of W
affect the loss right so you can
basically think of it as a function like
you know y equals ax 1 plus BX 2 plus C
right and say like oh what's the
derivative of that with respect to a B
and C and you would have three numbers
the derivative with respect to a and B
and C and that's all this is right if
the derivative with respect to that
weight that weight and that weight and
that weight that went that way to get
there inside the chain rule we had to
calculate and a lot of detail here but
we had to calculate like jacobians so
like the derivative when you take a
matrix product is you've now got
something where you've got like a a
weight matrix and you've got an input
vector these are the activations and the
previous layer right and you've got some
new output activations right and so now
you've got to say like okay for this
particular sorry for this particular
weight hablas changing this particular
weight change this particular output and
how does changing this particular weight
change this particular output and so
forth so you kind of end up with these
higher dimensional tensors showing like
for every weight how does it affect
every output all right but then by the
time you get to the last function the
last function is going to have like a
mean or a sum or or something so they're
all going to get added up in the end and
so this kind of thing like I don't know
it drives me a bit crazy to try and
calculate it out by hand or even think
of it step by step because you tend to
have like you just have to remember for
every input and Aleya for every output
in the next layer you know you're going
to have to account for every weight for
every output you're going to have to
have a separate grant yet one good way
to look at this is to learn to use PI
torches like dot grad attribute and got
backward method manually and like look
up the to tour the pi torched
tutorials and so you can actually start
setting up some calculations with a
vector import in the vector output and
then type dot backward and then say type
grad and like look at it right and then
do some really small ones with just two
or three items in the input and output
vectors and let make the make the
operation like plus two or something and
like see what the shapes are make sure
it makes sense yeah because it's kind of
like this vector matrix calculus is not
like introduces zero new concepts to
anything you learnt in high school like
strictly speaking but getting a feel for
how these shapes move around I find took
a lot of practice you know the good news
is you almost never have to worry about
it okay so we were talking about then
using this kind of logistic regression
for NLP and before we got to that point
we were talking about using naive Bayes
for NLP and the basic idea was that we
could take a document write a review
like this movie is good and turn it into
a bag of words representation consisting
of the number of times each word appears
right and we call this the vocabulary
this is the unique list of words okay
and we used the SK learn count
vectorizer to automatically generate
both the vocabulary which in SK low and
they call they call the features and to
court create the bag of words
representation z' and the whole group of
them then is called a term document
matrix okay and we kind of realized that
we could calculate the probability that
a positive review contains the word this
by just averaging the number of
time disappears and the positive reviews
and we could do the same for the and we
could do the same for the negatives all
right and then we could take the ratio
of them to get something which if it's
greater than one was a word that
appeared more often in the positive
reviews or less than one was a word that
appeared more often than the negative
reviews okay and then we realized you
know using using Bayes rule that we and
taking the logs that we could basically
end up with something where we could add
up the logs of these plus the log of the
ratio of the probabilities that things
are in class one versus class zero and
end up with something we can compare to
zero if it's be greater than zero then
we can predict a document is positive or
if it's less than zero we can predict
the document is negative and that was
our Bayes rule all right so we kind of
did that from math first principles and
I think we agreed that the the naive in
naive Bayes was a good description
because it assumes independence when
it's definitely not true but it's an
interesting starting point and I think
it was interesting to observe when we
actually got to the point where like
okay now we've you know calculated the
the ratio of the probabilities and took
the log and now rather than multiply
them together of course we have to add
them up and when when we actually wrote
that down we realized like oh that is
you know just a standard weight matrix
product plus a bias right and so then we
kind of realized like oh okay so like if
this is not very good accuracy eighty
percent accuracy
why not improve it by saying hey we know
other ways to calculate a cut you know a
bunch of coefficients and a bunch of
biases which is to learn them in a
logistic regression alright so in other
words this this is the
meanwhile we use for a logistic
regression and so why don't we just
create a logistic regression and fit it
okay and it's going to be give us the
same thing but rather than coefficients
and biases which are theoretically
correct based on you know this
assumption of Independence and based on
Bayes rule there'll be the coefficients
and biases that are actually the best in
this data right so that was kind of
where we got to and so the kind of key
insight here is like just about
everything I find a machine learning
ends up being either like a tree or you
know a bunch of matrix products and
monomi era T's right like it's
everything seems to end up kind of
coming down to the same thing including
as it turns out Bayes rule okay and then
it turns out that nearly all of the time
then whatever the parameters are in that
function nearly all the time it turns
out that they're better learnt then
calculated based on the theory right and
indeed that's what happened when we
actually tried learning those
coefficients we got you know 85% okay so
then we noticed that we could also
rather than take the whole term document
matrix we could instead just take them
the you know ones and zeros for presence
or absence of a word and you know
sometimes it was you know this equally
as good but then we actually tried
something else which is we tried adding
regularization and with regularization
the binarized approach turned out to be
a little better all right so then
regularization was where we took the
loss function and again let's start with
our MSE and then we'll talk about
cross-entropy loss function was our
predictions
- our actuals
sum that up take the average plus a
penalty okay
and so this specifically is the l2
penalty if this instead was the absolute
value of W then that would be the l1
penalty okay we also noted that we don't
really care about the loss function per
se we only care about its derivatives
that's actually the thing that updates
the weights so we can because this is a
sum we can take the derivative of each
part separately and so the derivative of
this part was just that right and so we
kind of learnt that even though these
are mathematically equivalent they have
different names this version it's called
weight decay and it's kind of what's
used that term is used in the neural net
literature okay so cross-entropy
on the other hand you know it's just
another loss function like root mean
squared error but it's specifically
designed for classification alright and
so here's an example of a binary
cross-entropy
so let's say this is our you know is it
a cat or a dog so as to say is cat one
or a zero
so Cat Cat Cat and these are our
predictions this is the output of our
final layer of our neural net or a
logistic regression or whatever all
right then all we do is we say okay
let's take the actual times the log of
the prediction and then we add to that 1
minus actual times the log of 1 minus
the prediction and then take the
negative of that whole thing right so
I suggested to to you all that you tried
to kind of write the if statement
version of this so hopefully you've done
that by now otherwise I'm about to spoil
it for you so this was Y times log y
plus 1 minus y times log 1 minus y right
and negative of that okay so here wants
to tell me how to write this as an if
statement can she hit me okay if y equal
to sorry if y equal to 1 mm-hmm then in
return
I love Y mm-hmm otherwise well um else
return log 1 minus 1 okay oh that's the
things at brackets and you take C my
name is good
so the key inside Chen she's using is
that Y has two possibilities 1 or 0 okay
and so very often the math can hide the
key insight which I think happens here
until you actually think about what the
values it can take right so that's
that's all it's doing it's saying either
give me that or give me that all right
could you pass that to the back please
Jason all right I'm missing something
but do you know the two variables in
that statement if you got Y soon it'd be
like white hat on the wires yeah yeah
thank you
as usual it's me missing something okay
okay and so then the you know the multi
category version is just the same thing
but you're saying you know it four
different more than just y equals one or
zero but y equals zero one two three
four five six seven eight nine
for instance okay and so that you know
that loss function has a you can figure
it out yourself in particularly simple
derivative and it also you know another
thing you could play with at home if you
like is like thinking about how the
derivative looks when you add a sigmoid
or a softmax before it you know it turns
out it all turns out very nicely because
you've got an X P thing going into a log
e thing so you end up with you know very
well behaved derivatives the reason I
guess there's lots of reasons that
people use IR MSE for aggression and
cross-entropy for classification but
most of it comes back to this
statistical idea of a best linear
unbiased estimator you know and based on
the likelihood function that kind of
turns out that these have some nice
statistical properties it turns out
however in practice root means great
error in particular the properties are
perhaps more theoretical than actual and
actually nowadays using the the absolute
deviation rather than some as grads
deviation can often work better so in
practice like everything in machine
learning I normally try both for
particular data set I'll try both loss
functions and see which one works better
and us of course it's a cattle
competition in which case you're told
how capital is going to judge it and you
should use the same loss function as
caracals evaluation metric all right so
yeah so this is really the key insight
is like hey let's let's not use theory
but instead learn things from the data
and you know we hope that we're going to
get better results particularly with
regularization we do and then I think
the key regularization insight here is
hey let's not like try to reduce the
number of parameters in our model but
instead like use lots of parameters and
then use regularization to figure out
which
are actually useful and so then we took
that a step further by saying hey given
we can do that with wrecker ization
let's create lots more features by
adding by grams and trigrams you know by
grams like by vast and by vengeance and
trigrams like by vengeance . and by Vera
miles right and you know just to keep
things a little faster we limited it to
800,000 features but you know even with
the full 70 million features it works
just as well and it's not a hell of a
lot slower so we created a term document
matrix again using the full set of
engrams for the training set the
validation set and so now we can go
ahead and say okay our labels as the
training set labels as before our
independent variables is the binarized
term document matrix as before and then
let's fit a logistic regression to that
and do some predictions and we get 90%
accuracy so this is looking pretty good
okay so the logistic regression let's go
back to our naive Bayes right in our
naive Bayes we have this term document
matrix and then for every feature we're
calculating the probability of that
feature occurring if it's class 1 that
probability of that feature occurring if
it's plus 2 and then the ratio of those
two all right and in the paper that
we're actually load basing this off they
call this P this Q and this right maybe
I should just fill that in P here maybe
then we'll say probability to make it
more obvious
okay and so then we kind of said hey
let's let's not use these ratios as the
coefficients in that in that matrix
multiply
but let's instead like try and learn
some coefficients you know so maybe
start out with some random numbers you
know and then try and use stochastic
gradient descent to find slightly better
ones
so you'll notice you know some important
features here the R vector is a vector
of Rank 1 and it's length is equal to
the number of features and of course our
logistic regression coefficient matrix
is also of length 1
sorry Rank 1 and length 1/4 the number
of features right and we know we're
saying like they're kind of two ways of
calculating the same kind of thing right
one based on theory one based on data so
here is like some of the numbers in R
right remember it's using the log so
these numbers which are less than zero
represent things which are more likely
to be negative and these ones are here
are more likely so this one here is more
likely to be positive and so here's E ^
that and so these are the ones we can
compare to one rather than to zero so
I'm going to do something that hopefully
is going to seem weird and so first of
all I'm going to talk about I got to say
what we got to do and then I'm gonna try
and describe why it's weird and then
we'll talk about why it may not be as
weird as we first thought so here's what
we got to do we're going to take our
term document matrix and we're going to
multiply it by
so what that means is we're gonna I can
do it here in Excel right so we're going
to say let's grab everything in our term
document matrix and multiply it by the
equivalent value in the vector of our
right so this is like a broadcasted
element-wise multiplication not a matrix
multiplication okay and that's what that
does
okay so here is the value of the term
document matrix times R in other words
everywhere that a zero appears there a
zero appears here and every time a one
appears here the equivalent value of R
appears here so we haven't really we
haven't really changed much all right
we've just we've just kind of changed
the ones into something else than two
into the into the odds from that feature
all right and so what we're now going to
do is we're going to use this as our
independent variables instead in our
logistic regression okay so here we are
multiply x x NB x naive Bayes version is
x times R and now let's do a logistic
regression fitting using those
independent variables and let's then do
that for the validation set okay and get
the predictions and lo and behold we
have a better number okay so let me
explain why this hopefully seem
surprising given that we're just
multiplying oh I picked out the wrong
ones I should have said ah not going
okay that's actually uh I got the wrong
number
okay so that's our independent variables
right and then the the logistic
regression has come up with some set of
coefficients let's pretend for a moment
that these are the coefficients that it
happened to come up with okay we could
now say well let's not use this set
let's not use this set of independent
variables but let's use the original
binarized feature matrix right and then
divide all of our coefficients by the
values in R and we're going to get
exactly the same result mathematically
so you know we've got our X naivebayes
version of the independent variables and
we've got some some set of weights some
some sort of coefficients I'll call it W
right W one let's see where it's found
like this is a good set of coefficients
for making our predictions from right
that X and B is simply equal to x times
as in element wise x ah right so in
other words this is equal to x times ah
times the weights and so like we could
just change the weights to be that right
and get the same number so this ought to
mean that the change that we made to the
dependent variable shouldn't have made
any difference because we can calculate
exactly the same thing without making
that change so there's the question why
did it make a difference so in order to
answer this question I got to try and
get you all to try and think about this
in order to answer this question you
need to think about like okay
what are the things that aren't
mathematically the same why is why is it
not identical what are the reasons like
come up with some hypotheses what are
some reasons that maybe we've actually
ended up with a better answer and to
figure that out we need to first of all
start with like well why is it even a
different answer why is that different
to that is it subtle all right what do
you think I just wondering if there was
two different kinds of multiplications
you said that one is the element wise
multiplication no they do end up
mathematically being the same okay
pretty much there's a minor in corporate
not it's not that it's not some order
operation see let's try
kimchee you are on a roll today so let's
see how you go I feel like Z features
aren't less correlated to each other I
mean I've made a claim that these are
mathematically equivalent so so what are
you saying really you know why are we
getting different answers it's good keep
on coming up with hypotheses we need
lots of wrong answers before we start
finding it's really right ones it's like
that you know warmer hotter colder you
know Ernest you're gonna get as hot Oh
does it have anything to do with the
regularization ah yes and is it the fact
that when you let's start there right so
Ernest point here is like okay Jeremy
you've said they're equivalent but
they're equivalent outcomes right but
you got through and through a process to
get there and that process included
regularization and they're not
necessarily equivalent regularization
like our loss function as a penalty so
yeah help us think through Ernest how
much that might impact things well this
is I'm just noticing that the numbers
are bigger in the ones that have been
weighted by the naive phase mm-hmm our
weights and so these are bigger and some
are smaller some are bigger right but
there are some bigger ones like the
variance between the columns is much
higher the variance is bigger yeah I
think that's a very interesting insight
okay that's all yeah okay
so build on that prince has been on a
roll or month
so here's not sure is it also consider
like considering the dependency of
different words instead why this
performing better rather than all but
independent of each other no really I
mean it's it's you know again
theoretically these are creating
mathematically equivalent outputs so
they're not they're not doing something
different except as Ernest mentioned
they're getting impacted differently by
regularization so what's so what's
regularization right regularization is
we start out with our that was the
weirdest thing I forgot to go to
screenwriting mode and it just turns out
that you can actually write in Excel and
I had no idea that was true I still use
screenwriting Rosewood's could kill up
my spreadsheet I'd never trade so our
loss was equal to like our cross entropy
loss you know based on the predictions
of the predictions and the actuals right
plus our penalty so if your if your
weights a large right then that piece
gets bigger right and it drowns out that
piece right but that's actually the
piece we care about right we actually
want it to be a good fit so we want to
have as little regularization going on
as we can get away with we want so we
want to have less weights so here's the
thing right our value yes can you pass
it over here we should let less weights
did you mean lesser weights I do yeah
yeah and I
use the two words are level equivalently
which is not quite fair I agree but the
idea is that weights that are pretty
close to zero were kind of not there so
here's the thing our values of ah you
know and I'm not a Bayesian weenie but
I'm still gonna use the word prior right
they're kind of like a prior so like we
think that the the different levels of
importance and positive or negative of
these different features might be
something like that right we think that
like bad you know might be more
correlated with negative then and good
right so our kind of implicit assumption
the before was that we have no priors so
in other words when we'd said squared
weights we're saying a nonzero weight is
something we don't want to have right
but actually I think what I really want
to say is that differing from the naive
Bayes expectation is something I don't
want to do right like only very from the
naive Bayes prior unless you have good
reason to believe otherwise
right and so that's actually what this
ends up doing right we end up saying you
know what we think this value is
probably three right and so if you're
going to like make it a lot bigger or a
lot smaller right that's going to create
the kind of variation in weights that's
going to cause that squared term to go
up right so so if you can you know just
leave all these values about similar to
where they are now all right and so
that's what the penalty term is now
doing right the penalty term when our
inputs is already multiplied by our is
saying penalize things where we're
burying it from our naive Bayes prior
can you pass it
why multiply only with our not constant
like a square or something later when
the variance would be much higher
deciding because our our prior comes
from an actual theoretical model right
so I said like I don't like to rely on
the theory but I have if I have some
theory then you know maybe we should use
that as our starting point rather than
starting off by assuming everything's
equal so our prior said hey we've got
this model coordinate phase and the
naive Bayes model said if the naive
Bayes assumptions were correct then R is
the correct coefficient right in this
specific formulation that that's why we
pick that because our our prior is based
on that that theory okay so this is a
really interesting insight which I never
really see covered which is this idea is
that we can use these like you know
traditional machine learning techniques
we can imbue them with this kind of
Bayesian sense by by starting out you
know incorporating our theoretical
expectations into the data that we give
our model right and when we do so that
then means we don't have to regularize
as much and that's good right because if
we regularize a lot let's try it let's
go back to you know here's our
remember the the way they do it in the
eschaton logistic regression is this is
the reciprocal of the amount of
vectorization penalty so will kind of
add lots of regularization by making a
small so that like really hurts
that really hurts our accuracy because
now it's trying really hard to get those
weights down the loss function is
overwhelmed by the need to reduce the
weights and the need to make it
predictive is kind of now seen as
totally unimportant right so so by kind
of starting out and saying you know what
don't push the weights down so that you
end up ignoring the the terms but
instead push them down so that you try
to get rid of you know ignore
differences from our expectation based
on the naive Bayes formulation so that
ends up giving us a very nice result
which actually was originally this this
technique was originally presented I
think about 2012 Chris Manning who's a
terrific NLP researcher up at Stanford
and CETA Wang who I don't know but I
assume is awesome because his paper is
awesome they basically came up with this
with this idea and what they did was
they compared it to a number of other
approaches on a number of other data
sets so one of the things they tried is
this one is the IMDB data set that and
so here's naive Bayes SVM on diagrams
and as you can see this approach
outperformed the other linear based
approaches that they looked at and also
some restricted Boltzmann machine kind
of neural net based approaches they
looked at now nowadays there are better
ways there are you know there are better
ways to do this and in fact in the deep
learning course we showed
new state-of-the-art result that we just
developed at first a a that gets well
over ninety four percent but still you
know like particularly for a linear
technique that's easy fast and intuitive
this is pretty good and you'll notice
when they when they did this they only
used by grams and I assume that's
because they I looked at their code and
it was kind of pretty slow and ugly you
know I figured out a way to optimize it
a lot more as you saw and so we were
able to use here try grams and so we get
quite a lot better so we've got ninety
one point eight versus a ninety one
point two but other than that it's
identical also I mean they used a
support vector machine which is almost
identical to a logistic regression in
this case so there's some minor
differences right so I think that's a
pretty cool result and you know I will
mention you know what you get to see
here in class is the result of like many
weeks and often many months of research
that I do and so I don't want you to
think like this stuff is obvious it's
not at all like reading this paper
there's no description in the paper of
like why they use this model how it's
different why they thought it works you
know it took me a week or two to even
realize that it's kind of like
mathematically equivalent to a normal
logistic regression and then a few more
weeks to realize that the difference is
actually in the regularization you know
like this is kind of like machine
learning as I'm sure you've noticed from
the Carroll competitions you enter you
know like you come up with a thousand
good ideas 999 of them no matter how
confident you are they're going to be
great they always turn out to be
you know and then finally after four
weeks one of them finally works and kind
of gives you the enthusiasm to spend
another four weeks of misery and
frustration this is the norm right and
and like for sure that the the best
practitioners I know in machine learning
all share one particular trait in common
which
they're very very tenacious you know
also known as stubborn and bloody-minded
right which is definitely a reputation I
seem to have probably fare along with
another thing which is that they're all
very good coders you know they're very
good at turning their ideas into new
code so yeah so you know this was like a
really interesting experience for me
working through this a few months ago to
try and like figure out how to at least
you know how to explain why this at
there at the time kind of
state-of-the-art result exists and so
once I figured that out I was actually
able to build on top of it and make it
quite a bit better and I'll show you
what I did and this is where it was very
very handy to have hi torch at my
disposal because I was able to kind of
create something that was customized
just the way that I want it to be and
also very fast by using the GPU so
here's the kind of fast AI version of
the NBS vm actually my friend Steven
marady who's a terrific researcher in
NLP has christened this the NBS VM plus
plus which I thought was lovely so
here's that even though there is no SVM
it's a logistic regression but as I said
nearly exactly the same thing so let me
first of all show you like the code so
this is like we try to like once I
figure out like okay this is like the
best way I can come up with to do a
linear bag of words model I kind of
embed it into fast AI so you can just
write a couple of lines of code so the
code is basically hey I want to create a
data class for text classification I
want to create it from a bag of words
all right here is my bag of words here
are my labels here is the same thing for
the validation set and use up to 2,000
unique words per review right which is
plenty so then from that model data
construct a learner which is kind of the
faster I generalization of a moral
which is based on a dot product of naive
Bayes and then fit that model and then
do a few epochs and after five epochs I
was already up to ninety two point two
okay so this is now like you know
getting quite well above this this
linear based one so let me show you the
code for for that so the code is like
horrifyingly short that's it right and
it'll also look on the whole extremely
familiar right there's if there's a few
tweaks here pretend this thing that says
embedding pretend it actually says
linear okay I'm going to show you
embedding in a moment pretend it says
linear so we've got basically a linear
layer where the number of features
coming with the number of features as
the rows and remember SK learn features
means number of words basically and then
for each row we're going to create one
weight which makes sense right for like
a logistic regression every every sort
of for each row for each word each word
has one weight and then we're going to
be multiplying it by the our values so
each word we have one our value per
class so I actually made this so this
can handle like not just positive versus
negative but maybe figuring out like
which author created this work they're
cooking five or six authors whatever
right and basically we kind of use those
linear layers to to get the the value of
the weight and the value of the R and
then we take the weight times the R and
then sum it up and so that's just a dot
product okay so just just a simple dot
product just as we would do for any
logistic regression and then do the
softmax
so the very minor tweak the
we add to get the the better result is
this the main one really is this year
this plus something right and the thing
I'm adding is it's a parameter but I
pretty much always use this this version
of this value 2.4 so what does this do
so what this is doing is it's again kind
of changing the prior right so if you
think about it even once we used this R
times the term document matrix as their
independent variables you really want to
start with a question okay the penalty
terms are still pushing W down to 0
right so what did it mean for W to be 0
all right so what would it mean if we
had you know coefficient 0 0 0 0 0 all
right so what that would do when we
go.okay this matrix times these
coefficients we still get 0 right so a
weight of 0 still ends up saying I have
no opinion on whether this thing is
positive or negative on the other hand
if they were all one right then it's
basically says my opinion is that the
naive Bayes coefficients are exactly
right okay and so the idea is that I
said 0 is almost certainly not the right
prior right we shouldn't really be
saying if there's no coefficient it
means ignore the naive Bayes coefficient
one is probably too high right because
we actually think that naive Bayes is
only kind of part of the answer all
right and so I played around with a few
different data sets where I basically
said take the weights and add to them
some constant right and so 0 would
become in this case 0.4
all right so in other words the the
regularization
penalty is pushing the weights not
towards zero but towards this value
right and I found that across a number
of data sets zero point four works
pretty well but and it's pretty
resilient alright so again this is the
basic idea is to kind of like get the
best of both worlds you know where where
we're learning from the data using a
simple model but we're incorporating you
know our prior knowledge as best as we
can and so it turns out when you say
okay let's let's tell it you know as
white matrix of zeros actually means
that you should use about you know about
half of the values that ends up that
ends up working better than the prior
that the weights should all be 0 yes is
the the weights the W is it that the
point for the amount of regression
required the amount of so we have this
you know bad things we have the term
where we reduce the amount of error the
prediction error rmse plus we have the
regularization and is it W to the point
for denote the amount of visualization
required so W are the weights right so
this is calculating our activations okay
so we calculate our activations as being
equal to the weights times there are
some right so that's just our normal
normal linear function right so so the
the thing which is being penalized is my
weight matrix that's what gets penalized
so by saying hey you know what don't
just use W use W plus 0.4 so that's not
being penalized
it's not part of the weight matrix okay
so effectively the weight matrix gets
point four for free
yeah so by doing this even after
regularization then every I'm sorry
every feature is getting some form of
fate some form of weight or something
um not necessarily because it could end
up choosing a coefficient of negative
0.4 for a feature and so that would say
you know what
even though though naive Bayes says it's
the AH should be whatever for this
feature I think you should totally
ignore it yeah great questions okay we
started at 20 past - okay
let's take a break for about eight
minutes or so and start back about 25 -
okay so a couple of questions at the
break the first was just for a kind of
reminder or a bit of a summary as to
what's going on here right and so here
we have W plus I'm writing it out yeah
plus adjusted weight of weight
adjustment times right so so normally
what we were doing so normally what we
are doing is saying hey logistic
regression is basically WX right I'm
going to ignore the bias okay and then
we were changing it to be W dot times X
right and then we were kind of saying
let's do that bit first right although
in this particular case actually now I
look at it I'm doing it in this code it
doesn't matter obviously in this code
I'm actually doing
and during this bit first and so so this
thing here actually I call it W which is
probably pretty bad it's actually W
times X right so so instead of W times X
times R I've got W times X plus a
constant times R right so the key idea
here is that regularization can't draw
in yellow that's fair enough
regularization wants the weights to be 0
right because we're trying it's trying
to reduce that okay and so what we're
saying is like ok we want to push the
weights towards 0 because we're saying
like that's our like default starting
point expectation is the weights 0 and
so we want to be in a situation where if
the weights are 0 then we have a model
that like makes theoretical or intuitive
sense to us right this model if the
weights are 0 doesn't make intuitive
sense to us right because it's saying
hey multiply everything by 0 gets rid of
all of that and gets rid of that as well
and we were actually saying no we
actually think our R is useful we
actually want to keep that right so so
instead we say you know what let's take
that piece here and add 0.4 to it all
right so now if the regularizer is
pushing the weights towards 0 then it's
pushing the value of this sum towards
0.4
right and so therefore it's pushing a
whole model to 0.4 times R right so in
other words our kind of default starting
point if you've regularize to all the
weights out altogether is to say yeah
you know let's use a bit of our that's
probably a good idea okay
[Music]
so that's the idea right that's the idea
is basically you know what happens when
when that's zero but you and you want
that to like be something sensible
because otherwise regularizing the
weights to move in that direction
wouldn't be such a good idea okay second
question was about engrams so the N in
Engram can be uni by try whatever one
two three whatever grounds so so the
this movie is good right it has four
unique grams this movie is good it has
three by grams this movie movie is is
good it has two trigrams this movie is
movie is good okay doc can you pass it
do you mind go back to the double ad
change that zero point four stuff yeah
so I was wondering if this adjustment
will harm the predictability of the
model because think of extreme extreme
case if it's not zero point four if it's
four thousand and or black coefficients
will be like right so so exactly so so
our prior needs to make sense and so our
prior here and you know this is why it's
called dot prod NB is there prior is
that this is something where we think
naive Bayes is a good prior right and so
naive Bayes says that our equals
p over that's not how you write P P over
Q I have not had much sleep P over Q is
a good prayer and not only do we think
it's a good prior that we think our
times X plus B is a good model that's
that's the naive Bayes model so in other
words we expect that you know a
coefficient of one is a good coefficient
not not 4,000 yeah so we think
specifically we don't think we think 0
is probably not a good coefficient all
right but we also think that maybe the
naive Bayes version is a little
overconfident
so maybe one's a little high so we're
pretty sure that the right number
assuming that our moral only Bayes model
is appropriate is between 0 &amp; 1
no but what I was thinking is as long as
it's not 0 you are pushing those
coefficients that are supposed to be 0
to something not zero and make the like
high coefficients less distinctive from
0 coefficients well but you see they're
not supposed to be 0 they're supposed to
be are like that's that's what they're
supposed to be they're supposed to be
are right and so and remember this is
inside our forward function so this is
part of what we're taking the gradient
of right so it's basically saying okay
we're still gonna you know you can still
set self W to anything you like but just
the regularizer wants it to be zero and
so all we're saying is okay if if you
want it to be zero then I'll try to make
0 B you know give a sensible answer
that's the basic idea and like yeah
nothing says point fours perfect for
every data set I've tried a few
different data sets and found various
numbers between point three and point
six that are optimal but I've never
found one where point four is less good
than
zero which is not surprising and I've
also never found one where one it's
better right so the idea is like this is
a reasonable default but it's another
parameter you can play with which I kind
of like right it's another thing you
could use grid search or whatever to
figure out from your data set what's
best and you know really the key here
being every model before this one as far
as I know has implicitly assumed it
should be zero because they just they
don't have this parameter right and you
know by the way I've actually got a
second parameter here as well which is
the same thing I do to R is actually
divided by a parameter which I'm not
going to worry too much about it now but
again it's another parameter you can use
to kind of adjust what the nature of the
regularization is you know and I mean in
the end I'm a empiricist not a
theoretician you know the I thought this
seemed like a good idea
nearly all of my things that seem like a
good idea turn out to be stupid
this particular one Dave good results
you know on this data set and a few
other ones as well okay could you pass
that newest data yep yeah I'm sure a
little bit confused about the W plus W
is it huh so you mentioned that we do W
plus W adjusted so that the coefficients
don't get set to zero that we place some
importance on the priors but you also
said that the the effect of learning can
be that W get set to a negative value
which is mentally W plus W right zero so
if if we are we are allowing the
learning process to indeed set the
priors to zero so why is that in any way
different from just having W because
yeah great question because of
regularization because we're penalizing
it by that right so in other words we're
saying you know what if you're if the
best thing to do is to ignore the value
of R that'll cost you you're going to
have to set W to a negative number right
so only do that if that's fairly a good
idea unless it's clearly a good idea
then you should leave
leave it where it is that that's the
only reason like all of this stuff we've
done today is basically entirely about
you know maximizing the advantage we get
from regularization and saying
regularization pushes us towards some
default assumption and nearly all of the
machine learning literature assumes that
default assumption is everything zero
and I'm saying like it turns out you
know it makes sense theoretically and
turns out empirically that actually you
should decide what your default
assumption is and that'll give you
better results so would it be right to
say that in a way you are putting an
additional hurdle in the along the way
towards getting all coefficients to zero
so it will be able to do that if it is
really worth it yeah exactly so I'd say
like the default herd or without this is
is making a coefficient non zero is the
heck hurdle and now I'm saying no the
coefficient not be equal to 0.40 so this
is some of the W squared in to see some
of into some lambda or C penalty
constant yeah yeah times something yeah
so the beta K should also depend on the
value of C if it is very less like if C
is I say to you - hey yeah so if a is
point one then the wage might not go
towards zero yeah then we might not need
weight decay so well that the whatever
this value I mean if the if the value of
this is zero then there is no
recordation right but if this value is
higher than zero then there is some
penalty right and and presumably we've
set it to non zero because we're
overfitting so he wants some penalty and
so if there is some penalty then then my
assertion is that we should penalize
things that are different to our prior
not that we should penalize things that
are different to zero and
prior is that things should be you know
around about equal to our ok let's move
on thanks for the great questions I want
to talk about embedding I said pretend
it's linear and indeed we can pretend
it's linear let me show you how much we
can pretend it's linear as in n n dot
linear create a linear layer here is our
data matrix alright here are our
coefficients if we're in the R version
here are coefficients are right so if we
were to put those into a column vector
like so right then we could do a matrix
multiply of that by that right and so
we're going to end up with so here's our
matrix here's our vector right so we're
going to end up with 1 times 1 plus 1
times 1 1 times 1 1 times 3 right 0
times 1 0 times point 3 all right and
then the next one 0 times 1 1 times 1 so
forth ok so like that the matrix
multiply you know of this independent
variable matrix by this coefficient
matrix is going to give us an answer
ok so that's that is just a matrix
multiply so the question is like ok well
why didn't Jeremy right and n minion why
did Jeremy right and n dot embedding and
the reason is because if you recall we
don't actually store it like this
because this
actually of whit's 800,000 and of height
25,000 right
so rather than storing it like this we
actually store it as 0 1 2 3 right 1 2 3
4 0 1 2 5 1 2 4 5 okay
that's actually how we store it that is
this bag of words contains which word
indexes that makes sense ok so that's
like this is like a sparse way of
storing it right it's just list out the
indexes in each sentence so given that I
want to now do that matrix multiply that
I just showed you to create that same
outcome right but I want to do it from
this representation so if you think
about it all this is actually doing is
it saying a 1 hot you know this is
basically one hot encoded right it's
kind of like a dummy dummy matrix
version does it have the word this
doesn't have the word movie doesn't have
the word is and so forth so if we took
the simple version of like doesn't have
the word this 100 right and we
multiplied that by that right then
that's just going to return the first
item that makes sense so in general a
one hot encoded vector times a matrix is
identical to looking up that matrix to
find the end
row in it all right so this is identical
to saying find the zero first second and
fifth coefficients right so they're
they're the same they're exactly the
same thing and like it doesn't like in
this case I only have one coefficient
per feature right but actually the way I
did this was to have one coefficient per
feature for each class right so in this
case is both positive and negative so I
actually had kind of like an AA positive
and a negative so our negative would be
just the opposite right equals that
divided by that now in the binary case
obviously it's redundant to have both
but what if it was like what's the
author of this text is it Jeremy or
Savannah or Terrence right now we've got
three categories we want three values of
R right so the nice thing is doing this
sparse version you know you can just
look up you know the 0th and the first
and the second and the fifth alright and
again it's identical mathematically
identical to a multiplying by a one
Haughton coded matrix but when you have
sparse inputs it's obviously much much
more efficient so this computational
trick which is mathematically identical
to not conceptually analogous to
mathematically identical to multiplying
by a one hot encoded matrix is called an
embedding right so I'm sure you've all
heard or most of you probably heard
about embeddings like word embeddings
word to their core glove or whatever and
people love to make them sound like this
amazing new complex neural net thing
right they're not embedding means make a
multiplication by a one hot encoded
matrix faster by replacing it with a
simple array
cup okay so that's why I said you can
think of this as if it said self W
equals n n dot linear and F plus one by
one right because it actually does the
same thing right it actually is a matrix
with those dimensions this actually is a
matrix with those dimensions right it's
a linear layer but it's expecting that
the input we're going to give it is not
actually one hot encoded matrix but is
actually a list of integers right the
indexes for each word of each item so
you can see that the forward function in
fast AI automatically gets for this
Werner for feature indexes right so they
come from the sparse matrix
automatically numpy makes it very easy
to just grab those those indexes okay so
in other words there we've got here
we've got a list of H word index of a of
the 800-thousand that are in this
document and so then this here says look
up each of those in our embedding matrix
which is got 800,000 rows and return
each thing that you find okay so
mathematically identical to multiplying
by the one hunting coded matrix so make
sense so that's all an embedding is and
so what that means is we can now handle
building any kind of model like a you
know whatever kind of neural network
where we have potentially very high
cardinality categorical variables as our
inputs we can then just turn them into a
numeric code between zero and the number
of levels and then we can learn a you
know a linear layer
from that as if we had one hot encoded
it without ever actually constructing
the one hot encoded version and without
ever actually doing that matrix model
play okay instead we will just store the
index version and simply do the array
lookup okay and so the gradients that
are flowing back you know basically in
the one hot encoded version everything
that was a zero has no gradient so the
gradients flowing back is best go to
update the particular row of the
embedding matrix that we used okay and
so that's fundamentally important for
NLP just like here like you know I
wanted to create a PI torch model that
would implement this this ridiculously
simple little equation alright and to do
what without this trick would have meant
I was feeding in a twenty five thousand
by adherence to 800,000 element array
which would have been kind of crazy
right and so this this trick allowed me
to write you know you know I've just
replaced the word linear with embedding
replace the thing that feeds the one-hot
encodings in with something to dispense
the indexes in and that was it that then
it kept working and so this now trains
you know in about a minute per epoch
okay so what we can now do is we can now
take this idea and apply it not just to
language but to anything right for
example predicting the sales of items at
a grocery yes where's that asset just a
quick question so you're not actually
looking up anything right we are just
seeing that now that array with the
indices that is the representation so
the represent so we are doing a lookup
right the representation that's being
stored it for the book but for the bag
of words is now not one one 100 one but
oh one two
five right and so then we actually have
to do our matrix product right but
rather than doing the matrix product we
look up the zero thing and the first
thing and the second thing and the fifth
thing so that means we are still
retaining the one hard encoded matrix no
we didn't there's no one hot encoded
matrix used here this here's the one who
decoded matrix which is not currently
highlighted we've currently highlighted
the list of indexes and the list of
coefficients from the weight matrix so
it says okay okay so what we're going to
do now is we're kind of go to just go to
go a step further and saying like let's
not use a linear model at all let's use
a multi-layer neural network right and
let's have the input to that potentially
be include some categorical variables
and those categorical variables we will
just have as numeric indexes and so the
first layer for those won't be a normal
linear layer
there'll be an embedding layer which we
know behaves exactly like a linear layer
mathematically and so then our hope will
be that we can now use this to create a
neural network for any kind of data all
right and so there was a competition on
Kaggle a few years ago called
rossmann which is a German grocery chain
where they asked to predict the sales of
items in in their stores right and that
included the mixture of categorical and
continuous variables and in this paper
by Gordon Burke and they described their
third-place winning entry which was much
simpler than the first placed winning
entry but nearly as good but much much
simpler because they took advantage of
this idea of what they call ng
embeddings
in the paper they they thought I think
that they had invented this actually had
been written before earlier by yoshua
bengio and his co-authors in another
cackle competition which was predicting
taxi destinations although I will say I
feel like war went a lot further in
describing how this can be used in many
other ways and so will will talk about
that as well so the so this one is
actually in the is in the deep learning
one repo okay deal one lesson three okay
because we talked about some of the deep
learning specific aspects in the deep
learning course where else in this
course we're going to be talking mainly
about the feature engineering and we're
also going to be talking about you know
kind of this this embedding idea so
let's start with the data right so the
data was you know store number one on
the 31st of July 2015 was open they had
a promotion going on there was a school
holiday it was not a state holiday and
they sold five thousand two hundred and
sixty three items so that's the key data
they provided and so the goal is
obviously to predict sales in a test set
that has the same information without
sales they also tell you that for each
store it's of some particular type it
sells some particular assortment of
goods its nearest competitor competitor
is some distance away the competitor
opened in September 2008 and there's
some more information about promos I
don't know the details of what that
means like in many Carroll competitions
they let you download external data sets
if you wish as long as you share them
with other competitors so people oh they
also told you what's
date each store is in so people
downloaded a list of the names of the
different states of Germany they
downloaded a file for each state in
Germany for each week some kind of
Google trend data I don't know what
specific Google trend they got but there
was that for each date they downloaded a
whole bunch of temperature information
[Music]
that's it and then here's the test set
okay so I mean one interesting insight
here is that the it was probably a
mistake in some ways for Russman to
design this competition as being one
where you could use external data
because in reality you don't actually
get to find out next week's weather or
next week's Google Trends you know but
you know when you're competing in
category you don't care about that you
just want to win so you use whatever you
can get so let's talk first of all about
data cleaning you know that there wasn't
really much feature engineering done in
this third place winning entry like by
particularly by cattle standards where
normally every last thing counts this is
a great example of how far you can get
with with a neural net and it certainly
reminds me of the claims prediction
competition we talked about yesterday
where the winner did no feature
engineering and entirely relied on deep
learning the laughter in the room I
guess is from people who did a little
bit more than no feature engineering in
that competition so you know I should
mention by the way like I find that bit
where like you work hard at a
competition and then it closes and you
didn't win and the winner comes out and
says this is how I won like that's the
bit where you learn the most right like
sometimes that's happened to me and it's
been like oh I thought of that I thought
I tried that and then I go back and I
realize I like had a bug there I didn't
test properly and I learn like oh okay
like I really need to learn to like test
this thing in this
away sometimes it's like oh I thought of
that but I assumed it wouldn't work I've
really got to remember to check
everything before I make any assumptions
and you know sometimes it's just like oh
I I did not think of that technique Wow
now I know it's better than everything I
just tried because like otherwise
somebody says like hey you know here's a
really good technique you're like okay
great
right but when you spent months trying
to do something and like somebody else
did it better by using that technique
that's pretty convincing right and so
like it's kind of hard like I'm standing
up in front of you saying here's a bunch
of techniques that I've I've used and
I've won some capital competitions and
I've got some state of the art results
but it's like that's kind of second-hand
information by the time it hits you
right so it's really great to yeah try
things out and and also like it's been
kind of nice to see particularly I've
noticed in the deep learning course
quite a few of my students have you know
I've said like this technique works
really well and they've tried it and
they've got into the top ten of a Keagle
competition the next day and they're
like okay that that counts is working
really well so so yeah caryl
competitions are helpful for lots and
lots of reasons but you know one of the
best ways is what happens after it
finishes and so definitely like for the
ones that you that are now finishing up
make sure you you know watch the forums
see what people are sharing in terms of
their solutions and you know if you want
to learn more about them like don't feel
free to ask the winners like hey could
you tell me more about this or that
people are normally pretty pretty good
about explaining and then ideally try
and replicate it yourself right and that
can turn into a great blog post you know
or a great kernel is to be able to say
okay such-and-such said that they use
this technique here's a really short
explanation of what that technique is
and here's a little bit of code showing
how it's implemented and you know here's
the results showing you you can get the
same result that can be a really
interesting write-up as well
okay so you know it's it's always nice
to kind of have your data reflect like
oh no bee is kind of easy to understand
as possible so in this case the data
that came from Kegel used various you
know integers for the holidays we can
just use a boolean if like was it a
holiday or not so like just clean that
up we've got quite a few different
tables we need to join them all together
right I have a standard way of joining
things together with pandas I just used
the pandas merge function and
specifically I always do a left joint so
who wants to tell me what a left join is
since it's there go ahead you retain all
the rows in the left table and you take
so you have a key column you match that
with a key column in the right side
table and you just merge the rules that
are also present in the right side table
yeah that's a great explanation good job
I don't have much to add to that the key
reason that I always do a left join is
that after I do the join I always then
check if there were things in the
right-hand side that a noun no right
because if so it means that I some
things yeah I haven't shown it here but
I also check that the number of rows
hasn't varied before and after if it has
that means that the right hand side
table wasn't unique okay so even when
I'm sure something's true I always also
assume that I've screwed it up so I
always check so I could go ahead and
merge the state names into the whether I
can also if you look at the Google
Trends table it's got this week range
which I need to turn into a date in
order to join it right and so the nice
thing about doing this in pandas is that
pandas gives us access to you know all
of Python right and so for example
inside the the series object
Str attribute that gives you access to
all the string processing functions not
just like cat gives you access to the
categorical functions DT gives you
access to the date/time functions so I
can now split everything in that column
and it's really important to try and use
these pandas functions because they you
know they're going to be vectorized
accelerated through you know often
threesome D at least through you know C
code so that runs nice and quickly and
then you know as per usual let's add
date metadata to our dates in the end we
are basically denormalizing all these
tables we're going to put them all into
one table so in the Google trend table
there was also though they were mainly
trends by state but there was also
trends for the whole of Germany so we
kind of put the Germany on you know the
whole of Germany ones into a separate
data frame so that we can join that so
we're going to have that Google trend
for this state and Google trend for the
whole of Germany and so now we can go
ahead and start joining both for the
training set and for the test set and
then which both check that we don't have
zeros my merge function i set the suffix
if there are two columns are the same I
set their suffix on the left to be
nothing at all so it doesn't screw
around with the name and the right hand
side to be underscore Y and in this case
I didn't want any of that you look at
ones so I just went through and deleted
them okay and then we're gonna in a
moment we're going to try to create a
competition you know the the the main
competitor for this store has been open
since some date right and so you can
just use pandas to date I'm passing in
the year the month and the day right and
so that's going to give us an error
unless they all have years and months so
so we're going to fill in the missing
ones with the 1900 and a1 okay
and then what we really know it we
didn't want to know is like how long is
this store been open for at the time of
this particular record all right so we
can just do a date subtract okay now if
you think about it sometimes the
competition you know open later than
this particular row so sometimes it's
going to be negative and it doesn't
probably make sense to have negative
spending like it's going to open in X
days time now having said that I would
never put in something like this without
first of all running a model with it in
and without it in right because like our
assumptions about about the data very
often turned out not to be true now in
this case I didn't invent any of these
pre-processing steps I wrote all the
code but it's all based on the
third-place winners github repo right so
knowing what it takes to get third place
in the cable competition I'm pretty sure
they would have checked every one of
these pre-processing steps and made sure
it actually improved their their
validation set score okay so what we're
going to be doing is creating a neural
network where some of the inputs to it
are continuous and some of them are
categorical and so what that means in
the in the neural net that you know we
have we're basically going to have you
know this kind of initial weight matrix
right and we're going to have this this
input feature vector right and so some
of the inputs are just going to be plain
continuous numbers like you know what's
the maximum temperature here or what's
the number of kilometers to the nearest
store and some of them are going to be
one HUD encoded effectively right but
we're not actually going to store it as
one hot encoded we're actually going to
store it as the index right and so the
neural net model is going to need to
know which of these columns should you
should you basically create an embedding
for which ones should you treat you know
as if they were kind of one hot encoded
and which ones should you just you feed
directly into the linear layer right and
so we're going to tell the model when we
get there which is which but we actually
need to think ahead of time about like
which ones do we want to treat as
categorical and which ones are
continuous in particular things that
were going to treat it as categorical we
don't want to create more categories
than we need right and so let me show
you what I mean the the the third-place
getters in this competition decided that
the number of months that the
competition was open was something that
they were going to use as a categorical
variable all right and so in order to
avoid having more categories than they
needed they truncated it at 24 months
they said anything more than 24 months
old truncate to 24 so here are the
unique values of competition months open
and it's all the numbers from naught to
24 right so what that means is that
there's going to be you know an
embedding matrix that's going to have
basically an embedding vector for things
that aren't open yet for things that are
open a month for things that are open
two months and so forth now they
absolutely could have done that as a
continuous variable right they could
have just had a number here which is
just a single number of how many months
has it been open and they could have
treated it as continuous and fed it
straight into the initial weight matrix
what I found though and obviously what
these competitors found is where
possible it's best to treat things as
categorical variables right and the
reason for that is that like when you
feed some
things through an embedding matrix you
basically mean it means every level can
be treated like totally differently
right and so for example in this case
whether something's been open for zero
months or one months is right really
different right and so if you fed that
in as a continuous variable it would be
kind of difficult for the neural net to
try and find a functional form that kind
of has that that big difference as
possible because neural Nets can do
anything right but you're not making it
easy for it where else if you used an
embedding treated it as categorical then
it will have a totally different vector
for zero versus one right so it seems
like particularly as long as you've got
enough data that the treating columns as
categorical variables where possible is
a better idea
and so I say when I say we're possible
that kind of basically means like where
the cardinalities not too high you know
so if this was like you know the sales
ID number that was like uniquely
different on every row you can't treat
that as a categorical variable right
because you know it would be a huge
embedding matrix and everything only
appears once or ditto for like
kilometers away from the nearest store
to two decimal places you wouldn't make
a categorical variable all right so
that's kind of that's kind of the rule
of thumb that they both used in this
competition in fact if we scroll down to
their choices here is how they did it
right they're continuous variables with
things that were genuinely continuous
like number of kilometers away to the
competitor the temperature stuff right
the number you know the specific number
in the Google trend right where else
everything else basically they treated
as categorical okay so that's it for
today so yeah next time we'll we'll
finish this off we'll see we'll see how
to turn this into a neural network
and yeah kind of wrap things up so see
then