well welcome back to machine learning
one of the most exciting things this
week almost certainly the most exciting
the thing this week is that fast AI is
now on Pitt so you can pip install fast
AI and so thank you to Prince and perk
to creme for making that happen to USF
students who had never published a hit
package before and this is one of the
harder ones to publish because it's got
a lot of dependencies so it's you know
probably still easiest just to do the
Condor end of update thing but a couple
of places that it would be handy instead
to pip install fast AI would be well
obviously if you're working outside of
the the repo in the notebooks then this
gives you access to fast AI everywhere
also I believe they submitted a pull
request to CAG or to try and get it
added to the Capitol kernels so
hopefully you'll be able to use it on
Kapil kernels soon and yeah you can use
it at your work or whatever else so
that's that's exciting
I mean I I'm not gonna say it's like
officially released yet you know it's
still very early obviously and we're
still you're helping add documentation
and all that kind of stuff but it's
great that that's now there a couple of
cool kernels from USF students this week
thought of highlight two that were both
from the text normalization competition
which was about trying to take text
which was written out you know wrote a
standard English text they also had one
per Russian and you're trying to kind of
identify things that could be like first
second third and say like that's a
cardinal number or this is a phone
number or whatever and I did a quick
little bit of searching and I saw that
there had been some attempts in academia
to use deep learning for this but they
hadn't managed to make much progress and
actually noticed so up here is Colonel
here which gets 0.99 two on the leader
board which i think is like top
is yeah it's kind of entirely heuristic
and it's a great example of kind of
feature engineering that's in this case
the whole thing is basically entirely
feature engineering so it's basically
looking through and using most of
regular expressions to figure out for
each token what is it you know and I
think she's done a great job here kind
of laying it all out clearly as to what
all the different pieces are and how
they all fit together and she mentioned
that she's maybe hoping to turn this
into a library which I think would be
great right you know you could use this
to grab a piece of text and pull out
what are all the pieces in it
it's the kind of thing that the the
natural language can like natural
language processing community hopes to
be able to do without like lots of hand
written code like this but for now this
is I'll be interesting to see like what
the winners turn out to have done but I
haven't seen machine learning being used
really to do this particularly well
perhaps the best approaches or ones
which combine this kind of feature
engineering along with some machine
learning but I think this is a great
example of effective feature engineering
and this is a another USF student who
has done much the same thing got a
similar kind of score but used used her
own different set of rules
again this is gets you it would get you
a good leader board position with these
as well so I thought that was
interesting to see examples of some of
our students entering a competition and
getting kind of top 20 ish results by
you know basically just handwritten
heuristics and this is where for example
computer vision was six years ago still
basically all the best approaches was a
whole lot of like carefully handwritten
heuristics often combined with some
simple machine learning and so I think
over time you know the field is kind of
definitely trying to move towards
automating much more of this and
actually interestingly very
interestingly in the safe driver
diction competition was just finished
one of the Netflix Prize winners won
this competition and he invented a new
algorithm for dealing with structured
data which basically doesn't require any
feature engineering at all so he came
first place using nothing but five deep
learning models and one gradient
boosting machine and his his basic
approach was very similar to what we've
been learning in this class so far and
what we'll be learning also tomorrow
which is using fully connected neural
network somewhere and one hot encoding
and specifically embedding which we'll
learn about but he had a very clever
technique which was there was a lot of
data in this competition which was
unlabeled so in other words where they
didn't know whether that driver would go
under claim or not or or whatever so
unlabeled data so when you've got some
labeled in some unlabeled data we call
that semi-supervised learning and in
real life most learning is
semi-supervised learning like in real
life normally you have some things that
are labeled and some things that are
unlabeled so this is kind of the most
practically useful kind of learning and
then structured data is it's the most
common kind of data that companies deal
with day to day so the fact that this
competition was a semi-supervised
structured data competition made it
incredibly practically useful and so
what his technique for winning this was
was to through data augmentation which
those of you doing the deep learning
course have learned about which is
basically the idea like if you had
pictures you would like flip them
horizontally or rotate them a bit later
orientation means creating new data
examples which are kind of slightly
different versions of ones you already
have and the way he did it was for each
row from the data he would like at
random replaced 15% of the variables
with a different row so each row now
would represent like a mix of like 80%
85% of the original row the 15% randomly
selected from a different
and so this was a way of like randomly
changing the data a little bit and then
he used something called an autoencoder
which we will probably won't study into
a part too with a deep learning course
but the basic idea of an autoencoder is
your dependent variable is the same as
your independent variable so in other
words you try to predict your input
which obviously is trivial if you're
allowed to like like you know the
identity transporting for example Rivoli
predicts the input but the trick with an
autoencoder
is to have less activations in at least
one of your layers than your input right
so if your input was like a hundred
dimensional vector and you put it
through a 100 by 10 matrix okay create
ten activations and then have to
recreate the original 100 long vector
from that then you've basically come you
had to have compressed it effectively
and so it turns out that that kind of
neural network you know is forced to
find correlations and features and
interesting relationships in the data
even when it's not labeled so he used
that rather than doing any he didn't do
any hand engineering he just used an
autoencoder
so you know these are some interesting
kind of directions that if you keep
going with your machine learning studies
you know particularly if you do a part
two with a deep learning course next
year your your lone about and you can
kind of see how feature engineering is
going away and this was just yeah an
hour ago so this is very recent using to
eat but it's one of this is one of the
most important breakthroughs I've seen
in a long time okay so we were working
through a simple logistic regression
trained with SJD for MS
and here's the summary of where we got
to we have nearly built a module a model
module and a training loop from scratch
and we were going to kind of try and
finish that and after we finished that
and then going to go through this entire
notebook backwards right so having gone
like top to bottom but I'm going to go
back through bottom to top okay so you
know this was that little handwritten
and end module class we created we
defined our loss we defined our learning
rate and we defined our optimizer and
this is the thing that we're going to
try and write by hand in a moment so
that stuff that and that we're stealing
with from pi torch but that we've
written ourselves and this week written
us all so the basic idea was we're going
to go through some number of epochs so
let's go through one epoch okay and
we're going to keep track of how much
for each mini batch what was the loss so
that we can report it at the end we're
going to turn our training data loader
into an iterator so that we can loop
through it live through every mini batch
and so now we can go and go ahead and
say for tensor in the length of the data
loader and then we can call next to grab
the next independent variables and the
dependent variables from our data loader
from that iterator okay so then remember
we can then pass the X tensor into our
model by calling the model as if it was
a function but first of all we have to
turn into a variable last week we were
typing variable blog CUDA to turn it
into a variable a shorthand for that is
just the capital V now it's a capital T
for a tensor capital B for a fever
variable that's just a shortcut in fast
AI okay so that returns our predictions
and so the next thing we needed was to
calculate our loss because we can't
calculate the derivatives of the loss of
U and calculate the loss so the loss
takes the predictions and the actuals
okay so the actuals again are the the Y
tensor and again we have to turn that
into a variable now can anybody remind
me what a
variable is and why we would want to use
a variable here I think once you turn it
to variable then it tracks it so then
you can do a backward on that so you can
yeah what sorry when you turned a
variable it it contract like this
process of like you know as you add the
function as the function starting
earlier than each other they can track
it and I may need to backward on it back
propagates and those days yeah right so
right so a variable keeps track of all
of the steps to get computed and so
there's actually a fantastic tutorial on
the PI torch website so on the pipe
torch website there's a tutorial section
and there's a tutorial there about Auto
grad Auto grad is the name of the
automatic differentiation package that
comes with a torch and it's a it's an
implementation of automatic
differentiation and so the variable
class is really the key the key class
here because that's the thing that makes
turns a tensor into something where we
can keep track of its gradients so
basically here they show how to create
their variable do an operation to a
variable and then you can go back and
actually look at the grand function
which is the the function that it's
keeping track of basically to calculate
the gradient right so as we do more and
more operations to this very variable
and the variable calculated from that
variable it keeps keeping track of it so
later on we can go dot backward and then
print grad and find out the gradient
right and so you notice we never defined
the gradient we just defined it as being
X plus 2 squared times 3 whatever and it
can calculate the gradient
okay so that's why we need to turn that
into a variable so L is now a variable
containing the loss so it contains a
single number for this mini batch which
is the loss for this mini batch but it's
not just a number it's a it's a number
as a variable so it's a number that
knows how it was calculated all right so
we're going to append that loss to our
array just so we can get the average of
it later basically and now we're going
to calculate the gradient so L drop
backward is a thing that says calculate
the gradient so remember when you recall
the the network it's actually calling
our forward function so that's like cap
go through it forward and then backward
is like using the chain rule to
calculate the gradients backwards okay
and then this is the thing we're about
to write which is update the weights
based on the gradients and the learning
rate okay zero grad will explain when we
write this out by hand okay and so then
at the end we can turn our validation
data loader into an iterator and we can
then go through its length grabbing each
X and way out of that and asking for the
score which we defined up here to be
equal to which thing did you predict
which thing was actual and so check
whether they're equal right and then the
main of that is going to be our accuracy
okay could you pass that over to Chen XI
what's the advantage that you found
converted into iterator resident like
used normal and on a Python loop or
we're using a normal Python loop so it's
still them this is a normal Python loop
so the question really is like compared
to what right so like the alternative
perhaps nothing here could be like we
could use like a something like a list
with an index oh okay so you know the
problem there is the
we want as a few things I mean one key
one is we want each time we grab a new
mini batch we want to be random we want
a different different shuffled thing so
this you can actually kind of iterate
from forever you know you can look
through it as many times as you like
so this is kind of idea it's called
different things in different languages
but a lot of languages a lot like stream
processing and it's this basic idea that
rather than saying I want the third
thing or the ninth thing is just like I
want the next thing right it's great for
like network programming it's like grab
the next thing from the network it's
great for UI programming it's like we
have the next event where there's
somebody clicked a button it also turns
out to be great for this kind of numeric
programming's it's like I just want the
next batch of data it means that the
data like can be kind of arbitrarily
long as we're just grabbing one piece at
a time yeah so you know I mean and also
I guess the short answer is because it's
our PI approach works if I torch that
light torches data loaders are designed
to be poured in this way and then so
Python has this concept of a generator
which is like an and and just a
different type of generator
I want to physical gonna be a snake
generator or a computer of generator
okay a generator is a way that you can
create a function that as it says
behaves like an iterator so like python
has recognized that this stream
processing approach to programming is
like super handy and helpful and
supports it everywhere so basically
anywhere that you user for in loop any
way you use a list comprehension those
things can always be generators or
iterators so by programming this way we
just get a lot of flexibility I guess
does that sound about right Terrence
you're the programming language expert
did you do you want to grab that box so
you can hear so Terrence actually does
programming languages for a living so we
should ask him yeah I mean the short
answer is what you said you might say
something about space but in this case
that all that data has to be in memory
because we've got no doesn't have to be
a memory so that most of the time if we
could pull a mini batch from something
that most of the time with pipe torch
the mini batch will be read from like
separate images spread over your disk on
demand so most of the time it's not in
memory but in in general you want to
keep his little in memory as possible at
a time and so the idea of stream
processing also is great because you can
do compositions you can pipe the data to
a different machine you can yeah yeah
the composition is great you can grab
scrap the next thing from here and then
send it off to the next stream which you
can then grab it and do something else
which you guys all recognize of course
in the command-line pipes and
redirection yes okay thanks Terrence
it's a benefit of working with people
that actually know what they're talking
about all right so let's know take that
and get rid of the optimizer okay so the
only thing that we're going to be left
with is the negative log likelihood loss
function which we could also replace
actually we have a implementation of
that from scratch that you know wrote in
the in the notebooks so it's only one
line of code as we learned earlier you
can do it with a single if statement
okay so I don't know why I was so lazy
is to include this so what we're going
to do is we're gonna again grab this
module that we've written ourselves the
logistic regression module we're going
to have one epoch again we're going to
loop through each thing in an iterator
again they're going to grab our
independent and dependent variable for
the mini batch again pass it into our
network again calculate the loss so this
is all the same as before but now we're
going to get rid of this optimizer dot
step and we're going to do it by hand so
the basic trick is as I mentioned we're
not going to do the calculus by hand so
we call L drop backward to calculate the
gradients automatically and that's going
to fairly in our weight matrix so do you
remember when we created our let's go
back and look at the code for here's
that module we built so the weight
matrix for the for the
linear layer weights recall l1 w and for
the BIOS record l1 B all right so though
they were the attributes we created so
I've just put them into things called W
and B just to save some typing basically
so W is our weights B is our biases and
so the weights remember the weights are
a variable and to get the tensor out of
the variable we have to use data all
right so we want to update the actual
tensor that's in this variable so we say
weights data minus equals so we want to
go in the opposite direction to the
gradient the gradient tells us which
wears up we want to go down whatever is
currently in the gradients times the
learning rate so that is the formula for
gradient descent all right so as you can
see it's it's like as as easier thing as
you can possibly imagine it's like
literally update the weights to be equal
to be equal to whatever they are now
minus the greater the gradients times
our learning rate and do the same thing
for the bias anybody have any questions
about that step in terms of like why we
do it or how it did you have a question
about that that step but when we do the
next job deal the next here yes yes so
when is the end of the loop how do you
grab the next element so this is going
through each h-index in range of length
so is this going 0 1 2 3 at the end of
this loop it's going to print out the
mean of the validation set go back to
the start of the epoch at which point
it's going to recreate a new a new
iterator okay so basically behind the
scenes in Python when you call it a on
on this it basically tells it like reset
its state to create a new iterator and
if you're interested in how that works
the
the code is all you know available for
you to look at so we could look at like
MD trained your is a fast AI dot data
setup model data loader so we could like
take a look at the code of that so we
could take a look at the code of that
and see exactly how it's being built
right and so you can see here that
here's the next function right which
basically is keeping track of how many
times it's been through in this self dot
I and here's the Edith function which is
the thing that gets pretty cold when you
when you create a new iterator and you
can see it's basically passing it off to
something else which is a type data
loader and then you can check out data
loader if you're interested to see how
that's implemented as well um so the
data loader that we wrote basically uses
multi-threading to allow it to have
multiple of these going on at the same
time it's actually a great it's really
simple it's like it's only about a
screen full of code so if you're
interested in simple Modi threaded
programming it's a good thing to look at
okay now oh yes
why how do you wrap this in four epoch
in range one since that'll only run once
because in real life we would normally
be running multiple so like in this case
because it's a linear model it actually
basically trains to as good as it's
going to get in one he park so if I type
three here it actually it actually won't
really improve after the first epoch
much at all as you can see right but
when we go back up to the top we're
going to look at some slightly deeper
and more interesting versions which will
take more a box so you know if I was
turning this into a into a function you
know I'd be going like you know death
train model and one of the things you
would pass you and is like number of
epochs kind of thing okay great so one
thing to remember is that when you're
you know creating these neural network
layers and remember like this is just as
pipe Rogers concerned this is just a
it's an end up module it could be a week
could be using it as a layer who could
be using to a function we could be using
it as a neural net pipe torch doesn't
think of those as different things right
so this could be a layer inside some
other network okay so how do gradients
work so if you've got a layer which
remember is just a bunch of we can think
of it basically as its activations right
or some activations that get computed
through some other nonlinear activation
function or through some linear function
and from that layer we it's very likely
that we're then like let's say putting
it through a matrix product right to
create some new layer and so each one of
these so if we were to grab like one of
these activations right is actually
going to be used to calculate every one
of these outputs right and so if you
want to calculate the the derivative you
have to know how this weight matrix
impacts that output and that output and
that output and that output right and
then you have to add all of those
together to find like the total impact
of this you know across all of its
outputs and so that's why in PI torch
you have to tell it when to set the
gradients to zero right because the idea
is that you know you could be like
having lots of different loss functions
or lots of different outputs in your
next activate set of activations
or whatever all adding up increasing or
decreasing your gradients right so you
basically have to say okay this is a new
calculation
reset okay so here is where we do that
so before we do LDAP backward we say
reset okay so let's take our weights
let's take the gradients let's take the
ten so that they point to and then zero
underscore does anybody remember from
last week
what underscore does as a suffix in pi
torched yeah I have to read the language
but basically it changes I put into
place
that language is in place yeah exactly
so it sounds like a minor technicality
but it's super useful to remember every
function pretty much has an underscore
version suffix which does it in place
yeah so normally zero returns a tensor
of zeros of a particular size so zero
underscore means replace the contents of
this with a bunch of zeros okay all
right
so that's that's it right so that's like
SJD from scratch and if I get rid of my
menu bar we can officially say it fits
within a screen yeah so of course we
haven't got our definition of logistic
regression here that's another half the
screen but basically there's there's not
much to it yes sir so later on we have
to do this more the gradient is it
because you might find like a wrong
minima local minima that way we have to
kick it out and that's we have to do
multiple times when the surface is
getting more common why do you need
multiple epochs is that your question
well I mean a simple way to answer that
would be let's say our learning rate was
tiny right then it's just not gonna get
very far right there's nothing that says
going through one epoch is enough to get
you all the way there
so then it'd be like okay well let's
increase our learning rate and it's like
yeah sure will increase our learning
rate but who's to say that the highest
learning rate that learned stabili is is
enough to learn this as well as it can
be learned and for most data sets for
most architectures one epoch is very
rarely enough to get you to the best
result you can get too
you know linear models are just they're
very nicely behaved you know so you can
often use higher learning rates and
learn them well quickly also they they
don't you can't like generally get as
good at accuracy so there's not as far
to take them either so yeah doing one
epoch is going to be the rarity all
right so let's go backwards so going
backwards we're basically going to say
all right let's not write those two
lines again and again again let's not
write those three lines again and again
and again let's have somebody do that
for us
right so that's like that's the only
difference between that version in this
version is rather than saying dot zero
ourselves rather than saying - gradient
times Amara ourselves
these are wrapped up for us okay there
is another wrinkle here which is this
approach to updating the the weights is
actually pretty inefficient it doesn't
take advantage of momentum and curvature
and so in the do course we learn about
how to do momentum from scratch as well
okay so if we actually just use plain
old SGD then you'll see that this
Alone's much slower so now that I've
typed just plain old SGD here this is
now literally doing exactly the same
thing as our slow version so I have to
increase the learning rate okay there we
go so this this is now the same as the
one we wrote by hand so then all right
[Music]
let's do a little bit more stuff
automatically let's not you know given
that every time we train something we
have to loop through epoch flip through
batch do forward get the loss zero the
gradient do backward do a step of the
optimizer
let's put all that in a function okay
and that function is called fit alright
there it is okay so let's take a look at
fit fit go through each epoch go through
each batch do one step keep track of the
loss and at the end calculate the
validation all right and so then step so
if you're interested in looking at this
this stuff's all inside fast AI dot
model and so here is dead right zero the
gradients calculate the loss remember
pipe torch tends to call it criterion
rather than loss all right do it
backward and then there's something else
we haven't learned here but we do learn
the deep learning course which is
gradient reading so you can ignore that
alright so you can see now like all the
stuff that we've learnt when you look
inside the actual frameworks that's the
code you see okay so that's what fit
does and so then the next step would be
like okay well this idea of like having
some weights and a bias and doing a
matrix product in addition let's put
that in a function this thing of doing
the log softmax let's put that in a
function and then the very idea of like
first doing this and then doing that
this idea of like chaining functions
together let's put that into a function
and that finally gets us to that
okay so sequential simply means through
this function take the result send it to
this function etc right and linear means
create the weight matrix create the
biases
okay so that's that's yeah right so we
can then you know as we started to talk
about like turn this into any deep
neural network by saying you know rather
than sending this straight off into ten
activations let's let's put it into say
100 activations we could pick whatever
one number we like put it through a RAL
you to make it nonlinear put it through
another linear layer another rally ER
and then our final output with our final
activation function right and so this is
now a deep network so we could fit that
and this time now because it's like
deeper I'm actually going to run a few
more a pox right and you can see the
accuracy increasing okay so if you try
and increase the learning rate here it's
like 0.1 further it actually starts to
become unstable now I'll show you a
trick this is called learning rate
annealing and the trick is this when
you're trying to fit to a function right
you've been taking a few steps step step
step as you get close to the middle like
get close to the bottom your steps
probably want to become smaller right
otherwise what tends to happen is you
start finding you're doing this right
and so you can actually see it here
right it got 93 94 and a bit 94 694
eight like it's kind of starting to
flatten now right now that could be
because it's kind of done as well as it
can or it could be that it's going to
growing backwards and forwards so what
does a good idea as is later on in
training is to decrease your learning
rate and to take smaller steps okay
that's called learning rate annealing so
there's a function in fast AI called set
learning rates
you can pass in your optimizer and your
new learning rate and you don't see if
that helps right and very often it does
about about an order of magnitude in the
deep learning course we learn a much
much better technique than this to do
this all automatically and at a more
granular level but if you're doing it by
hand you know like an order of magnitude
at a time is what people generally do so
you'll see people in papers talk about
learning rate schedules this is like a
learning rate schedule so this schedule
just a moment Erica will come to us
first has got us 297 okay and I tried
kind of going further and we don't seem
to be able to get much better than that
so yeah so here we've got something
where we can get 97% accuracy
yes Erica so it seems like you change
the learning rate to something very
small ten times smaller than we started
with so we had point one now its point
everyone yep but that makes the whole
model train really slow so I was
wondering if you can make it so that it
changes dynamically as it approaches
closer to the minimum yeah pretty much
yes so so that's some of the stuff we
learned in the deep planning course
these more advanced approaches yep so
how it is different from using an
immobilizer or something that that's the
kind of stuff we can do I mean you still
need annealing as I say we do this kind
of stuff in the deep learning course so
for now we're just going to stick to
standard SGD I had a question about the
data loading yeah I know it's a fast day
i Function but could you go into a
little bit detail of how it's creating
batches how it's done and how it's
making those decisions
sure I'd be good to ask that on Monday
night so we can talk about it in detail
in the dig learning class but let's
let's do the quick version here so
basically there's a really nice design
in PI torch where they basically say
let's let's create a thing called a data
set right and a data set is basically
something that looks like a list
it has a length right and so that's like
how many images are in the data set and
it has the ability to index into it like
a list right so if you had like D equals
data set you can do length D and you can
do D or some index right that's
basically all the data set is as far as
pipe torch is concerned and so you start
with the data set so it's like okay
d3 gives you the third image you know or
whatever and so then the idea is that
you can take a data set and you can pass
that into a constructor for a data
loader and that gives you something
which is now iterable right so you can
now say it a DL and that's something
that you can call next on and what that
now is going to do is if when you do
this you can choose to have shuffle on
or shuffle off shuffle on means give me
random mini-batch shuffle off means
drove through it sequentially and so
what the data loader does now when you
say next is it basically assuming you
said shuffle equals true
it's going to grab you know if you've
got a batch size of 64 64 random
integers between 0 and length and call
this 64 times to get 64 different items
and jam them together so fast AI uses
the exact same terminology and the exact
same API we just do some of the details
differently so specifically particularly
with computer vision you often want to
do a lot of pre pre processing data
augmentation like flipping changing the
colors a little bit rotating those turn
out to be really computationally
expensive even just reading the JPEGs
turns out to be computationally
expensive so plate or chooses an
approach where it fires off multiple
processors to do that in parallel where
else the faster I librarian says does
something called multi-threading which
is a much
faster way of doing it yes you know so I
mean pork is there really pork in the
sense that all of the elements so it's a
shuffle at the beginning of the pork
something like that yeah yeah I mean not
all libraries work the same way some do
sampling with replacement some don't we
actually the first a a library hands off
the shuffling off to the set to the
actual pipe torch version and I believe
the pipes version yeah actually shuffles
and an epoch covers everything once I
believe okay
now the thing is when you start to get
these bigger networks potentially you're
getting quite a few parameters right so
I want to ask you to calculate how many
parameters there are but let's let's
remember here we've got 28 by 28 input
into a hundred output and then a hundred
into a hundred and then 100 into 10 all
right and then for each of those we've
got weights and biases so we can
actually do this net dot parameters
returns a list where each element of the
list is a matrix or actually a tensor of
the parameters for that not just for
that layer but if it's a layer with both
weights and biases that would be two
parameters right so basically returns us
a list of all of the tensors containing
the the parameters some elements in pi
torch tells you how how big that is
right so if I run this here is the
number of parameters in each layer so
I've got 784 inputs and the first layer
has a hundred outputs so therefore the
first weight matrix is of size 78,000
400 and the first bias vector is of size
100 okay and then the next one is a
hundred by hundred okay
and there's 100 and then the next one is
100 by 10 and then there's my bias okay
so there's the number of elements in
each layer and
I add them all up it's nearly a hundred
thousand okay
and so I'm possibly at risk of
overfitting yeah all right so we might
want to think about using regularization
so a really simple common approach to
regularization in all of machine
learning is something called l2
regularization and it's super important
super handy you can use it with just
about anything right and the basic idea
anyway so LT rotor ization the basic
idea is this normally we'd say our loss
is equal to let's just do our MSE to
keep things kind of simple it's equal to
our predictions
- our actuals you know squared and then
we sum them up take the average take the
square root okay so what if we then want
to say you know what like if I've got
lots and lots of parameters don't use
them unless they're really helping
enough right like if you've got a
million parameters and you only really
needed ten parameters to be useful just
use ten all right so how could we like
tell the loss function to do that and so
basically what we want to say is hey if
a parameter is zero that's no problem
it's like it doesn't exist at all
so let's penalize a parameter for not
being zero right so what would be a way
we could measure that how can we like
calculate how under Oh our parameters
are I can you pass that to Qin Shi
please Ernest you calculates the average
of positive parameters
can't quite be the average plus yes
Taylor yeah yes you figured it out okay
so I think if we like assuming all of
our data has been normalized
standardized however you want to call it
we want to check that they're like
significantly
different from zero right not the data
that the parameter is rather would be
significantly and the parameters don't
have to be normalized or anything that
is calculated right yes a significantly
different from zero right I suppose I
just assuming that the data has been
normalized so that we can compare that
money oh yeah I thought of yeah right
and then those that are not
significantly different from zero we can
provoke I just draw and I think Chen
she's going to tell us how to do that
you just figured it out right
the could do that that would be called
l1 which is great so l1 would be the
absolute value of the weights average l2
is actually the sum yeah yeah exactly so
we just take this we can just we don't
even have to square root so we just take
the squares of the weights themselves
and then like we want to be able to say
like okay
how much do we want to penalize not
being zero right because if we actually
don't have that many parameters we don't
want to regularize much at all if we've
got heaps we do want to regularize a lot
right so then we put a parameter yeah
right except I have a role in my classes
which is never to use Greek letters so
normally people use alpha I'm going to
use hey okay so so this is some number
which you often see something around
kind of 1e neg 6 to 1 enoch 4 ish right
now we actually don't care about the
loss when you think about it we don't
actually care about the loss other--
than like maybe to print it out or we
actually care about is the gradient of
the loss okay so the gradient of that
right is
that right so there are two ways to do
this we can actually modify our loss
function to add in this square penalty
or we could modify that thing where we
said weights equals weights minus
gradient times learning rate to subtract
that as well right actually to add that
as well and these are roughly these are
kind of basically equivalent but they
have different names this is called l2
regularization right this is called
weight decay so in the neural network
literature you know that version kind of
was the how it was first posed in the
neural network literature where else
this other version is kind of how it was
posed in the statistics literature and
yeah you know they're they're equivalent
as we talked about in the deep learning
class it turns out they're not exactly
equivalent because when you have things
like momentum and atom it can behave
differently and two weeks ago a research
figured out a way to actually do proper
weight decay in modern optimizers and
one of our first day students just
implemented that in the first day I
library so first a is now the first
library to actually support this
properly so anyways so for now let's do
the the version which applied torch
calls weight decay but actually it turns
out based on this paper two weeks ago is
actually l2 regularization it's not
quite correct but it's close enough so
here we can they weight decay as one in
x3 so it's going to set our constant our
penalty multiplier a21 in X 3 and it's
going to add that to the loss function
okay and so let's make a copy of these
cells just so we can compare hope this
actually works
okay and we'll set this running okay
because there's now optimizing well
except if you actually so I've made a
mistake here which is I didn't rerun
this cell this is an important thing to
kind of remember since I didn't run this
rerun this cell here when it created the
optimizer and said net dot parameters it
started with the parameters that I had
already trained right so I actually
hadn't recreated my network okay so
actually you go back and rerun this cell
first to recreate the network then go
through and run this okay there we go so
let's see what happens
so you might notice them notice
something kind of kind of
counterintuitive here which is that
that's our training error right now you
would expect our training error with
regularization to be worse that makes
sense right because we're like we're
penalizing parameters that specifically
can make it better and yet actually it
started out better not worse so why
could that be so the reason that can
happen is that if you have a function
that looks like that right
it takes potentially a really long time
to train where else if you have a
function that kind of looks more like
that it's going to train a lot more
quickly and there are certain things
that you can do which sometimes just
like can take a function that's kind of
horrible and make it less horrible and
it's sometimes weight decay you can
actually make your functions a little
more nicely behaved and that's actually
happened here so like I just mentioned
that to say like don't let that confuse
you right like white decay really does
penalize the training set and look so
strictly speaking the final number we
get to for the training set shouldn't
end up be beat being better but it can
train sometimes more quickly all right
yes can you pass it a chance you don't
get it okay why making it faster like
Zee Time Matters like the training time
memories no it's just after one epoch
right so after one epoch now
congratulations for saying I don't get
it that's like the best thing anybody
can say you know so hopeful this here
was our training without wait okay okay
and this here is our training with wait
okay okay so this is not really just a
time this is related to just an epoch
right after one Apoc my claim was that
you would expect the training set all
other things being equal to have a worse
loss with weight decay because we're
penalizing it you know this has no
penalty this has a penalty so the thing
with the penalty should be worse and I'm
saying oh it's not that's weird
right and so the reason it's not is
because in a single epoch it matters a
lot as to whether you're trying to
optimize something that's very bumpy or
whether you're trying to optimize
something that's kind of nice and smooth
if you're trying to optimize something
that's really bumpy like imagine in some
high dimensional space right you end up
kind of rolling around through all these
different tubes and tunnels and stuff
you know where else if it's just smooth
you just go boom item it's like imagine
of marble rolling down a hill where one
of them you've got like it's a called
Lombard Street in San Francisco it's
like backwards forwards backwards
forwards it takes a long time to drive
down the road right where else you know
if you kind of took a motorbike and just
went straight over the top you just make
sure boom right so so weather so kind of
the shape of the loss function surface
you know impacts or kind of defines how
easy it is
optimized and therefore how far can it
get in a single epoch and based on these
results it would appear that weight
decay here has made it this function
easier to optimize so just to make sure
it's the penalizing is making the
optimizer more than likely to reach the
global minimum
no I wouldn't say that my claim actually
is that at the end it's probably going
to be less good on the training set and
indeed this does look to be the case at
the end after five epochs our training
set is now worse with weight decay now
that's what I would expect right I would
expect like if you actually find like I
never used a term global optimum because
it's just not something we have any
guarantees about we don't really care
about or just care like where do we get
to after a certain number of epochs we
hope that we found somewhere that's like
a good solution and so by the time we
get to like a good solution the training
set with weight decay the loss is worse
because it's very right but on the
validation set the loss is better right
because we penalized the training set in
order to kind of try and create
something it generalizes better so we've
got more parameter you know that the
parameters that are kind of pointless in
l0 and it generalizes better right so so
all we're seeing is that it just got to
a good point after one epoch is really
orbiting obviously no no I but if you
buy if you mean just weight decay you
always make the function surface
smoother no it's not always true but
it's like it's worth remembering that if
you're having trouble training of
function adding a little bit of weight
decay may may help what so by analyzing
the parameters what it does as its moons
out the loss function I mean it's not
it's not why we do it you know the
reason why we do it is because we want
to penalize things that aren't zero to
say like don't make this per
a high number unless it's really helping
the Lasser lodge right set it to 0 if
you can
because setting as many parameters to
zero as possible means that it's going
to generalize better right it's like the
same as having a smaller network okay so
that's that's we do that's why we do it
but it can change how it learns as well
so let's okay this one moment okay so I
just wanted to check how we actually
went here so after the second epoch yeah
so you can see here it's really has
helped right after the second epoch
before we got to 97% accuracy now we're
nearly up to about 98% accuracy right
and you can see that the loss was 0.08
versus 0.13 right so adding
regularization has allowed us to find a
you know three percent versus two
percent so like a fifty percent better
solution yes Erica so there are two
pieces to this right what is l2
regularization and the way to key know
they're the same so my claim was they're
the same thing right so white decay is
the version if you just take the
derivative of LT regularization you get
weight decay so you can implement it
either by changing the loss function
with an with a squared loss penalty or
you can implement it by adding the
weights themselves as part of the the
gradient okay yeah it's just gonna
finish the questions yes
okay pass it to division can we use the
regularization convolution absolutely so
a compilation layer just is is White's
aim Jeremy can you explain why you
thought you needed weight decay in this
particular problem not easily I mean
other than to say it's something that I
would always try speaking well yeah I
mean okay so even if I yeah okay that's
a good point unit so if if my training
loss was higher than my validation loss
then I'm under fitting
right so there's definitely no point
recognizing right if like that would
always be a bad thing that would always
mean you need like more parameters in
your model in this case I'm I'm
overfitting that doesn't necessarily
mean regularization will help but it's
certainly worth trying
thank you you know that's a great point
there's one more question yep Tyler
doing a pass over there so how do you
choose the optimal number of epic you do
my take learning cause it's a it's
that's a long story and a lot to lots of
users by here on here ollie it's a bit
of both we just don't as I say we don't
have time to cover best practices in
this class we're going to learn the kind
of fundamentals yeah okay
so let's take a six minute break and
come back at 11:10 alright so something
that we cover in great detail in the
deep learning course but it's like
really important to mention here is that
is it the secret in my opinion to kind
of modern machine learning techniques is
to massively over parameterize the
solution to your problem right like as
we've done here you know we've got like
a hundred thousand weights when we only
had a small number of 28 by 28 images
and then use regularization okay it's
like the direct opposite of how nearly
all statistics and learning was done for
decades before and still most kind of
like senior lecturers at most
universities in most areas of have this
background where they've learned the
correct way to build a model is to like
have as few parameters as possible right
and so hopefully we've learnt two things
so far you know one is we can build
very accurate models even when they have
lots and lots of parameters like a
random forest has a lot of parameters
and you know this here deep network has
a lot of parameters and they can be
accurate right and we can do that by
either using bagging or by using
regularization okay and regularization
in neural nets means either weight decay
also known as kind of filter
regularization or drop out which we
won't worry too much about yeah so like
it's a it's a very different way of
thinking about building useful models
and like I just wanted to kind of warn
you that once you leave this classroom
like even possibly when you go to the
next faculty members talk like there'll
be people at USF as well who entirely
trained in the world of like models with
small numbers of parameters you know
your next boss is very likely to have
been trained in the world of models with
small numbers of parameters the idea
that they are somehow more pure or
easier or better or more interpretable
or whatever I I am convinced that that
is not true probably not ever true
certainly very rarely true and that
actually models with lots of parameters
can be extremely interpretive all as we
learn from our whole lesson of random
forest interpretation you can use most
of the same techniques with neural nets
but with neural nets are even easier
right remember how we did feature
importance by randomizing a column to
see how it changes in that column would
impact the output well that's just like
a kind of dumb way of calculating its
gradient how much does varying this
import change the output with a neural
net we can actually calculate its
gradient right so with PI torch you can
actually say what's the gradient that
the output with respect to this column
okay you can do the same kind of thing
to do partial dependence plot with an
Anette and you know I mentioned for
those of you interested in making a real
impact nobody's written basically any of
these things for neural nets right so
that that that whole area needs like
libraries to be written blog posts to be
written
you know some papers have been written
but only in very narrow domains like
computer vision as far as I know
nobody's written the paper saying here's
how to do structured data neural
networks
you know interpretation methods so it's
a really exciting big area so what we're
going to do though is we're going to
start with applying this with a simple
linear model this is mildly terrifying
for me because we're going to do NLP and
NLP faculty expert is in the room so
David just yell at me if I screw this up
too badly and so NLP refers to you know
any any kind of modeling where we're
working with with natural language tests
right and it interestingly enough we're
going to look at a situation where a
linear model is pretty close to the
state of the art for solving a
particular problem it's actually
something where I actually surpassed
this baited state of the art in this
using a recurrent neural network a few
weeks ago but this is actually going to
show you pretty close to the state of
art with with a linear model we're going
to be working with the IMDB
I am DVD data set so this is a data set
of movie reviews you can download it by
following these steps and once you
download it you'll see that you've got a
train and a test directory and in your
train directory you'll see there's a
negative and a positive directory and in
your positive directory you'll see
there's a bunch of text files
and here's an example of a text file so
somehow we've managed to pick out a
story of a man who has a natural
feelings for a pig as our first choice
that wasn't intentional
but it'll be fun so we're going to look
at these movie reviews and for each one
we're going to look to see whether they
were positive or negative so they've
been put into one of these folders they
were downloaded from from IMDB the movie
database and review site the ones that
were strongly positive went positive
strongly negative went negative and the
rest they didn't label at all so there's
only highly polarized reviews so in this
case you know we have an insane violent
mob which unfortunately it is too absurd
too off-putting those in the area be
turned off so the label for this was a
zero which is negative okay
so this is a negative review so in the
FASTA guy library there's lots of little
functions and classes to help with most
kinds of domains that you do machine
learning on for NLP one of the simple
things we have is texts from folders
there's just going to go ahead and go
through and find all of the folders in
here with these names and create a
labeled data set and you know don't let
these things ever stop you from
understanding what's going on behind the
scenes okay we can grab its source code
and as you can see it's tiny you know
it's like five lines okay so I don't
like to write these things out in full
you know but hide them behind at all
functions so you can reuse them but
basically it's going to go through each
directory and then within that so I go
through yeah go through each directory
and then go through each file in that
directory and then stick that into this
array of texts and figure out what
folder it's in and stick that into the
array of labels okay so that's how we
basically end up with something where we
have an array of the reviews and an
array of the labels
okay so that's our data so our job will
be to take that and to predict that okay
and the way we're going to do it is
we're gonna throw away like all of the
interesting stuff about language which
is the order in which the words are in
right now this is very often not a good
idea but in this particular case it's
going to turn out to work like not too
badly so let me show you what I mean by
like throwing away the order of the
words like normally the order of the
words matters a lot if you've got a not
before something then that not refers to
that thing right so but the thing is
when in this case we're trying to
predict whether something is positive or
negative if you see the word absurd
appear a lot right then maybe that's a
sign that this isn't very good so you
know cryptic maybe there's a sign that
it's not very good
so the idea is that we're going to turn
it into something called a term document
matrix where for each document are you
each review we're just going to create a
list of what words are in it rather than
what order they're in so let me give an
example can you see this okay okay so
here are four movie reviews that I made
up this movie is good the movie is good
they're both positive this movie is bad
the movie is bad they're both negative
right so I'm going to turn this into a
term document matrix so the first thing
I need to do is create some in-court of
vocabulary a vocabulary is a list of all
the unique words that appear okay so
here's my vocabulary this movie is good
the bad that's all the words okay and so
now I'm going to take each one of my
movie reviews and turn it into a vector
of which words appear and how often do
they appear right and in this case none
of my words appear twice so this movie
is good has those four words in it where
else this movie is bad has those four
words in it okay so this is called a
term document matrix
alright and this representation we call
a bag of words representation right so
this here is a bag of words
representation of the view of the review
it doesn't contain the order of the text
anymore it's just a bag of the words
what words are in it it contains bad is
movie this okay so that's the first
thing we're going to do is we're going
to turn it into a bag of words
representation and the reason that this
is convenient for linear models is that
this is a nice rectangular matrix that
we can like do math on okay and
specifically we can do a logistic
regression and that's what we're going
to do is we're going to get to a point
we do a logistic regression before we
get there though we're going to do
something else which is called naive
Bayes okay so SK learn has something
which will create a term document matrix
for us it's called count vectorizer okay
so what does use it now in NLP you have
to turn your text into a list of words
and that's called tokenization okay and
that's actually non-trivial because like
if this was actually this movie is good
dot right or if it was this movie is
good like how do you deal with like that
punctuation
well perhaps more interestingly what if
it was this movie isn't good alright so
how you turn a piece of text into a list
of tokens is called tokenization right
and so a good tokenizer would turn this
movie isn't good into this this base
quote movie space is space and good
space right so you can see in this
version here if I now split this on
spaces every token is either a single
piece of punctuation or like this suffix
and is considered like a word right
that's kind of like how we would
probably want to tokenize that piece of
text because you wouldn't want good . to
be like an object right because there's
no
concept of good . right or double-quote
movie is not like an object right so
tokenization is something we hand off to
a tokenizer first AI has a tokenizer in
it that we can use so this is how we
create our term document matrix with a
tokenizer s Kaitlyn has a pretty
standard API which is nice I'm sure
you've seen it a few times now before
so once we've built some kind of model
think we can kind of think of this as a
model just ish this is just defining
what it's going to do but you can call
fit transform - to do that right so in
this case fit transform is going to
create the vocabulary okay and create
the term document matrix based on the
training set transform is a little bit
different that says use the previously
fitted model which in this case means
use the previously created vocabulary we
wouldn't want the validation set in the
training set to have you know the words
in different orders in the matrices
right because then they'd like to have
different meanings so this is here
saying use the same vocabulary to create
a bag of words for the validation set
could you pass that back in please what
if the violation set has different set
of words other than training yeah that's
a great question so generally most of
these kind of vocab creating approaches
will have a special token for unknown
sometimes you can you'll also say like
hey if a word appears less than three
times call it unknown but otherwise it's
like if you see something you haven't
seen before call it unknown so that
would just become a column in the bag of
words is good question all right so when
we create this term document matrix the
training set we have 25,000 rows because
there are 25,000 movie reviews and there
are 70 5132 columns
what does that represent what does that
mean there are seven hundred and
seventy-five thousand hundred thirty-two
what can you pass that to device
just a moment okay power sector
diversion locality yeah come on what do
you mean
so like the number of words Union or the
number of words that the number of
unique words yeah exactly
good okay now most documents don't have
most of these 75,000 words right so we
don't want to actually store that as a
normal array in memory because it's
going to be very wasteful so instead we
store it as a sparse matrix okay and
what a sparse matrix does is it just
stores it as something that says
whereabouts of the non-zeros right so it
says like okay term number so document
number one word number four appears and
it has four of them you know document
one term number 123 has that that
appears and it's a one right and so
forth that's basically how it's done
there's actually a number of different
ways of storing and if you do Rachel's
computational linear algebra course
you'll learn about the different types
and why you choose them and how to
convert and so forth but they're all
kind of something like this right and
you don't really on the whole have to
worry about the details the important
thing to know is it's it's efficient
okay
and so we could grab the first review
all right and that gives us 75,000 long
sparse
one long one row long matrix okay with
93 stored elements so in other words 93
of those words are actually used in the
first document okay we can have a look
at the vocabulary by saying vectorizer
docket fetcher feature names that gives
us the vocab and so here's an example of
a few of the elements of feature names I
didn't intentionally pick the one that
had Ozzie but you know that's the
important words obviously I haven't you
the tokenizer here I'm just bidding on
space so this isn't quite the same as
what the vectorizer did but to simplify
things let's grab a set of all the
lowercased words by making it a set we
make them unique so this is roughly the
list of words that would appear right
and that length is 91 which is pretty
similar to 93 and just the difference
will be that I didn't use a real
tokenizer yeah right so that's basically
all that's been done there it's probably
created this unique list of words and
mapped them we could check by calling
vectorizer cavalry underscore to find
the ID of a particular word so this is
like the reverse map of this one right
this is like integer two word here is
word two integer and so we saw absurd
appeared twice in the first document so
let's check train term dark zero comma
one two nine seven there it is is two
right or else
unfortunately Ozzie didn't appear in the
unnatural relationship with a pig movie
so zero comma five thousand is zero okay
so that's that's our term document
matrix yes so does it care about the
relative relationship between the words
as in the ordering of the words no we've
thrown away the orderings that's why
it's a bag of words and I'm not claiming
that this is like necessarily a good
idea what I will say is that like the
vast majority of NLP work that's been
done over the last few decades generally
uses this representation because we
didn't really know much better nowadays
increasingly we're using recurrent
neural networks instead which we'll
learn about in our last deep learning
lesson of part one but sometimes this
representation works pretty well and
it's actually going to work pretty well
in this case okay so in fact you know
most like back when I was at first me or
my email company a lot of the spam
filtering we did
used this next technique naivebayes
which is as a bag of words approach just
kind of like you know if you're getting
a lot of email containing the word
viagra and it's always been a spam and
you never get email from your friends
talking about viagra then it's very
likely something that says by Agra
regardless of the detail of the language
is probably from a spammer all right so
that's the basic theory about like
classification using a term document
matrix okay
so let's talk about naive Bayes and
here's the basic idea
we're going to start with our term
document matrix right and these first
two is our corpus of positive reviews
these next two is our corpus of negative
reviews and so here's our whole corpus
of all reviews so what I could do is now
to create a probability I've got to call
the as we tend to call these more
generically features rather than words
right this is a feature movie as a
feature is as a feature right so it's
kind of more now like machine learning
language a column is a feature look all
those we call those earth in naive Bayes
so we can basically say the probability
that you would see the word this given
that the class is 1 given that it's a
positive review is just the average of
how often do you see this in the
positive reviews right now we've got to
be a bit careful though because if you
never ever see a particular word in a
particular class right so if I've never
received an email from a friend that
said viagra right that doesn't actually
mean the probability of a friend send me
sending me an email about viagra is zero
it's not really zero right I I hope I
don't get an email you know from
Terrence tomorrow saying like Jeremy you
probably could use this you know
effortless meant for viagra but you know
it could happen
you know I'm sure it'd be in my best
interest yeah so so what we do is we say
actually what we've seen so far is not
the full sample of everything that could
happen it's like a sample of what's
happened so far so let's assume that the
next email you get actually does mention
viagra and every other possible word
right so basically we're going to add a
row of ones okay so that's like the
email that contains every possible word
so that way nothing's ever infinitely
and unlikely yeah so I take the average
of all of the times that this appears in
my positive corpus plus the ones okay
so that's like the the probability that
feature equals this appears in a
document given that class equals one and
so not surprisingly here's the same
thing for probability that this feature
this appears given class equals zero all
right same calculation except for the
zero rows and obviously these are the
same because this appears twice in the
positives sorry once in the positives
and once in the negatives okay let's
just put this back to what it was
all right so we can do that for every
feature for every class right so our
trick now is to basically use Bayes rule
to kind of fill this in so what we want
is the probability that given that I've
got this particular document so somebody
sent me this particular email or I have
this particular IMDB review what's the
probability that its class is equal to I
don't know positive right so for this
particular movie review what's the
probability that it's plus is positive
right and so we can say well that's
equal to the probability that we got
this particular movie review given that
its class is positive multiplied by the
probability that any movie reviews plus
is positive divided by the probability
of getting this particular movie review
all right that's just basis rule okay
and so we can calculate all of those
things but actually what we really want
to know is is it more likely that this
is plus 0 or plus 1 right so what if we
actually took probability that's plus 1
and divided by probability that's plus 0
what if we did that right and so then we
could say like okay if this number is
bigger than 1 that it's more likely to
be class 1 if it's smaller than 1 it's
more likely to be class 0 right so in
that case we could just divide this
whole thing right by the same version
for class 0 right which is the same as
multiplying it by the reciprocal and so
the nice thing is now that's going to
put a probability D on top here which we
can get rid of right and a probability
of getting the data given
zero down here and the probability of
getting class zero here right and so if
we basically what that means is we want
to calculate the probability that we
would get this particular document given
that the class is 1 times the
probability that the class is 1 divided
by the probability of getting this
particular document given the classes to
0 times the probability that the class
is 0 so the probability that the class
is 1 is just equal to the average of the
labels write probability the class is 0
is just 1 minus that right so so there
are those two numbers right I've got an
equal amount of both so it's both 0.5
what is the probability of getting this
document given that the class is 1
can anybody tell me how I would
calculate that can somebody pass that so
remember so it's going to be for a
particular document so for example would
be saying like what's the probability
that this review is positive all right
so what so you're on the right track but
what we have to gonna have to do is
going to have to say let's just look at
the words it has and then multiply the
probabilities together for class equals
1 right so the probability that a class
1 review has this is 2/3 the probability
it has movie is one is is 1 and good is
1 so the probability it has all of them
is all of those multiplied together
kinda and the kinder phyla why is it not
really can you press it in Taylor
so glad you look horrified and skeptical
where choices not independence thank you
so nobody can call Tyler naive because
the reason this is naive Bayes is
because this is what happens if you take
bayes's theorem Xander naive why and
Tyler is not naive anything better right
so naive Bayes says let's assume that if
you have this movie is bloody stupid I
hate it but the probability of hate is
independent of the probability of bloody
is an independent of the probability of
stupid right which is definitely not
true right and so naive Bayes ain't
actually very good but I'm kind of
teaching it to you because it's going to
turn out to be a convenient piece for
something we're about to learn later
it's okay right I mean it's it's it's I
would never I would never choose it like
I don't think it's better than any other
technique that's equally fast and
equally easy but you know it's the thing
you can do and it's certainly going to
be a useful foundation so so here is now
calculation right of the probability
that this document is that we get this
particular document assuming it's a
positive review here's the probability
given us a negative and here's the ratio
and this ratio is above one so we're
going to say I think that this is
probably a positive review okay so
that's the Excel version and so you can
tell that I let your net touch this
because it's got latex in it we've got
actual math so so here is the here is
the same thing the log count ratio of H
feature FH would if and so here it is
written out as Python okay so our
independent variable is our term
document matrix a dependent variable is
just the labels of the way so using
numpy this is going to grab the rows
where the dependent variable is one okay
and so then we can sum them
over the rows to get the total word
count for that feature across all the
documents right plus one all right
because that's the email Terrance is
totally going to send me something about
Viagra today I can tell that's that's
that yeah okay so do the same thing for
the negative reviews right and then of
course it's nicer to take the log right
because if we take the log then we can
add things together rather than multiply
them together and once you like multiply
enough of these things together it's
going to get kind of so close to zero
that you'll probably run out of
floating-point right so we take the log
of the ratios and then we come as I say
we then multiply that or a log we
subtract that from the so you add that
to the ratio of the class the whole plus
probabilities all right
so in order to say for each document
multiply the phase probabilities by the
accounts we can just use matrix model
plane okay and then to add on the the
log of the class ratios we can just use
plus B and so we end up with something
that looks a lot like our logistic
regression right but we're not learning
anything right not in kind of assess GED
point of view we're just we're
calculating it using this theoretical
model okay and so as I said we can then
compare that as to whether it's bigger
or smaller than zero not one anymore
because we're now in log space right and
then we can compare that to the mean and
we say okay that's 80% accurate 81 was
inaccurate right so naive Bayes you know
is not it's not nothing it gave us
something okay it turns out that this
version where we're actually looking at
how often a word appears like absurd
appeared twice it turns out at least for
this problem and quite often it doesn't
matter whether absurd appeared twice or
once all that matters is that it
appeared so what what people tend to try
doing is to say take the two other
term document matrix and go dot sine dot
sign replaces anything positive as one
and anything negative with negative one
we don't have any negative counts
obviously so this buying arises it so it
says it's I don't care that you saw
absurd twice and it's care that you saw
it right so if we do exactly the same
thing with the binarized version then
you get a better result okay okay now
this is the difference between theory
and practice right in theory naive Bayes
sounds okay but it's it's naive unlike
Tyla it's naive right so what Tyler
would probably do would instead say
rather than assuming that I should use
these coefficients ah why don't we learn
them so it sound reasonable Tyler yeah
okay so let's learn them so we can you
know we can totally learn them so let's
create a logistic regression right and
let's fit some coefficients and that's
going to literally give us something
with exactly the same functional form
that we had before but now rather than
using a theoretical R and a theoretical
B we're going to calculate the two
things based on logistic regression and
that's better okay so so it's kind of
like yeah why why do something based on
some theoretical model because
theoretical models are never gonna be as
accurate pretty much as a data-driven
model right because theoretical models
unless you're dealing with some I don't
know like physics thing or something
where you're like okay this is actually
how the world works there really is no I
don't know we're working in a vacuum and
this is the exact gravity and blah blah
blah right but most of the real world
this is how things are like it's better
to lie on your coefficients and
calculate them yes you know generally
what's this do liquid through I was
hoping you'd ignore not notice but
or basically in this case our term
document matrix is much wider than it is
tall
there is a reformulation of
mathematically basically almost a
mathematically equivalent reformulations
of logistic regression that happens to
be a lot faster when it's wider than it
is tall so the short answer is if you
don't put that here anytime it's wider
than it is tall what really comes true
it'll run this runs in like two seconds
if you don't have it here it'll take a
few minutes so like in math this is kind
of concept of dual versions of problems
which are kind of like equivalent
versions that sometimes work better for
certain situations okay here is so here
is the binarized version okay and it's
it's about the same right so you can see
I've fitted it with the the sine of the
dock of the dr. Murdock matrix and
predicted it with this right now the
thing is that this is going to be a
coefficient for every term where I was
about 75,000 terms in their vocabulary
and that seems like a lot of
coefficients given that we've only got
twenty five thousand reviews so maybe we
should try regularizing this so we can
use regularization built into SK learns
logistic regression class which is C is
the parameter that they use a small
process is slightly weird as smaller
parameter is more regularization right
so that's why I used wanting eight to
basically turn off regularization yeah
so if I turn on regularization set it to
0.1 then now it's 88% okay which makes
sense you know you wouldn't you would
think like 75,000 parameters for 25,000
documents you know it's likely to
overfit indeed it did overfit so this is
adding l2 regularization to avoid
overfitting I mentioned earlier that as
well as l2 which is looking at the
weight squared
there's also l1 which is looking at just
the absolute value of the way
right I I was kind of pretty sloppy in
my wording before I said that l/2 who
tries to make things zero that's kind of
true but if you've got two things that
are highly correlated then l2
regularization will make move them both
down together it won't make one of them
zero and one of them nonzero right so l1
regularization actually has the property
that it'll try to make as many things
zero as possible where else l2
regularization has a property that it
tends to try to make kind of everything
smaller we actually don't care about
that difference in really any modern
machine learning because we very rarely
try to directly interpret the
coefficients we try to understand our
models through interrogation using the
kind of techniques that we've learned
the reason that we would care about l1
versus l2 is simply like which one ends
up with a better error on the validation
set okay and you can try both with SK
learns logistic regression l2 actually
turns out to be a lot faster because you
can't use your equals true unless you
have L 2 so you know and l2 is the
default so I didn't really worry too
much about that difference yet so you
can see here if we use regularization
and binarized we actually do pretty well
okay so yes can you pass that back to W
please before we learned about elastic
net right like combining l1 and l2 yeah
yeah yeah you can do that but I mean
it's like you know with with deeper
models and yeah I've never seen anybody
find that useful okay so the last thing
I'll mention is that you can when you do
your count vectorizer order that was
when you do your account vectorizer you
can also ask for n grams right by
default we get uni grams that is single
words but if we if we say Engram range
equals 1 comma 3 that's also going to
give us by grams and trigrams by which I
mean if I now say okay let's go ahead
and do the count vectorizer cat feature
names now my vocabulary includes a
bigram right bypassed by vengeance and a
trigram by vengeance
. 5 euro miles right so this is now
doing the same thing but after
tokenizing it's not describing each word
and saying that's part of our vocabulary
two words next to each other and each
three words next to each other and this
10 this turns out to be like super
helpful in like taking advantage of bag
of word approaches because we now can
see like the difference between like you
know not good versus not bad this is not
terrible right
or even like double quote good double
quote which is probably going to be
sarcastic
right so using trigram features actually
is going to turn out to make both
naivebayes
and logistic regression quite a lot
better
it really takes us quite a lot further
and makes them quite useful I have a
question about the token icers so you
are saying some marks features so how
are these diagrams and trigrams selected
right so since I'm using a linear model
I didn't want to create too many
features I mean it actually worked fine
even without max features I think I had
something like I can't remember 70
million coefficients it still worked
right but just there's no need to have
70 million coefficients so if you say
max features equals 800,000 the count
vectorizer
will sort the vocabulary by how often
everything appears whether it be uni
ground by graham diagram and it will cut
it off after the first 800,000 most
common engrams Engram is just a generic
word for uni gram by Graham and trigram
so that's why the train term doctype is
now 25
thousand by 800,000 and like if you're
not sure what number this should be I
just picked something that was really
big and you know didn't didn't worry
about it too much and it seemed to be
fine like it's not terribly sensitive
all right
okay well that's we're out of time so
what we're going to see next week and by
the way you know we could have replaced
this logistic regression with our PI
torch version and next week we'll
actually see something in the fast a
library that does exactly that but also
what we'll see next week starting next
week tomorrow is how to combine logistic
regression and naive Bayes together you
get something that's better than either
and then we'll learn how to move from
there to create a deeper neural network
to get a pretty much state-of-the-art
result for structured learning all right
so we'll see you then