so I I don't want to embarrass Rachel
but I'm very excited that Rachel's here
so this is Rachel for those of you that
don't know she's not quite back on her
feet after her illness but well enough
to at least come to at least part with
this lesson so worried if she can't stay
for the whole thing and I'm really glad
she's here because Rachel actually wrote
the vast majority of the lesson we're
gonna see it's I think it's a really
really cool work so I'm glad she's gonna
at least see it being taught even if
unfortunately she's not teaching it
herself so good Thanksgiving present
best for Thanksgiving present so where
as we discussed at the end of last
lesson we're kind of moving from the C
decision tree ensembles to two neural
Nets broadly defined and as we discussed
you know random forests and decision
trees are limited by the fact in the end
that they're basically they're basically
doing nearest neighbors right you know
that all they can do is to get return
the average of a bunch of other points
and so they can't extrapolate out to you
know if you're thinking what happens if
I'll increase my prices by 20% and
you've never priced at that level before
or what's going to happen to sales next
year and obviously we've never seen next
year before it's very hard to
extrapolate it's also hard if it needs
to you know like it can only do around
log base two n decisions you know and so
if there's like a time series it needs
to fit too that takes like four steps to
kind of get to the right time area then
suddenly there's not many decisions left
for it to make so it's kind of this
limited amount of computation that it
can do so there's a limited complexity
of relationship that it can model yes
Prince can I ask about one more drawback
of random forests yeah so if we have a
data as categorical variable which are
not in sequential order
so for random forests we
and coat them and treat them as numbers
let's say we have 20 cardinality and 1
to 20 so the result at random for our
skills is like the spirit and important
skills is something like less than 5
less than 6 but if the categories are
not sequential not in any order what
does that mean yeah so so if you've got
like oh let's go back to bulldozers
erupts erupts with AC erupts na I don't
know whatever right and we arbitrarily
label them like this right
and so actually we know that all that
really mattered was if it had air
conditioning so what's going to happen
well it's basically going to say like
okay if I group it into those together
and those together that like that's an
interesting break just because it so
happens that the air conditioning ones
are going to end up in the right hand
side and then having done that right
it's then going to say okay well within
the group with the two and three it's
going to notice that it's furthermore
going to have to split it into two more
groups so eventually it's going to get
there it's going to pull out that
category it's just it's going to take
more splits than we would ideally like
so it's kind of similar to the fact that
they get to model a line it can only do
it with lots of splits and only
approximately let's just fine with
categories that are not sequential also
yeah so I can't do it it's just like in
some way it's sub-optimal because we
just need to do more breakpoints than we
would have liked but it gets there it
does a pretty good job
and so even although random forests you
know do you have some deficiencies
they're incredibly powerful you know
particularly because they have so few
assumptions they really had to screw up
and you know it's kind of hard to
actually win
Cagle competition with a random first
but it's very easy to get like 10% so in
like in real life where often that third
decimal place doesn't matter random
forests are often like what you end up
doing but for some things like this
Ecuadorian groceries competition it's
very very hard to get a good result with
a random forest because like there's a
huge time series component and like
nearly everything is these two massively
high cardinality categorical variables
which is the store and the item and like
so this so there's very little there to
even throw at a random forest and the
you know the difference between every
pair of stores is kind of different in
different ways and so you know there are
some things that are just hard to get
even relatively good results for the
random forest another example is
recognizing numbers you can get like
okay results with a random forest but in
the end they're kind of the relationship
between you know like that the spatial
structure turns out to be important
right and you kind of want to be able to
do like computations like finding edges
or whatever that kind of carry forward
through through the computation so you
know just doing a kind of a clever
nearest neighbors like a random forest
you know turns out not to be ideal so if
it's stuff like this neural networks
turn out that they are ideal neural
networks turn out to be something that
works particularly well for both things
like the Ecuadorian groceries
competition so forecasting sales over
time buy store and buy item and for
things like recognizing digits and for
things like turning voice into speech
and so it's kind of nice between these
two things neural nets and random
forests we kind of cover the territory
right I don't I haven't needed to use
anything other than these two things for
a very long time and will actually learn
I don't know them what course exactly
but at some point we'll learn also how
to combine the two because you can
combine the two in really cool ways
so here's a picture from Adam guide key
of an image so an image is just a bunch
of numbers right and each of those
numbers is not to 255 and the dark ones
are too close to 255 white ones are
close to zero all right so here is an
example of a digit from this amnesty
data set amnesties are really old it's
like a hello world of machine of
neuro-networks and so here's an example
and so there are 28 by 28 pixels if it
was color there would be three of these
one for red one for green okay so our
job is to look at you know the array of
numbers and figure out that this is the
number eight which is tricky right how
do we do that
so we're going to use a few a small
number of fast AI pieces and we're
gradually going to remove more and more
and more until by the end we'll have
implemented our own euro network from
stretch our own training loop from
scratch and our own matrix
multiplication from scratch so we're
gradually going to dig in further and
further alright so the data for amnesty
which is the name of this very famous
data set is available from here and we
have a thing in fast AI dot IO called
get data which will grab it from a URL
and store it from your on your computer
unless it's already there in which case
it'll just go ahead and use it okay and
then we've got a little function here
called load em nest which simply loads
it up you'll see that it's zipped so we
could just use pythons gzip to open it
up and then it's also pickled so if you
have any kind of Python object at all
you can use this built-in etham library
called pickle to dump it out onto your
disk share it around
load it up later and you get back the
same Python object you started with so
you've already seen this something like
this with like
pandas feather format right pickle is
not just for pandas it's not just for
anything it works for basically nearly
every - object so which might lead to
the question well why didn't we use
pickle for a panda's data frame right
and the answer is pickle works for
nearly every Python object but it's
probably not like optimal for nearly any
Python object right so because like we
were looking at pandas dataframes with
like over a hundred million rows we
really want to save that quickly and so
feather is a format that's specifically
designed for that purpose and so it's
going to do that really fast if we tried
to pickle it it would have been taken a
lot longer right
also note that pickle files are only for
Python so you can't give them to
somebody else where else like a feather
file you can hand around yeah so it's
worth knowing that pickle exists because
if you've got some dictionary or some
kind of object floating around that you
want to save for later or send to
somebody else you can always just pickle
it okay so in this particular case the
folks at deep learning network kind
enough to provide a pickled version
pickle has changed slightly over time
and so old pickle files like this one
you actually have to this was a Python
to one so you have to tell it that it
was encoded using this particular Python
2 character set but other than that
Python 2 &amp; 3 you can normally open each
other's pickle files all right so once
we floated that in we loaded in like so
and so this thing which we're doing here
this is called D structuring and so D
structuring means that load M nest is
giving us back a couple of tuples and so
if we have on the left hand side of the
equal sign a couple of tuples we can
fill all these things in so we're given
back a couple of training data a couple
of validation data and a couple of test
data in this case I don't care about the
test data so I just put it into a
variable called
score which kind of by like people in
pick Python people tend to think of
underscore as being a special variable
which we put things we're going to throw
away into it's actually not special but
it's just it's really common if you see
something assigned to underscore it
probably means you're just throwing it
away right by the way in a jupiter
notebook it does have a special meaning
which is the last cell that you
calculate is always available in
underscore by the way but that's kind of
a separate issue so then the first thing
in that topple is itself at Apple and so
we're going to stick that into X&amp;Y
for our training data and then the
second one goes into X&amp;Y
for our validation data okay so that's
called destructuring and it's pretty
common in lots of languages some
languages don't support it but those
that do life becomes a lot easier so as
soon as I you know look at some new data
set I just check out what's what if I
got all right so what's its tight okay
it's an umpire right what's its shape
it's 50,000 by seven eight four and then
what about the dependent variables
that's an array its shape is 50,000 so
this image is not of length seven eight
four it's at size 28 by 28 so what
happened here well we could guess and we
can check on the website it turns that
we would be right that all they did was
they took the second row and concatenate
it to the first row and the third row
and concatenate it to that and the
fourth row and competitive's of that so
in other words they took this whole 28
by 28 and flattened it out into a single
1d array that makes sense so it's going
to be of size 28 squared this is not
like normal
by any means so don't think like
everything you see is going to be like
this most of the time when people share
images they share them as JPEGs or PNG s
you load them up you get back a nice 2d
array but in this particular case for
whatever reason the thing that they
pickled was flattened out to be 784
and this word flatten is very common
with you know kind of working with
tenses so when you flatten a tensor it
just means that you're turning it into a
a lower rank tensor than you start up
with in this case we started with a rank
two tensor and the matrix for each image
and we turned each one into a rank one
tensor ie a vector so overall the whole
thing you know is a rank two matrix for
a rank two tensor rather than a rank
three tensor so just to remind us of you
know the jargon here
this and math we would call a vector
right in computer science we would call
it a 1d array but because deep learning
have people have to come across as
smarter than everybody else we have to
call this a rank 1 tensor okay they all
mean the same thing more or less unless
you're a physicist in which case this
means something else and you get very
angry at the deep learning people
because you say it's not a tensor so
there you go
don't blame me this is just what people
say so this is either a matrix or a 2d
array or a rank two tensor and so once
we start to get into three dimensions we
start to run out of mathematical names
right which is why we start to be nice
just to say rank three tensor and so
there's actually nothing special about
vectors and matrices that make them in
any way more important than rank three
tenses or rank for tensors or whatever
so I try not to use the terms vector and
matrix where possible because I don't
really think they're there any more
special than any other rank of tensor
okay so kind of it's good to get used to
thinking of this as a rank two tensor
okay and then the the rows and columns
if it was a if we're computer science
people we would call this dimension zero
and dimension one but if we're deep
learning people we would call this axis
zero or access one okay and then just to
be really confusing if you're an image
person this is the first axis and this
is the second axis all right so if you
think about like TVs you know 1920 by
1080 columns by rows
everybody else including deep-learning
and mathematicians rows by columns so
this is pretty confusing if you use like
the Python imaging library you get back
columns by rows pretty much everything
else rows by columns so be careful
because they hate us because they're bad
people
I guess I mean there's a lot of just um
particularly in deep learning like a
whole lot of different areas have come
together like information theory
computer vision statistics signal
processing and - you've ended up with
this hodgepodge of nomenclature in deep
learning often like every version of
things will be used so today we're going
to hear about something that's called
either negative log likelihood or
binomial or categorical cross entropy
depending on where you come from we've
already seen something that's called
either one hot encoding or dummy
variables depending on where you come
from it really is just like the same
concept gets kind of somewhat
independently invented in different
fields and eventually they find their
way to machine learning and then we
don't know what to call them so we call
them all of the above something like
that so I think that's what's happened
with with computer vision rows and
columns so
there's this idea of normalizing data
which is subtracting out the mean and
dividing by the standard deviation so a
question for you do like often it's
important to normalize the data so that
we can more easily train a model do you
think it would be important to normalize
the independent variables for a random
forest if we're training a random forest
be honest I don't know why we don't need
to normalize I just know that we've done
okay does anybody want to think about
why kara it wouldn't matter because each
scaling and transformation we can have
will be applied to each row and we will
be computing means as we were doing like
local averages and at the end we will of
course want to denormalize it back to
give so it wouldn't change the results
I'm doing about the independent
variables not the dependent variable I
taught to us the world depend okay let's
have a go Matthew
it might be because we just care about
the relationship between the independent
variables an independent variable so
scale doesn't matter okay come on cat
why why well why do we own we could like
because at each split point we can just
divide to see which
regardless of what scale you're on what
minimizes variance and that would right
so really the key is that when we're
deciding where to split all that matters
is the order like it all that matters is
how they're sorted so if we divide by
the subtract the mean and divide by the
standard deviation they're still sorted
in the same order so remember when we
implemented the random first we said
sort them and then we liked it then we
completely ignored the values we just
said like now add on one thing from the
dependent at a time so so random forests
only care about the sort order of the
independent variables they don't care at
all about their size and so that's why
they're wonderfully immune to outliers
because they totally ignore the fact
that it's an outlier they only care
about which one's higher than what other
thing right so this is an important
concept it doesn't just appear in random
forests it occurs in some metrics as
well for example area under the ROC
curve you come across a lot that area
under the ROC curve completely ignores
scale and only cares about sort we saw
something else when we did the
dendrogram Spearman's correlation is a
rank correlation only cares about order
not about scale so random forests one of
the many wonderful things about them are
that we can completely ignore a lot of
these statistical distribution issues
but we can't for deep learning because
for deep learning we're trying to train
a parameterised model so we do need to
normalize our data if we don't then it's
going to be much harder to create a
network that trains effectively so we
grab the mean and the standard deviation
of our training data and subtract out
the mean divided by the standard
deviation and that gives us a mean of 0
and a standard deviation of 1 now for
our validation data we need to use the
standard deviation and mean from the
training data right we have to normalize
it the same way just like categorical
variables we had to make sure they had
the same indexes mapped to the same
levels for a random forest or missing
values we had to
make sure we have the same median used
when we were replacing the missing
values you need to make sure anything
you do in the training set you do
exactly the same thing and the test and
validation set so here I'm subtracting
out the training set me in the training
set standard deviation so this is not
exactly zero this is not exactly one but
it's pretty close
and so in general if you find you try
something on a validation set or a test
set and it's like much much much worse
than your training set that's probably
because you normalized in an
inconsistent way or encoded category is
an inconsistent way or something like
that all right so let's take a look at
some of this data so we've got 10,000
images in the validation set and each
one is a rank one tensor of length seven
eight four in order to display it I want
to turn it into a rank two tensor of 28
by 28 so there's a dump a has a reshape
function that takes a tensor in and
reshapes it to whatever size tensor you
request now if you think about it you
only need to tell it about if there are
d axes you only need to tell it about D
minus one of the axes you want because
the last one it can figure out for
itself right so in total there are
10,000 by 784 numbers here altogether
right so if you say well I want my last
axes to be 28 by 28 then you can figure
out that this must be 10,000 otherwise
it's not going to fit it makes sense so
if you put minus 1 it says like make it
as big or as small as you have to to
make it fit and so you can see here it
figure it out it has to be 10,000
so you'll see this used in neural net
software pre-processing and stuff like
that all the time like I could have
written 10,000 here but I try to get
into a habit of like anytime I'm
referring to like how many items in my
input
I tend to use minus one because like it
just means later on I could like use a
subsample this code wouldn't break I
could you know do some kind of
stratified sampling it was unbalanced
this code wouldn't break so by using
this kind of approach of saying like
minus one here for the size it just
makes it more resilient to change us
later it's a good habit to get into so
this kind of idea of like being able to
take tensors and reshape them and and
and change axes around and stuff like
that is something you need to be like
totally do without thinking because it's
going to happen all the time so for
example here's one I tried to read in
some images they were flattened I need
to unflattering them into a bunch of
matrices okay reshape thing I read some
I read some images in with OpenCV and it
turns out OpenCV orders the channels
blue green red everything else expects
them to be red green blue I need to
reverse the last access how do you do
that I read in some images with place
and imaging library it reads them as you
know rows by columns by channels quiet
which expects channels by rows by
columns how do I transform that so these
are all things you need to be able to do
without thinking like straightaway
because they just it happens all the
time and you never want to be sitting
there thinking about it for ages so make
sure you spend a lot of time over the
week just practicing with things like
all the stuff ago to see today reshaping
slicing reordering dimensions stuff like
that and so the best way is to create
some small tensors yourself and start
thinking like okay what shall I
experiment with so here can we pass that
over there
a backtrack a little bit of course I
love it so back in normalize you say
like you might have gone over this but
I'm still like wrestling with a little
bit yes in many machine learning
algorithms or Milan yeah but you also
just said that scale isn't really
mattered so I said it doesn't matter for
random forests yeah so random forests
are just kind of split things based on
order and so we loved them we love
random forests further away there so
immune to worrying about distributional
assumptions but we're not doing random
forests we're doing deep learning and
deep learning does care can you pass it
over there we have a parametric don't we
should skill no not quite right because
like K nearest neighbors is
nonparametric and scale matters a
helluva lot so I would say things
involving trees generally you're just
going to split at a point and so
probably you don't care about scale but
you know you probably just need to think
like is this an algorithm that uses
order or does it use specific numbers
and can you please give us an intuition
of why it needs scale just Bureau says
that would make modify simulations not
until we get to doing SGD so we're going
to get to that yeah so for now we're
just gonna say take my word for it
okay positive Daniel so this is probably
a dumb question but can you like explain
a little bit more what you mean by scale
because I guess when I think of scale
I'm like oh all the numbers should be
generally the same size that's like you
mean but is that like the case like with
the cats and dogs that we went over with
like the deep learning like you could
have a small cat and like a larger cat
but it would still know that those were
both cats oh I guess you know this is
one of these problems where language
gets overloaded yeah so in computer
vision when we scale an image we're
actually increasing the size of the cat
in this case we're scaling the actual
pixel values so in both case Kali means
to make something bigger and smaller in
this case we're taking armors from
naught to 255 and making them so that
they have an average of 0 and a standard
deviation
unit one Jeremy could you please explain
us is it by column by row by pixel by
pixel so when you're scaling I'm just
not thinking about every picture but I
am kind of an input yeah so okay yeah
sure so I mean it's a little bit subtle
but in this case I've just got a single
mean and a single standard deviation
right so it's basically on average how
how much black is there right and so on
average you know we have a mean and a
standard deviation across all the pixels
in computer vision we would normally do
it by channel so we would normally have
one number for read one number for green
one number for blue in general you you
need a different set of normalization
coefficients for each leg each thing you
would expect to behave differently so if
we were doing like a structured data set
where we've got like income distance in
kilometers and a number of children but
you need three separate normalization
coefficients for those they're like very
different kinds of things so yeah it's
kind of like a bit domain-specific here
it's like in this case all of the pixels
are you know levels of gray so we just
got a single scaling number where else
you could imagine if they were red
versus cream versus blue you could need
to scale those channels in different
ways and plus they're better please so
I'm having a little bit of trouble
imagining what would happen if you do
normalize in this case um so we'll get
there so for next oh wait so this is
kind of what your net was saying is like
why would we normalize and for now we're
normalizing because I say we have to
when we get to looking at stochastic
gradient descent will basically discover
that if you
basically to skip ahead a little bit
we're going to be doing a matrix
multiply by a bunch of weights we're
going to pick those weights in such a
way that when we do the matrix multiply
we're going to try to keep the numbers
at the same scale that they started out
as and that's going to basically require
the initial numbers we're going to have
to know what their scale is so basically
it's much easier to create a single kind
of neural network architecture that
works for lots of different kinds of
inputs if we know that they're
consistently going to be mean 0 standard
deviation 1 that would be the short
answer but we'll learn a lot more about
it and if in a couple of lessons you're
still not quite sure why let's come back
to it because it's a really interesting
thing to talk about yes I'm just trying
to visualize the axes we're working with
you so under plots when you when you
write x valid shape we get ten thousand
by seven eight four yeah that mean that
we brought in 10,000 pictures yeah of
that dimension exactly okay and then in
the next line when you choose to reshape
it is there a reason why you put 28 28
on azzam Y or z coordinates or is there
a reason why they're in that order
yeah there is pretty much all neural
network libraries assume that the first
axis it's like kind of the equivalent of
a row it's like a separate thing it's a
sentence or an image or you know example
of sales or whatever so I want each
image you know to be as a separate item
of the first axis and then so that
leaves two more axes for the rows and
columns of the images and that's pretty
standard
that's totally standard yeah I don't
think I've ever seen a library that
doesn't work that way
can you pass the table here so while
normalizing the validation data
I saw you have used mean of X and
standard deviation of X data training
data only yes so shouldn't we use mean
and standard deviation of validation
data
you mean like join them together or
separately goodwill didn't mean no
because you see then you would be
normalizing the validation set using
different numbers and so now the meaning
of like this this pixel has a value of 3
in the validation set has a different
meaning to the meaning of 3 in the in
the training set it would be like if we
had like days of the week encoded such
that Monday was a 1 in the training set
and was a 0 in the validation set we've
got now two different sets where the
same number has a different meaning so
we we want to make sure that we so let
me give an example let's say we were
doing like full-color images and our
tests their training set can contained
like green frogs green snakes and gray
elephants right we're trying to figure
out which was which now we normalized
using you know the each channel mean and
then we have a validation set and the
test set which are just green frogs and
green snakes so if we would have
normalized by the validation sets
statistics we would end up saying things
on average a green and so we would like
remove all the greenness out and so we
would now fail to recognize the green
frogs and the green snakes effectively
right so we actually want to use the
same normalization coefficients that we
were training on and for those of you
doing the deep learning class we
actually go further than that when we
use a pre tracking network we have to
use the same normalization coefficients
that the original authors trained on so
the idea is that you know that the a
number needs to have this consistent
meaning across every data set where you
use it how can you pass the test meter
that means when you are looking at the
test set you normalize the test set
based on this this meanness
that's right okay
[Music]
so um here's a you know so so the valid
validation y-values I just rank one
tensor of 10,000 remember there's this
kind of weird Python thing where at
Apple with just one thing in it there's
a trailing comma okay so this is a rank
one tensor of length 10,000 and so
here's an example of something from that
it's just the number three so that's our
labels so here's another thing you need
to be able to do in your sleep slicing
into a tensor so in this case we're
slicing into the first axis with 0 so
that means we're grabbing the first
slice so because this is a single number
this is going to reduce the rank of the
tensor by one it's going to turn it from
a 3-dimensional tensor into a
two-dimensional tensor right so you can
see here this is now just a matrix and
then we're going to grab 10 through 14
inclusive rows 10 through 14 inclusive
columns and here it is right so this is
the kind of thing you need to be super
comfortable like grabbing pieces out
looking at the numbers and looking at
the picture right so here's an example
of a little piece of that first image
and so you kind of want to get used to
this idea that if you're working with
something like pictures or audio you
know this is something your brain is
really good at interpreting right so
like keep showing pictures of what
you're doing whenever you can but also
remember behind the scenes they're
numbers so like if something's going
weird print out a few of the actual
numbers you might find somehow some of
them have become infinity or they're all
0 or whatever right so like use this
interactive environment and to explore
the data as you go did you have a
question with just a quick I guess
semantic question why when it's a tensor
of Rank 3 is it stored as like XYZ
instead of like tamiya would make more
sense to store it as like a list of like
2d
tensors its let's do it as either right
so remember the formatting because let's
look at this as a 3d okay so here's a 3d
right so a 3d tensor is formatted as
showing a list of 2d tensors basically
but when you're extracting it why isn't
it like if you're extracting the first
one why isn't it X images square
brackets 0 close square brackets and
then a second set of squares because
this has a different meaning right so
it's kind of the difference between
tenses and jagged arrays right so
basically if you do like something like
something like that that says take the
second list item and from it grab the
third list item and so we tend to use
that when we have something called a
jagged array which is where each sub
array may be of a different length right
where else we have like a single object
of three dimensions and so we're trying
to say like which little piece of it do
we want and so the idea is that that is
a single slice object to go in and grab
that piece out ok so here's an example
of a few of those images along with
their labels and this kind of stuff you
want to be able to do pretty quickly
with matplotlib it's it's going to help
you a lot in in life in your exam so you
can have a look at you know what Rachel
wrote here when she wrote plots we can
use we can use add sub plot to basically
create those little separate plots and
you need to know that I am show is how
we basically take a numpy array and draw
it as a picture okay and then we've also
added the title on top so there it is
all right so let's you know
take that data and try to build a neural
network with it and so a neural network
and sorry this is going to be a lot of
review for those of you already doing
deep learning a neural network is just a
particular mathematical function or a
class of mathematical functions but it's
a really important class because it has
the property it supports what's called
the universal approximation theorem
which is that which means that a neural
network can approximate any other
function arbitrarily closely right so in
other words it can do in theory it can
do anything
as long as we make it big enough so this
is very different to a function like 3x
plus 5 right which can only do one thing
it's a very specific function or the
class of functions ax plus B which can
only represent lines of different slopes
moving it up and down different amounts
or even the function ax squared plus BX
plus C plus sine D you know again only
can represent a very specific subset of
relationships the neural network however
is a function that can represent any
other function to arbitrarily close
accuracy right so what we're going to do
is we're going to learn how to take a
function so let's take like ax plus B
and we're going to learn how to find its
parameters in this case a and B which
allow it to fit as closely as possible
to a set of data and so this here is
showing example from a notebook that
we'll be looking at in deep learning
course which basically shows what
happens when we use something called
stochastic gradient descent to try and
set a and B and basically what happens
is we're going to pick a random a to
start with a random B to start with and
then we're going to basically figure out
do I need to increase or decrease a to
make it closer at the line closer to the
dots do I need to increase or decrease B
to make the line closer to the dots and
then just keep increasing and decreasing
a and B lots and lots of times okay so
that's what we're going to do and
to answer the question do I need to
increase or decrease a and B we're going
to take the derivative right so the
derivative of the function with respect
to a and B tells us how will that
function change as we change a and B all
right so that's basically what we're
going to do but we're not going to start
with just a line the idea is we're to
build up to actually having a neural net
and so it's going to be exactly the same
idea but because it's an infinitely
flexible function we're going to be able
to use this exact same technique to fit
arbitrarily to arbitrarily complex
relationships now that's basically the
idea so then what you need to know is
that a neural net is actually a very
simple thing a neural net actually is
something which takes as input let's say
we've got a vector does a matrix product
by that vector right so this is like
this is of size let's draw this properly
so like if this is sighs ah this is like
our bye see a matrix product will spit
out something of size C all right and
then we do something called a
non-linearity which is basically we're
going to throw away all the negative
values so can so it's basically max zero
comma X and then we're going to put that
through another matrix multiply and then
we're going to put that through another
max zero comma X and we're going to put
that through another matrix multiply and
so on right until eventually we end up
with the single vector that we want so
in other words each stage of our neural
network is the key thing going on is a
matrix multiplied so in other words a
linear function so basically deep
learning most of their calculation is
lots and lots of linear functions but
between each one we're going to replace
the negative numbers with zeros can you
yes so why are we throwing away the
negative numbers well we'll see right
the short answer is if you apply a
linear function to a linear function to
a linear function it's still just a
linear function so it's totally useless
but if you throw away the negatives
that's actually a nonlinear
transformation and so it turns out that
if you apply a linear function to the
thing we threw away the negatives that
applies that to a linear function that
creates a neural network and it turns
out that's the thing that can
approximate any other function
arbitrarily closely so this tiny little
difference actually makes all the
difference and if you're interested in
it
check out the deep learning video where
we cover this because I actually show a
nice visual intuitive proof not
something that I created that's
something that Michael Nielsen created
or if you want to skip straight to his
website you could go to Michael Nielsen
universe or I think I spelled his name
wrong
never mind Haitian theorem
[Music]
we go neural networks and deep learning
chapter four and he's got a really nice
walkthrough basically with lots of
animations where you can see why this
works one I feel like the the hardest
thing I feel like the hardest thing with
getting started like technical writing
on the Internet
is just like posting your first thing so
if you do a search for Rachel Thomas
medium blog you'll find this will put it
on the lesson wiki where she talks about
she actually says the top advice she
would give to her younger self would be
to start blogging sooner and she has
like both reasons why you should do it
some examples of things that you know
examples of places she's blog has turned
out to be great for her and her career
but then some tips about how to get
started I remember when I first
suggested to Rachel she might think
about blogging because she had so much
interesting to say and you know at first
he was kind of surprised at the idea
that like she could blog you know and
now people come up to us at conferences
and they're like you're Rachel Thomas I
love your writing you know so like I've
kind of seen that that transition from
like wow could I blog to being known as
a strong technical author so yeah so
check out this article if you still need
convincing or if you're wondering how to
get started and since the first one is
the hardest maybe your first one should
be like something really easy for you to
write you know so it could be like you
know here's a summary of the first 15
minutes of lesson three of our machine
learning costs you know here's why it's
interesting here's what we lit or it
could be like here's a summary of how I
used to random forests to solve a
particular problem in my practicum I
often get questions like on my practicum
my organization we've got like sensitive
commercial data
that's fine like you know just find
another data set and do it on that stair
to show the example or you know
anonymize all of the values and change
the names of the variables or whatever
like you can talk to your employer or
your practicum partner to make sure that
they're comfortable with whatever it is
you're writing in general though you
know people love it when they're interns
and staff blog about what they're
working on because it makes them look
super cool you know it's like hey I'm on
you know intern working at this company
and I wrote this post about this cool
analysis I did and then other people
would be like wow that looks like a
great company to work for so generally
speaking you should find people are
pretty supportive um besides which
there's lots and lots of data sets out
there available so even if you can't
base it on the work you're doing you can
find something similar for sure alright
so we're going to start building our
neural network we're going to build it
using something called a torch PI torch
is a library that basically looks a lot
like numpy but when you create some code
with PI torch you can run it on the GPU
rather than the CPU so the GPU is
something which is basically going to be
probably at least an order of magnitude
possibly hundreds of times faster than
the code that you might write for the
CPU for particularly stuff involving
lots of linear algebra right so with
deep learning neural nets you can if you
if you don't have a GPU you can do it on
the CPU right but it's it's going to be
frustratingly slow your Mac does not
have a GPU that we can use for this
because I'm actually talking today we
need an NVIDIA GPU I would actually much
prefer that we could use your Mac's
because competition is great
right but in video we're really the
first ones to create a GPU
which did a good job of supporting
general purpose graphics programming
units GPGPU so in other words that means
using a GPU for things other than
playing computer games they used they
created a framework called CUDA see UDA
it's it's a very good framework it's
pretty much universally used in deep
learning if you don't have an NVIDIA GPU
you can't use it no current max have an
NVIDIA GPU most laptops of any kind
don't have an NVIDIA GPU if you're
interested in doing deep learning on
your laptop the good news is that you
need to buy one which is really good for
playing computer games on there's a
place called exotic PC gaming laptops
where you can go and buy yourself a
great lap up for doing deep learning you
can tell your parents that you need the
money to do deep learning so could you
please have yeah so you'll generally
find a whole bunch of laptops with names
like predator and Viper with pictures of
robots and stuff so stealth pro Raider
leopard anyway
having said that like I don't know that
many people that do much deep learning
on their laptop most people will log
into a cloud environment by far the
easiest I know a few users called cresol
with Kressel you can basically sign up
and straightaway the first thing you get
is a throne straight into a jupiter
notebook backed by a GPU cost 60 cents
an hour with all of the fast AI
libraries and data already available so
that makes life really easy it's less
flexible and in some ways less fast then
using AWS which is the Amazon Web
Services option cost a little bit more
ninety cents an hour rather than 60
cents and
but it's very likely that your employer
is already using that it's like it's
good to get to know anyway they've got
more different choices around GPUs and
it's a good good choice if you're Google
for github student pack if you're a
student you can get a hundred and fifty
dollars of credits straight away pretty
much and so it's a really good way to
get started
Daniel did you have a question yeah I
just wanted to know your opinion on I
know that until recently published like
an open source like way of like boosting
like regular packages that they claim is
equivalent like if you use the bottom
tier GPU on your seat like on your CPU
if you use their boost packages like you
can get the same performance do you know
anything about that yeah I do it's a
good question so I'm actually intro
makes some great numerical programming
libraries particularly this one called
mkl the matrix colonel library they they
definitely make things faster they're
not using those libraries but if you
look at a graph of performance over time
GPUs have consistently throughout the
last 10 years including now are about 10
times more floating-point operations per
second than the equivalent CPU and
they're generally about a fifth of the
price for that performance so yeah it
and then because of that like everybody
doing anything with deep learning
basically does it on NVIDIA GPUs and
therefore using anything other than
NVIDIA GPUs is currently very annoying
so slower more expensive more annoying
I really hope there will be more
activity around AMD GPUs in particular
in this area but AMD's got like
literally years of catching up to do so
it might take a while yeah so I just
wanted to point out that you can also
buy at things such as like a GPU
extender to a laptop yeah that's also
like kind of making like maybe a first
step solution if you only really want to
yeah yeah I think for like 300 bucks or
so you can buy something that plugs into
your Thunderbolt port if you have a Mac
and then for another five or six hundred
bucks you can buy a GPU to plug into
that having said that for about a
thousand bucks you can actually create a
pretty good you know GPU based desktop
and so if you're considering that the
fast AI forums have like lots of threads
where people help each other
spec out something at a particular price
point anyway so to start with out so use
cresol and then you know when you're
ready to invest a few extra minutes
getting going use AWS to use AWS you
basically huh yeah yeah yeah I'm just
talking to the folks online as well okay
so so AWS when you get there go to ec2
ac2 like there's lots of stuff on AWS
ec2 is the bit where we get to like a
rent computers by the hour right now
we're gonna need a GPU based instance
unfortunately when you first sign up for
AWS they don't give you access to them
so you have to request that access so go
to limits up in the top left right and
the main GPU instance we'll be using is
called the p2 so scroll down to p2 and
here P 2 dot X large you need to make
sure that that numbers not 0 if you've
just got a new account it probably is 0
which means you won't be allowed to
create one you have to go request limit
increase and the trick there is when it
asks you why do you want the limit
increase type faster AI because AWS
knows to look out and they know that
faster day I people are good people so
they'll do it quite quickly that takes a
day or two generally speaking to go
through so once you get the email saying
you've been approved for p2 instances
you can then go back here and say launch
instance
and so we've basically set up one that
has everything you need so if you click
on community ama and ami is an Amazon
machine image it's basically a
completely set up computer right and so
if you type fast AI or one word you'll
find here fast AI do part one version
two for the p2 right so that's all set
up ready to go so if you click on select
and it'll say okay what kind of computer
do you want right and so we have to say
all right I want a GPU compute type
and specifically I want to pee to
extra-large right and then you can say
review and launch I'm assuming you
already know how to deal with SSH keys
and all that kind of stuff if you don't
check out the introductory tutorials and
workshop videos that we have online or
Google around for SSH keys very
important skill to know anyway all right
so hopefully you get through all that
you have something running on a GPU with
the past AI repo if you use cresol just
CD fast AI to the the repo is already
there get Paul AWS CD fast AI the repo
is already there get Paul if it's your
own computer you'll just have to get
clone and then away you go all right
so part of all of those is PI torch is
pre-installed and so PI torch basically
means we can write code that looks a lot
like numpy but it's going to run really
quickly on the GPU secondly since we
need to know like which direction and
how much to move our parameters to
improve our loss we need to know the
derivative of functions PI torch has
this amazing thing where any code you
write using the PI torch library it can
automatically take the derivative of
that for you so we're not going to look
at any capitalist in this course and I
don't look at any calculus in any of my
courses or at any of my work basically
ever in terms of like actually
calculating derivatives myself because
I've never had to it's done for me
by the library so as long as you write
the Python code it's the derivative it's
done so the only calculus you really
need to know to be an effective
practitioner is like what is it what
does it mean to be a derivative and you
also need to know the chain rule which
will come - all right so we're going to
start out kind of top-down create a
neural net and we're going to assume a
whole bunch of stuff and gradually we're
going to dig into each piece right so to
create neural Nets we need to import the
PI torch neural net library
hi torch funnily enough is not called
play torch
it's called torch okay so torch NN is
the PI torch subsection that's
responsible for neural nets okay so
we'll call that n N and then we're going
to import a few bits out of fast AI just
to make life a bit easier for us so
here's how you create a neural network n
PI torch by the simplest possible neural
network you say sequential and
sequential means I am now going to give
you a list of the layers that I want in
my neural network right so in this case
my list has two things in it
the first thing says I want a linear
layer now a linear layer is something
that's basically going to do y equals ax
plus B right but matrix matrix multiply
not not univariate obviously so it's
going to do a matrix product basically
so the input of the matrix product is
going to be a vector of length 28 times
28 because that's how many pixels we
have and the output needs to be of size
10 we'll talk about why in a moment but
for now you know this is how we define a
linear layer and then again we're going
to dig into this in detail but every
linear layer just about in neural nets
has to have a non-linearity after it
then we're going to learn about this
particular non-linearity in a moment
it's called the softmax and if you've
done the DL course you've already seen
this so that's how we define a neuron it
this is a two layer neural net there's
also kind of an implicit additional
first layer which is the input but with
PI torch you don't have to explicitly
mention the input that normally we think
conceptually like the input image is
kind of also a layer because we're kind
of doing things pretty manually with PI
torch we're not taking advantage of any
of their convenience is in fast AI for
building your stuff we have to then
write CUDA which tells PI torch to copy
this neural network across to the GPU so
now on from now on that network is going
to be actually running on the GPU
we didn't say that it would run on the
CPU so that gives us back a neuron it
very simple neural net so we're then
going to try and fit the neural net to
some data so we need some data so first
AI has this concept of a model data
object which is basically something that
wraps up training data validation data
and optionally test data and so to
create a model data object you can just
say I want to create some image
classifier data I'm going to grab it
from some arrays right and you just say
ok this is the path then I'm going to
save any temporary files this is my
training data arrays and this is my
validation data arrays ok and so that
just returns an object that's going to
wrap that all up and so we're going to
be able to fit to that data so now that
we have a neural net and we have some
data we're going to come back to this in
a moment but we basically say what loss
function do we want to use what
optimizer do we want to use and then we
say fit we say fit this network to this
data going over every image once using
this loss function this optimizer and
print out these metrics bang ok and this
says here this is 91.8% accurate ok so
that's like the simplest possible neuron
it so what that's doing is it's creating
a matrix multiplication followed by a
non-linearity and that it's trying to
find the values for this matrix which
cause which basically that fit the data
as well as possible that a product that
end up predicting this is a 1 this is a
9s is a 3 and so we need some definition
for as well as possible and so the
general term for that thing is called
the loss function so the loss function
is the function that's going to be lower
if this is better right just like with
random forests we had this concept of
information gain and we got to like pick
what
function do you want to use to define
information gain and we were mainly
looking at root mean square error right
most machine learning algorithms recall
something very similar to at loss right
so the loss is how do we score how good
we are and so in the end we're going to
calculate the derivative of the loss
with respect to the weight matrix that
we're multiplying by to figure out how
to how to update it right so we're going
to use something called negative log
likelihood loss so negative log
likelihood loss is also known as cross
entropy they're literally the same thing
there's two versions one called binary
cross entropy or binary negative log
likelihood and another court categorical
cross entropy the same thing one is for
when you've only got a zero or one
dependent the other is if you've got
like cat dog airplane or horse or at 0 1
through 9 and so forth so what we've got
here is the binary version of cross
entropy and so here is the definition I
think maybe the easiest way to
understand this definition is to look at
an example so let's say we're trying to
protect cat versus dog one is cat zero
is dog so here we've got cat dog dog cat
and here are our predictions we said 90%
sure it's a cat 90% sure it's a dog 80%
sure it's a dog 80% sure it's a cat all
right so we can then calculate the
binary cross entropy by calling our
function so it's going to say okay for
the first one we've got y equals 1 so
it's going to be 1 times log of 0.9
plus 1 minus y 1 minus 1 is 0 so that's
going to be skipped okay and then the
second one is going to be a 0 so it's
going to be 0 times something so that's
going to be skipped and the second part
will be 1 minus 0 ah so this is 1 times
log of 1 minus p1 minus point 1 is point
9 so in other words the first piece and
the second piece of this are going to
give exactly the same number which makes
sense because the first one we said we
were 90% confident it was a cat and it
was and the second we said we were 90%
confident it was a dog and it was so in
each case the loss is coming from the
fact that you know we could have been
more confident yeah so if we said we're
a hundred percent confident the loss
would have been zero right so let's look
at that in Excel so here's our
Oh point nine point one point two point
eight right and here's our predictions
101 so here's one minus the prediction
right here is log of our prediction here
is log of one minus our prediction and
so then here is our sum okay so if you
think about it
and I want you to think about this
during the week you could replace this
with an if statement
rather than Y because Y is always 1 or
zero right then it's only ever going to
use either this or this so you could
replace this with an if statement so I'd
like you during the week to try to
rewrite this with an if statement okay
and then see if you can then scale it
out to be a categorical cross-entropy so
categorical cross-entropy works this way
let's say we were trying to predict
three and then six and then seven and
then two so if we were trying to predict
three and the actual thing that was
predicted was like four point seven
right versus like well actually putting
it this way we're trying predict three
and we actually predicted five or a try
to predict three and we accidentally
predicted nine like Bing five instead of
three is no better than being mine
instead of three so we're not actually
going to say like how far away is the
actual number we're going to express it
differently or to put it another way
what if we're trying to predict cats
dogs horses and airplanes
you can't like how far away is cat from
horse so we're going to express these a
little bit differently rather than
thinking of it as a three let's think of
it as a vector with a 1 in the third
location and rather than thinking it was
a six let's think of it as a vector of
zeros for the one in the sixth location
so in other words one hot encoding right
so that's one hot in code a dependent
variable and so that way now rather than
predicting trying to predict a single
number let's predict ten numbers
alright let's predict what's the
probability that it's a zero what's the
probability it's a 1 what's the
probability it's a 2 and so forth
alright and so let's say we're trying to
predict the two right then here is our
binary cross-entropy sorry categorical
cross-entropy
so it's just saying okay did this one
predict correctly or not how far off was
it and so forth for each one all right
and so add them all up so categorical
cross-entropy is identical to binary
cross-entropy
we just have to add it up across all of
the categories so try and turn the
binary cross-entropy function in python
into a categorical cross-entropy python
and maybe create both the version with
the if statement and the version with
the sum and the product alright alright
so that's why in our PI torch we had 10
as the output as the put dimensionality
for this matrix because when we multiply
sup by a matrix with 10 columns we're
going to end up with something of length
10 which is what we want we want to have
10 predictions ok so so that's the loss
function that we're using all right so
then we can fit the model and what it
does is it goes through every image this
many times so in this case it's just
looking at every image once and go into
slightly update the values in that
weight matrix based on those gradients
and so once we've trained it we can then
say predict using this model on the
validation set right and now that spits
out something of 10,000 by 10 consumers
Elmi why is this shape these predictions
why are they have shaked 10,000 by 10
don't fret Chris it's right next to you
well it's because we have 10,000 images
we're training up 10,000 images training
on so that's what we're validating on
north coast but it's the same thing so
10,000 be validating on so that's the
first axis as percent the second axis is
because we actually make 10 predictions
per image
good good exactly so each one of these
rows is the probabilities that it's Anor
that it's a one that isn't true that's
three and so forth okay very good so in
math there's a really common operation
we do called Arg max notice though it's
common it's funny you like at high
school I never saw odd max first year
undergrad I never saw Arg max but
somehow after university everything's
about Arg max so one of these things
that's for some reason not really taught
at school but it actually turns out to
be super critical and so odd max is both
something that you'll see in math and
it's just written out in full Arg max
it's in numpy it's in PI torch it's
super important and what it does is it
says let's take this array of creds
right and let's figure out on this axis
remember access one is columns right so
across as Chris said the 10 predictions
for each one for each row let's find
which prediction has the highest value
and return not that if it does hit max
it would return the value Arg max
returns the index with their value all
right
so by saying arc max Axess equals 1 it's
going to return the index which is
actually the number itself right so
let's grab the first 5 okay so for the
first one it thinks is a 3 then it
thinks six one's an eight next one's a
six the next one's a nine next one's a
six again okay so that's how we can
convert our probabilities back into
predictions all right so if we I'm safe
that away call it Preds
we can then say okay when does Preds
equal the ground truth right so that's
going to return an array of balls which
we can treat as ones and zeros and the
mean
of a bunch of ones and zeroes is just
the average so that gives us the
accuracy so there's our 91.8% and so you
want to be able to like replicate the
numbers you see and here it is there's
our 91.8% all right so when we train
this it tells us the last thing it tells
us is whatever metric we asked for and
we asked for accuracy okay so the last
thing it tells us is our metric which is
accuracy and then before that we get the
training set loss and the loss is again
whatever odds we asked for negative log
likelihood and the second thing is the
validation set loss PI torch doesn't use
the word loss they use the word
criterion so you'll see here crit okay
so that's criterion equals loss this is
what loss function do we want to use
they call that the criterion same thing
okay so here's how we can recreate that
accuracy so now we can go ahead and plot
eight of the images along with their
predictions and we've got three eight
six nine Oh wrong five wrong okay and
you can see like why they are wrong like
this is pretty close to a nine it's just
missing a little cross at the top this
is pretty close to a five it's got a
little bit at the extra here right so
we've made a start and and all we've
done so far is we haven't actually
created a deep neural net we've actually
got only one layer so what we've
actually done is we've created a
logistic regression okay so a logistic
regression is is literally what we just
built and you could try and replicate
this with SK learns logistic regression
package when I did it I got similar
accuracy but this version ran much
faster because this is running on the
GPU
where else SK learn runs on the CPU okay
so even for something like logistic
regression we can you know implement it
very quickly with PI torch actually pass
that in
so when we're when we're creating our
net we have to do dot CUDA what would be
the consequence of not doing that what
it does not run it wouldn't run quickly
yeah it'll run on the CPU can you pass
it to jail so may build up your network
why is that we have to do linear and
followed by a nonlinear so the short
answer is because that's what the
universal approximation theorem says is
the structure which can give you
arbitrarily accurate functions for any
functional form you know so the long
answer is the details of why the
universal approximation theorem works
another version of the short answer is
that's the definition of a neural
network so the definition of a neural
network is a linear layer followed by a
activation function followed by a linear
layer followed by an activation function
etc we go into a lot more detail of this
in the deep learning of course but you
know for this purpose it's it's enough
to know like that it works so far of
course we haven't actually built a deep
neural net at all we've just built a
logistic regression and so at this point
if you think about it all we're doing is
we're taking every input pixel and
multiplying it by a weight for each
possible outcome right so we're
basically saying you know on average the
number one you know has these pixels
turned on the number two has these
pixels turned on and that's why it's not
terribly accurate right that's that's
not how digit recognition works in real
life but that's that's always built so
far ok can you pass that to Devon so you
keep saying this Universal approximation
theorem yeah did you define yeah but
let's cover it again because it's worth
talking about so all right so Michael
Nielsen has this great website called
neural networks and deep learning and
his chapter 4 is
actually kind of famous now and in it he
does this walkthrough of basically
showing that a neural network can can
approximate any other function to
arbitrarily close accuracy as long as
it's big enough and we walk through this
in a lot of detail in the deep learning
course but the basic trick is that he
shows that with a few different numbers
you can basically kind of cause these
things to kind of create little boxes
you can move the boxes up and down you
can move them around you can join them
together to eventually basically create
like connections of towers which you can
like use to approximate any kind of
surface right so that's you know that's
basically the trick and so all we need
to do given given that is to kind of
find the parameters for each of the
linear functions in that neural network
so to find the weights in each of the in
each of the matrices and so so far we've
got just one matrix and so we've just
built a simple logistic regression so
far just a small doubt I just want to
confirm that when you showed images of
the examples of the images which were
misclassified
yeah they look rectangular so it's just
that while rendering pixels are being
scale differently so are they still 28
by 28 Square 20 hyper 20 I think it's
square I think I just look like angular
cuz they've got titles on the top I'm
not sure yeah I don't know anyway they
are square and um like matplotlib yeah
it does often fiddle around with you
know what it considers black versus
white and you know having different size
axes and stuff so yeah you do have to be
careful there sometimes
um okay so hopefully this will now make
more sense because what we're going to
do is like dig in a layer deeper and
define logistic regression without using
an n dot sequential without using an end
on linear without using an end log
softmax
so we're going to do nearly all of the
layer definition from scratch ok so to
do that we're going to have to define a
PI torch module a PI torch module is
basically either a neural net or a layer
in a neural net which is actually kind
of a powerful concept of itself
basically anything that can kind of
behave like a neural net can itself be
part of another neuron net and so this
is like how we can construct
particularly powerful architectures
combining lots of other pieces so to
create a PI torch module just create a
Python class but it has to inherit from
an end module so we haven't done
inheritance before other than that this
is all the same concepts we've seen an
oo already basically if you put
something in parentheses here what it
means is that our class gets all of the
functionality of this class for free
it's called sub classing it so we're
going to get all of the capabilities of
a neural network module that the PI
torch authors have provided and then
we're going to add additional
functionality to it when you create a
sub class there is one key thing you
need to remember to do which is when you
initialize your class you have to first
of all initialize the superclass right
so the superclass is the NN module so
the NN module has to be built before you
can start adding your pieces to it and
so this is just like something you can
copy and paste into every one of your
modules you just say super dot in it
this just means construct the superclass
first ok so having done that we can now
go ahead and define our weights and our
bias so our weights is the weight matrix
is the actual matrix that we're going to
multiply our data
by and as we discuss it's going to have
28 times 28 rows and 10 columns and
that's because if we take an image which
we flattened out into a 28 by 28 length
vector right then we can multiply it by
this weight matrix to get back out a
length 10 vector which we can then use
to
consider it as a set of predictions so
that's our weight matrix now the problem
is that we don't just want y equals ax
we want y equals ax plus B so the plus B
in neural nets is called bias and so as
well as defining weights we're also
going to find bias and so since this
thing is going to spit out for every
image something of length 10 that means
that we need to create a vector of
length 10 to be our biases in other
words for everything naught 1 2 3 up to
mine we're going to have a different
plus B that would be adding right so
we've got our data matrix here which is
of length 10,000 by 28 times 28 all
right and then we've got our weight
matrix
which is 28 by 28 rose by 10 so if we
multiply those together we get something
of size 10,000 by 10 okay and then we
want to add on our bias
up run way around add on our bias okay
like so and so when we add on and we're
going to learn a lot more about this
later but when we add on a vector like
this it basically is going to get added
to every row okay so that bias is going
to get added to every road so we first
of all define those and so to define
them we've created a tiny little
function called get weights which is
over here alright which basically just
creates some normally distributed random
numbers so a torch Rand n returns a
tensor filled with random numbers from a
normal distribution we have to be a bit
careful though when we do deep learning
like when we add more linear layers
later imagine if we have a matrix which
on average tends to increase the size of
the inputs we give to it if we then
multiply it by lots of matrices of that
size it's going to make the numbers
bigger and bigger and bigger like
exponentially bigger well what if it
made them a bit smaller it's going to
make them smaller and smaller and
smaller exponentially smaller so like
because a deep network applies lots of
linear layers if on average they result
in things a bit bigger than they started
with or a bit smaller than they started
with it's going to like exponentially
multiply that difference so we need to
make sure that the weight matrix is of
an appropriate size that the inputs to
it they're kind of the mean of the
inputs basically is not going to change
so it turns out that if you use normally
distributed random numbers and divided
by the number of rows in the weight
matrix it turns out that particular
random initialization keeps your numbers
at about the right scale right so this
idea that like if you've done linear
algebra basically if the eigen value the
first eigenvalue is like bigger than one
or smaller than one it's
cause the gradients to like get bigger
and bigger or smaller and smaller
that's called gradient explosion right
so we'll talk more about this in the
deep learning course but if you're
interested you can look at climbing her
initialization and read all about this
concept right
but for now you know it's probably just
enough to know that if you use this type
of random number generation you're gonna
get random numbers that are and nicely
behaved you're going to start out with
an input which is mean 0 standard
deviation 1 once you put it through this
set of random numbers you'll still have
something that's about mean 0 standard
deviation 1 that's basically the goal
okay one nice thing about hi torch is
that you can play with this stuff right
so choice dot Randi and like try it out
every time you see a function being used
run it go ahead and take a look and so
you'll see it looks a lot like numpy
right but it doesn't return a numpy
array it returns a tensor and in fact
now I'm GPU programming okay
like put CUDA and now it's doing it on
the GPU so like I just multiplied that
matrix by 3 very quickly on the GPU
right so that's how we do GPU
programming with pay torch all right so
this this is our weight matrix so we
create as I said we create one pretty at
the 28 by 10 1 is just Rank 1 of 10 for
the biases we have to make them a
parameter this is basically telling PI
torch which things to update when it
does SGD that's very minor technical
detail so having created the weight
matrices we then define a special method
with the name forward this is a special
method the word the name forward has a
special meaning in pi torch a method
called forward in PI torch is the name
of the method that will get called when
your layer is calculated ok so if you
create a neural net or a layer you have
to define
forward and it's going to get past the
data from the previous layer so our
definition is to do a matrix
multiplication of our input data times
our weights and add on the biases so
that's it that's what happened
earlier on when we said n n dot linear
that created this this thing for us okay
now unfortunately though we're not
getting a 28 by 28 long vector we're
getting a 28 row by 28 column matrix so
we have to flatten it
unfortunately in torch high torch they
tend to rename things they they spell re
sigh reshape they spell it view okay so
view means reshape so you can see here
we end up with something where the
number of images we're going to leave
the same and then we're going to replace
row by column with a single axis again
negative one meaning as long as required
okay so this is how we flatten something
using PI torch so we flatten it do a
matrix multiply and then finally we do
our soft maps so softmax is the
activation function we use if you look
in the deep learning repo you'll find
something called entropy example where
you'll see an example of softmax
but a soft Mac simply takes the outputs
from our final layer so we get our
outputs from our from our linear layer
and what we do is we go e ^ for each
output and then we take that number and
we divide by the sum of the eight of the
perils that's called softmax why do we
do that well because we're dividing this
by the sum that means that the sum of
those itself must add to one right and
that's what we want we want the
probabilities of all the possible
outcomes add to one furthermore because
we're using e ^ that means we know that
everyone
these is between zero and one and
probabilities we know should be between
zero and one and then finally because
we're using e to the power of it tends
to mean that slightly bigger values in
the input turn into much bigger values
in the output
so you'll see generally speaking my
softmax there was going to be one big
number and lots of small numbers and
that's what we want right because we
know that the output is one hot encoded
so in other words a softmax activation
function the softmax non-linearity is
something that returns things that
behave like probabilities and where one
of those probabilities is more likely to
be kind of high and the other ones are
more likely to be low and we know that's
what we want for a to map to our one hot
encoding so a softmax is a great
activation function to use to kind of
help the neural net make it easier for
the neural net to to map to the output
that you wanted and this is what we
generally want when we're kind of
designing neural networks we try to come
up with little architectural tweaks that
make it as easy for it as possible to to
to match the output that we know we want
so that's basically it right like rather
than doing sequential you know and using
an end linear and in dot softmax we've
defined it from scratch we can now say
just like before our net is equal to
that plastic CUDA and we can say dot
fetch and we get to within a slight
random deviation exactly the same output
okay so I'm what I'd like you to do
during the week is to play around with
like torture and n to generate some
random tensors Torche drop map mole to
start multiplying them together adding
them up try to make sure that you can
rewrite softmax yourself from scratch
you know like try to fiddle around a bit
with you know reshaping view or that
kind of stuff so that by the time you
come back next week you feel like pretty
comfortable with pi torch and if you
google for pi torch tutorial you'll see
there's a lot of great material actually
on the PI torch website
to help you along basically showing you
how to create tensors and modify them
and do operations on them all right
great
yes you had a question can you pass it
over so I see that the forward is the
layer that gets applied after each of
the linear layers so not quite the
forward is just the definition of the
module so this is like how it this is
how we're implementing linear so does
that mean after each linear layer you
have to apply the same function let's
say we can't do a log softmax after
layer one and then apply some other
function after layer two if we have like
a multi-layer neural network so normally
way to find neural networks normally we
define neural networks like so we just
say here is a list of the layers we
wander right we don't you don't have to
write your own forward right all we did
just now is to say like okay instead of
doing this let's not use any of this at
all but write it all by hand ourselves
all right so you can you can write as
many layers you see like in what any
order you like here the point was that
here we're not using any of that we've
written our own mat mole plus bias our
own softmax so this is like this is this
is just Python code you can write
whatever Python code inside forward that
you like to define your own neural net
so like you you won't normally do this
yourself normally you'll just use the
layers that pie chart provides and your
use dot sequential to put them together
or even more likely your download or
predefined architecture and use that
we're just doing this to learn how it
works behind the scenes
all right great thanks everybody