so we've looked at a lot of different
random and random forest interpretation
techniques and a question that's come up
a little bit on the forums is like
what are these for really like like how
do these help me get a better score on
cattle and my answers kind of been like
they don't necessarily and so I want to
talk more about like why do we do
machine learning like what's the point
and to answer this question I'm gonna
put this PowerPoint in the github repo
so you can have a look I want to show
you something
really important which is examples of
how people have used machine learning
mainly in business because that's where
most of you are probably going to end up
after this is working for some company
I'm going to show you a plication zuv
machine learning which are either based
on things that I've been personally
involved in myself or know of people who
are doing them directly so these are
none of these are going to be like
hypotheticals these are all actual
things that people are doing and I'm got
direct or secondhand knowledge of I'm
going to split them into two groups
horizontal and vertical so in business
horizontal means something that you do
like across different kinds of business
whereas vertical means that something
that you do within you know within a
business or within a supply chain or
within a process so in other words an
example of horizontal applications is
everything involving marketing so like
every company pretty much has to try to
sell more products to its customers and
so therefore does marketing and so each
of these boxes are examples of some of
the things that people are using machine
learning for in marketing so let's take
an example all right let's take Chen
okay so Chen refers to a model which
attempts to predict who's going to leave
that's why I've done some churn modeling
fairly recently in in telecommunications
and so we're trying to figure out this
big cellphone company which customers
are going to leave that is not of itself
that interesting like building a highly
predictive predictive model that says
Jeremy how it is almost certainly going
to leave next month
is probably not that helpful because
like if I'm almost certainly going to
leave next month there's probably
nothing you can do about it but it's
it's too late what could have cost you
too much to keep me right so in order to
understand like or why would we do churn
modeling I've got a little framework
that you might find helpful so if you
google for Jeremy Howard data products I
think I've mentioned this thing before
there's a paper you can find designing
great data products that I wrote with a
couple of colleagues a few years ago and
in it I describe my experience of
actually turning machine learning models
into like stuff that makes money right
and the basic trick is this thing I call
the drive train approach which is which
is these four steps the starting point
to actually turn a machine learning
project into something that's actually
useful is to know what am I trying to
achieve and that doesn't mean like I'm
trying to achieve a high area under the
ROC curve around trying to achieve a
large difference between classes no it
would be I'm trying to sell more books
or I'm trying to reduce the number of
customers that leave next month or I'm
trying to detect lung cancer earlier
right these are things that these are
objectives so the objective is something
that absolutely directly is the thing
that the the company or the organization
actually wants no company or
organization lives in order to create a
you know a more accurate predictive
model but there's some reason right so
that's your objective now that's
obviously the most important thing if
you don't know the purpose of what
you're modeling for then you can't
possibly do a good job of it and
hopefully people are starting to you
know pick that up in out there in the
world of data science but interestingly
what very few people are talking about
but it's just as important as the next
thing which is levers
lever is a thing that the organization
can do to actually drive the objective
so let's take the example of churn
modeling right what is a lever that an
organization could use to reduce the
number of customers that are leaving
they could look take a closer look at
the model and do some of this random
forest interpretation and see some of
the causes that are causing people to
leave and potentially change those
issues in the company okay so that's it
that's a data scientist answer but I
want you to go to the next level what
are the things that levers are the
things they can do you want to put it
past behind you what are the things that
they can do just reach like calling or
else they could call someone and say
like are you happy anything we could do
okay yeah so they could like give them a
free pen or something if they you know
buy 20 bucks worth of product next month
yep you are going to do that as well
okay so you guys you guys are the giving
out carrots rather than the handing out
sticks you know over in a couple of yeah
special all right so these are levers
right and so whenever you're working as
a data scientist you know keep coming
back and thinking what are we trying to
achieve we being the organization and
how we try to achieve it being like what
are the actual things we can do to make
that objective happen so building a
model is never ever a lever okay but it
could help you with the lever so then
the next step is what data does the
organization have that could possibly
help them to set that lever to achieve
that objective right and so this is not
what data did they give you when you
started the project right but like think
about it from a first principles point
of view okay I'm working for a
telecommunications company they gave me
some certain set of data but I'm sure
they must know where their customers
live how many phone calls they made last
month how many times they call customer
service whatever like
so have a think about like okay if we're
trying to decide like who should we
reduce the you know give a special offer
to proactively then we want to figure
out like what information do we have
that might help us to identify who's
going to react well or badly to that
perhaps more interestingly would be what
if we were doing like a fraud algorithm
right and so we're trying to figure out
like who's going to like not pay for the
phone that they take out of the store
you know that they once on 12-month
payment plan we never see them again
now in that case the data we have
available it doesn't matter what's in
the database what matters is what's the
data that we can get when the custom is
in the shop right so there's often
constraints around the data that we can
actually use so we need to know what am
I trying to achieve what can I actually
what can this organization actually do
specifically to change that outcome and
at the point that that decision is being
made what data do they have or could
they collect right and so then the way I
put that all together is with a model
and this is not a model in the sense of
a predictive model but it's a model in
the sense of a simulation model so one
of the main examples I gave in this
paper is when I spent many years
building which is if an insurance
company changes their prices how does
that impact their profitability
right and so generally your simulation
model contains a number of predictive
models so I had for example a predictive
model called an elasticity model that
said for a specific customer if we
charge them a specific price for a
specific product what's the probability
that they would say yes both when it's
new business and then a year later
what's the probability that they're good
new and then there's another predictive
model which is what's the probability
that they're going to make a claim and
how much is that plan going to be right
and so like you can combine these models
together then to say all right if we
changed our pricing by reducing it by
10% for everybody through body between
18 and 25
and we can run it through these models
that combined together into a simulation
than the overall impact on our market
share in ten years time is X and our
cost is y and our profit is Z and so
forth right so in practice most of the
time you really are going to care more
about kind of the results of that
simulation than you do about the
predictive model directly but most
people are not doing this effectively at
the moment so for example when I go to
Amazon right I read all of Douglas Adams
as books right and so having read all
with Douglas Evans's books the next time
I went to Amazon they said would you
like to buy the collected works of
Douglas Adams this is after I had bought
every one of his books so like from a
machine learning point of view some some
data scientist had said oh people that
buy one of Douglas Adams as books often
go on to buy the collected works right
but recommending to me that I buy the
collected works of Douglas Adams isn't
smart that and it's actually not smart
at a number of levels like not only is
unlikely to buy a box set of something
of which I have everyone individually
but furthermore it's not going to change
my buying behavior like I already know
about Douglas Adams I already know I
like him so taking up your valuable web
space to tell me hey maybe you should
buy more of the author who you're
already familiar with in the port lots
of times isn't actually going to change
my behavior right so what if instead of
creating a predictive model Amazon had
built an optimization model that said
like that could simulate and said if we
show Jeremy this ad how likely is he
then to go on to buy this book and if I
don't show him this ad how likely is
here to go on to buy this book and so
that's the counterfactual right the
counterfactual is what would have
happened otherwise and then you can take
the difference and say okay what should
we recommend him that is going to
maximally change his behavior so
maximally result in more
books and so you'd probably say like oh
he's never bought me terry pratchet box
he probably doesn't know about terry
pratchet but like lots of people that
like to douglas adams's did turn out to
like terry pratchett so let's like
introduce him to a new author right so
it's the difference between a predictive
model on the one hand versus an
optimization model on the other hand so
the two tend to go hand in hand right
the optimization model basically is
saying well first of all we have a
simulation model right the simulation
model is saying in a world where we put
terry pratchett's book on the front page
of amazon for Jeremy Howard this is what
would have happened he would have bought
it with a money four percent probability
right and so that then tells us with
this lever of like what do I put on
there on my homepage for Jeremy today we
say okay well the different settings of
that lever that put Terry Patchett on
the homepage has the highest simulated
outcome right and then that's the thing
which maximizes our profit from Jeremy's
visit to amazon.com today okay so
generally speaking your predictive
models kind of feed in to this
simulation model but you kind of got to
think about like how do they all work
together so for example let's go back to
churn right so I'd turn out that Jeremy
Howard is very likely to leave his cell
phone company next month what are we
gonna do about it
oh let's call him right and I can tell
you if my cell phone company calls me
right now and says just calling to say
we love you I'd be like I'm cancelling
right now like like that would be a
terrible idea so again you would want a
simulation model that says like what's
the probability that Jeremy is going to
change his behavior as a result of
calling him right now right so elite one
of the levers I have is call him on the
other hand if I like got a piece of mail
tomorrow that said like for each month
you stay with us we're going to give you
a hundred thousand dollars
okay then that's going to definitely
change my behavior right so but then
feeding that into the simulation model
it turns out that overall that would be
an unprofitable choice to make so do you
see how this fits in together all right
so so when we look at something like
churn we want to be thinking like what
are the levers we can pull right and so
what are the kind of models that we
could build with what kinds of data to
help us pull those levers better to
achieve our objectives and so when you
think about it that way you realize that
the vast majority of these applications
are not largely about a predictive model
at all they're about interpretation
they're about understanding what happens
if right so if we kind of take the
cross-product or not the cross-product
or either inter intersection between on
the one hand here are all the levers
that we could pull like here or all the
things we can do and then here are all
of the features from our random forest
feature importance that turn out to be
strong drivers of the outcome and so
then the intersection of those is here
are the levers we could pull that
actually matter right because if you
can't change the thing that is not very
interesting and if it's not actually a
significant driver it's not very
interesting right so we can actually use
our random forest feature importance to
tell us what can we actually do to make
a difference and then we can use the
partial dependence to actually build
this kind of simulation model to say
like okay well if we did change that
what would happen okay so you know there
are examples lots and lots of these
vertical examples and so what I want you
to kind of think about as you think
about the machine learning problems
you're working on is like why does
somebody care about this right and like
what would a good answer to them look
like and how could you you know how
could you actually positively impact
this business so if you're creating like
a Keagle
you know try to think about from the
point of view of the competition
organizer like what would they want to
know and how can you give them that
information so something like fraud
detection on the other hand you probably
just basically want to know whose
fraudulent right so you probably do just
care about the predictive model but then
you do have to think carefully about the
data availability here so it's like okay
that we need to know who is fraudulent
at the point that we're about to deliver
them a product right so it's no point
like looking at data that's available
like a month later for instance so
you've kind of got this this key issue
of thinking about you know the actual
operational constraints that you're
working under you know lots of
interesting applications in human
resources but like employee churn it's
another kind of churn model we're
finding out that Jeremy Howard sick of
lecturing he's going to leave tomorrow
what are you going to do about it
well knowing that wouldn't actually be
helpful it'd be too late right you would
actually want a model that said what
kinds of people you know are leaving USF
and it turns out that like Oh
everybody that goes to the downstairs
cafe leaves USF you know I guess their
food is awful or you know whatever right
or everybody that we're paying less than
half a million dollars a year is leaving
USF you know because they can't afford
basic housing in San Francisco so like
you could use your employee churn model
not so much to say like which employees
hate us but why do employees leave right
and so again it's really the
interpretation there that that matters
now lead prioritization is a really
interesting one right like this is one
where a lot of companies yes Dana can
you pass that over there
you know so I was just wondering select
the Shawn thing or you suggest it so one
being is like being an employee like a 1
million a year or something but then it
sounds like there are two predictors
that you need to predict put I mean one
each Shawn and one you need to optimize
for it like you're profiting so how does
it work yeah exactly so this is what
this like simulation model is all about
so it's a great question so like you
kind of figure out this objective we're
trying to maximize which is like company
profitability you can kind of create
like a pretty simple like Excel model or
something that says like here's the
revenues and here's the costs and the
cost is equal to them you know number of
people we employ multiplied by their
salaries blah blah blah blah blah right
and so inside that kind of Excel model
there are certain cells there are
certain inputs where you're like oh that
thing's kind of stochastic you know or
that thing is kind of uncertain but we
could predict it with a model and so
that's kind of what I what I do then is
I then say okay we need a predictive
model for how likely somebody is to stay
if we change their salary how much how
likely they are to leave you know with
the current salary how likely they are
to leave next year if they if I increase
their salary now why blah so you could
have ruled a bunch of these models and
then you can bind them together with
simple business logic and then you can
optimize that you can then say okay if I
you know pay Jeremy Howard half a
million dollars that's probably a really
good idea you know and if I pay him less
than you know it's probably not or
whatever like you can figure out the the
overall impact and so it's it's really
shocking to me how few people do this
but most people in industry measure
their models using like a UC or our MSC
or whatever which is never actually what
you want
yes can you pass it over here
I wanted to stress the point that you
made before um in my experience a lot of
the problem was to define the problem
right so you you are in a company you're
talking to somebody that doesn't have
like this mentality that you have they
don't know that you have to have x and y
and so on so you have to try to get that
out of them you know what exactly do you
want and try to go through a few
iterations of understanding what they
want and then you know the data you know
what it is you know actually what you
can measure which is often know what
they want so you have to kind of get a
proxy for what they want and then so a
lot of what you do is not that much of
like well some people do actually just
work on really good models for you know
but a lot of people also just work on
this kind of how do you put this I say
you know classification regression or
some other type of modeling that's
actually kind of the most interesting I
think and also kind of what's kind of
what you have to do well understand the
technical model building deeply but also
understand the kind of strategic context
deeply and so this is one way to think
about it and as I say like you know I
actually think you know there aren't
many articles I wrote in 2012 I'm still
recommending but this one I think is
still equally valid today so yeah so
like another great example is lead
prioritization right so like a lot of
companies like every one of these boxes
I'm showing you can generally find a
company or many companies whose sole job
in life is to build models of that thing
right so there are lots of companies
that sell laid prioritization systems
but again like the question is how would
we use that information right so if it's
like oh our best lead is Jeremy you know
he's a highest probability of buying
does that mean I should send a
salesperson out to Jeremy or I shouldn't
like if he's highly probable to buy why
I waste my time with him you know so
like again it's like he really wants
some kind of simulation that says like
what's the chain the likely change in
Jeremy's behavior if I send my best
salesperson your net out to go and like
encourage him to sign okay so
yeah I think this this is like there are
many many opportunities for data
scientists in the world today to move
beyond predictive modeling to actually
bringing it all together you know and
with the kind of stuff that Dena was
talking about in the question so as well
as these horizontal applications that
basically apply to like every company
there's a whole bunch of applications
that are specific to like every part of
the world right so if for those of you
that end up in health care some of you
will become experts in one or more of
these areas like readmission risk okay
so what's the probability that this
patient is going to come back to the
hospital and readmission is depending on
the details of the jurisdiction and so
forth it can be a disaster for hospitals
when somebody is readmitted right so if
you find out that this patient has a
high probability of readmission what do
you do about it
well again the predictive model is
helpful of itself right it rather
suggests like we just shouldn't send
them home yet because they're going to
come back but wouldn't it be nice if we
had the tree interpreter and it said to
us the reason that they're at high risk
is because we don't have a recent EKG
for them and without a recent EKG we
can't have a high confidence about their
you know cardiac health in which case it
wouldn't be like well let's keep them in
the hospital for two weeks it'll be like
let's give them an EKG okay so this is
this is interaction between
interpretation and predictive accuracy
the predictive models are a really great
starting point but in order to actually
like answer these questions we really
need to focus on the interpretability of
these models yeah I think so and and
more specifically I'm saying like we
just learnt a whole raft of random
forest interpretation techniques and so
I kind of just to kind of try to justify
like well
why right and so the reason why is
because actually maybe I'd say most of
the time the interpretation is the thing
we care about and like you can create a
chart you know or a table without
machine learning and indeed that's how
most of the world works right most
managers like build all kinds of tables
and charts without any machine learning
behind them
but they often make terrible decisions
because they don't know the future
importance of the objective they're
interested in and so the table they
create is of things that actually are
the least important things anyway or
they just do a univariate chart rather
than a partial dependence plot so they
don't actually realize that the
relationship they thought they're
looking at is drew entirely to something
else right so you know I'm kind of
arguing for data scientists getting like
much more deeply involved in in strategy
and in trying to use machine learning to
really help you know help a business
with all of its objectives right now
there's like there companies like dun
hum B is a huge company that does
nothing but retail applications with
machine learning and so like I believe
there's like a dun Humby product you can
buy which will help you
which will help you figure out like if I
put my new store in this location versus
lat location how much you know how many
people are going to shop there or if I
put like you know my diapers in this
part of the shop versus that part of the
shop how's that going to impact you know
purchasing behavior or whatever right so
it's I think it's also good to realize
that like the subset of machine learning
applications you tend to hear about you
know in in the tech press or whatever is
this massively biased tiny subset of
stuff which kind of Google and Facebook
do where else the vast majority of stuff
that actually makes the world go around
is you know these kinds of applications
that actually help people make things
buy things sell things build things so
forth so about create repetition the way
we looked at the tree was we manually
check which feature could cause good was
more important for for particular
observation but for businesses they
would have a huge amount of data and
they they want this interpretation for a
lot of observations so how do they
automate it
I don't think the automation is at all
difficult like you just you can run any
of these algorithms like looping through
the rows or doing them in parallel it's
all this code oh I miss understand your
question is it like they set a threshold
that if some feature is about like four
different different people will have
different behavior oh so so yeah okay I
guess it's good question that the
important thing this is a really
important issue actually is the vast
majority of machine learning models
don't automate anything they're designed
to provide information to humans right
so for example if you're appointed sales
customer service phone operator for an
insurance company and your customer asks
you why is my renewal $500 more
expensive than last time then hopefully
you know the insurance company has
provides in your terminal those little
screen that shows the result of the tree
interpreter or whatever then chills so
that you can jump there and tell the
customer like okay well here's last year
you're in this different zip code which
you know is less has lower amounts of
car theft and this year also you've
actually changed your vehicle to more
expensive one or whatever right so it's
not so much about thresholds and
automation but about you know making
these model outputs available to the
decision-makers in an organization
whether they be at the top strategic
level of like you know are we going to
shut down this whole product or not all
the way to the operational level look
like it that that individual discussion
with a customer
so like another example is like aircraft
scheduling and gate management like
there's lots of companies that do that
right and basically what happens is that
the the people you know there are there
are people in at an airport whose job it
is to basically tell each aircraft what
gate to go to
to figure out when to close the doors
stuff like that and so the idea is you
know you're giving them software which
has the information they need to make
good decisions
so the machine learning models end up
embedded in that software to kind of say
like okay that plane that's currently
coming in from Miami there's a 48
percent chance that it's going to be
over five minutes late and if it does
then this is going to be the knock-on
impact through the rest of the terminal
for instance okay well that's kind of
how these things turned a bit together
so there's so many of these right
there's lots and lots and so it's not
like I don't expect you to like remember
all these applications but what I do
want you to do is to like spend some
time like thinking about them like sit
down with one of your friends and like
talk about a few examples of like okay
how would we go about like doing failure
analysis and manufacturing like you know
who-who would be doing that why would be
they doing it what kind of models might
they use what kind of data might they
use like start to like practice this and
get a sense so because then this you're
like interviewing and then when you're
at the workplace and you you know you're
talking to managers you wouldn't be like
straightaway able to kind of recognize
that the person you're talking to what
do they try to achieve what are the
levers that they have to pull right what
if the data they have available to pull
those levers to achieve that thing and
therefore how could we build models to
help them do that and what kind of
predictions would they have to be making
right and so then you can have this
really thoughtful empathetic
conversation with those people and the
same like hey you know in order to
reduce the number of customers that are
leaving you know I guess you're trying
to figure out like you know who should
you be providing better pricing to or
whatever and so forth
so what I'm noticing like from your
beautiful little chart above is that
like a lot of this to me at least still
seems like the primary purpose is like
at the at least base level like is
predictive power and so I guess my thing
is is like for explanatory problems like
a lot of the ones that are people are
faced with like in social sciences is
that something machine learning can be
used for or is used for or is that not
really the realm that it yeah it's um
that's a great question and I've had a
lot of conversations about this with
people in social sciences and currently
machine learning is not well applied in
like economics or psychology or whatever
on the whole but I'm Jun convinced it
can be for the exact reasons we're
talking about so if you're trying to
figure out like you're going try to do
some kind of behavioral economics and
you're trying to understand like why
some people behave differently to other
people you know a random forest with a
feature importance what would be a great
way to start or like more interestingly
if you're trying to do some kind of
sociology experiment or analysis based
on a large social network data set where
you have an observational study you
really want to try and pull out all of
the sources of kind of exogenous
variables you know all the stuff that's
going on outside and so if you use a
partial dependence plot with a random
forest that happens automatically so I
actually gave a talk at MIT a couple of
years ago for the first conference on
digital experimentation which was really
talking about like how do we experiment
in you know things like social networks
in kind of these digital environments
and yeah economists economists all do
things with like you know classic
statistical tests but um the group of
yeah yeah um so but anyway in this case
the The Economist's I talked to were
absolutely fascinated by this and they
actually asked me to give a a
introduction to machine learning session
at MIT to these various faculty and
graduate folks in the Economics
Department and so and some of those
folks have gone on to be you know write
some pretty famous books and stuff and
so hopefully it's been useful so like
it's definitely early days but it's a
it's it's a big big opportunity but as
unit says it's you know there's plenty
of skepticism still out there huh well
the skepticism comes from unfamiliarity
basically with like this totally
different approach so like if you've if
you spent 20 years studying econometrics
and somebody comes along and says you
know here's a totally different approach
to all the econometrics all these stuff
that econometricians do you know
naturally your first reaction will be
like prove it you know so let's do
enough but I think it's you know over
time the next generation of people who
are growing up with machine learning
some of them will move into the social
sciences they'll make huge impacts that
nobody's ever managed to make before and
people will start going wow you know
just like happened in computer vision
right when you know computer vision
spent a long time of people saying like
hey maybe you should use deep learning
for computer vision and everybody in
computer vision is like proven you know
we have decades of work on amazing
feature detectors for computer vision
and then finally in 2012 you know Hinton
and cadets key came along and said okay
and models like twice as good as yours
and you know we've only just started on
this and everybody was like okay that's
pretty convincing
nowadays every computer vision
researcher basically uses the big
wedding so I think that time will come
in there in this area too
okay I think what we might do then is
take a break and we're going to come
back and talk about these random forest
interpretation techniques and do a do a
bit of a review so let's come back at
two o'clock so let's have a go at
talking about these different random
forest interpretation methods having
talked about like why they're important
so let's now remind ourselves like what
they are so I gotta let you folks have a
go so let's let's start with confidence
based on tree variance so can one of you
tell me one or more of the following
things about confidence based on tree
variance to do what does it tell us why
would we be interested in that and how
is it calculated this is going back a
ways first when we looked at even if
you're not sure you only know a little
piece of it give us your piece and we'll
build on it together
I think I got a piece of it it's it's
getting the variance of our predictions
from random forests that's true that's
the how can you be more specific what is
it the variance of I think it's
remembering correctly I think it's just
the overall prediction the variance of
the predictions of the trees yes so
normally the prediction is just the
average this is the variance of the
trees and so it kind of just gives you
an idea of how much your prediction is
going to vary so if maybe even want to
minimize variance maybe that's your goal
for whatever reason that could be that's
not so much the reason so I like your
calculation description let's see if
somebody else can tell us how you might
use that
it's okay if you're not sure now have a
start so I remember that we talked about
the independence of the trees and so
maybe something about if the branch of
the trees is higher or lower than no not
so much that um that's that's that's an
interesting question but it's it's not
what we're going to see here I'm gonna
pass it back behind you so to remind you
just to fill in a detail here what we
generally do here is we take us just one
row like one observation often and like
find out how confident we are about that
like how much variance there are in the
trees for that or we can do it as we did
here for different groups for each row
we calculate the standard deviation that
we get from the random forest model and
then maybe group according to different
variables or predictors and see for
which particular predictor the standard
deviation is high then go deep donnas
why it is happening maybe it is because
a particular category of that variable
has very less number of observation yeah
that's great so that that would be one
approach is kind of what we've done here
is to say like is there any groups that
have that where we're very unconfident
something that I think is even more
important would be when you're using
this like operationally right let's say
you're doing a credit decisioning
algorithm so we're trying to say like
okay is jeremy a good risk or a bad risk
should we loan him a million dollars and
the random forest says I think he's a
good risk but I'm not at all confident
in which case we might say okay maybe I
shouldn't give him a million dollars
where else if we if if the Rena first
said I think he's a good risk I am very
sure of that then we're much more
comfortable giving him a million dollars
right and I'm a very good risk so feel
free to give me a million dollars right
I checked the random forest before a
different notebook
not in the repo so like this is like
it's quite hard for me to give you folks
direct experience with this kind of like
single observation interpretation stuff
because it's really like the kind of
stuff that that you actually need to be
putting out to the front line do you
know what I mean like it's not something
which you can really use so much in a
kind of casual context but it's more
like okay if you're actually putting out
some algorithm which is making like big
decisions that could cost a lot of money
you probably don't so much care about
the average prediction of the random
forest but maybe you actually care about
like the average minus a couple of
standard deviations you know like what's
the kind of worst-case prediction and so
magic I mentioned it's like maybe
there's a whole group that we're kind of
unconfident about so yeah so that's
confidence based on tree variance all
right who wants to have a go with
answering feature importance what is a
why is it interesting how do we
calculate it or any subset thereof you
know
I think it's like that's basically to
find out which which of those which
features are important for your model so
you take each feature and you like
randomly sample all the values in the
feature and you see how the predictions
are if it's very different it means that
that feature was actually important as
if it's fine to take any random values
for that feature it means that maybe
probably it's not very okay that was
terrific there's this that was all
exactly right there was some details
that maybe were skimmed over a little
bit I wonder if anybody else wants to
jump into like a more detailed
description of how it's calculated
because I know this morning some people
were not quite short
is there anybody who's like not quite
sure maybe he wants to like have a go or
yeah well it was put it next to there
let's see how exactly do we calculate
feature importance for a particular
feature check the validation school if
it gets pretty bad for after opening one
of the columns that means that column
was important so and as higher
importance I'm not exactly sure how we
quantify the feature importance okay
great
Dana do you know how we quantify the
feature importance that was a great
description or score or some sort
exactly yeah so let's say we've got our
dependent variable which is price right
and there's a bunch of independent
variables including year made right and
so we basically we use the whole lot to
build a random forest right and then
that gives us our predictions right and
so then we can let's call this Y right
and so then we can compare that to get I
don't know whatever R squared R MSC
whatever you're interested in right from
the model now the key thing here is I
don't want to have to retrain my whole
random forest
that's kind of slow and boring right so
using the existing random forests how
can I figure out how important year made
was right and so the suggestion was
let's randomly shuffle the whole column
right so now that column is totally
useless it's got the same mean same
distribution everything about it is the
same but there's no connection at all
between particular people actual year
made and what's now in that column I've
randomly shuffled it okay and so now I
put that new version through with the
same random forest so there's no
retraining done okay to get some new y
hat I call it Y hat way M right and then
I can compare that to my actuals to get
like an RSC ym right and so now I can
start to create a little table so now I
can create a little table where I
basically got like the original here our
MSC and then I've got with year made
scrambled so this one had an ARMA see of
like three this one had an ARMA see of
like two enclosure scrambling that had a
our MSC of like 2.5 right and so then I
just take these differences so I'd say
year made the importance is one 3-2
enclosure is 0.53 minus 2 and 1/2 and so
forth right so how much worse did my
model get after I shuffled that variable
anybody have any questions about that
can you pass that to Danielle please
um I assume you just chose those numbers
randomly but I question I guess is does
it stop do all them be ready I'm not a
perfect model to start out with like are
they welded all the important says seven
to one or is that not no they're just I
don't honestly I've never actually
looked at what the units are so I'm not
I'm actually not quite sure sorry we can
check it out during the week if
somebody's interested how the Vulcans
have a look at the this SK learn code
and see exactly what those units of
measure are cuz I've never bothered to
check although I don't check like the
units of measure specifically what I do
check is the relative importance and so
like here's an example so rather than
just saying like what are the top ten
yesterday one of the practicum students
asked me about a feature importance
where they said like oh I think these
three are important and I pointed out
that the top one was a thousand times
more important than the second one right
so like look at the relative numbers
here and so in that case it's like no
don't look at the top three look at the
one that's a thousand times more
important and ignore all the rest and so
this is where sometimes the kind of your
natural tendency to want to be like
precise and careful you need to override
that and be very practical it's like
okay this thing's a thousand times more
important don't spend any time on
anything else right so then you can go
and talk to the manager of your project
and say like okay this thing's a
thousand times more important and then
they might say oh that was a mistake it
shouldn't have been in there we don't
actually have that information at the
decision time or you know but for
whatever reason we can't actually use
that variable and so then you could
remove it and and have a look or they
might say gosh I had no idea that like
that was more by far more important than
everything else put together so let's
forget this random virus thing and just
focus on like understanding how we can
better collect that one variable and
better use that one variable so that's
like something which comes up quite a
lot and actually another
place that came up just yesterday again
another practicum student asked me hey
I'm doing this medical diagnostics
project and my r-squared is 0.95 for a
disease which I was told is very hard to
diagnose you know is this random
forrester genius or is something going
wrong and I said like remember the
second thing you do after you build a
random forest is to do feature
importance so do feature importance and
what you'll probably find is that the
top column is something that shouldn't
be there
and so that's what happened he came back
to me half an hour later he said yeah I
did the feature importance you were
right the top column was basically a
something that was another encoding of
the dependent variable I've removed it
and now my a squared is negative 0.1 so
that's an improvement okay the other
thing I like to look at is this chat
right is to basically say like you know
where the kind of things flatten off in
terms of like which ones should I be
really focusing on so that's the most
important one right and so when I did
credit scoring in telecommunications I
found there were nine variables that
basically predicted very accurately who
was it going to end up paying for their
phone and who wasn't and like apart from
ending up with a model that saved them
three billion dollars a year in in fraud
and credit costs it also let them
basically rejigger their their process
so they focused on collecting those nine
variables much better all right who
wants to do partial dependence
this is an interesting one very
important but you know somebody's kind
of tricky to think about yeah please do
not always necessarily like a
relationship between the strictly the
dependent variable in this independent
variable that necessarily like is
showing importance but rather than an
interaction between two variables that
are working together right yeah oh
that's weird
yeah and so for this example what we
found was that it's not necessarily your
maid or when the sale was elapsed but
it's actually the age of the model and
so it's that is easier to just like to
tell a liked company well obviously
you're younger models are gonna sell for
more and it's less about when the year
was made yeah so let's come back to how
we calculate this in a moment but the
first thing to realize is that the vast
majority of the time you know post your
course here when somebody shows you a
chart it'll be like a univariate chat
that'll just like grab the data from the
database and they'll plot X against Y
and then managers have a tendency to
want to like make a decision all right
so be like oh there's this like drop off
here so we should like stop dealing in
equipment made between 1990 and 1995 or
whatever right and this is like a big
problem because like real world data has
lots of these interactions going on so
like you know maybe there was a
recession going on around the time that
those things are being sold or maybe
around that time people were buying more
of a different type of equipment or
whatever right so generally what we
actually want to know is all other
things being equal what's the
relationship between ear made and sale
price right because like if you think
about the drivetrain approach idea of
like the levers you really want a model
that says if I change this lever how
will it change my objective okay and
it's by pulling them apart using partial
dependence that you can say okay
actually this is the relationship
between year made and sale price all
other things being equal right so how do
we calculate that for the variable you
made for example you're gonna train you
keep every other car variable constant
and then you're gonna pass every single
value of the year mate and then train
the model after that so for every model
you might have their light blue or the
values of it and the median is gonna be
the yellow line okay so let's try and
draw that
so bye leave everything else constant
what she means is leave them at whatever
they are in the data set so just like
when we did feature importance right
we're going to leave the rest of the
data set as it is and we're going to do
partial dependence plot for year made
all right so we've got all of these
other rows of data that we'll just leave
as they are and so instead of randomly
shuffling em8 instead what we're going
to do is replace every single value with
exactly the same thing 1960 okay and
just like before we now pass that
through our existing random forests
which we have not retrained or changed
in any way to get back out a set of
predictions why 1960 okay and so then we
can plot that on a chart
yeah I'd against partial dependence 1960
here
okay now we can do it for 1960 one two
three four five and so forth right and
so we can do that for four on average
for all of them or we could do it just
for one of them right and so when we do
it for just one of them and we change
its year may to pass that single thing
through our model that gives us one of
these blue lines
that's a each one of these blue lines is
a single row as we change its year made
from 1960 up to 2008
and so then we can just take the median
of all of those blue lines to say you
know on average what's the relationship
between year made and price all other
things being equal so why is it that why
is it that this works why is it that
this process tells us the relationship
between year made and price all other
things being equal well maybe it's good
to think about like a really simplified
approach a really simplified approach
would say what's the average auction
you know what's the average sale date
what's the most common type of machine
we sell which location do we mainly
mostly sell things and like we could
come up with a single row that
represents the the average option and
then we could say okay let's run that
row through the random forest but
replace its year made with 1960 and then
do it again with 1961 and then do it
again with 1962 and we could like plot
you know those on our little chart right
and that would give us a version of the
relationship between year made and sale
price all other things being equal right
but what if like tractors looked like
that and backhoe loaders looked like
that right then taking the average one
would hide the fact that there are these
totally different relationships right so
instead we basically say okay our data
tells us what kinds of things we tend to
sell and who we tend to sell them - and
when we tend to sell them so let's use
that right so then we actually find out
like for every blue line like here are
actual examples of these relationships
right and so then what we can do is as
well as flooding the median is we can do
a cluster analysis to find out like a
few different shapes right and so we may
find
in this case they all look like pretty
much the different versions of the same
thing with different slopes so my main
takeaway from this would be that the
relationship between sale price and year
is basically a straight line right and
remember this was log of sale price
right so this is actually showing us an
exponential and so this is where I would
then like bring in the domain expertise
which is like okay things depreciate
over time by a constant ratio so
therefore I would expect older stuff
year made to have this exponential shape
so this is where like I said of
mentioned like the very start of my
machine learning project I generally try
to avoid as using as much domain
expertise as I can and let the data do
the talking all right so like one of the
questions I got this morning was like if
there's like a sale I'd be a model ID I
should throw those away right because
they're just IDs no don't assume
anything about your data right leave
them in and if they turn out to be super
important predictors you want to find
out you know why is that okay but then
now I'm at the other end of my project
right I've done my feature importance
I've pulled out the stuff which is like
you know from that dendogram you know
the kind of redundant features I'm
looking at the partial dependence and
now I'm thinking like okay is this
shaped what I expected okay so even
better before you plot this first of all
think what shape would I expect this to
be because it's always easy to justify
to yourself after the fact oh I knew it
would look like this right so what
straight you expect and then is it that
shape so in this case I'd be like yeah
this is this is what I would expect okay
where else this is definitely not what
I'd expect so the partial dependence
plot has really pulled out the
underlying truth
okay does anybody have any questions
about like why we use partial dependence
or how we calculate it it's got the are
you better don't say you have a few
thousand say twenty features everything
are important are you gonna measure the
partial dependence for every single one
of them if there are twenty features
that are important then I will do the
partial dependence for all of them we're
important means like it's a lever I can
actually pull it's like the magnitude of
its size is like not much smaller than
the other nineteen like you know based
on all of these things it's like yeah
it's a feature I ought to care about
then I will want to know how it's
related it's pretty unusual to have that
many features that are important both
operationally and from a modeling point
of view in my experience so how do you
define internationally so important
means it's it's a lever so it's
something I can change
and it's like you know kind of at the
spiky end of this tail
or you know it maybe it's not a lever
directly like maybe it's like zip code
and I can't actually tell my customers
where to live but I could like focus my
new marketing attention on a different
zip code you know
would it make sense to do pairwise
shuffling for every combination of two
features and hold everything else
constant like in future importance to
see interactions and compare scores so
you wouldn't do that so much for partial
dependence I think your question is
really getting to the question of could
we do that for feature importance all
right so I think interaction feature
importance is a very important and
interesting question but doing doing it
by randomly shuffling every pair of
columns you know if you've got a hundred
columns sounds computationally intensive
possibly infeasible so what I'm going to
do is after we talk about tree
interpreter I'll talk about interesting
but largely unexplored approach that
will probably work okay who wants to do
tree interpreter all right over here
Prince
can you pass that over here to principal
I was thinking this to be more like
feature importance but teacher
importance is for complete random forest
model and this tree interpreter is for
feature importance for particular
observation so if that let's say it's
about hospital readmission so if a
patient a one is it is going to be
readmitted to a hospital
which featured for that particular
patient is going to impact and how can
we change that and it is calculated
starting from the prediction of mean
then seeing how each feature is changing
the behavior of that particular patient
I'm smiling because that was one of the
best examples of technical communication
I've heard in a long time so it's really
good to think about like what why was
that effective right so what Prince did
there was he used as specific an example
as possible right so if humans are much
less good at understanding abstractions
right so if you kind of say oh it takes
some kind of feature and then there's an
observation in that feature river you
know where's like know it's it's the
hospital readmission okay and so we take
a specific example the other thing he
did was very effective was to kind of
take an analogy to something we already
understand
so we already understand the idea of
feature importance across all of the
rows in a data set so now we're going to
do it for a single row okay so like you
know one of the things I was really
hoping we would learn from from this
experience is how to become effective
technical communicators
so you know that was a really great role
model from Prince of like using all the
tricks we have at our disposal for
effective technical communication so
hopefully you found that useful
explanation I don't have a hell of a lot
to add to that other than to show you
you know what that looks like so with
the tree interpreter we peaked out a row
okay and so remember when we talked
about the
the confidence intervals at the very
start the confidence based on tree
variance we mainly said like you
probably mainly use that for a Rome so
this would also be for our crow so it's
like okay why is this patient likely to
be readmitted okay so here is all of the
information we have about that patient
or in this case this option now why is
this auction so expensive so then we
call tree interpreter dot predict and we
get back the prediction of the price
right the bias which is the root of the
tree so this is just the average price
for everybody so this is always going to
be the same and then the contributions
which is how important is each of these
each of these things right and so the
way we calculated that
so the way we calculated that was to say
okay at the very start the average price
was ten right and then we split on
enclosure right and for those with
dissin closure
the average was nine point five
and then we split on year made
I don't know less than 1990 and for
those with that year made the average
price was nine point seven right and
then we split on the number of hours on
the meter and for you know with this
branch we got nine point four all right
and so we then have a particular option
which we we pass it through the tree and
it just so happens that it takes this
path all right so one row can only have
one path through the tree right and so
we ended up at this point okay so then
we can create a little table right and
so as we go through we start at the top
and we start with 10 right that's that
bias and we said enclosure resulted in a
change from 10 to 9 and 1/2 minus 0.5
yeah man changed it from nine point five
to nine point seven so plus 0.2 right
and then meter changed it from nine
point seven down to nine point four
which is minus 0.3 and then if we add
all that together can minus a half is
nine and a half plus 0.2 is nine point
seven minus point three is nine point
four low and behold that's that number
which takes us to our Excel spreadsheet
where's Chris who did our waterfall
there you are all right so last week we
had to use Excel for this because there
isn't a good Python library for doing
waterfall charts and so we saw we got
our starting point this is the bias and
then we had each of our contributions
and we ended up with our total the road
is now a better place
because Chris has created a Python
waterfall chart module for us and put it
on pip so never again where we have to
use Excel for this and I wanted to point
out that like waterfall charts have been
very important in business
communications at least as long as I've
been in business so that's about 25
years
Python is you know what couple of
decades old a little bit less yeah maybe
a couple of decades old but you know
despite that no one in the Python world
ever got to the point where they
actually thought you know I'm gonna make
a waterfall chart so they didn't exist
until two days ago which is to say like
the world is full of staff which ought
to exist in doesn't and doesn't
necessarily take a hell a lot of time to
build Chris how long did it take you to
build the first Python waterfall chart
well there was a you know a gist of it
yeah yeah yeah
about eight hours okay so you know a
hefty TYIN amount but not unreasonable
and now forevermore people when they
want the place and waterfall chart will
end up at Chris's github repo and
hopefully find lots of other USF
contributors who have made it even
better so for in order for you to help
improve Chris's plaything waterfall you
need to know how to do that right and so
you're going to need to submit a pull
request life becomes very easy for
submitting pull requests if you use
something called hub so if you go to
github slash hub
that will send you over here and what
they suggest you do is that you alias
get to hub because it turns out that hub
actually is earth strict superset if get
but what it lets you do is you can go
get fork get push get pull request and
you've now sent Chris a pull request
now without hub this is actually a pain
and requires like own to the website and
filling informants and stuff right so
this gives you no reason not to do pull
requests and I mention this because like
when you're interviewing for a job or
whatever I can promise you that the
person you're talking to will check your
github and if they see you have a
history of submitting thoughtful pull
requests that are accepted to
interesting libraries that looks great
right it looks great because it shows
you're somebody who actually contributes
it also shows that if they're being
accepted that you know how to create
code that fits with people's coding
standards has appropriate documentation
passes their tests and coverage and so
forth right so when people look at you
and they say oh here's somebody with a
history of successfully contributing
accepted pull requests to open-source
libraries that's a great part of your
portfolio okay and you can specifically
refer to it right so either I'm the
person who built Python waterfall here
is my repo or you know I'm the person
who contributed currency number
formatting to Python waterfall here's my
pull request you know that anytime you
see something that doesn't work right in
any open source software you use is not
a problem it's a great opportunity
because you can fix it and send in the
pull requests so yeah give it a go it
actually feels great the first time you
have a pull request accepted and of
course one big opportunity is the faster
a library and thank you who it was the
person here the person who added all the
docs to fast a I structured
in the other class okay so thanks to one
of our students we now have docstrings
for most of the FASTA i dot structured
library again came by a pull request so
thank you okay does anybody have any
questions about how to calculate any of
these random forest interpretation
methods or why we might want to use any
of these random first interpretation
methods towards the end of the week
you're going to need to be able to build
all of these yourself from scratch over
there can you pass that test that's
right just looking at the tree
interpreter I noticed that some of the
the values are in a ends how I got I get
my you keep them in the tree but how can
an NA and have a future importance okay
let me pass it back to you why not
so in other words how is ni n handled in
pandas and therefore in the tree such as
some default value
everybody remember how pandas these are
notices are all in categorical variables
how does pandas handle an NA ends in
categorical variables and how does fast
AI deal with them
can somebody pass it to the person who's
talking negative one through yeah
pandas sets into negative one category
code and do you have to remember what we
then do doesn't matter really we add one
to all of the category codes so it ends
up being zero so in other words we have
a category with remember by the time it
hits the random forest is just a number
and it's just it's just the number zero
right and we map it back to the
descriptions back here so the question
really is why shouldn't the random first
be able to split on zero it's just it's
just another number so it could be na n
high medium or low zero one two three
four and so you know missing values are
one of these things that are generally
taught really badly like often people
get taught like here are some ways to
remove columns with missing values or
remove rows with missing values or to
replace missing values that's like never
what we want because missingness is very
very very often interesting and so we
actually learnt that from our future
importance that cupola system n a n is
like one of the most important features
and so for some reason well I could I
could guess right coupla system n am
presumably means this is a kind of
industrial equipment that doesn't have a
coupler system now I don't know what
kind that is but apparently it's more
it's a more expensive kind that makes
sense yeah ok ok so I did this
competition for university grant
research success where by far the most
important predictors were whether or not
some of the fields were a null and it
turned out that this was data leakage
that these fields only got filled in
most of the time after a research grant
was accepted
right so you know it allowed me to win
that cowgirl competition but didn't
actually help the university very much
okay great
so let's talk about um extrapolation and
I am going to do something risky and
dangerous which is we're going to do
some live coding and the reason we're
going to do some live coding is I want
to explore extrapolation together with
you and I kind of also want to get kind
of help give you a feel of you know like
how you might go about like writing
writing code quickly in this notebook
environment right and this is the kind
of stuff that you're going to need to be
able to do you know in the real world
and in the exam is kind of quickly
create the kind of code that we're going
to talk about so I really like creating
synthetic datasets
anytime I'm trying to like investigate
the behavior of something because if I
have a synthetic data set I know how it
should behave
which reminds me before we do this I
promised that we would talk about
interaction importance and I just about
forgot trie interpreter tells us the
contributions for our particular row
based on the difference in the tree we
could calculate that for every road in
our data set and add them up right and
that would tell us that would tell us
feature importance and would tell us
feature importance in a different way
right one way of doing feature
importance is by shuffling the columns
one at a time
another way is by doing tree interpreter
for every row and adding them up
neither is right more right than the
others they're actually both quite
widely used so this is kind of type 1
and type 2 feature importance so we
could try to expand this a little bit
- do not just single variable feature
importance but interaction feature
importance
now here's the thing what I'm going to
describe is very easy to describe it was
described by Bremen right back when
random forests were first invented and
it is part of the commercial software
product from Salford systems who have
the trademark on random forests but it
is not part of any open-source library
I'm aware of and I've never seen an
academic paper that actually studies it
closely so what I'm going to describe
here is a huge opportunity but it's also
like there's lots and lots of details
that kind of need to be fleshed out but
here's the basic idea this particular
this particular difference here right is
not just because of year made but
because of a combination of year made
and enclosure
right the fact that this is 9.7 is
because enclosure was in this branch and
year made was in this branch so in other
words we could say the contribution of
enclosure interacted with year made is
minus 0.3 yeah and so what about that
difference well that's an interaction of
year made and hours on the meter
so you made interacted with am using
star here not to mean times but to mean
interacted with it's a it's a kind of a
common way of doing things like ours
formulas do it this way as well here
made by interacted with meter has a
import has a importance sorry a
contribution of minus 0.1
perhaps we could also say from here to
here that this also shows an interaction
between meter and enclosure like with
one thing in between them so maybe we
could say meter by enclosure equals and
then what should it be
you know should it be 0.6 I sorry minus
0.6 I mean some ways that kinda seems
unfair because we're also including like
the impact of a vm aid right so maybe it
should be maybe it should be minus 0.6
you know maybe we should add back this
point to right and these are like
details that I actually don't know the
answer to right like how should we best
kind of assign a contribution to each
pair of variables in this path right but
but clearly conceptually we can write
the pairs of variables in that path all
represent interactions all right yes
Chris can you could you pass that to
Christmas why don't you first have to be
next to each other in the tree I I mean
I'm not gonna say it's the wrong
approach
I I don't think it's the right approach
though because it feels like this path
here
Mayda and enclosure are interacting so
it seems like not recognizing that
contribution is throwing away
information but I'm not sure you know I
had one of my staff at cattle actually
do some R&amp;D on this a few years ago and
actually found you know and I wasn't
close enough to know how they dealt with
these details but they got it working
pretty well but unfortunately it never
saw the light of day is a software
product but like this is something which
you know maybe a group of you could get
together and build you know I mean do
some googling to check but I really
don't think that there are any
interaction feature importance
parts of any open source library can you
cross the flip
wouldn't this exclude interactions
though between variables that don't
matter
until they interact so say your road
never chooses to split down that path
but that variable interacting with
another one becomes your most important
split I don't think that happens right
because if this if there's an
interaction that's important only
because it's an interaction and not in a
univariate basis it will appear
sometimes they cut assuming that you set
max features to less than one and so
therefore it will appear in in some file
what is meant by indirection or is it
multiplication ratio addition
interaction means appears branches
appears on the same path through a tree
like an interaction in this case the
tree there's an interaction between
enclosure and ear made because we
branched on enclosure and then we branch
on your mode so to get to here we have
to have some specific value of enclosure
and some specific value of you made
sorry I just membranes kind of working
on this right now what if what if you
went down the middle Leafs between the
two things you're trying to observe and
you could just sort of norm and you
would also take into account what the
final measure is so I mean if we extend
the tree downwards you'd have many
measures both of like the two things
you're trying to look at and also the in
between steps there seems to be a way to
like average information out in between
them there could be so I think what we
should do is talk about this on the
forum I think this is fascinating and I
hope we build something great but I need
to do my live coding so let's yeah
that's a great discussion
thinking about it and news of
experiments and so to experiment with
that you almost certainly want to create
a synthetic data set first right
it's like y equals X 1 plus X 2 plus X 1
times X 2 or something you know like
something where you know there's this
interaction effect and there isn't that
interaction effect and then you want to
make sure that the feature importance
you get at the end is what you expected
right and so probably the first step
would be to do single variable feature
importance using the tree interpreter
style approach and one nice thing about
this is like it's
it doesn't really matter how much data
you have like all you have to do to
calculate feature importance is just
like slide through the tree right so you
should be able to write in a way that's
actually pretty fast and so even writing
it in pure Python might be fast enough
depending on your tree size okay so
we're going to talk about extrapolation
and so the first thing I want to do is
create a synthetic data set that has a
simple linear relationship we're going
to pretend it's like a time series right
so we need to basically create some X
values so the easiest way to kind of
create some synthetic data of this type
is to use linspace which just creates
some evenly spaced some evenly spaced
data right between start and stop with
by default 50 observations so if we just
do that right there it is okay
and so then we're going to create a
dependent variable and so let's assume
there's just a linear relationship
between x and y and let's add a little
bit of randomness to it right so uniform
random between low and high so we could
like add somewhere between like minus
0.2 and 0.2 say okay and so the next
thing we need is is a shape right which
is basically how what dimensions do you
want this this randomness these random
numbers to be and obviously we want them
to be the same shape as X's shape so we
can just say X dot shape
okay so in other words that's
xscape remember when you see something
in parentheses with a comma that's at
Apple with just one thing in it okay so
this is of shape 15 and so we've added
50 random numbers and so now we could
plot those okay so shift-tab x comma y
all right so there's no data okay so
like when you were both working as a
data scientist or for doing your exams
in this course you need to be able to
like quickly whip up a data set like
that throw it up in our plot without
thinking too much okay and like as you
can see you don't have to really
remember much if anything you just have
to know how to like hit shift I have to
check the names of parameters and you
know everything in the exam will be open
up and broke up and internet so you can
always like google her something to try
and find linspace if you forgot what
it's called all right so let's assume
that's out data all right and so we're
now going to build a random first model
and what I want to do is build a random
first model that kind of acts as if this
is a time series so I'm going to take
this as a training set right I'm going
to take of this as our validation or
test set just like we did in you know
groceries or bulldozers or whatever okay
so we can use exactly the same kind of
code that we used in split bells right
so we can basically say X train comma X
tau equals x up to 40 comma X
from 40 okay so that just fits it into
the first audio since the last 10 right
and so we can do the same thing for Y
and there we go okay so the next thing
to do is we want to create a random
forest okay and fit it and that's going
to require X's and Y's all right now
that's actually going to give an error
and the reason why is that it expects X
to be a matrix not a vector because it
expects X to have a number of columns of
data right so it's important to know
that a matrix with one column is not the
same thing as a vector all right so if I
try to run this right expect a 2d array
got 1d array instead so we need to
convert our 2d array into a 1d array so
remember I said X dot shape is 50 comma
right so X has one axis so here's
important to measure X is rank is 1 the
rank of a variable is equal to the
length of its shape
how many axes does it have so a vector
we can think of as an array of Rank 1
matrix as an array of Rank 2 I very
rarely used words like vector and matrix
because like they're kind of meaningless
specific examples of something more
general which is they're all n
dimensional tensors right or n
dimensional arrays ok so an n
dimensional array we can say it's a
tensor of Rank
they basically mean kind of the same
thing physicists get crazy when you say
that because to a physicist a tensor has
quite a specific meaning but in machine
learning we generally use it in the same
way okay so how do we turn an array a
one-dimensional array into a
two-dimensional array there's a couple
of ways we can do it but basically we
slice it right so colon means give me
everything in that axis right colon
comma none means give me everything in
the first axis which is the only axis we
have and then none is a special indexer
which means add a unit axis here so let
me show you that is a sort of shape 50
comma one
so it's a prank - it has two axes one of
them is a very boring access right
it's a length one access so let's move
this over here there's 1 comma 50 ok and
then to remind you the original is just
50 right so you can see I can put none
as a special indexer to introduce a new
unit axis there ok so this thing has one
row in 50 columns this thing has 50 rows
of one column so that's what we want
right we want 50 rows and one column
this kind of playing around with ranks
and dimensions is going to become
increasingly important in this course
and in the deep learning course right so
I spend a lot of time slicing with non
slicing with other things try to create
three dimensional four dimensional
chances and so forth I'll show you a
trick I'll show you two tricks the first
is you never ever need to write karma :
it's always assumed so if I delete that
this is exactly the same thing okay and
you'll see that in code all the time so
you need to recognize it the second
trick is this is adding an axis in the
second dimension right or I guess the
index one dimension what if I always
want to put it in the last dimension
right and like often our tensors change
dimensions without us looking because
like you went from a one channel image
to a three channel image or you went
from a single image to a mini batch of
images like suddenly you get new
dimensions appearing so to make things
general I would say this dot dot dot dot
dot dot means as many dimensions as you
need to fill this up okay and so in this
case it's exactly the same thing but I
would always try to write it that way
because it means it's going to continue
to work as I get you know higher
dimensional tenses alright so in this
case I want 50 rows in one column so
I'll call that say X
okay so let's now use that here and so
this is now a 2d array and so I can
create my
random forest okay so then I could plot
that and this is where you're going to
have to turn your brains on because the
folks this morning got this very quickly
which was super impressive I'm going to
plot white rain against MDOT predict
next rain okay before I hit go what is
this going to look like yeah it should
basically be the same right a
predictions hopefully are the same as
the actuals so this should fall on a
line but there's some randomness so it
won't quite I should have used scatter
plot okay all right so that's cool right
that was the easy one let's now do the
hard one the fun one what's that going
to look like
you
okay so I'm gonna say no but nice try
you know it's like hey we're
extrapolating to the to the validation
that's what I'd like it to look like but
that's not what it is going to look like
think about what trees do and think
about think about the fact that we have
a validation set here and a training set
here so think about a forest is just a
bunch of trees well the first tree is
going to okay Melissa is going to have a
go can you pass that to Melissa well
let's start grouping yeah that's what I
mean that's what it does okay but you
know let's think about how it groups the
dots so yeah I'm guessing since all the
new data is actually outside of the
original scope it's all going to be
basically the same it's like one huge
group yeah right so like we make it like
forget the forest let's create one tree
right so we're probably going to split
somewhere around here first and then
we're kind of probably split somewhere
around here and then we're going to
split somewhere around here and
somewhere around here right and so our
final split is here right so our
prediction when we say okay let's take
this one and so it's going to put that
through the forest right and end up
predicting this average it can't predict
you anything higher than that because
there is nothing higher than that to
average right so this is really
important to realize if a random forest
is not magic right
it's just returning the average of
nearby observations where nearby is kind
of in this like tree space so let's run
it let's see if Tim's right but holy
that's awful right and like if you
don't know how when firsts works and
this is going to totally screw right if
you think that it's actually going to be
able to extrapolate to any kind of data
it hasn't seen before like particularly
like future time periods it's just not
like it just can't
it's just averaging stuff it's already
seen that's all it can do
okay so we're going to be talking about
like how to avoid this problem we talked
a little bit in the last lesson about
trying to avoid it by just like in
avoiding unnecessary time dependent
variables where we can write but in the
end if you really have a time series
that looks like this
we actually have to deal with a problem
all right so one way we could deal with
the problem would be used like a neural
net right use something that actually
has a function or shape that can
actually like fit something that can she
fit something like this right and so
then it will extrapolate nicely another
approach would be to use all the time
series techniques you guys are learning
about in the morning class to fit some
kind of time series right and then D
trend it right and so then you'll end up
with D trended dots and then use the
random chorus to predict those right and
that's particularly cool right because
if you're like imagine that your random
forest was actually trying to predict
data that like I don't know maybe it was
two different states and so the blue
ones you know that down here and the red
ones are up here right now if you try to
use a random forest it's going to do a
pretty crappy job because like time is
going to see much more important so it's
basically still gonna like split like
this and it's going to split like this
and then finally once it kind of gets
down to this piece it'll be like oh okay
now I can see the difference between the
states right so in other words like when
you've got this big timepiece going on
you're not gonna see the other
relationships in the random forest until
you've dealt and kill every tree deals
with time so one way to fix this would
be with a gradient boosting machine GBM
right now what a GBM does is it creates
a little tree right and runs everything
through that first little tree which
could be like the time tree and then it
calculates the residuals and then the
next little tree just predicts the
residuals so it'd be kind of like D
trending it right so GPM has handle this
GBM still can't extrapolate to the
future but at least they can deal with
time-dependent data more conveniently
right so we're going to be talking about
this quite a lot more over the next
couple of weeks right and in the end
that a solution is going to be just used
neural nets right but
for now you know using it some kind of
time series analysis D trend it and then
use a random forest on that isn't a bad
technique at all and if you're playing
around something like the Ecuador
groceries competition that would be a
really good thing to to fiddle around
with alright see you next time