Oh
good okay so let me introduce everybody
to everybody else first of all so we're
here at the university of san francisco
learning machine learning or you might
be at home watching this on video
so hey everybody wave here is the
University of San Francisco graduate
students thank you everybody
and wave back from the future and from
home to all the students here if if
you're watching this on youtube please
stop and instead go to course a I and
watch it from there instead that there's
nothing wrong with YouTube but I can't
edit these videos after I've created
them so I need to be able to like if you
updated information about like what
environments to use how the technology
changes and so you need to go here
right so you can also watch the lessons
from here
here's lots of lessons and so forth
right so that's tip number one for the
video tip number two for the video is
because I can't edit them all I can do
is add these things called cards and
cards or little things that appear in
the top corner of the top right hand
corner of the screen so by the time this
video comes out I'm going to put a
little card there right now for you to
click on and try that out unfortunately
they're not easy to notice so keep an
eye out for that because that's going to
be important updates to the video all
right so welcome we're going to be
learning about machine learning today
then so after everybody in the class
here you all have Amazon Web Services
setup so you might want to go ahead and
launch your AWS instance now or go ahead
and create one short Jupiter notebook on
your own computer if you don't have
Jupiter notebook setup then what I
recommend is you go to cresol calm wws
or calm sign in there sign up
[Music]
and you can then turn off enable GPU and
click start Jupiter and you'll have a
Jupiter notebook instantly that costs
you some money it's three cents an hour
okay so if you don't mind spending three
cents an hour to learn machine learning
here's a good way so I'm going to go
ahead and say start Jupiter and so
whatever technique you use there you go
one of the things that you'll find on
the website is links to lots of
information about the costs and benefits
and approaches to setting up lots of
different environments for Jupiter
notebook both the deep learning and for
regular machine learning so check them
out because there's lots of options so
if I then go open a Jupiter and Jupiter
in a new tab Here I am in Kressel or on
AWS or your own computer we use the
Anaconda Python distribution for
basically everything you can install
that yourself and again there's lots of
information on the website about how to
set that up we're also assuming that
either you're using Kressel or there's
something else which I really like
called paper space comm which is another
place you can fire up if you put a
notebook pretty much instantly both of
these have already have all of the fast
AI stuff pre-installed for you so as
soon as you open up cresol or paper
space assuming you chose the paper space
fast AI template you'll see that there's
a fast AI folder okay if you are using
your own computer or AWS you'll need to
go to our github repo fast AI fast AI
and clone it okay and then you'll need
to do a condor and update to install the
libraries and again that's all
information we put on the website and
we've got some previous workshop videos
to help you through all of those deaths
so for this class I'm assuming that you
have a Jupiter notebook running okay
so here we are in the in the Jupiter
notebook
and if I click on fast AI that's what
you get if you get clone or if you're in
Chris all you can see our repo here all
of our lessons are inside the courses
folder and the machine learning part one
is in the ml one folder if you're ever
looking at my screen and wondering where
are you look up here and you'll see that
tells you the path fast AI forces ml 1
and today we're going to be looking at
less than one random forests so here is
lesson 1 RF
you
so there's a couple of different ways
you can do this both here in person or
on the video you can either attempt to
follow along as you watch or you can
just watch and then follow along later
with the video it's up to you I would
maybe have a loose recommendation to say
to watch now and follow along with the
video later just because it's quite hard
to motor tasks and if you're working on
something you might miss a key piece of
information which you're welcome to ask
about okay but if you follow along with
the video afterwards then you can pause
stop experiment and so forth but anyway
you can choose either way I'm going to
go of you
Topol header view toggle tool bar and
then full screen it so to get a bit more
space so the basic approach we're going
to be teaching here taking here is to
get straight into code start building
models not to look at theory we've got
to get to other theory okay but at the
point where you deeply understand what
it's for and at the point that you're
able to be an effective practitioner so
my hope is that you're going to spend
your time focusing on experimenting so
if you take these notebooks and try
different variations of what I show you
try it with your own data sets the more
coding you can do the better the more
you'll learn ok don't in you know my
suggestion or at least and all of my
students have told me the ones who have
gone away and spent time studying books
of theory rather than coding found that
they learnt less machine learning and
that they often tell me they wish that's
one more time coding the stuff that
we're showing in this course a lot of
it's never been shown before this is not
a summary of other people's research
this is more a summary of 25 years of
work that I've been doing in machine
learning
so a lot of this is going to be shown
for the first time and so that's kind of
cool because if you want to write a blog
post about something that you learn here
you might be building something but a
lot of people find super useful all
right so there's a great opportunity to
practice your technical writing and
here's some examples of good technical
writing
okay page by showing people stuff which
you've it's not like hey I just learnt
this thing I bet you all know it often
it'll be I just want this thing and I'm
going to tell you about it and other
people haven't seen it in fact this is
the first course ever that's been built
on top of the first AI library so even
just stuff in the library is going to be
new to like everybody okay so when we
use a droopin a notebook or anything
else in python we have to import the the
libraries that we're going to use
something that's quite convenient as if
you use these to auto reload commands at
the top of your notebook you can go in
and edit the source code of the modules
and your notebook will automatically
update with those new modules you won't
have to like restart anything so that's
super handy then to show your plots
inside the notebook you're wanting that
plot in line so these three lines appear
at the top of all of my notebooks you'll
notice when I import the libraries that
for anybody here who is a experienced
Python programmer I am doing something
that would be widely considered very
inappropriate I'm importing star okay
generally speaking in software
engineering we're taught to like it
specifically figure out what we need and
import those things
the more experienced you are as Python
programmer the more extremely offensive
practices you're going to see me use for
example I don't follow what's called pap
8 which is the normal style method style
of code used in Python so I'm going to
mention a couple of things first is go
along with it for a while don't judge me
just yet
right there's reasons that I do these
things and if it really bothers you then
feel free to to change it right but the
basic idea is data science is not
software engineering right there's a lot
of overlap you know we're using the same
languages and in the end these things or
may become software engineering projects
but what we're doing right now is we're
prototyping models and prototyping
models has a very different set of best
practices that are taught basically
nowhere right they're not really even
really written down but the key is to be
able to do things very interactively and
very iteratively right so for example
from library import star means you don't
have to figure out ahead of time what
you're going to need from that library
it's it's all there okay also because
we're in this wonderful interactive
Jupiter environment it lets us
understand what's in the libraries
really well so for example later on I'm
using a function called display right so
an obvious question is like well what is
display so you can just type the name of
a function and press shift enter member
shift enter is is to run a cell and it
will tell you where it's from right so
anytime you see a function you are not
familiar with you can find out where
it's wrong and then if you want to find
out what it does put a question mark at
the start okay and here you have the
documentation and then particularly
helpful for the faster I library so the
faster I library I try to make as many
functions as possible be like no more
than about five lines of code it's just
going to be really easy to read right if
you put a second question mark at the
star
it shows you the source code of the
function right so all the documentation
plus the source code so you can see like
nothing has to be mysterious and we're
going to be using the other library
we'll use a lot is scikit-learn which is
kind of implements a lot of machine
learning stuff in Python the
scikit-learn source code is often pretty
readable and so very often if I want to
really understand something
I'll just go question mark question mark
and the name of the scikit-learn
function I'm typing and I'll just go
ahead and read the source code as I say
the first day I library in particular is
designed to have source code that's very
easy to read and we're going to be
reading it a lot okay all right so today
we're going to be working on a cattle
competition called Blue Book for
bulldozers so the first thing we need is
to get that data so if you go Cargill
bulldozers
then you can find it so cackle
competitions allow you to download a
real-world data set that's somebody a
real problem that somebody's trying to
solve and solve it according to a
specification that that actual person
with that actual problem decided would
be actually helpful to them right so
these are pretty authentic experiences
for applied machine learning now of
course you're missing all the bit that
went before which was why did this
company to start up the side that
predicting the option sale price of
bulldozers was important where did they
get the data from how did they clean the
data and so forth okay and that's all
important stuff as well but the focus of
this course is really on what happens
next which is like how do you actually
build the model one of the great things
about you working on Cargill
competitions whether they be running now
or whether they be old ones is that you
can submit yours to the leaderboard even
old closed competitions you can submit
to the leaderboard and find out how
would you have gone right and there's
really no other way in the world of
knowing whether you're competent at this
kind of data in this kind of model than
doing that right because otherwise if
your accuracy is really bad is it
because this is just very hard like it's
just not possible then the data is so
noisy you can't do better or is it
actually that it's an easy data set and
you've made a mistake and like when you
finish this course and apply this to
your own projects this is going to be
something you're going to find very hard
and there isn't a simple solution to it
which is you're now using something that
hasn't been on cog or your own data set
do you have a good enough answer or not
okay
so we'll talk about that more during the
course and in the end we just have to
know that we have good effective
techniques to reliably building baseline
models otherwise yeah there's really no
way to know there's no way other than
creating a cackle competition
or getting you know a hundred top data
scientists to work at your problem to
really know what's possible
SoCal competitions are fantastic for for
learning and as I've said many times
I've learned more from kept from
competing in cackled competitions and
everything else I've done in my life
so to compete in the caracal competition
you need the data this one's a an old
competition so it's not running now but
we can still access everything so we
first of all want to understand what the
goal is and I suggest that you read this
later but basically we're to try and
predict the sale price of heavy
equipment and one of the nice things
about this competition is that if you
are like me you probably don't know very
much about heavy heavy industrial
equipment options right
I actually know more than I used to
because my toddler loves building
equipment so we actually like watched
youtube videos about front end loaders
and forklifts but you know two months
ago I was you know a real layman so one
of the nice things is that machine
learning should help us understand a
data set not just make predictions about
it
so by picking an area which we're not
familiar with it's a good test of
whether we can build an understanding
right because otherwise what can happen
is that your intuition about the data
can make it very difficult for you to be
open-minded enough to see what does the
data really say it's easy enough to
download the computer sorry to download
the data to your computer you just have
to click on the data set so here is
train zip and click download right and
so you can go ahead and do that if
you're running on your own computer
right now if you're running on AWS it's
a little bit harder right because unless
you're familiar with textmode browsers
like a links or links it's quite tricky
to get the data set to cable so a couple
of options one is you could download it
to your computer and then SCP it to AWS
so SCP works just like SSH but it copies
data rather
logging in I'll show you a trick though
that I really like and it relies on
using Firefox for some reason chrome
doesn't work correctly with cable for
this so if I go on Firefox to the
website
eventually
you
and what we're going to do is we're
going to use something called the
JavaScript console so every web browser
comes with a set of tools for web
developers to help them see what's going
on and you can hit 0 3 here
developer control-shift a okay so you
can hit ctrl shift I to bring up this
this web developer tools and one of the
tabs is network okay and so then if I
click on train zip and I click on
download
okay and I'm not even going to download
on let's gonna say cancel but you'll see
down here it's shown me all of the
network connections that were just
initiated right and so here's one which
is downloading a zip file from storage
Google API is calm blah blah blah that's
probably what I want now that looks good
so what you can do is you can
right-click on that and say copy
copy as curl so curl is a UNIX command
like W get that downloads stuff right so
if I go copy as curl that's going to
create a command that has all of my
cookies headers everything in it
necessary to download this authenticated
data set so if I now go into my server
right and if I paste that you can see a
really really long curl command one
thing I notice is that at least recent
versions have started adding this - -
2.0 thing to the command that doesn't
seem to work with all versions of curl
so something you might want to do is to
oopsy-daisy a PE is to pop that into an
editor find that to get rid of it and
then use that instead okay now one thing
to be very careful about by default curl
downloads the file and displays it in
your terminal so if I try to display
this it's going to display gigabytes of
binary data in my terminal and crash it
okay so to say that I want to output it
using some different file name I always
type - o
for output file name and then the name
of the file bulldozers dot and make sure
you give it a suitable a suitable
extension so in this case the file was
train's it okay so bulldozers dot zip
there it is okay and so there it all is
so I could make directory bulldozers
and I couldn't move my zip file into
there oops wrong way around
[Music]
yes thank you
ah
you
okay and then you if you don't have
unzip install you may need to sudo apt
install unzip or if then you're on a Mac
that would be brew install unzip if brew
doesn't work you haven't got homebrew
installed so make sure you install it
and then unzip okay and so there the
basic steps one nice thing is that if
you're using Kressel most of the data
sets should already be pre-installed for
you so what I can do here is I can say
open a new tab here's a cool trick in
Jupiter you can actually say new
terminal and you can actually get a
web-based terminal and so you'll find
one cresol there's a slash data sets
folder slash data sets flash Cagle slash
data set slash birthday I often the
things you need are going to be in one
of those places okay so assuming that we
don't have it already downloaded in
paper actually paper space should have
most of them as well then we would need
to go to far say I let's go into the
courses machine learning folder and what
I tend to do is I tend to put all of my
data for a course into a folder called
data you'll find that if you try and if
you're using what we using get right
you'll find that that doesn't get added
to get because it's in the get ignore
right so so don't worry about creating
the data folder it's not going to screw
anything up so I generally make a folder
called data and then I tend to create
folders for everything I need there so
in this case I'll make bulldozes CD and
remember the last word of the last
command is exclamation mark dollar
[Music]
I'll go ahead and grab that kill command
again
[Music]
you
okay and zip bulldozers there we go okay
so you can now see I generally have like
anything that would change that might
change from person to person I kind of
put in a constant so here I just defined
something called path but if you've used
the same path I just did just got to go
ahead and run that and let's go ahead
and keep moving along so we've now got
all of our libraries imported and we've
said the path to the data you can run
shell commands from within
Tripta notebook by using an exclamation
mark so if I want to check what's inside
that path I can go LS data slash
bulldozers okay and you can see that
works or you can even use Python
variables if you use a Python variable
inside a Jupiter show command you have
to put it in Curly's okay so that makes
me feel good that my path is pointing at
the right place if you say LS curly
capital's path and you get nothing at
all then you're pointing at the wrong
spot yes this up here usually yeah so
the curly brackets refer to the fact
that I put an exclamation mark at the
front which means the rest of this is
not a Python command
it's a bashed command and bash doesn't
know about capital path because capital
Park is part of them - so this is a
special Jupiter thing which says expand
this Python thing please before you pass
it to the show
question thank you so the goal here is
to use the training set which contains
data through the end of 2011 to predict
the sale price of bulldozers and so the
main thing to start with then is of
course to look at the data now the data
is in CSV format right so one easy way
to look at the data would be to use
shell command head to look at the first
two lines paired bulldozers and even
tab-completion works here Jupiter does
everything right so here's the first few
five lines okay so there's like a bunch
of column headers and then there's a
bunch of data so that's pretty hard to
look at so what we want to do is take
this and read it into a nice tabular
format okay so just Terrance putting
classes on mean I should make this
bigger or is it okay is this big enough
font size okay so this kind of data
where you've got columns representing a
wide range of different types of things
such as an identifier of value a
currency a date a size I refer to this
as structured data now I say I refer to
this as structured data because like
there have been many arguments in the
machine learning community on Twitter
about what is structured data weirdly
enough this is like the most important
type of distinction is between data that
looks like this and data like images
where every column is of the same type
like that's the most important
distinction in machine learning yet we
don't have standard accepted terms so
I'm going to use the term structured and
unstructured but note that other people
you talk to
particularly in NLP and NLP people use
structured to mean something totally
different right so when I refer to
structured data
I mean columns of data that can have
varying different types of data in them
by far the most important tool
in Python if you're working with
structure data is pandas pandas is so
important that it's one of the few
libraries that everybody uses the same
abbreviation for it which is PD so
you'll find that one of the things I've
got here is from fast AI imports import
star okay
the faster I imports module has nothing
but imports of a bunch of hopefully
useful tools so all of the code for
first AI is inside the fast a I
directory inside the first AI repo and
so you can have a look at imports and
you'll see it's just literally a list of
inputs and you're fine there pandas as
PD and so everybody does this right so
you'll see lots of people using PD dot
something they're always talking about
pandas so pandas lets us read a CSV file
and so when we read the CSV file we just
tell it the path to the CSV file a list
of any columns that contain dates and I
always add this low-memory equals false
that's going to actually make it read
more of the file to decide what the
types are this here is something called
a Python 3.6 format string it's one of
the coolest parts of python 3.6
you've probably used lots of different
ways in the past in Python of
interpolating variables into your
strings python 3.6 has a very simple way
that you'll probably always want to use
from now on and it's you to create a
normal string you type an F for the
start and then if I define a variable
then I can say hello
Curly's - function okay this is kind of
confusing these are not the same Curly's
that we saw earlier on in that LS
command right that LS command is
specific to Jupiter and interpolates -
code into shell code these Curly's are
Python 3.6 format string Curly's they
require an F at the start so if I get
rid of the F it doesn't interpolate okay
so the F tells it to interpolate and the
cool thing is inside that Curly's you
can write any Python code you'd like
just about so for example name dot Papa
hello Jeremy okay so I use this all the
time and it doesn't matter because it's
a format string it doesn't matter if the
thing was I always forget my age I think
I'm 43 it doesn't matter if it's an
integer right normally if you like to do
string concatenation with integers place
and complains no such problem here okay
so so this is going to read path slash
train dot CSV into a thing called a data
frame pandas data frames and hours data
frames are kind of pretty similar so if
you've used R before then you'll find
that this is a you know reasonably
comfortable so this file is nine point
three Meg and it's size is sorry 112 Meg
112 Nick and it has 400,000 rows in it
okay so it takes a moment to import it
but what it's done we can type the name
of the data frame DF raw and then use
various methods on it so for example
deer fur or tail will show us the last
few rows of the data frame by default
it's going to show the columns along the
top and the rows down the side but in
this case there's a lot of columns so
I've just said dot transpose to show it
the other way around
I've created one extra function here
display all normally if you just type DF
R or if it's too big to show
conveniently it truncates it and put
little ipsus in the middle so the
details don't matter but this is just
changing your couple of settings to say
even if it's got a thousand rows in a
thousand columns please still show the
whole thing okay so this is finished I
can actually show you that so if I just
type this is really cool in in Jupiter
notebook you can type a variable with
almost any kind a video HTML an image
whatever and it'll generally figure out
a way of displaying it for you okay so
in this case it's a panda's data frame
it picks it out a way of just playing it
for me and so you can see here that by
default it's actually doesn't show me
the whole thing so so here's the data
set we've got a few different rows this
is the last bit the tail of it alright
last few rows this is the thing we want
to predict price okay and then all of
the other we call this the dependent
variable the dependent variable is the
price and then we got a whole bunch of
things we could predict it with and when
I start with a data set I tend yes
Terrance how can I give you this
hello Jeremy hi Tara I've read in books
that you should never look at the data
because of the risk of overfit why do
you start by looking at the data yeah so
I think she's gonna mention I actually
kind of don't like I I want to find out
at least enough to know that I've like
managed to imported okay but I tend not
to really study it at all at this point
because I don't want to make too many
assumptions about it I would actually
say most books say the opposite most
books do a whole lot of expediate
exploratory data analysis first
yeah academic books say that that's one
of the biggest risks of everything but
the practical books say let's do some
EDA first yeah so that the truth is kind
of somewhere in between and I generally
I generally try to do machine learning
driven EDA
and that's what we're going to learn
today okay so the do thing I do care
about though is what's the purpose of
the project and for capital projects the
purpose is very easy we can just look
and find out there's always an
evaluation section how is it evaluated
and this is evaluated on root mean
squared log error so this means they're
going to look at the difference between
the log of our prediction of price and
the log of the actual price and then
they're going to square it and addemup
okay
so because they're going to be focusing
on the difference of the logs that means
that we should focus on the logs as well
and this is pretty common like for a
price generally you care not so much
about did I miss by ten dollars but did
I miss by ten percent right so if it was
a million dollar thing and you're a
hundred thousand dollars off or if
you're it's a ten thousand dollar thing
and you're a thousand dollars off often
we would consider those equivalent scale
issues and so for this oxygen problem
the organizers are telling us they care
about ratios more than differences and
so the log is the thing we care about so
the first thing I do is to take the log
okay now NP
is numpy I'm assuming that you have some
familiarity with numpy if you don't
we've got a video called deep learning
workshop which actually isn't just for
deep learning it's Rahal it's basically
for this as well and one of the parts
there which we've got a time coded link
to there's a quick introduction to numb
pay but basically numpy lets us treat
arrays matrices vectors high dimensional
chances as if they're Python variables
and we can do stuff like log to them and
it'll apply it to everything numpy and
pandas work together very nicely so in
this case DF fraud sale price is pulling
a column out of a panda's data frame
which gives us a pandas series right
shows us the sale prices and their
indexes right and a series can be passed
to a number I function okay which is
pretty handy and so you can see here
this is how I can replace a column with
a new column pretty easy so okay now
that we've replaced its sale price with
its log we can go ahead and try to
create a random forest
what's a random forest we'll find out in
detail but in brief a random forest is a
kind of universal machine learning
technique it's a way of predicting
something that can be of any kind it
could be a category like is it a dog or
a cat or it could be a continuous
function you aspera like price it can
predict it with columns of pretty much
any kind pixel data zip codes revenues
whatever in general it doesn't overfit
it can and will learn to check whether
it is but it doesn't generally overfit
too badly and it's very very easy to
make to stop it from overfitting you
don't need and we'll talk more about
this you don't need a separate
validation set in general it can tell
you how well it
generalizes even if you only have one
data set it has few if any statistical
assumptions it doesn't assume that your
data is normally distributed it doesn't
assume that the relationship so linear
it doesn't assume that you've just
specified the interactions it requires
very few pieces of feature engineering
for many different types of situation
you don't have to take the log of the
data you don't have to multiply
interactions together so in other words
it's a great place to start right if
your first random forest does very
little useful then that's a sign that
there might be problems with your data
like it's designed to work pretty much
first off can you please throw it out or
towards this gentleman thank you what
about the national year and of course
yeah great question so there's this
concept of curse of dimensionality in
fact there's two concepts I'll touch on
curse of dimensionality and the low free
lunch theorem these are two concepts you
often hear a lot about
they're both largely meaningless and
basically stupid and yet I would say
maybe the majority of people in the
field not only don't know that but think
the opposite so it's well worth
explaining the curse of dimensionality
is this idea that the more columns you
have it basically creates a space that's
more and more empty and this is kind of
fascinating mathematical idea which is
the more dimensions you have the more
all of the points sit on the edge of
that space alright so if you've just got
a single dimension where things are like
random then they're spread out all over
right where else if it's a square then
the probability that they're in the
middle means that they've kind of been
on the edge of either dimension so it's
a little bit less likely that they're
not on the edge edge dimension you add
it becomes more addictive ly less likely
that the point isn't on the edge of at
least one dimension right and so
basically in high dimensions everything
sits on the edge and what that means in
theory is that the distance between
points is much less meaningful and so if
we assume that somehow that matters that
it would suggest that when you've got
lots of columns and you just use them
without being very careful to remove the
ones you don't care about that somehow
things won't work that turns out just
not to be the case it's not the case for
a number of reasons one is that the
points still do have different distances
away from each other just because
they're on the edge they still do vary
and far where they are from each other
and so this point is more similar at
this point that it is to that point so
even things will learn about K nearest
neighbors actually work really well
really really well in high dimensions
despite what the theoreticians claimed
and what really happened here was that
in the 90s theory totally took over
machine learning and so particularly
there was this concept of these things
called support vector machines that were
theoretically very well justified
extremely easy to analyze mathematically
and you could like kind of prove things
about them and we kind of lost a decade
of real practical development in my
opinion and all these theories became
very popular like the curse of
dimensionality nowadays and a lot of
theoreticians hate this and the the
world of machine learning has become
very empirical which is like which
techniques actually work and it turns
out that in practice building models on
lots and lots of columns works really
really well so yeah the other thing to
quickly mention is the no free lunch
theorem there's a mathematical theorem
by that name that you will often hear
about their claims that there is no type
of model that works well for any kind of
data set which is true and is obviously
true if you think about it in the
mathematical sense any random data set
by definition is random right so there
isn't going to be some way of looking at
every possible random data set that's in
some way more useful than any other
approach in the real world we look at
data which is not random mathematically
we would say it sits on some lower
dimensional manifold it was created by
some kind of caused all structure there
are some relationships in there
so the truth is that we're not using
random datasets and so the truth is in
the real world there are actually
techniques that work much better than
other techniques for nearly all of the
datasets you look at and nowadays there
are empirical researchers who spend a
lot of time studying this which is which
techniques work a lot of the time and
ensembles of decision trees with which
random for a one is perhaps the
technique which most often comes at the
top and that is despite the fact that
until the library that we're showing you
today first day I came along there
wasn't really any standard way to
pre-process them properly and to
properly set their parameters so I think
it's even more strong than that so yeah
I think this is where the difference
between theory and practice is is is
huge so when I try to create a ratso
random forest regressor what is that
random forest regressor okay it's part
of something called SK learn SK learn is
scikit-learn it is by far the most
popular and important package for
machine learning in python it does
nearly everything it's not the best at
nearly everything but it's perfectly
good at nearly everything so like you
might find in the next part of this
course with your net you're going to
look at a different kind of decision
tree ensemble called gradient roost in
trees where actually there's something
called x3 boost which is better than
gradient boosting trees in psyche alone
but it's pretty good at everything so
where I'm really going to focus on cycle
in random forests you can do two kinds
of things with a random forest if I hit
tab I haven't imported it so let's go
back to where we import
[Music]
so you can hit tab in Jupiter notebook
to get tab-completion for anything
that's in your environment you'll see
that there's also a random forest
classifier so in general there's an
important distinction between things
which can predict continuous variables
that's called regression and therefore a
method for doing that would be a
regresar and things that predict
categorical variables and that is called
classification and the things that do
that are called plasa fires now so in
our case we're trying to predict a
continuous variable
pres so therefore we are doing
regression and therefore we need a
regress or a lot of people incorrectly
use the word regression to refer to
linear regression now it is just not at
all true or appropriate regression means
an assumed learning model that's trying
to predict some kind of continuous
outcome it has a continuous dependent
variable
so pretty much everything in
scikit-learn has the same form you first
of all create an instance of an object
for the machine learning model you want
you then call fit passing in the
independent variables the things you're
gonna use to predict and the dependent
variable the thing that you want to
predict so in our case the dependent
variable is is the data frames sale
price column and so we the thing we want
to use to predict is everything except
that in pandas the drop method returns a
new data frame with a list of columns
removed right well a list of rows or
columns removed so access equals 1 means
removed columns so this here is the data
frame containing everything except for
sale price okay so you just pass a list
let's find out so to find out I could
hit shift tab and that will bring up the
you know a quick inspection of the
parameters in this case it doesn't quite
tell me what I want so if I hit shift
tab twice it gives me a bit more
information yes and that tells me it's a
single label or list like list like
means like anything you can index in
Python there's lots of things by the way
if I hit three times it will give me a
whole little window at the bottom okay
so that was shift tab another way of
doing that of course which we learned
would be question mark question mark DF
bra drop okay sorry question mark
question mark would be the source code
for it for a single question mark is the
documentation
so I think that trick of like tab
complete shift-tab parameters question
mark and double question mark for the
docs and the source code like if you
know nothing else about using Python
libraries know that because now you know
how to find out everything else okay so
we try to run it and it doesn't work
okay so why didn't it work so anytime
you get a stack trace like this so an
error the trick is to go to the bottom
because the bottom tells you what went
wrong a buffer it tells you all of the
functions the court other function could
cause other functions to get there could
not convert string to float conventional
so there was a column name sorry a there
was a value rather inside my data set
conventional the word conventional and
it didn't know how to create a model
using that string now that's true we
have to pass numbers to most machine
learning models and certainly to random
forests so step one is to convert
everything into numbers so our data set
contains both continuous variables so
numbers where the meaning is numeric
like price and it contains categorical
variables which could either be numbers
where the meaning is not continuous like
zip code or it could be a string like
large small and medium it's a
categorical and continuous variables we
want to basically get to a point where
we have a data set where we can use all
of these variables so they have to all
be numeric and they have to be usable in
some way so one issue is that we've got
something called say all date which you
might remember right at the top we told
it that that's a date so it's been
passed as a date and so you can see here
it's Dana type D type very important
thing data type is date/time 64-bit so
that's not a number right and this is
actually where we need to do our first
piece of feature engineering right
inside a date there's a lot of
interesting
all right so since you've got the catch
box can you tell me what are some of the
interesting bits of information inside a
date what we can see like a time series
that's true I'm hadn't expressed for
real what are some columns that we could
pull out of this
yeah month the date as in like it come
Ian at least to be a number
yeah month quarter you're a pleasure to
your right and get some more behind you
just pass it to your right you go you
got some more columns for us the day of
month yeah keep going to the right yeah
week 30 of week yeah week of here yeah
okay I'll give you a few more like that
you might want to think about would be
like is it a holiday is it a weekend was
it raining that day was there a sports
event that day like it depends a bit on
what you're doing right so like if
you're predicting soda sales in soma you
would probably want to know was there a
San Francisco Giants ball game on that
day right so like what's in a date is
one of the most important pieces of
feature engineering you can do and no
machine learning algorithm can tell you
whether the Giants were playing that day
and that it was important right so this
is where you need to do feature
engineering so I to as much things as
many things automatically as I can for
you right so here I've got something
called add date pad what is that it's
something inside fast AI dot structured
okay and what is it well let's read the
source code here it is so you'll find
most of my functions are less than half
a page of code alright so here is
something it's going to so rather than
often rather than having Docs I'm going
to try to add Doc's over time but that
is their design
you can understand them I reading the
code so we're passing in a data frame
and the name of some field okay which in
this case was sale date and so in this
case we can't go D F dot field name
because that would actually find a field
called field name it literally so DF
square bracket field name is how we grab
a column where that column name is
stored in this variable
okay so we've now got the field itself
the series yeah and so what we're going
to do is we're going to go through all
of these different strings right and
this is a piece of Python which actually
looks inside an object and finds a
attribute with that name so this is
going to go through and you can again
you can google for Pais and get
attribute it's a cool little advanced
technique but this is going to go
through it's going to find for this
field it's going to find its Year
attribute now planter's has got this
interesting idea which is if I actually
look inside let's go field equals this
is the kind of experiment I want you to
do right play around say all date okay
so I've now got that in a field object
and so I can go field right and I can go
field dot tab okay and let's see is year
in there oh it's not okay why not
well that's because year is only going
to apply to pandas series that date time
objects
so what pandas does is it lets out
different methods inside attributes that
are specific to what they are so
date/time objects will have a DT
attribute defined and at that is where
you'll find all the date/time specific
stuff so what I went through was I went
through all of these and picked out all
of the ones that could ever be
interesting for having any reason right
and this is like the opposite of the
curse of dimensionality it's like if
there is any column or any variant of
that column that could be ever be
interesting at all add that to your data
set and every variation of it you can
think of there's no harm in adding more
columns nearly all the time right so in
this case we're going to go ahead and
all of these different attributes and so
for every one I'm going to create a new
field that's going to be called the name
of your field with the word date removed
sort of a sale and then the name of the
attribute so we're going to get a sale
year sale months so a week say all day
etc etc okay and then at the very end
I'm going to remove the original field
right because remember we can't use say
all date directly because it's not a
number
so your sickness only worked because it
was a date type did you make the data it
was already saved as one in the original
yeah it's already a date type and the
reason it was a date tonight is because
when we imported it we said PA's dates
equals and told pandas it's a date type
so as long as it looks
date-ish and we tell it to parse it as a
date if you don't have an intranet
i I think there might be but for some
reason it wasn't ideal like maybe it
took lots of time or it didn't always
work or for some reason I had to list it
here
I would suggest checking out the docs
for pandas don't read CSV and maybe on
the forum you can tell us what you find
because I can't remember offhand
you
I got telephoning so how about the time
zone let's do that one on the same forum
thread that savanah creates because I
think it's a reasonably advanced
question but generally speaking the time
zone in a properly formatted date will
be included in the string and it should
format it it should pull it out
correctly and turn it into a universal
time zone so generally speaking it
should handle it for you so I noticed
you for indexing a column to shrink when
we use the is there any consideration
the square brackets one is safer
particularly if you're assigning to a
column if it didn't already exist you
need to use the square brackets format
otherwise you'll get weird errors so the
square brackets format is sofa the dart
version saves me like a couple of
keystrokes so I probably use it more
than I should
in this particular case because I wanted
to grab something that was had field
name was had something inside it wasn't
the name itself I have to use square
brackets so square brackets is going to
be your your safe bet if in doubt so
after I run that you'll notice that DF r
or dark columns gives me a list of all
of the columns just as strings and at
the end there they all are right so it's
removed sale date and it's added all
those so that's not quite enough the
other problem is that we've got a whole
bunch of strings in there right so you
can just think that they're doing to
pass a bet
so is like low high medium thank you so
a panda's actually has a concept with a
category data type but by default it
doesn't turn anything into a category
for you so I've created something called
Train cats which creates categorical
variables for everything that's the
string okay and so what that's going to
do is behind the scenes it's going to
create a column that's actually a number
right as an integer and it's going to
store a mapping from the integers to the
streets okay
the reason it's trained cats as it uses
for the training set more advanced usage
is that when we get to looking at the
test and validation sets this is really
important idea in fact Terrence came to
me the other day and he said my models
not working why not and he figured it
out for himself it turned out the reason
why was because the mappings he was
using from string to number in the
training set were different to the
mappings he was using from string to
number in the test set so therefore in
the training set hi might have been
three but in the trait test set it might
have been two so the two were totally
different and so the model was basically
non predictive okay so I have another
function called apply categories where
you can pass in your existing training
set and it all use the same mappings to
let you all make sure your test set of
validation set uses the same mappings
okay so when I go trained cats it's
actually not going to make the data
frame look different at all but behind
the scenes it's going to turn them all
into numbers when we finish at 12 11:50
let's see here we go I'll try to finish
on time so you'll see now remember I
mentioned there was this dot DT
attribute that gives you access to
everything assuming it's a date time
about the date time there's a dot count
attribute that gives you access to
things as
something's a category all right and so
usage banned was a string and so now
that I've run train cats it's turned it
into a category so I can go to your or
usage banned cat right and there's a
whole bunch of other things we've got
there okay
so one of the things we've got there is
dot categories and you can see here is
the list now one of the things you might
notice it's that this list is in a bit
of a weird order high low medium the
truth is it doesn't matter too much but
what's going to happen when we use the
random forest is it's actually good that
this is going to be 0 this is going to
be 1 this is gonna be true and we're
going to be creating decision trees and
so we're going to have a decision tree
that can split things at a single point
so it either be high versus low and
medium or medium versus high and low
that would be kind of weird right it
actually turns out not to work too badly
but it'll work a little bit better if
you have these in sensible orders okay
so if you want to reorder a category
then you can just go caps net categories
and pass in the order you want until it
is ordered and almost every pandas
method has an in-place parameter which
rather than returning a new data frame
is going to change that data frame okay
so I'm not going to do that like I
didn't check that carefully for
categories it should be ordered but this
seems like a pretty obvious one
you reiterate that issue I don't
understand what the chart so um the
usage banned column it's actually going
to be this is actually what I random
forest is gonna see these numbers one
zero two one
okay and they map to the position in
this array and as we're going to learn
shortly a random forest consists of a
bunch of trees it's going to make a
single split and the single split is
going to be either greater than or less
than 1 or greater than a less than two
right so we could split it into high
versus low and medium which that
semantically makes sense it's like is it
big or we could split it into medium
versus high and low it doesn't make much
sense right so in practice the decision
tree could then make a second split to
say like medium versus high and low and
then within the high and low into high
and low but by putting it in a sensible
order if it wants to spit out low it can
do it in one decision rather than two
and we'll be learning more about this
shortly it's it honestly it's not a big
deal but I just wanted to mention it's
there and it's also good to know that
people when they talk about like
different types of categorical variable
specifically you need to know there's a
kind of categorical variable called
ordinal and an ordinal categorical
variable is one that has some kind of
order like high medium and low okay and
random forests are terribly sensitive
for that fact but it's worth noting it's
there and trying it out still ordering
wouldn't sell for maximum that that's
what I'm saying it helps a little bit
right it means you can get there with
one decision rather than two
I noticed there is a negative one in
that list of categories is that like an
NA yeah exactly so for free we get a
negative one which prefers to missing
and what are the things we're going to
do is we're going to actually add one
can somebody pass the vector Paul is
we're going to add one to our codes
maybe in two guys let people know it's
coming yeah so let people know we're
going to add one to all of our codes to
make missing a zero later on yeah we're
going to get to that yeah yeah so get
dummies which we'll get to in a moment
is going to create three separate
columns ones and zeros for high once
there's a million ones in series for low
where else this one creates a single
column with an integer zero one or two
we're going to get to that one shortly
yep
did you have a question to Paul or just
pointing out okay okay so at this point
as long as we always make sure we use
dot cat codes the thing with the numbers
in we're basically done all of our
streams have been turned into numbers
dates been turned into a bunch of
numeric columns and everything else is
already a number okay the only other
main thing we have to do is notice that
we have lots of missing values so here
is DFA is null that's going to return
true or false depending on whether
something is empty dot some is going to
add up how many empty for each series
and then I'm going to sort them and
divide by the size of the data set so
here we have some things which have like
quite high percentages of
Nantz sir so missing values we call them
in play or what I call it maybe I didn't
run it there we go okay so we're going
to get to that in a moment but I will
point something out which is reading the
CSV talk a minute or so the processing
took another ten seconds or so from time
to time when I've done a little bit of
work I don't want to wait for again I
will tend to save where I'm at so here
I'm going to save it and I got to save
it in a format called feather format
this is very very new all right but what
this is going to do is it's going to
save it to disk in exactly the same
basic format but it's actually in RAM
this is by far the fastest way to save
something in the fastest way to read it
back right so most of the folks you deal
with unless they're on the cutting edge
won't be familiar with this format so
this would be something you can teach
them about it's becoming the standard
right it's actually becoming something
that's going to be used not just in
pandas but in Java in spark in lots of
like things for like communicating
across computers because it's incredibly
fast and it's actually co-designed by
the guy that made Panthers by where's
McKinney so we can just go deer 4.2
feather and pass in some name I tend to
have a folder called temp for all of my
like as I'm going along stuff and so
when you go OS don't make do as you can
pass in any path path here you like it
won't complain if it's already there
exists okay equals true if there are
some sub directories it'll create them
for you so this is a super handy little
function okay so it's not installed so
because I'm using Kressel for the first
time it's complaining about that so if
you get a message that something's not
installed if you're using anaconda you
can condor install Kressel actually
doesn't use anaconda it uses a pit
you
and so we wait for that to go along okay
and so now if I run it and so sometimes
you may find you actually have to
restart Jupiter so I won't do that now
it's really out of time so if you
restart Jupiter you'll be able to keep
moving a lot so from now on you don't
have to rerun all the stuff they love
you could just say PD don't read further
and we've got our data frame back so the
last step we're going to do is to
actually replace the strings with their
numeric codes and we're going to pull
out the dependent variable sale price
into a separate variable and we're going
to also handle missing continuous values
and so how are we going to do that
so you'll see here we've got a function
called proc DF what is that croc DF
so it's in so fast AI dot structured
again and here it is so quite a lot of
the functions have a few additional
parameters that you can provide and
we'll talk about them later but
basically we're providing the data frame
to process and the name of the dependent
variable that the the Y field name okay
and so what it's going to do is it's
going to make a copy of the data frame
it's going to grab the Y value it's
going to drop the dependent variable
from the original and then it's going to
fix missing so how do we fix missing so
what we do to fix missing is pretty
simple if it's numeric then we fix it by
basically saying let's first of all
check that it does have some missing
right so if it does have some missing
values so in other words the is not some
is nonzero then we're going to create a
new column called with
name as the original plus underscore na
and it's going to be a bullion column
with a 1 anytime that was missing and a
0 anytime it wasn't we're going to talk
about this again next week but this is
you know give you the quick version
having done that where they're going to
replace the NA s the missing with the
median
okay so anywhere that used to be missing
will be replaced with the median or add
a new column to tell us which ones were
missing we only do that for numeric we
don't need it for categories because
pandas had is handles categorical
variables automatically by setting them
to minus one so what we're going to do
is if it's not numeric and it's a
categorical type we'll talk about the
maximum number of categories later but
lets us units is always true so if it's
not a numeric type we're going to
replace the column with its codes the
integers okay plus one right so the by
default pandas uses minus one for
missing so now zero will be missing and
one two three four will be all the other
categories so we're going to talk about
dummies later on in the course
but basically optionally you can say
that if you already know about dummy
values there are columns with a small
number of possible values you can put in
two dummies instead you can America
lysing them but we're not going to do
that for now okay
so for now all we're doing is we're
using the categorical codes plus one
replacing missing values with the median
adding an additional column telling us
which ones were replaced and removing
the dependent variable so that's what
proc DF does runs very quickly okay so
you'll see now sale price is no longer
here okay we've now got a whole new
color a whole new variable called Y the
contain sale press you'll see we put a
couple of extra blah underscore na s at
the end okay and if I look at that
[Music]
everything is a number
okay these boolean z' are treated as
numbers they're just considered
contributed a zero or one that is
displayed as false and true
they can see here is at the end of a
month is at the start of a month is at
the end of a quarter it's kind of funny
right because we've got things like a
model ID which presumably is something
like that could be a serial number it
could be like the model identifier
that's created by the factory or
something we've got like a data source
ID like some of these are numbers but
they're not continuous it turns out
actually random forests work fine with
those we'll talk about why and how and a
lot about that in detail but for now all
you need to know is no problem okay so
as long as this is all numbers which it
now is we can now go ahead and create a
random forest so m dot random forest
regressor random forests are trivially
paralyse abour so what that means is
that they if you've got more than one
CPU which everybody will basically on
their computers at home and if you've
got a t2 dot medium or bigger at AWS
you've got multiple CPUs trivially
paralyse Abul means that it will split
up the data across your different CPUs
and basically linearly scale right so
the more CPUs you have pretty much it
will divide the time it takes by that
number
not exactly but roughly so n jobs equals
minus one tells the random forest
regressor to create a separate job it's
a separate process basically for each
CPU you have so that's pretty much what
you want all the time
fit the model using this new data frame
we created using that Y value we pulled
out and then get the score ok the score
is going to be the r-squared we'll
define that next week hopefully some of
you already know about the r-squared one
is very good zero is very bad so as you
can see we've mmediately got a very high
score okay so that looks great but what
we'll talk about next week a lot more is
that it's not quite great because maybe
we had data that had points that look
like this and we fitted a line that
looks like this when actually we want to
want normal it looks like that ok the
only way to know whether we've actually
done a good job is by having some other
data set that we didn't use to train the
model now we're going to learn about
some ways with random fire
we can kind of get away without even
having that other data set but for now
what we're going to do is we're going to
split into twelve thousand rows which
we're going to put in a separate data
set called the validation set versus the
training sets going to take contain
everything else right and our data set
is going to be sorted by date and so
that means that the most recent twelve
thousand rows are going to be our
validation set again we'll talk more
about this next week it's a really
important idea but for now we can just
recognize that if we do that and run it
I've created a little thing called print
score and it's going to print out the
root mean square error between the
predictions and actuals
for the training set for the validation
set that r-squared for the training set
and the validation set and you'll see
that actually the r-squared for the
training was 0.98 but for the validation
was 0.89 okay then the RMS see and
remember this is on the logs was point
oh nine for the training set 0.25 for
the validation set now if you actually
go to cattle and go to the leaderboard
okay let's do it right now
he's got private and public I click on
public leaderboard and we can go down
and find out where is point two five so
there are four hundred seventy-five
teams
and generally speaking if you're in the
top half of a capital competition you're
doing pretty well so a point two-five
here we are point two five
what was it exactly point two five
by two 507 yeah about a hundred and
tenth so we're about in the top 25% so
so the idea like this is pretty cool
right with with like with no thinking at
all using the defaults of everything
we're in the top 25% of a caracal
competition so like random forests are
insanely powerful and this totally
standardized process is insanely good
for like any datasets so we're gonna
wrap up well what I'm going to ask you
to do for Tuesday it's like take as many
tackle competitions as you can whether
they be running now or old ones or
datasets that you're interested in for
your hobbies will work and and please
try it right try this process and if it
doesn't work you know tell us on the
forum here's the data so I'm using
here's where I got it from his like the
stack trace of where I got an error or
here's like you know if you use my print
score function or something like it like
you know show us what the training
versus tests it looks like we'll try and
figure it out right but what I'm hoping
we'll find is that all of you will be
pleasantly surprised that with with the
you know hour or two with information
you got today you can already get better
models than most of the very serious
practicing data scientists that
competing table competitions okay great
good luck and I'll see you on the forums
oh one more thing Friday the other class
said a lot of them had class during my
office hours so if I made them one till
three instead of two two or four on
Fridays is that okay seminar oh okay I
have to find a whole another time all
right I will talk to somebody who
actually knows what they're doing unlike
me about finding other cells
absolutely