all right welcome back to machine
learning I am really excited to be able
to share some amazing stuff that
University of San Francisco students
have built during the week or written
about during the week and quite a few
things are going to show you have
already spread around the internet quite
a bit lots of tweets and posts and all
kinds of stuff happening one of the the
first to be widely shared was this one
by Tyler who did something really
interesting he he started out by saying
like what if I like create the synthetic
data set where the independent variables
is like the X and the y and the
dependent variable is like color right
and interestingly he showed me an
earlier version of this where he wasn't
using color he was just like putting the
actual numbers in here and this thing
kind of wasn't really working at all and
as soon as he started using Kawa it
started working really well and so I
wanted to mention that one of the things
that unfortunately we we don't teach you
at USF is a theory of human perception
perhaps we should because actually when
it comes to visualization its kind of
the most important thing to know is what
is the human eye or what is what what it
was the human brain good at perceiving
there's a whole area of academic study
on this and one of the things that we're
best at perceiving is differences in
color right so that's why as soon as we
look at this picture of this synthetic
data he created you can immediately say
oh there's kind of four areas of you
know lighter red color so what he did
was he said okay what if we like tried
to create a machine learning model of
this synthetic data set and so
specifically he created a tree and the
cool thing is that you can actually draw
the tree right so after he created the
tree he did this all in matplotlib
matplotlib is very flexible right he
actually drew the tree boundaries so
that's already a pretty neat trick is to
be actually able to draw the tree but
then he did something even cleverer
which is he said okay so what
predictions does the tree make well as
the
average of each of these areas and so to
do that we can actually draw the average
color alright there's actually kind of
pretty
here is the predictions that the tree
makes now here's where it gets really
interesting is like you can as you know
randomly generate trees through
resampling and so here are four trees
generated through resampling they're all
like pretty similar but a little bit
different and so now we can actually
visualize bagging and to visualize
bagging we literally take the average of
the four pictures all right that's what
bagging is and there it is alright and
so here is like the the fuzzy decision
boundaries of a random forest and I
think this is kind of amazing right
because it's it's like a I wish I had
this actually when I started teaching
you all random forest because I could
have skipped a couple of classes it's
just like okay that's what we do you
know we create the decision boundaries
we average each area and then we we do
it a few times in average all of them
okay so that's what a random forest does
and I think like this is just such a
great example of making the complex easy
through through pictures so congrats to
Tyler for that it actually turns out
that he has actually reinvented
something that somebody else has already
done a guy called Christian any who went
on to be one of the world's foremost
machine learning researchers actually
included almost exactly this technique
in a book he wrote about decision
forests so it's actually kind of cool
that Tyler ended up reinventing
something that one of the world's
foremost authorities on v decision
forests actually it has created so I
thought that was me that's nice because
when we pup when we posted this on
Twitter you know got a lot of attention
and finally somebody with it was able to
say like oh you know what this this
actually already exists so Tyler has
gone away and you know started reading
that book something else which is super
cool is Jason Carpenter created a whole
new library called Parfitt and Parfitt
is a
parallelized fitting of multiple models
for the purpose of selecting hyper
parameters and there's a lot I really
like about this he's shown a clear
example of how to use it right and like
the API looks very similar to other grid
search based approaches but it uses the
validation techniques that Rachel wrote
about and that we learnt about a couple
of weeks ago of using a good validation
set and you know what he's done here is
in his blog post that introduces it you
know he's he's gone right back and said
like what are hyper parameters why do we
have to train them and he's kind of
explained every step and then the the
module itself is like it's it's very
polished you know he's added
documentation to it he's added a nice
readme to it and it's kind of
interesting when you actually look at
the code you realize you know it's very
simple you know which is it's definitely
not a bad thing that's a good thing as
to is to make things simple but by kind
of writing this little bit of code and
then packaging it up so nicely he's made
it really easy for other people to use
this technique which is great and so one
of the things I've been really thrilled
to see is then Vinay went along and
combined two things from our class one
was to take profit and then the other
was to take the kind of accelerated SGD
approach to classification we turn
learned about in the last lesson and
combine the two to say like okay well
let's now use half it to help us find
the parameters of a SGD logistic
regression so I think that's really a
really great idea something else which I
thought was terrific is print sexually
basically went through and summarized
pretty much all the stuff we learnt in
the random and random forest
interpretation plus and he went even
further than that as he described each
of the different approaches to random
forest interpretation he described how
it's done so here for example is feature
importance
a variable permutation a little picture
of each one and then super cool here is
the code to implement it from scratch so
I think this is like really nice post
you know describing something that not
many people understand and showing you
know exactly how it works both with
pictures and with code that implements
it from scratch so I think that's really
really great one of the things I really
like here is that for like the tree
interpreter but he actually showed how
you can take the tree interpreter output
and feed it into the new waterfall chart
package that Chris USF student built to
show how you can actually visualize the
contributions of the tree interpreter in
a waterfall chart so again kind of a
nice combination of multiple pieces of
technology we both learned about and and
built as a group I also really thought
this kernel there's been a few
interesting kernels share it and I'll
share some more next week and diverse
wrote this really nice kernel showing
this is quite challenging careful
competition on detecting icebergs versus
chips and it's a kind of a weird two
channel satellite data which is very
hard to visualize and he actually went
through and basically described kind of
the formulas for how these like radar
scattering things actually work and then
actually managed to come up with a code
that allowed him to recreate you know
the actual 3d icebergs or ships and I
have not seen that done before or like I
you know it's it's quite challenging to
know how to visualize his data and then
he went on to show how to build a neural
net to try to interpret this so that was
pretty fantastic as well so yeah
congratulations
for all of you I know for a lot of you
you know you're posting stuff out there
to the rest of the world for the first
time you know and it's kind of
intimidating you're used to writing
stuff that you got a hand into a teacher
and there
any ones who see it and you know it's
kind of scary the first time you do it
but then the first time somebody you
know that votes your cable kernel or ATS
a clap to your medium post he suddenly
realized oh I'm actually I've written
something that people like that's that's
pretty great so if you haven't tried
yourself yet
I again invite you to try writing
something and if you're not sure you
could write a summary of a lesson you
could write a summary of like if there's
something you found hard like maybe you
found it hard to fire up a gpu-based AWS
instance you eventually figured it out
you know you could write down just
describe how you solve that problem or
if one of your classmates didn't
understand something and you explained
it to them then you could like write
down something saying like oh there's
this concept that some people have
trouble understanding here's a good way
I think of explaining it there's all
kinds of stuff you could you could do
okay
so let's go back to SGD and so we're
going back through this logbook which
Rachel put together basically taking us
through kind of SGD from scratch for the
purpose of digit recognition and
actually quite a lot of the stuff we
look at today is going to be closely
following part of the computation or
linear algebra course which you can both
find the MOOCs on faster I or at USF
it'll be an elective next year alright
so if you find some of this this stuff
interesting and I hope you do then
please consider signing up for the
elective or checking out the video
online so we're building neural networks
and we're starting with an assumption
that we've downloaded the eminence data
we've normalized it by subtracting the
main and divided by the standard
deviation okay
so the data is it's slightly unusual in
that although they represent images they
where they were downloaded as each image
was a 784 long rank one tensor so it's
been flattened out okay and so for the
purpose of drawing pictures of it
we had to resize it to 28 by 28 but the
actual data we've got is not 28 by 28 it
says it's it's 784 long flattened out
okay four basic steps we're gonna take
here is to start out with training the
world's simplest neural network
basically a logistic regression right so
no hidden layers and we're going to
Train it using a library fast AI and
we're going to build the network using a
library plate watch right and then we're
going to gradually get rid of all the
libraries right so first of all well get
rid of the N n neural net library and pi
torch and write that ourselves then
we'll get rid of the fast a I fit
function and write that ourselves and
then we'll get rid of the PI torch
optimizer and write that ourselves and
so by the end of this notebook
we'll have written all the pieces
ourselves the only thing that will end
up relying on is the two key things that
pi torch gives us which is a the ability
to write Python code and have it run on
the GPU and be the ability to write
Python code and have it automatically
differentiated for us okay so there are
two things we're not going to attempt to
write ourselves because it's boring and
pointless but everything else we'll try
and write ourselves on top of those two
things ok so our starting point is like
not doing anything ourselves it's
basically having it all done for us and
so PI torch has an N n library which is
where the neural net stuff lives
you can create a multi-layer neural
network by using the sequential function
and then passing in a list of the layers
that you want and we asked for a linear
layer followed by a softmax layer and
that defines our logistic regression
okay
the input to our linear layer is 28 by
28 as we just discussed the output is 10
because we want a probability for each
of the numbers not through 9 for each of
our images okay CUDA sticks it on the
GPU and then fit fits a model ok so we
start out with a random set of weights
and then fit users gradient descent to
make it better we had to tell the fit
function what criterion to use in other
words what counts is better and we told
it to use negative log likelihood we'll
learn about that in the next lesson what
that is exactly
we had to tell it what optimizer to use
and we said please use opt M not Adam
the details of that we won't cover in
this course we're going to use something
build something simpler called SGD if
you interested in Adam we just covered
that in the dick learning course and
what metrics do you want to print out we
decided to print out accuracy ok so that
was that and so if we do that ok so
after we fit it we get an accuracy of
generally somewhere around 91 92 percent
so what we going to do from here is
we're going to gradually we're going to
repeat this exact same thing so we're
going to rebuild this model you know
four or five times fitting it building
it and fitting it with less and less
libraries ok
so the second thing that we did last
time was to try to start to define the
the module ourselves right so instead of
saying the network is a sequential bunch
of these layers let's not use that like
at all and try and define it ourself
from scratch okay so to do that we have
to use our because that's how we build
everything in play torch and we have to
create a class which inherits from an
end module so n n dot module is a PI
torch class that takes our class and
turns it into a neural network module
which basically means we'll anything
that you inherit from an end module like
this you can pretty much insert into a
neural network as a layer or you can
treat it as a neural network it's going
to get all the stuff that it needs
automatically to to work as a part of or
a full neural network now we'll talk
about exactly what that means today in
the next lesson right so we need to
construct the object so that means we
need to define the constructor Thunder
in it and then importantly this is a
Python thing is if you inherit from some
other object then you have to create the
thing you inherit from first
so when you say super dot dunder init
that says construct the enn module piece
of that first right if you don't do that
then the NN dot module stuff never gets
a chance to actually get constructed
right so this is just like a standard
Python oo subclass constructor
okay and if any if that's on unclear to
you then you know this is where you
definitely want to just grab a Python
intro 200 because this is the standard
approach all right so inside our
constructor we want to do the equivalent
of an end linea all right so what n n
dot linea is doing is it's taking our
it's taking our 28 by 28 vector so 768
long vector and we're going to be that's
going to be the input to a matrix
multiplication
so we now need to create a something
with 768 rows and that's 768 and 10
columns ok so because the input to this
is going to be a mini batch of size
actually let's move this into a new
window 768 by 10 and the input to this
is going to be a mini batch of size 64
by 768 right so we're going to do this
matrix product ok so when we say in pie
chart and in linea it's going to
construct this matrix for us right so
since we are not using that we're doing
things from scratch we need to make it
ourselves so to make it ourselves we can
say generate normal random numbers with
this dimensionality which we passed in
here 768 by 10 okay so that gives us our
our randomly initialized matrix okay
then we want to add on to this you know
we don't just want y equals ax we want y
equals ax plus B all right so we need to
add on what we call in neural Nets of
bias vector so we create here a bias
vector of length 10 okay again randomly
initialized and so now here are our two
randomly initialized weight tensors so
that's our constructor okay now we need
to find for word why do we need to
define for word this is a PI torch
specific thing what's going to happen is
this is when you create a module in PI
torch the objects that you get back
behaves as if it's a function you can
call it with parentheses which will do
it that
a moment and so you need to somehow
define what happens when you call it as
if it's a function and the answer is
tight which calls a method called
forward okay that's just that that's the
pie that the PI torch kind of approach
that they picked right so when it calls
forward we need to do our actual
calculation of the output of this module
or letter okay so here is the thing that
actually gets calculated in a logistic
regression so basically we take our
input X which gets passed to forward
that's basically how forward works it
gets past the mini-batch and we matrix
multiply it by the layer one weights
which we defined up here and then we add
on the layer one bias which we defined
up here okay and actually nowadays we
can define this a little bit more
elegantly using the Python three matrix
multiplication operator which is the at
sign and when you when you use that I
think you kind of end up with something
that looks closer to what the
mathematical notation looked like and so
I find that nicer okay all right so
that's that's our linear layer in our
logistic regression you know a zero
hidden layer neural net so then the next
thing we do to that is soft next okay so
we get the output of this matrix model
play okay who wants to tell me what the
dimensionality of my output of this
matrix model play is sorry 64 by 10
thank you Karen I should mention for
those of you that weren't at deep
learning class yesterday we actually
looked at a really cool post from Karam
who described how to do structured data
analysis with neural nets which has been
like super popular and a whole bunch of
people who kind of said that they've
read it and found it
interesting so that was really exciting
so we get this matrix of outputs and we
put this through a softmax and why do we
put it through a softmax we put it
through a softmax because in the end we
want probably you know for every image
we want a probability that is a 0 or a 1
or a 2 or 3 or 4 all right so we want a
bunch of probabilities that add up to 1
and where each of those probabilities is
between 0 &amp; 1 so a softmax
does exactly that for us so for example
if we weren't picking out you know
numbers from nought to 10 but instead of
picking it out cat dog play an official
building the output of that matrix
multiplied for one particular image
might look like that these are just some
random numbers and to turn that into a
softmax
I first go a to the power of each of
those numbers i sum up those eight of
the power offs and then I take each of
those eight of the power of z' and
divide it by the sum and that softmax
that's the definition of softmax
so because it was in the power of it
means it's always positive because it
was divided by the sum it means that
it's always between zero and one and it
also means because it's divided by the
sum that they always add up to one so by
applying this softmax activation
function so anytime we have a layer of
outputs which we call activations and
then we apply some function some
nonlinear function to that that map's
1:1 scale at a one scalar like softmax
does we call that an activation function
okay so the softmax activation function
takes our outputs and turns it into
something which behaves like a
probability right we don't strictly
speaking need it we could still try and
train something which where the output
directly is the probabilities right but
by creating using this function that
automatically makes them always behave
like probabilities it means there's less
for the network to learn
so it's going to learn better alright so
generally speaking whenever we design an
architecture we try to design it in a
way where it's as easy as possible for
it to create something of the form that
we want so that's why we use softmax
right so that's the basic steps right we
have our input which is a bunch of
images right which is here it gets
multiplied by a weight metrics we
actually also add on a bias right to get
a output of the linear function we put
it through a nonlinear activation
function in this case softmax and that
gives us our probabilities so there
there that all is hi torch also tends to
use the log of softmax for reasons that
don't particularly need fatherís now
it's basically a numerical stability
convenience okay so to make this the
same as our version up here that you saw
log softmax I'm going to use log here as
well okay so we can now instantiate this
class that is create an object of this
class so I have a question back for the
probabilities where we were before
hmm so if we were to have a photo with a
cat and a dog together would that change
the way that that works or does it work
in the same basic yes that's a great
question so if you had a photo with a
cat and a dog together and you wanted it
to spit out both cat and dog this would
be a very poor choice so softmax is
specifically the activation function we
use for categorical predictions where we
only ever want to predict one of those
things right and so part of the reason
why is that as you can see because we're
using e to the right e to the slightly
bigger numbers creates much bigger
numbers as a result of which we
generally have just one or two
large and everything else is pretty
small right so if I like recalculate
these rounded numbers a few times you'll
see like it tends to be a bunch of
zeroes and one or two high numbers right
so it's really designed to try to kind
of make it easy to predict like this one
thing is the thing I want if you're
doing multi-label prediction so I want
to just find all the things in this
image rather than using softmax we would
instead use sigmoid that's a sigmoid
recall it would cause each of these
between to be between 0 &amp; 1 but they
would no longer add to 1 it's a good
question and like a lot of these details
about like best practices are things
that we cover in the deep learning
course and we won't cover heaps of them
here and the machine learning course
we're more interested in the mechanics I
guess but we're trying to do them we've
they're quick all right so now that
we've got that we can instantiate an
object of that class and of course we
want to copy it over to the GPU so we
can do computations over there again we
need an optimizer we're we talking about
what this is shortly but you'll see here
we've called a function on our class
called parameters but we never defined a
method called parameters and the reason
that is going to work is because it
actually was defined Forest inside an
end up module and so an end up module
actually automatically go through the
attributes we've created and finds
anything that basically we we said this
is a parameter so the way you say
something is a parameter is you wrap it
in an end off parameter so this is just
the way that you tell PI torch this is
something that I want to optimize ok so
when we created the weight matrix we
just wrapped it with an end up parameter
it's exactly the same as a regular 5
torch variable which we'll learn about
shortly it's just a little flag to say
hey you should you should optimize this
and so when you call net to parameters
on our net to object we created it goes
through everything that we created in
the constructor checks to see if any of
them are of type parameter and if so it
sets all of those being things that we
to train with the optimizer and we'll be
implementing the optimizer from scratch
later okay
so having done that we can fit and we
should get basically the same answers
before 91 ish so that looks good all
right so what if we actually built here
well what we've actually built as I said
is something that can behave like a
regular function all right so I want to
show you how we can actually call this
as a function so to be able to call it
as a function we need to be able to pass
data to it to be able to pass data to it
I'm going to need to grab a mini batch
of analyst images okay so we used for
convenience the image classifier data
from arrays method from fast AI and what
that does is it creates a PI torch data
loader for us a PI torch data loader is
something that grabs a few images and
sticks them into a mini batch that makes
them available and you can basically say
give me another mini batch pick me
another mini batch give me another mini
batch and so in Python we call these
things generators generators are things
where you can basically say I want
another I want another I want another
right there's this kind of very close
connection between iterators and
generators are not going to worry about
the difference between them right now
but you'll see basically to turn to
actually get hold of something which we
can say please give me another of in
order to grab something that we can we
can use to generate mini batches we have
to take our data loader and so you can
ask for the training data loader from
our model data object you'll see there's
a bunch of different data loader as you
can ask for you can ask for the test
data loader the Train date loader
the validation loader or wintered images
data loader and so forth so we're going
to grab the training data loader that
was created for us this is a pice
and plate or data loader well slightly
optimized by us but same idea and you
can then say this is a standard Python
thing we can say turn that into an
iterator turn that into something where
we can grab another one at a time from
and so once you've done that we've now
got something that we can iterate
through you can use the standard Python
next function to grab one more thing
from that generator okay so that's
returning and the X's from a mini-batch
and the Y's found our mini batch the
other way that you can use generators
and iterators in python is with a for
loop I could also said like for you know
X mini batch comma Y mini batch in data
loader and then like do something right
so when you do that it's actually behind
the scenes it's basically syntactic
sugar for calling next lots of times
okay so this is all standard Python
stuff so that returns a tensor of size
64 by 784 as we would expect right the
the FASTA I library we used defaults to
a mini batch size of 64 that's why it's
that long these are all of the
background 0 pixels but they're not
actually zero in this case why aren't
they zero yeah they're normalized
exactly right so we subtracted the mean
divided by the standard deviation right
so there there it is so now what we want
to do is we want to pass that into our
our logistic regression so what we might
do is we'll go variable X M B equals
variable okay I can take my X mini-batch
I can move it onto the GPU because
remember my net to object is on the GPU
so our data for it also has to be on the
GPU and then the second thing I do is I
have to wrap it in variable so what is
variable do
this is how we get for free automatic
differentiation hi torch can
automatically differentiate you know
pretty much anything right any tensor
but to do so takes memory and time so
it's not going to always keep track like
to do what have any differentiation it
has to keep track of exactly how
something was calculated we added these
things together we multiplied it by that
we then took the sign blah blah blah
right you have to know all of the steps
because then to do the automatic
differentiation it has to take the
derivative of each step using the chain
rule multiply them all together right so
that's slow and memory intensive so we
have to opt in to saying like okay this
particular thing we're going to be
taking the derivative of later so please
keep track of all of those operations
for us and so the way we opt-in is by
wrapping a tensor in a variable right so
that's how we do it and you'll see that
it looks almost exactly like a tensor
but it now says variable containing this
tensor right so in pi torch a variable
has exactly identical api to a tensor or
actually more specifically a superset
with the api of a tensor anything we can
do to a tensor we can do to a variable
but it's going to keep track of exactly
what we did so we can later on take the
derivative okay so we can now pass that
into our net to object remember I said
you can treat this as if it's a function
right so notice we're not calling dot
forward we're just treating it as a
function and then remember we took the
log so to undo that I'm taking the X and
that will give me my probabilities
okay so there's my probabilities and
it's got return something of size 64 by
10 so for each image in the mini batch
we've got ten probabilities and you'll
see most probabilities are pretty close
to zero right and a few of them are
quite a bit bigger which is exactly what
we do we're hope right is that it's like
okay it's not a zero it's not a one it's
not a two it is a three it's not a four
it's not a five and so forth so maybe
this would be a bit easier to read if we
just grabbed like the first three of
them okay just like 10 to the negative
the neg two five five four okay and then
suddenly here's one which is ten to Nick
one right so you can kind of see what
it's trying to I was trying to do here I
mean we could call like net two dot
forward and it will do exactly the same
thing right but that's not how all of
the PI torch mechanics actually work
it's actually they actually call it as
if it's a function right and so this is
actually a really important idea like
because it means that when we define our
own architectures or whatever anywhere
that you would put in a function you
could put in a layer anyway you put in a
layer you can put in a neural net anyway
put it on your neck you can put in a
function because as far as pi torch is
concerned they're all just things that
it's going to call just like as if
they're functions so they're all like
interchangeable and this is really
important because that's how we create
really good neural nets is by mixing and
matching lots of pieces and putting them
all together right let me give an
example here is my logistic regression
which got 91 and a bit percent accuracy
I'm now going to turn it into a neural
network with one hidden layer all right
and the way I'm going to do that is I'm
going to create my more layer I'm going
to change this so it's
spits out a hundred rather than ten
which means this one input is going to
be a hundred
rather than ten now this as it is can't
possibly make things any better at all
yet why is this definitely not going to
be better than what I had before
yeah can somebody pass the yeah bishop
your combination of two linear layers
which is just the same as exactly right
so we've got two linear layers which is
just a linear layer right so to make
things interesting I'm going to replace
all of the negatives from the first
layer with zeros because that's a
nonlinear transformation and so that
nonlinear transformation is called a
rectified linear unit okay
so n n dot sequential simply is going to
call each of these layers in turn for
each mini batch right so dual linear
layer replace all of the negatives with
zero do another linear layer and do it
softbank's this is now a neural network
with one hidden layer and so let's try
trading that instead yeah accuracies now
been up to 96% okay so the this is the
idea is that the basic techniques we're
learning in this lesson like become
powerful at the point where you start
stacking them together okay can somebody
pass the green box there and then yes
Daniel
no reason it was like easier to type an
extra zero like this question of like
how many activations should I have a
neural network layer is kind of part of
the the scale of a deep learning
practitioner we covered in the deep
learning course and not in this class
when adding that additional I guess
transformation additional layer
additional this one here is called a
nonlinear layer or an activation
activation function direct activation
function does it matter that like if you
would have done for
like to soft Max's or is that something
you cannot do like yo you can absolutely
use the softmax there but it it's
probably not gonna give you what you
want and the reason why is that a soft
max tends to push most of its
activations to zero
and an activation just be clear like
I've had a lot of questions in deep
learning course about like what's an
activation an activation is the value
that is calculated in a layer right so
this is an activation right it's not a
weight a weight is not an activation
it's the value that you calculate from a
layer so soft max will tend to make most
of its activations pretty close to zero
and that's the opposite of what you want
you generally want your activations to
be kind of as rich and diverse and and
used as possible so nothing to stop you
doing it but it probably won't work very
well basically pretty much all of your
layers will be followed by non by
nonlinear activation functions that will
nearly always be value except for the
last layer it's going to or three layers
deep do you want to switch up these
activation layers that's a great
question so if I wanted to go deeper I
would just do that okay that's an outer
hidden layer Network so I think I'd
heard you said that there are a couple
of different activation functions like
that rectified linear units what are
some examples and why would you use each
yeah great question so basically like as
you add like more linear layers you kind
of got your input comes in and you put
it through a linear layer and then a
nonlinear layer linear layer nonlinear
layer
learning a linear layer and then the
final nonlinear layer the final
nonlinear layer as we've discussed you
know if it's a multi category
classification but you only ever pick
one of them you would use softmax if
it's a binary classification or a
multi-label classification where you're
predicting multiple things you would use
sigmoid if it's a regression you would
often have nothing at all right although
we learnt in last night's DL course
where sometimes you can use sigmoid
there as well so they're basically the
options main options for the final layer
for the hidden layers you pretty much
always use value right but there is a
another another one you can pick which
is kind of interesting which is called
leaky value and it looks like this and
basically if it's above zero it's y
equals x and if it's below zero it's
like y equals 0.1 X okay so that's very
similar to value but it's you know
rather than being equal to 0 under X
it's it's like something close to that
so they're the main to rally and lake
here Lu there are various others but
they're kind of like things that just
look very close to that so for example
there's something called Lu which is
quite popular but like you know the
details don't matter too much
honestly like that they're like aou is
something that looks like this but it's
slightly more curvy in the middle and
it's kind of like it's not generally
something that you so much pick based on
the data set it's
more like over time we just find better
activation functions so two or three
years ago everybody is value you know a
year ago pretty much everybody used Lake
Erie Lu today I guess probably most
people are starting to move towards ALU
but honestly that the choice of
activation function doesn't matter
terribly much actually and you know
people have actually showed that you can
use like a pretty arbitrary nonlinear
activation functions like even a sine
wave and it still works okay
so although what we're going to do today
is showing how to create this network
with no hidden layers to turn it into
that Network which is 96% ish accurate
is it will be trivial right and in fact
it's something you should probably try
and do during the week right is to
create that version
okay so now that we've got something
where we can take our network parsing
our variable and get back some
predictions that's basically all that
happened when we called fish so we're
going to see how how that that approach
can be used to create this to cast a
gradient descent one thing to note is
that the to turn the predicted
probabilities into a predicted like
which digit is it we would need to use
AG max unfortunately pi torch doesn't
call it ad max instead pi torch just
calls it max and max returns two things
it returns the actual max across this
axis so this is across the columns right
and the second thing it returns is the
index of that maximum right so so the
equivalent of arc max is to call max and
then get the first indexed thing okay so
there's our predictions right if this
was in numpy we would instead use MP dot
admits okay all right so here are the
predictions from our hand created
logistic regression and in this case
looks like we've got all but one correct
so the next thing we're going to try and
get rid of in terms of using libraries
is for try to avoid using the matrix
multiplication operator and instead
we're going to try and write that by
hand
so this next part we're going to learn
about something which kind of seems it
kind of it's gonna seem like a a minor
little kind of programming idea but
actually it's going to turn out that at
least in my opinion it's the most
important programming concept that will
teach in this course and it's possibly
the most important programming kind of
concept in all of all the things you
need to build machine learning
algorithms and it's the idea of
broadcasting and the idea I will show by
example if we create an array of 10 6
NIC 4 and an array of 2 8 7 and then add
the two together it adds each of the
components of those two arrays in turn
we call that element wise so in other
words we didn't have to write a loop
right back in the old days we would have
to have looped through each one and
added them and then concatenate them
together we don't have to do that today
it happens for us automatically
so in lump a we automatically get
element wise operations we can do the
same thing with PI torch so in first day
I would just add a little capital T to
turn something into a pipe watch tensor
all right and if we add those together
exactly the same thing all right so
element wise operations are pretty
standard in these kinds of libraries
it's interesting not just because we
don't have to write the for loop right
but it's actually much more interesting
because of the performance things that
are happening here
the first is if we were doing a for loop
right
if we were doing a four loop that would
happen in Python right even when you use
play torch it still does the for loop in
Python it has no way of like optimizing
a for loop and so a for loop in Python
is something like 10,000 times slower
than in C so that's your first problem
like I remember is like 1,000 or 10,000
the second problem then is that you
don't just want it to be optimized in C
but you want C to take advantage of the
thing that your all of your CPUs do to
something called Cindy single
instruction multiple data which is yours
your CPU is capable of taking eight
things at a time right in a vector and
adding them up to another vector with
eight things in in a single CPU
instruction right so if you can take
advantage of Sim D you're immediately
eight times faster it depends on how big
the data type is it might be four might
be eight the other thing that you've got
in your computer is you've got multiple
processes multiple cores so you've
probably got like if this is inside
happening on one side one core
you've probably got about four of those
okay so if you're using Cindy your eight
times faster if you can use multiple
cores than your 32 times faster and then
if you're doing that in C you might be
something like 32 times per thousand
times faster right and so the nice thing
is that when we do that it's taking
advantage of all of these things okay
better still if you do it in PI torch
and your data was created with CUDA to
stick it on the GPU then your GPU can do
about 10,000 things at a time all right
so that'll be another hundred times
faster than C all right so this is
critical to getting good performance is
you have to learn how to write
Lewis code by taking advantage of these
element-wise operations and like it's
not it's a lot more than just plus I can
also use less then right and that's
going to return 0 1 1 or if we go back
to numpy false true true and so you can
kind of use this to do all kinds of
things without looping so for example I
could now multiply that by a and here
are all of the values of a as long as
they're less than B or we could take the
mean this is the percentage of values in
AE that are less than B all right so
like there's a lot of stuff you can do
with this simple idea but to take it
further
right to take it further than just this
element wise operation we're going to
have to go the next step to something
called broadcasting so let's take a
five-minute break come back at 2:17 and
we'll talk about broadcasting so
broadcasting this is the definition from
the numpy documentation of broadcasting
and I'm going to come back to it in a
moment rather than reading it now but
let's start by looking an example of
broadcasting so a is a array with one
dimension also known as a Rank 1 tensor
also known as a vector we can say a
greater than 0 so here we have a Rank 1
tensor right and a rank 0 tensor right a
rank 0 tensor is also called a scalar
the rank 1 tensor is also called a
vector
and we've got an operation between the
two all right now you've probably done
it a thousand times without even
noticing that's kind of weird right that
you've got these things of different
ranks and different sizes so what is it
actually doing right but what it's
actually doing is it's taking that
scaler and copying it here-here-here
right and then it's actually going
element-wise tan is greater than zero
six is greater than zero minus pore is
greater than zero you have been giving
us back the three answers right and
that's called broadcasting broadcasting
means copying one or more axes of my
tensor to allow it to be the same shape
as the other tensor it doesn't really
copy it though what it actually does is
it stores this kind of internal
indicator that says pretend that this is
a vector of three zeros but it actually
just like rather than kind of going to
the next row we're going to the next
scaler it goes back to where it came
from if you're interested in learning
about this specifically it's they set
the stride on that axis to be zero
that's a minor advanced concept for
those who procures so we could do a plus
one right it's going to broadcast the
scalar 1 to be 1 1 1 and then do element
wise addition if we could do the same
with a matrix right here's our matrix 2
times the matrix is going to broadcast
to to be to to to to to to to to to
and then do element wise multiplication
right so that's our kind of most simple
version of broadcasting
so here's a slightly more complex
version of broadcasting here's an array
called C right so this is a rank one
tensor and here's our matrix M from
before rank two tensor we can add M plus
C alright so what's going on here one
two three four five six seven eight nine
that's M all right and then C 10 20 30
you can see that what it's done is to
add that to each row right 11 22 33 14
25 36 and so we can kind of figure it
seems to have done the same kind of idea
is broadcasting a scaler it's like made
copies of it and then it treats those
as if it's a rank two matrix and now we
can do element wise addition that make
sense right now that's yes can can you
pass that Devin over there thank you
so it's like by looking at this example
it like copies it done making new rows
so how would we want to do it if we
wanted to get new columns I'm so glad
you asked so instead we would do this 10
20 30 all right and then copy that
10 20 30 10 20 30 and now treat that as
our matrix so to get numpy to do that we
need to not pass in a vector but to pass
in a matrix with one column a rank two
tensor right so basically it turns out
that numpy is going to think of a rank 1
tensor for these purposes as if it was a
rank two tensor which represents a row
right so in other words that it is 1 by
3 all right so we want to create a
tensor which is 3 by 1 there's a couple
of ways to do that one is to use NP
expand imps and if you then pass in this
argument it says please insert a length
1 axis here please so in our case we
want to turn it into a 3 by 1 so if we
said expanding c comma 1
okay so if we say expanding C comma one
it changes the shape to three comma one
so if we look at what that looks like
that looks like a column okay so if we
now go that plus M you can see it's
doing exactly what we hoped it would do
alright which is to add ten twenty
thirty to the column ten twenty thirty
to the column ten twenty thirty to the
column okay now because the location of
a unit axis turns out to be so important
it's really helpful to kind of
experiment with creating these extra
unit axes and know how to do it easily
and MP dot expand ins isn't in my
opinion the easiest way to do this the
easiest way the easiest way is to index
into the tensor with a special index
none and what none does is it creates a
new axis in that location of length one
right so this is going to add a new axis
at the start of length one this is going
to add a new axis at the end at length
one or why not they're both right so if
you think about it like a tensor which
has like three things in it could be of
any rank you like right you can just add
you know taxis all over the place and so
that way we can kind of decide how we
want our broadcasting to work so there's
a pretty convenient thing in numpy
called broadcast - and what that does is
it takes our vector and broadcasts it to
that shape and shows us what that would
look like
right so if you ever like unsure of
what's going on in some broadcasting
operation you can save broadcast too and
so for example here we could say like
rather than three comma three we could
say MJ right and see exactly what's
happening gonna happen and so that's
what's gonna happen before we add it to
em right so if we said turn it into a
column that's what that looks like makes
sense so that's kind of like the
intuitive definition of broadcasting and
so now hopefully we can go back to that
numpy documentation and understand what
it means right
broadcasting describes how numpy is
going to treat arrays of different
shapes when we do some operation right
the smaller array is broadcast across
the larger array by smaller array they
mean lower rank tensor basically our
broadcast across the light the higher
rank tensor so they have compatible
shapes it vector eise's array operation
so vectorizing generally means like
using sim D and stuff like that so that
multiple things happen at the same time
all the looping occurs in C but it
doesn't actually make needless copies of
theta
it kind of just acts as if it had okay
so there's our definition now in deep
learning you very often deal with
tensors of rank four or more and you
very often combine them with tensors of
rank one or two and trying to just rely
on intuition to do that correctly as
nearly impossible so you really need to
know the rules so here are the rules
okay here's my shop here's C dot shape
so the rule are that we're going to
compare the shapes of our two tensors
element-wise we're going to look at one
at a time and we're going to start at
the end all right so look at the
trailing dimensions and then go towards
the front
okay and so two dimensions are going to
be compatible when one of these two
things is true right so let's check
right we've got our our M&amp;C compatible m
is 3 3 c is 3 right so we're going to
start at the end trailing dimensions
first and check are they compatible
they're compatible if the dimensions are
equal okay so these ones are equal so
they are compatible right all right
let's go to the next one uh-oh we're
missing all right C is missing something
so what happens if something is missing
as we insert a 1 okay that's the rule
all right and so let's now check are
these compatible one of them is one yes
they're compatible okay so now you can
see why it is that numpy treats the one
dimensional array as if it is a rank two
tensor which is representing a row it's
because we're basically inserting a one
at the front okay so that's the rule so
for example this is something that you
very commonly have to do which is you
start with like an image there like 256
pixels by 256 pixels by 3 channels and
you want to subtract the mean of each
channel right so you've got 256 by 256
by 3 and you want to subtract something
of length 3 right so yeah you can do
that absolutely because 3 &amp; 3 are
compatible because they're the same
right 256 and empty is compatible it's
going to insert a 1 256 and empty is
compatible it's going to insert of 1
okay so you're going to end up with this
is going to be broadcast over all of
this access and then that whole thing
will be broadcast over this access and
so we'll end up with a 256 by 256 by 3
effective tensor here
right so interestingly like very few
people in the data science or machine
learning communities understand
broadcasting and the vast majority of
the time for example when I see people
doing pre-processing for computer vision
like subtracting the mean they always
write loose over the channels right and
I kind of think like it's it it's like
so handy to not have to do that and it's
often so much faster to not have to do
that so if you get good at broadcasting
you'll have this like super useful skill
that very very few people have and and
like it's it's it's an ancient skill you
know it goes it goes all the way back to
the days of APL so APL was from the late
50s stands for a programming language
and Kenneth Iverson wrote this paper
called notation as a tool for thought in
which he proposed a new math notation
and he proposed that if we use this new
math notation it gives us new tools for
thought and allows us to think things we
couldn't before and one of his ideas was
broadcasting not as a computer
programming tool but as a piece of math
notation and so he ended up implementing
this notation as a tool for thought as a
programming language called APL and his
son has gone on to further develop that
into a piece of software called J which
is basically what you get when you put
sixty years of very smart people working
on this idea and with this programming
language you can express very complex
mathematical ideas often just where the
line of code or two and so I mean it's
great that we have J but it's even
greater that these ideas have found
their ways into the languages we all use
like in Python the numpy and pi torch
libraries all right these are not just
little
kind of niche ideas is like fundamental
ways to think about math and to do
programming let me give an example of
like this kind of notation as a tool for
thought let's let's look here we've got
C right here we've got C none right
notice this is now up to square brackets
right so this is kind of like a one row
vector tensor here it is a little column
so what is round ones okay what's that
gonna do ever think about it
anybody want to have a go can't even
talk through your thinking okay can we
pass the check over there thank you yes
absolutely so take us through your
thinking how's that going to work so the
diagonally lumens can be directly
visualized from the squares then cross
1020 clothes 20 and 30 plus 30 and if
you multiply the first row for this
column you get the first row of the
matrix mm-hmm so finally we will get our
3 cross 3 matrix yeah and so to think of
this in terms of like those broadcasting
rules we're basically taking this column
right which is a rank 3 comma 1 right
and this kind of roll sorry have
dimension 3 comma 1 and this row which
is of dimension 1 comma 3 right and so
to make these compatible with our
broadcasting rules right this one here
has to be duplicated 3 times because it
needs to match this
okay and now this one's going to have to
be duplicated three times to match this
okay and so now I've got two matrices to
do an element-wise product of and so as
you say there is that outer product
right now the interesting thing here is
that suddenly now that this is not a
special mathematical case but just a
specific version of the general idea of
broadcasting we can do like and out a
plus or we can do an order greater than
right or whatever right
so it's suddenly we've kind of got this
this this concept that we can use to
build new ideas and then we can start to
experiment with those new ideas and so
you know interestingly
numpy actually uses this sometimes for
example if you want to create a grid
this is how numpy does it all right
actually this is kind of the sorry let
me show you this way if you want to
create a grid this is how numpy does it
it actually returns zero one two three
four and zero one two three four one is
a column one is a row so we could say
like okay that's X grid comma Y grid and
now you could do something like row I
mean we could obviously go
like that right and so suddenly we've
expanded that out into a grid right and
so yeah it's kind of interesting how
like some of these like simple little
concepts kind of get built on and built
on and built on so if you lose something
like APL or J it's this whole
environment of layers and layers and
layers of this we don't have such a deep
environment in numpy but you know you
can certainly see these ideas of like
broadcasting coming through in in simple
things like how do we create a grid in
non-pay so yeah so that's that's
broadcasting and so what we can do with
this now is use this to implement matrix
multiplication ourselves ok now why
would we want to do that well obviously
we don't write matrix multiplication has
already been handled perfectly nicely
for us by our libraries but very often
you'll find in all kinds of areas in in
machine learning and particularly in
deep learning that there'll be
particular types of linear function that
you want to do that aren't quite done
for you right so for example there's
like whole areas called like tensor
regression and tensor decomposition
which are really being developed a lot
at the moment and they're kind of
talking about like how do we take like
higher rank tensors and kind of turn
them into combinations of rows columns
and faces and it turns out that when you
can kind of do this you can basically
like deal with really high dimensional
data structures with not much memory and
not with not much computation time for
example there's a really terrific
library called tensile e which does a
whole lot of this kind of stuff for you
so it's a really really important area
it covers like all of deep learning lots
of modern machine learning in general
and so even though you're not going to
like define matrix multiplication you're
very likely to wanted to find some other
slightly different tensor product you
know so it's really useful to kind of
understand how to do that so let's go
back and look at our matrix and our our
2d array in 1d array rank two tensor
rank 1 tensor and remember we can do a
matrix multiplication using the @ sign
or the old way and PMML okay and so what
that's actually doing when we do that is
we're basically saying ok 1 times 10
plus 2 times 20 plus 3 times 30 is 140
right and so we do that for each row and
we can go through and do the same thing
for the next one and for the next one to
get our result right you could do that
in torch as well we could make this a
little shorter
okay same thing okay but that is not
matrix multiplication what's that okay
element wise specifically we've got a
matrix and a vector so broadcasting okay
good so we've got this is element wise
with broadcasting but notice the numbers
it's created 10 40 90 are the exact
three numbers that I needed to calculate
when I did that first piece of my matrix
multiplication so in other words if we
sum this over the columns which is axis
equals 1 we get our matrix vector
product okay so we can kind of do this
stuff without special help from our
library so now let's expand this out to
a matrix matrix product so a matrix
matrix product looks like this this is
this great site called matrix
multiplication XYZ and it shows us this
is what happens when we multiply two
matrices okay
that's what matrix multiplication is
operationally speaking so in other words
what we just did there was we first of
all took the first column with the first
row to get this one and then we took the
second column with the first row to get
that one right so we're basically doing
the thing we just did the matrix vector
product we're just doing it twice right
once with this column and once with this
column and then we concatenate the two
together okay so we can now go ahead and
do that like so M times the first column
dot some M times the second column
that's some and so there are the two
columns of our matrix multiplication
okay so I didn't want to like make our
code too messy so I'm not going to
actually like use that but like we have
it there now if we want to we don't need
to use torch or numpy matrix
multiplication anymore we've got we've
got our own that we can use using
nothing but element wise operations
Broadcasting and some okay so this is
our logistic regression from scratch
class again I just copied it here here's
where we instantiate the object copy to
the GPU we create an optimizer which
we'll learn about in a moment and we
call fit okay so the goal is to now
repeat this without needing to call fit
so to do that we're going to need a loop
which grabs a mini batch of data at a
time and with each mini batch of data we
need to pass it to the optimizer and say
please try to come up with a slightly
better set of predictions for this mini
batch right so as we learnt in order to
grab a mini batch of the training set at
a time we have to ask the model data
object for the training data loader we
have to wrap it an iterator to create an
iterator or a generator and so that
gives us our our data loader
okay so PI torch calls this a data
loader we actually wrote our own class
today as a loader but it's it's all it's
basically the same idea
and so the next thing we do is we grab
the X and the y tensor the next one from
our data loader okay wrap it in a
variable to say I need to be able to
take the derivative of the calculations
using this because if I can't take the
derivative then I can't get the
gradients and I can't update the weights
all right and I need to put it on the
GPU because my module is on the GPU and
so we can now take that variable and
pass it to the objects that we
instantiated our logistic regression
remember now module we can use it as if
it's a function because that's how
high-touch works and that gives us a set
of predictions as we saw on scene before
okay so now we can check the loss and
the loss we're defined as being a
negative log likelihood loss object okay
and we're going to learn about how
that's calculated in the next lesson and
for now think of it just like a root
mean squared error but for
classification problems so we can call
that also just like a function so you
can kind of see this it's very general
idea in pi torch that you know kind of
treat everything ideally like it's a
function so in this case we have a loss
negative log likelihood loss object we
could treat it like a function we pass
in our predictions and we pass in our
actuals all right again the actuals need
to be turned into a variable and put on
the GPU because the loss is specifically
the thing that we actually want to take
the derivative of right so that gives us
our loss and there it is that's our loss
to point four three okay so it's a
variable and because it's a variable it
knows how it was calculated all right it
knows it was calculated with this loss
function it knows that the predictions
were calculated with this network it
knows that this network consisted of
these operations and so we can get the
gradient automatically and so to get the
gradient
recall
I'll drop backward remember L is the
thing that contains our loss right so L
drop backward is is something which is
added to anything that's a variable you
even called drop backward and that says
please calculate the gradients okay
and so that calculates the gradients and
stores them inside that that the
basically for each of the weights that
was used it used each of the parameters
that was used to calculate that it's now
stored a dot grad well we'll see it
later
it's basically stored the gradient right
so we can then call optimizer dot step
and we're going to do this bit step
manually shortly and that's the bit that
says please make the weights a little
bit better right
and so what optimizer dot step is doing
is it saying like okay if you had like a
really simple function like this right
then what the optimizer does is it says
okay let's pick a random starting point
right and let's calculate the value of
the loss right so here's our parameter
here's our loss right let's take the
derivative right the derivative tells us
which way is down so it tells us we need
to go that direction okay and we take a
small step and then we take the
derivative again and we take a small
step derivative again take a small step
drove it again take a small step until
eventually we're taking such small steps
that we stop okay
so that's what gradient descent does
okay how big a step is a small step well
we basically take the derivative here so
let's say derivative there is like eight
right and we multiply it by a small
number like say 0.01 and that tells us
what step size to take this small number
here is called the learning rate and
it's the most important hyper parameter
to set right if you pick two smaller
learning rate
then your steps down are going to be
like tiny and it's going to take you
forever okay too big a learning rate and
your jump too far right and then you'll
jump too far and your diverge rather
than converge okay we're not going to
talk about how to pick a learning rate
in this class but in the deep learning
class we actually show you a specific
technique that very reliably picks a
very good learning rate so that's
basically what's happening right so we
calculate the derivatives and we call
the optimizer that does a step in other
words update the weights based on the
gradients and the learning rate we
should hopefully find that after doing
that we have a better loss than we did
before so I just really ran this and got
a loss here of 4.16
and after one step it's now 4.0 3 okay
so it worked the way we hoped it word
based on this mini batch it updated all
of the weights in our network to be a
little better than they were as a result
of which our loss went down okay
so let's turn that into a training loop
all right we're going to go through a
hundred steps grab one more mini batch
of data from the data loader calculate
our predictions from our network
calculate our loss from the predictions
and the actuals every 10 goes we'll
print out the accuracy just take the
mean of the whether they're equal or not
1 pi taut specific thing you have to 0
the gradients basically you can have
networks where like you've got lots of
different loss functions that you might
want to add all of the gradients
together right so you have to tell play
torch like when to set the gradients
back to zero right so this just says set
all the gradients to zero calculate the
gradients let's quote backward and then
take one step of the optimizer
so update the weights using the
gradients and the learning rate and so
once we run it you can see the loss goes
down and the accuracy goes up
okay so that's the basic approach and so
next lesson we'll see what that does
alright well we're looking in detail
we're not going to look inside here as I
say we're going to basically take the
calculation of the derivative says
that's a given right but basically
what's happening there in any kind of
deep network you have kind of like a
function that's like you know a linear
function and then you pass the output of
that into another function that might be
like a rally and you pass the output of
another linear net Lenny Olea you pass
that into another function that might be
another value and so forth right so at
these these deep networks are just
functions of functions of functions so
you could write them mathematically like
that right and so all backprop does is
it says let's just simplify this down to
the two version as we can say okay u
equals f of X right and so therefore the
derivative of G of f of X is we can
calculate with the chain rule as being G
- you f dash X right and so you can see
we can do the same thing for the
functions of the functions of the
functions and so when you apply a
function to a function of a function you
can take the derivative just by taking
the product of the derivatives of each
of those layers okay and in neural
networks we call this back propagation
okay so when you hear back propagation
it just means use the chain rule to
calculate the derivatives and so when
you see a neural network to find
like here right like if it's defined
sequentially literally all this means is
apply this function to the input apply
this function to that apply this
function to that apply this function to
that right so this is just defining a
composition of a function to a function
to a function to a function okay and so
yeah so although we're not going to
bother with calculating the gradients
ourselves you can now see why it can do
it right as long as it has internally
you know a it knows like what's the
what's the derivative of ^ what's the
derivative of sine what's the derivative
of + and so forth then our Python code
in here is just combining those things
together so it just needs to know how to
compose them together with the chain
rule and where it goes okay okay so I
think we can leave it there for now and
yeah and in the next class we'll go and
we'll see how to write our own optimizer
and then we'll have solved em mist from
scratch ourselves see you then