okay so welcome back so we're going to
start by doing some review and we're
going to talk about test sets training
sets validation sets and oob something
we haven't covered yet but we will cover
in more detail later is also cross
validation but I'm going to talk about
that as well right so we have a data set
with a bunch of rows in it and we've got
some dependent variable and so what's
the difference between my machine
learning and kind of pretty much any
other kind of work that the the
difference is that in machine learning
the thing we care about is the
generalization accuracy or the
generalization error where else in
pretty much everything else all we care
about is is how well we could have
mapped to the observations all stop and
so this this thing about generalization
is the key unique piece of with machine
learning and so if we want to know
whether we could doing a good job of
machine learning we need to do know
whether we're doing a good job of
generalizing if we don't know that we
know nothing right
by generalizing do you mean like scaling
being able to scale larger no III don't
mean scaling at all so scaling is an
important thing in many many areas it's
like okay we've got something that works
I'm on my computer with ten thousand
items I do need to work make it work on
ten thousand items per second or
something so scaling is important but
not just a machine learning for just
about everything we put in production
generalization is where I say okay here
is a model that can predict cats from
dogs I've looked at five pictures of
cats five pictures of dogs and I've
built a model that is perfect and then I
look at a different set of five cats and
dogs and it gets them all wrong so in
that case when it learned was not a good
Street a cat and a dog that it learned
what those five exact cats looked like
in those five exact dogs the play or I
built a model of predicting grocery
sales for a particular product so for
toilet rolls in New Jersey last month
and then I go and put it into production
and it scales great in other words it
can have the great latency I don't have
a high CPU load but it fails to predict
anything well other than toilet rolls in
New Jersey it also it turns out it only
did it well for last month not the next
month so these are all generalization
failures so the most common way that
people check for the ability to
generalize is to create a random sample
so they'll grab a few rows at random and
pull it out into a test set and then
they'll build all of their models on the
rest of the rows and then when they're
finished they'll check that the accuracy
they got on there so the rest of the
rows are called the training set
everything else everything
else we could call the training set and
so at the end of their modeling process
on the training set they got an accuracy
of 99 percent of predicting cats from
dogs at the very end they check it
against a test set to make sure that the
model really does generalize now the
problem is what if it doesn't right so
okay well I could go back and change
some hyper parameters do some data
augmentation and whatever else try to
create a more generalizable model and
then I'll go back again after doing all
that and check and it's still no good
and I'll keep doing this again and again
until eventually after fifty attempts it
does generalize but does it really
generalize because maybe all I've done
is accidentally found this one which
happens to work just for that test set
because I've tried 50 different things
right and so if I've got something which
is like right coincidentally 0.05 5
percent of the time they're not very
likely to accidentally get a good result
so what we generally do is we put aside
a second data set they'll get a couple
more of these and put these aside into a
validation set
it's an audacious set right and then
everything that's not in the validation
or tests is now training and so what we
do is we train a model check it against
the validation to see if it generalizes
do that a few times and then when we
finally got something we were like okay
we think this generalizes successfully
based on the validation set and then at
the end of the project we check it
against the test set yeah so basically
if I making this two layer test that
validation said if he gets one right the
other one wrong you're kind of
double-checking your errors it's
checking that we have an overfit to the
validation set so if we're using the
validation set again and again then we
could end up not coming up with a
generalizable sort of hyper parameters
and a set of private creditors that just
so happened to work on the training set
and the validation set so so if we
try 50 different models against the
validation set and then at the end of
all that we then check that against the
test set and it's still generalized as
well then we're kind of going to say
okay that's good we've actually come up
with generalizable model if it doesn't
then that's going to say okay we've
actually now overfit to the validation
set
at which point you're kind of in trouble
right because you don't you know you
don't have anything left behind right so
the idea is to use effective techniques
during the modeling so that so that
doesn't happen right but but if it's
going to happen you want to find out
about it like you need that test set to
be there because otherwise when you put
it in production and then it turns out
that it doesn't generalize that would be
a really bad outcome right you end up
with less people clicking on your ads or
selling less with your products or
providing car insurance to very risky
vehicles or whatever so just make sure
to need to ever check if the validation
set and the test antics is coherent or
you just keep tested so if you've done
what I've just done here which is to
randomly sample there's no particular
reason to check as long as there as long
as they're big enough right but we're
going to come back to your question in a
different context in just a moment now
another trick we've learned for renin
forests is a way of not needing a
validation set and the way what we
learnt was to use instead use the oob
era for the OO be scored and so this
idea was to say well every time we train
a tree in a random forest there's a
bunch of observations that are held out
anyway because that's how we get some of
the randomness and so let's calculate
our score for each tree based on those
held out samples and therefore the
forest by averaging the trees that that
each row was not part of training okay
and so the oob score gives us something
which is pretty similar to the
validation score but on average it's a
little less good can anybody either
remember or figure out why on average
it's a little less good quite a subtle
one don't give it to Kenji I'm not sure
but is it because you are treating like
you're doing every kind of probe
pre-processing on your tests and so the
OB score is reflecting the performance
on testing set no for the other piece
because not using the test set at all
the other Peace Corps is using the held
out rows in the training set at page
tree so I mean Z you are basically
testing each tree of some data from Z
training set yes so you are you have the
potential of over feeding with agents it
shouldn't cause overfitting because each
one is looking at a held out sample so
it's not an overfitting issue it's quite
a subtle issue
Enes through never trained aren't this
sample is from OB bootstrap samples they
also then you're never gonna grab 63% of
writes chance to OB is one minus 63
percent exactly yeah both you sure so
then if you know why would the score be
lower than the validation school and
then
that you're leaving sort of like a black
hole in the data that there's like there
two points you're never going to sample
and I'm not gonna be represented by the
model ah no that's not true though
because each tree is looking at a
different set right so that I won't be
so like we've got like I don't know
dozens of models right and a niche one
there's a different set of rows which
which happened to be held out right and
so when we calculate the oeob score for
like let's say row three we say okay row
three is in this tree this tree and
that's it and so we calculate the
prediction on that tree and for that
tree and we'd average those two
predictions and so with enough trees you
know each one has a 30 or so percent
chance
sorry forty or so percent chance that
the row is in that tree so if you have
fifty trees it's almost certain that
every row is going to be mentioned
somewhere did you have an idea term
which relevation said we can use the
whole forest to make the predictions but
here we cannot use the whole forest so
we cannot exactly see exactly so every
road is going to be using a subset of
the trees to make its prediction and
with less trees we know we get a less
accurate prediction so that's that's a
subtle one right and if you didn't get
it have a think during the week until
you understand why this is because it's
a really interesting test of your
understanding of random forests it like
why is our B score on average less good
and your validation is for they're both
using random subnet subsets anyway it's
really close enough right so why have a
validation set at all when you're using
random forests if it's a randomly chosen
validation set it's not strictly
speaking necessary but you know you've
got like four levels of things to test
right so you could like test on the oeob
when that's working well you can test on
the validation set you know and
hopefully by the time you check against
the test set there's going to be
surprises so that'll be one good reason
then what cattle do the way they do this
is kind of clever
while CAG will do is they split the test
set into two pieces a public and a
private and they don't tell you which is
rich so you submit your predictions to
cattle and then a random 30% of those
are used to tell you the leaderboard
score but then at the end of the
competition that gets thrown away and
they use the other 70% to calculate your
real score so what that's doing is that
you're making sure that you're not like
continually using that feedback from the
leaderboard to figure out some set of
hyper parameters that happens to do well
on the public that actually doesn't
generalize okay so it's a great test
like this is one of the reasons why it's
good practice to use cattle because at
the end of a competition at some point
this will happen to you and you'll drop
a hundred places on the leaderboard the
last day of the competition when they
use the private test set and say oh okay
that's what it feels like
to overfit and it's much better to
practice and get that sense there than
it is to do it in a company where
there's hundreds of millions of dollars
on the line okay so this is like the
easiest possible situation where you're
able to use a random sample for your
validation set why might I not be able
to use a random sample from my
validation set or possibly fail
in the case of something where we're
forecasting we can't randomly sample
because we need to maintain the temporal
ordering hello what is that because it
doesn't it doesn't make sense so in the
case of like an ARMA model I can't use
like I can't pull out random rows
because there's I'm thinking that
there's like a certain dependency or I'm
trying to model a certain dependency
that relies on like a specific lag turn
and if I randomly sample those things
then that lag term isn't there for me to
okay so it could be like a technical
modeling issue that like I'm using a
model that relies on like yesterday the
day before and the day before that and
if I randomly removed some things I
don't have yesterday and my model might
just fail okay that's true but there's a
more fundamental issue you want to pass
it to Tyler and it's a really good point
although you know in general we're going
to try to build models that are not
little more resilient than that
particularly with yet temporal order we
expect things that are close by in time
to be related to things close to them so
weeks so we destroy the water like if if
we destroy the order we really aren't
going to be able to use that this time
is close to this other time I don't
think that's true because I can pull out
a random sample for a validation set
and still keep everything nicely ordered
well lame reject things in the future
which we would require as much data
close to the hand alert okay that's true
I mean we could be like limiting the
amount of data that we have by taking
some of it out but my claim is stronger
my claim is that by using a random
validation set we could get totally the
wrong idea about our model Caribou wanna
have a try so if our data is imbalanced
for example we can if you're randomly
sampling it we can only
one class in our validation set so our
fitted model maybe that's true as well
so maybe you're trying to predict in a
medical situation who's going to die of
lung cancer and that's only one out of a
hundred people and we pick out a
validation set that we accidentally have
nobody that died of lung cancer that's
also true these are all good niche
examples but none of them quite say like
why could the validation set just be
plain wrong like give you a totally
inaccurate idea of whether this is going
to generalize and so let's talk about
and the closest is is what Tyler was
saying about time closeness in time the
important thing to remember is when you
build a model you're always you always
have a systematic error which is that
you're going to use the model at a later
time than the time that you built it
right like you're going to put it into
production by which time the world is
different to the world that you're in
now and even when you're building the
model you're using data which is older
than today anyway right so there's some
lag between the data that you're
building it on and the data that it's
going to actually be used on your life
and a lot of the time if not most of the
time that matters right so if we're
doing stuff in like predicting who's
going to buy toilet paper in New Jersey
and it takes us two weeks to put it in
production and we did it using data from
the last couple of years and by that
time you know things may look very
different right and particularly our
validation said if we randomly sampled
it right and it was like from a four
year period then the vast majority of
that data is going to be over a year old
right and it may be that the toilet
buying habits of folks in New Jersey may
have dramatically shifted maybe they've
got a terrible recession there now and
they can't afford a high-quality toilet
paper anymore or maybe they know their
paper making industry has gone through
the roof and suddenly you know they
they're buying what's more toilet paper
because it's so cheap or whatever right
so the world changes and therefore if
you use a random sample for your
validation set then you're actually
checking how good are you at predicting
things that are totally obsolete now but
how good are you at predicting things
that happened four years ago that's not
interesting okay so what we want to do
in practice anytime there's some temper
or peace is to instead say assuming that
we've ordered it by time all right so
this is old and this is new
that's our validation set okay or if we
you know I suppose actually do it
properly
that's how a validation set that's our
test set make sense right so here's that
training set and we use that and we try
and be able to model that still works on
stuff that's later in time than anything
the model was built on and so we're not
just testing generalization in some kind
of abstract sense but in a very specific
time sense which is it generalizes to
the future could you pass it to Suraj
please
so when we are as you said as you said
there is some temporal ordering in the
data so in that case is it wise to take
the entire full data for training or
only a few recent data set for
validation test or training training
yeah that's a whole other question all
right so how do you how do you get the
validation set to be good so I build a
random forest on all the training data
it looks good on the training data it
looks good on the oob right and this is
actually a really good reason to have OB
if it looks good on the OB that it means
you're not overfitting in a statistical
sense right like it's it's working well
on a random sample but then it looks bad
on the validation set so what happened
well what happened was that you you
somehow failed to predict the future
you're only predicted the past and so
Suraj had an idea about how we could fix
that would be okay well maybe we should
just train so like maybe we shouldn't
use the whole training set we should try
a recent period only and now it on the
downside we're now using less data so we
can create less rich models on the
upside it's it's more up-to-date data
and this is something you have to play
around with most machine learning
functions have the ability to provide a
weight that is given to each road solve
for example with a random forest rather
than bootstrapping at random you could
have a weight on every row and randomly
pick that row with some probability
right and we could like say here's our
like probability we could like pick a
curve that looks like that so that the
most recent rows have a higher
probability of being selected that can
work really well yeah it's it's
something that you have to try and and
if you don't have a validation set that
represents the future compared to what
you're training on you have no way to
know which of your techniques are
working how do you make the compromise
between amount of data versus recency of
data
so what I tend to do is is when I have
this kind of temporal issue which is
probably most of the time once I have
something that's working well on the
validation set
I wouldn't then go and just use that
model on the test set because the thing
that I've trained on is now like but you
know the test set is much more in the
future
compared to the training set so I would
then replicate building that model again
but this time I would combine the
training and validation sets together
okay and retrain the model and at that
point you've got no way to test against
a validation set so you have to make
sure you have a reproducible script or
notebook that does exactly the same
steps in exactly the same ways because
if you get something wrong then you're
going to find on the test set that
you've you've got a problem so so what
what I do in practice is I need to know
is my validation set a truly
representative of the test set so what I
do is I build five models on the
training set I build five models on the
training set and I try to have them kind
of vary in how good I think they are
right and then and then I score them my
five models on the validation set all
right and then I also score them on the
test set that so I'm not cheating so I'm
not using any feedback from the test set
to change my hyper parameters I'm only
using it for this one thing which is to
check my validation set so I get my five
scores from the test set and then I
check that they fall in a line okay and
if they don't then you're not going to
get good enough feedback from the
validation set so keep doing that
process until you're getting a line and
that can be quite tricky right sometimes
the the test set you know trying to
create something that's as similar to
the real-world outcome as possible it's
difficult right and when you're it kind
of in the real world the same is true of
creating the test set like the test set
has to be a close to production as
possible so like what's the actual mix
of customers that are going to be using
this how much time is there actually
going to be between when you build the
model and when you put it in production
how often you're going to be able to
refresh the model these are all the
things to think about when you build
that test set okay so you want to say
that first make five models on the
training data yeah and then dilute get a
straight-line relationship change your
validation and death set you can't
really change the test set generally so
this is assuming that the test sets
given it changed to change the
validation set so if you start with a
random sample validation set and then
it's all over the place and you realize
oh I should have picked the last two
months and then you pick the last two
months it's still going all over the
place in your eyes oh I should have
picked it so that's also from the first
of the month to the fifteenth of the
month and they'll keep going until
changing your validation set until you
found a validation set which is
indicative of your test set results
no sort of five models like he was
started maybe like just random data and
average and they just make it their own
yeah yeah yeah yeah maybe a exactly
maybe yeah I kind of five like not
terrible ones but you want some variety
and you also particularly want some
variety and like how well they might
generalize through time so one that was
trained on the whole training set one
that was trained on the last two weeks
one that was trained on the last six
weeks one which used as you know lots
and lots of columns and might have a fit
a bit more yeah so you kind of want to
get a sense of like oh if my validation
set fails to generalize temporarily I'd
want to see that if it fell to
generalize statistically I'd want to see
that sorry can you explain a bit more
detail what you mean by change your
validation set so it indicates the test
set like what does that look like
so posit so let's take the groceries
competition where we're trying to
predict the next two weeks of grocery
sales so possible validation sets that
Terrence and I played with was a random
sample the last month of data the last
two weeks of data and the other one we
tried was same day range one month
earlier so that the test set in this
competition was the first to the 15th of
August sorry if this 15 that maybe the
15 to the 30th of August so we tried
like a random sample as four years we
tried the 15th of July to the 15th of
August we tried the 1st of August to the
15th of August and we tried the 15th of
July to the 30th of July and so there
were four different validation sets we
tried and so with random you know our
kind of results were all over the place
with last month you know they were like
not bad but not great the last two weeks
there was a couple that didn't look good
but on the whole they were good and same
day range of months early
they've got a basically perfect line
that's the part I'm talking right there
what exactly are you comparing it to
from the test site I just confused what
you're creating that graph so for each
of those so for each of my so I build
five models right so there might be like
just predict the average do some kind of
simple group mean of the whole data set
do some group mean over the last month
of the data set build a read on forests
of the whole thing build a random forest
from the last three weeks on each of
those I calculate the validation score
and then I retrain the model on the
whole training set and calculate the
same thing on the test set and so each
of these points now she tells me how
about it ago in the validation set how
well did it go in the test set and so if
the validation set is useful we would
say every time the validation set
improves the test set should also score
should also improve yes so you just said
rate ring dreaming rich rings in
modeling on training and validations
yeah that was a step I was talking about
here so once I've got the validation
score based on just the training set and
then retrain it on the train and
validation and check against history
somebody else so just to clarify my test
set you mean submitting it to kaibaland
and checking the school if it's cattle
then your test set is Carol's
leaderboard in the real world the test
set is this third data set that you put
aside and it's that third data set that
having it reflect real world production
differences is the most important step
in a machine learning project
why is it the most important step
because if you screw up everything else
that you don't screw up that you're no
you screwed up right like if you've got
a good test set then you'll know you
screw it up because you screwed up
something else and you tested it and it
didn't work out and it's like okay
you're not going to destroy the company
right if you screwed up creating the
test set that would be awful right
because then you don't know if you've
made a mistake right you try to build a
model you test it on the test set it
looks good but the test set was not
indicative of real-world environment so
you don't actually know if you better
destroy the company right now hopefully
you've got ways to put things into
production gradually so you won't
actually destroy the company but you'll
at least destroy your reputation at work
right it's like Oh Jeremy tried to put
this thing into production and in the
first week the cohort we tried it on
their sales halved and we're never
better give Jeremy machine-learning job
again right but if Jeremy had used a
proper test set then like he would have
known oh this is like half as good as my
validation set said it would be I'll
keep trying right and now I'm not going
to get in any trouble I was actually
like Oh Jeremy is awesome he identifies
ahead of time when there's going to be a
generalization problem okay so this is
like this is something that kind of
everybody talks about a little bit in
machine learning classes but often it
kind of stops at the point where you
learned that there's a thing in SK learn
called make test trains flipped and it
returns these things and off you go
right but the fact that like or here's
the cross-validation function right so
the fact that these things always give
you random samples tells you that like
much if not most of the time you
shouldn't be using them the fact that
random forest gives you an oo B for free
it's useful but it only tells you that
this generalizes in a statistical sense
not in a practice
since right so then finally there's
cross-validation right which
outside of class you guys have been
talking about a lot which makes me feel
somebody's been over emphasizing the
value of this technique so I'll explain
what cross-validation is and then I
explain why you probably shouldn't be
using it most of the time so cross
validation says let's not just pull out
one validation set but let's pull out
five say so let's assume that we're
going to randomly shuffle the data first
all right this is critical right we
first randomly shuffle the data and then
we're going to split it into five groups
and then for model number one we'll call
this the validation set and we'll call
this the training set okay and we'll
train and we'll check against the
validation and we'll get some rmse R
squared whatever and then we'll throw
that away
and we'll call this the validation set
and we'll call this the training set and
we'll get another score we'll do that
five times and then we'll take the
average okay so that's a
cross-validation average accuracy so who
can tell me like a benefit of using
cross-validation over a the kind of
standard validation set I talked about
before how could you pass the phone if
you have a smokiness an chosen course
validation will make you solve with a
data you have yeah you can use all of
the data you don't have to put anything
aside and you kind of get a little
benefit as well in that like you've now
got five models that you could ensemble
together each one of used which used 80%
of the data so you know sometimes that
ensemble lane can be helpful
I'm fun could you tell me like what what
could be some reasons that you wouldn't
use cross-validation we have enough data
so we don't not want the validations and
to be included in the model trainings
process - - like - okay yeah I'm not
sure the cross-validation is necessarily
polluting the model what would be a key
like downside of cross-validation but
like for deepening if you have learned
them P be chosen as annual Network will
know the pictures it's more likely to
predicative as is right so sure but if
we if we put aside some data each time
in the cross-validation can you pass it
to Suraj I'm not so worried about like I
don't think there's like one of these
validation sets is more statistically
accurate yes Suraj Steven will you be
all fitting together late I think that's
what fun was worried about I don't see
why that would happen like each time
we're fitting a model just 100 each time
we're fitting a model we are absolutely
holding in 20 percent of the sample
right so yes the five models between
them have seen all of the data but but
it's kind of like a random forest
independence is a lot like a random
first each model has only been trained
on a subset of the data yes you should
see please David largely received like
it is deep load of time oh yes exactly
right so we have to fit five models
rather than one so here's a key downside
number one it's time and so if we're
doing deep learning and it takes a day
to run suddenly it takes five days or we
need five GPUs okay
what about my earlier issues about
validation sets Jona pass it over there
what's remaining was a so if you had
like
temporal data wouldn't you be like
shuffling when you e breaking that
relation
well we could unravel it afterwards we
could reorder it like we could shuffle
get the training set out and then sort
it by time
like and like this presumably there's a
date column there so I don't think I
don't think it's going to stop us from
building a model did you have with
cross-validation your building five even
validation sets and if there is some
sort of structure that you're trying to
capture in your validation sets of Mary
your test set you're essentially just
throwing that a chance to construct that
yourself right I think you're gonna say
that I think you said the same thing as
I'm gonna say which is which is that our
earlier concerns about why random
validation sets are a problem are
entirely relevant here well these
validation sets a random so if a random
validation set is not appropriate for
your problem most likely because for
example of temporal issues then none of
these four validation set of five
validation sets are any good they're all
random right and so if you have temporal
data like we did here there's no way to
do cross validation really or like
probably no good way to do cross
validation I mean you're wanna have your
validation set be as close to the test
set as possible and so you can't do that
by randomly sampling different things so
so as fone said you may well not need to
do cross validation because most of the
time in the real world we don't really
have that little data right unless your
data is based on some very very
expensive labeling process or some
experiments that take a look cost a lot
to run or whatever but nowadays that's
data scientists are not very often doing
that kind of work some um in which case
this is an issue
it must have assigned so we probably
don't need to as nishan said if we do do
it it's going to take a whole lot of
time all right and then as earnest said
even if we did do it and we took up all
that time it's like it was totally the
wrong answer because random validation
sets are inappropriate for a problem
okay so I'm not going to be spending
much time on cross validation because I
just I think it's an interesting tool to
have it's easy to use Sosuke learn has a
cross validation thing you can go
ahead and use but it's it's it's not
that often that it's going to be an
important part of your toolbox in my
opinion you'll come up some points okay
so that is validation tips so then the
other thing we started talking about
last week and got a little bit stuck on
because I screwed it up was tree
interpretation so I'm actually going to
cover that again without the error and
dig into it in a bit more detail so can
anybody tell me what tree interpreter
does and how it does it
what do you remember it's a difficult
one to explain I don't think I did a
good job of explaining it so don't worry
if you don't do a great job but does
anybody wanna have a go explaining it
well okay that's fine so let's start
with the output of tree interpreter so
if we look at a single model a single
tree in other words here is a single
tree okay
so to remind us the top of a tree is
before there's been any split at all so
ten point one eight nine is the average
log price of all of the options in our
training set so I'm going to go ahead
and draw right here
ten point one a nine eight nine is the
average of all okay and then if I go a
couple of system less than or equal to
0.5 then I get ten point three four five
okay so for this subset of 16,800
coupler is less than or equal to point
five the average is ten point three four
five and then off the people with a
couple of system less than or equal to
point 5 we then take the subset we're
enclosure at less than or equal to two
and the average there of rob sale price
is nine point nine five five against
nine point nine five and then final step
in our tree
as model ID just for this group with no
capitalist system with enclosed lesson
or - then let's just take model ID less
than or equal to forty five seventy
three and that gives us ten point two
two six okay so then we can say all
right starting with ten point one oh
nine one eight nine average for
everybody in our training set for this
particular tree subsample of twenty
thousand adding in the capital decision
or couple or less than a two point five
increased our prediction by point one
five six so if we predict it with a
naive model of just the mean that would
have been ten point when I known adding
in just the coupler decision would have
changed it to ten point three four five
so this variable is responsible for a
point one five six increase in a
prediction from that the enclosure no
decision was responsible for a - point
three nine five decrease the model ID
was responsible for eight point two
seven six increase until eventually that
was our final decision that is our
prediction for this option of this
particular sale price so we can draw
that as what's called a waterfall block
right and what our four plots are one of
the most useful plots I know about and
weirdly enough there's nothing in Python
to do them and this is one of these
things where there's this disconnect
between like the world of management
consulting and business where everybody
uses water for plots all the time and
like academia who have no idea what
these things are but like every time
like you're looking at say here is last
year's sales for Apple and then there
was a change in that iPhones increased
by this amount
max decreased by that amount and iPads
increased by that amount
every time you have a starting point in
a number of changes and a finishing
point waterfall charts are pretty much
always the best way to show it so here
our prediction for price based on
everything ten point one eight nine
there was an increased blue means
increase of 0.156 the coupler decrease
of 0.395 or enclosure increase
model ID of point two seven six so
decrease but I increase decrease
increase to get to our final ten point
two six six so you see how what a porch
light works so with Excel 2016 its
built-in you just click insert waterfall
chart and there it is if you want to be
a hero
create a waterfall chart package format
plot lab put it on pip and everybody
will love you for it there are some like
really crappy gist's and manual
notebooks and stuff around these are
actually super easy to build like you
basically do a stacked column plot where
the the bottom of this is like all white
right like you can kind of do it but if
you can wrap that up or all and put the
data the points in the right spots and
color them nicely that would be totally
awesome I think you've all got the
skills to do it and would make you know
be a terrific thing for your portfolio
so there's an idea could make an
interesting cattle Colonel even like
here's how to build a waterfall plot can
scratch and by the way I've been putting
this up on yep you can all use it so in
general therefore obviously going from
the all and then going through each
change then the some both all of those
is going to be equal to the final
prediction so that's how we could say if
we were just doing a decision tree then
you know you're coming along and saying
like how come this particular option was
this particular price and it's like well
your prediction for it and like oh it's
because of these three things had these
three impacts right so for a random
forest we could do that across all of
the trees right so every time we see
coupler we add up that change every time
we see enclosure we add up that
change every time we see model we add up
that change okay and so then we combine
them all together we get what tree
interpreter does right so you could go
into the source code for tree
interpreter right and it's not at all
complex logic or you could build it
yourself and you can see how it does
exactly this so when you go tree and
predict with a random forest model for
some specific option so I've got a
specific row here this my zero index row
it tells you okay this is the prediction
the same as the random forest prediction
bias this is going to be always the same
it's the average sale price for for
everybody for each of the random samples
in the tree and then contributions is
the average of all so the total of all
our contributions for each time we see
that specific column appear in a tree
right so last time I made the mistake of
not sorting this correctly so this time
MP dot arc sort is a super handy
function at sorts it doesn't actually
sort contribution zero it just tells you
where each item would move to if it were
sorted so now by passing ID access to
each one of the column the level
contribution I can then print out all
those in the right order so I can see
here here's my column here's the level
and the contribution so the fact that
it's a small version of this piece of
industrial equipment meant that it was
less expensive right but the fact that
was made pretty recently meant that was
more expensive the fact that it's pretty
old however made that it was less
expensive right so this is not going to
really help you much at all with like a
cattle styled situation where you just
need predictions it's going to help you
a lot in a production environment or
even pre production right so like
something which any good manager should
you should do if you say here's a
machine learning model I think we should
use as they should go away and grab a
few examples of actual customers or
actual options or whatever and check
whether your model looks intuitive
alright and if it says like my
prediction is that you know lots of
if people are going to really enjoy this
crappy movie you know it is like wow
that was a really crappy movie then
they're going to come back to you and
say like explain why your models telling
me that I'm going to like this movie
because I hate that movie and then you
can go back and you say well it's
because you like this movie and because
you're this age range and you're this
gender on average actually people like
you did like that movie okay yeah
what's the second element of each temple
this is saying for this particular row
it was a mini and it was 11 years old
and it was a hydraulic excavator track 3
to 4 metric tons so it's just feeding
back and telling you it's because this
is actually what it was it was these
numbers so I just went back to the
original data to actually pull out the
descriptive versions of each one okay so
if we sum up all the contributions
together and then add them to the bias
then that would be the same as adding up
those three things adding it to this and
as we know from our waterfall chart that
gives us our final prediction this is a
almost totally unknown technique and
this particular library is almost
totally unknown as well so like it's a
great opportunity to you know show
something that a lot of people like it's
totally critical in my opinion but but
rarely none so that's
that's kind of the end of the random
forest interpretation piece and
hopefully you've now seen enough that
when somebody says we can't use modern
machine learning techniques because
they're black boxes that are
interpretive all you have enough
information to say you're full of
right like they're extremely
interpretable and the stuff that we've
just done you know trying to do that
with a linear model good luck to you you
know even where you can do something
similar with a linear model trying to do
it so that's not giving you totally the
wrong answer and you had no idea it's a
wrong answer it's going to be a real
challenge so the last step we're going
to do before we try and build up our own
random forest is deal with this tricky
issue of extrapolation so in this case
if we look at our tree let's look at the
accuracy of our most recent trees
we still have you know a big difference
between our validation score and our
training score the actually in this case
it's not too bad that the difference
between the oob and the validation is
actually pretty close so if there was a
big difference between validation and
olb like I'd be very worried about that
we've dealt with the temporal side of
things correctly let's just have a look
at I think the most recent model here it
was yeah so there's a tiny difference
right and so on Tagle at least you kind
of need that last decimal place in the
real world I probably stopped here but
quite often you'll see there's a big
difference between your validation score
and your OB score now I will show you
how you would deal with that
particularly because actually we know
that the the oeob should be a little
worse because it's using this less trees
so it gives me a sense that we should
get to do a little bit better and so the
reason we the way we should be able to a
little bit better is by handling the
time component a little bit better so
here's the problem with random forests
when it comes to extrapolation when you
when you've got a data set that's like
you know four got four years of sales
data in it and you create your tree
right and it says like oh if these if
it's in some particular store and at
some particular item and it is on
special you know here's the average
price and it actually tells us the
average price you know over the whole
training set which could be pretty old
right and so when you then want to step
forwards like what's going to be the
price next month it's never seen next
month and and where else with a kind of
a linear model it can find a
relationship between time and price
where even though we only had this much
day
when you then go and predict something
in the future it can extrapolate that
but a random forest can't do that
there's no wave if you think about it
for a tree to be able to say well next
month it would be higher still so
there's a few ways to deal with this and
we'll talk about it over the next couple
of lessons but one simple way is just to
try to avoid using time variables as
predictors if there's something else we
could use that's going to give us a
better
you know something that kind of a
stronger relationship that's actually
going to work in the future so in this
case what I wanted to do was to first of
all figure out
what's the difference between our
validation set and our training set like
if I understand that difference between
our validation set and our training set
then that tells me what are the
predictors which which have a strong
temporal component and therefore they
may be irrelevant by the time I get to
the future time period so I do something
really interesting which is I create a
random forest where my dependent
variable is is it in the validation set
right so I've gone back and I've got my
whole data frame with the training and
validation altogether and I've created a
new column Court is valid which I've set
to one and then for all of the stuff in
the training set I set it to zero that's
about a new column which is just is this
in the validation set or not and then
I'm going to use that as my dependent
variable and build a random first so
this is a random forest not to predict
price that protect is this in the
validation set or not and so if your
variables were not time dependent then
it shouldn't be possible to figure out
if something's in the validation set or
not this is a great trick in cattle
records in cattle they often won't tell
you whether the test set is a random
sample or not so you could put the test
set and the training set together create
a new column called is test and see if
you can predict it if you can you don't
have a random sample which means you
have to come and figure out how to
create a validation set from it right
and so in this case I can see I don't
have a random sample because my
validation set can be predicted with a
0.9999
r-squared and so then if I look at
future importance the top thing is sales
ID and so this is really interesting it
tells us very clearly sales ID is not a
random identifier but probably it's
something that's just set consecutively
as time goes on we just increase the
sales ID so elapsed that was the number
of days since the first date in our data
set so not surprisingly that also is a
good predictor interestingly machine ID
clearly each machine is being labeled
with some consecutive identifier as well
and then there's a big don't just look
at the order look at the value so 0.7
0.1 0.0 7.00 - okay stop right these top
three are hundreds of times more
important than the rest right so let's
next grab those top three right and we
can then have a look at their values
both from the training set and in the
validation set and so we can see for
example sales ID on average is divided
by thousand on averages 1.8 million in
the training set and 5.8 million in the
validation set right so you'd like you
can see just confirm like okay they're
very different so let's drop them okay
so after I drop them let's now see if I
can predict whether something's in the
validation set I still can with 0.98
pass quit
so once you remove some things then
other things can like come to the front
and it now turns out okay that's not
surprisingly age you know things that
are old are you know more likely I guess
to be in the validation set because
there's you know earlier on in the
training set yet they can't be old yeah
yeah made same reason so then we can
try removing those as well
and so once we let's see where do we go
up here yeah so what we can try doing is
we can then say alright let's take the
saleslady so let's machine ID from the
first one the age year made sale day of
year from the second one and say okay
these are all time dependent features so
I still want them in my random forest if
they're important right but if they're
not important then taking them out if
there are some other long-term dependent
variables that that work just as well
that would be better right because now
I'm going to have a model that
generalizes over time better so here I'm
just going to go ahead and go through
each one of those features and drop each
one one at a time okay retrain a new
random forest and print out the score
okay so before we do any of that our
score was
point eight eight for our validation
versus point eight 900 B and you can see
here when I remove sales ID my score
goes up and this this is like what we're
hoping for we've removed a time
dependent variable there were other
variables that could find similar
relationships without the time
dependency so removing it cost our
validation to go up now oob didn't go up
right because this is genuinely
statistically you're useful predictor
right but it's a time dependent one when
we have a time dependent validation set
so this is like really subtle but it can
be really important right it's trying to
find the things that gives you a
generalizable time across time
prediction and here's how you can see it
so it's like okay we should remove sales
ID for sure right but sale elapsed
didn't get better okay so we don't want
that machine ID did get better right
from eight eight eight to eight nine
three right so it's actually quite a bit
better
age got a bit better you made got worse
sale day of year got a bit better okay
so now we can say alright let's get rid
of the three where we know that getting
rid of it actually made it better okay
and as a result look at this we're now
up to nine one five okay so we've got
rid of three time dependent things and
now as expected validation is better
than our Obi
okay so that was a super successful
approach there right and so now we can
check the feature importance and let's
go ahead and say all right that was
pretty damn good
let's now leave it for a while so give
it a hundred and sixty trees don't show
it and see how that goes
okay and so as you can see like we did
all of our interpretation all of our
fine-tuning basically with smaller
models subsets and at the end we run the
whole thing you actually still only took
16 seconds and so we've now got an RMS
see of 0.21 okay so now we can check
that against cattle again we can't we
unfortunately this older competition
we're not allowed to enter anymore to
see how he would have gone so the best
we can do is check whether it looks like
we could have done we're all based on
their validation set so it should be in
the right area and yeah based on that we
would have come first
okay so you know I think this is an
interesting series of steps right so you
can go through the same series of steps
in your cattle projects and more
importantly your real-world projects so
one of the challenges is once you leave
this learning environment
suddenly you're surrounded by people who
they they've had not have enough time
they always want you to be in a hurry
they're always telling you you know do
this and then do that you need to find
the time to step away right and go back
because this is a genuine real-world
modeling process you can use and it
gives when I said kids world-class
results I mean it right like this guy
who won this lista costs sadly he's
passed away but he is the top kaggle
competitor of all time like he he won I
believe like dozens of competitions so
we can get a score even within cuy of
him then we are doing really really well
okay so let's take a five-minute break
and we're going to come back and build
our own random first I just wanted to
clarify something quickly a very good
point during the break was going back to
the change in R squared between here and
here it's not just due to the fact that
we removed these three predictors we
also went reset our F samples right so
they actually see the impact of just
removing we need to compare it to the
final step earlier so it's actually
compared to 907 so removing those three
things took us from 907
nine one five okay so I mean and you
know in the end of course what matters
is our final model that yep just to
clarify okay so um some of you have
asked me about writing your own random
forests from scratch I don't know if any
of you have given it a try
yet my original plan here was to do it
in real time and then as I started to do
it I realized that that would have kind
of been boring because to you because I
screw things up all the time so instead
we might do more of like a walk through
the code together
just as an aside this reminds me talking
about the exam hammock she somebody
asked on the forum about like what what
can you expect on the exam the basic
plan is to make it a exam be very
similar to these notebooks so it'll
probably be a notebook that you have to
you know get a data set create a model
trainer feature importance whatever
right and the plan is that it'll be open
block open Internet you can use whatever
resources you like so basically if
you're entering competitions the exam
should be very straightforward I also
expect that there will be some pieces
about like here's a partially completed
random forest or something you know
finish finish writing this step here or
here's a random forest implement feature
importance or in you know implement one
of the things we've talked about so it
open it you know the exam will be much
like what we do in class and what you're
expected to be doing during the week
there won't be any define this or tell
me the difference between this word and
that word or whatever there's not going
to be any rote learning it'll be
entirely like are you an effective
machine learning practitioner ie can use
the algorithms do you know can you
create an effective validation set and
can you can you create parts of the
algorithm implement them from scratch so
it'll be all about writing code
basically so if you're not comfortable
writing code to practice machine
learning then you should be practicing
that all the time if you are comfortable
you should be practicing that all the
time also whatever you're doing write
code to implement random to do machine
learning okay
so I I kind of have a particular way of
writing code and I'm not going to claim
it's the only way of writing code but it
might be a little bit different to what
you're used to and hopefully you'll find
it at least interesting
creating implementing random forest
algorithms is actually quite tricky not
because the codes tricky like generally
speaking
most random first algorithms are pretty
conceptually easy at all that generally
speaking academic papers and books have
a knack of making them look difficult
but they're not difficult conceptually
what's difficult is getting all the
details right and knowing and knowing
when you're right and so in other words
we need a good way of doing testing so
if we're going to reimplemented a we
want to create a random forest in some
different framework different language
different operating system you know I
would always start with something that
does exist right so in this case we're
just going to do is learning its
exercise writing a random forest in
Python so for testing I'm going to
compare it to an existing random forest
implementation okay so that's like
critical anytime you're doing anything
involving like non-trivial amounts of
code and machine learning knowing
whether you've got it right or wrong is
kind of the hardest fit I always assume
that I've screwed everything up at every
step and so I'm thinking like okay
assuming that I screwed it up how do I
figure out that I screwed it up
right and then much to my surprise from
time to time I actually get something
right and then I can move on okay but
most of the time I get it wrong so
unfortunately with machine learning
there's a lot of ways you can get things
wrong that don't give you an error they
just make your result like slightly less
good and so that's that's what you want
to pick up so given that I want to kind
of compare it to an existing
implementation I'm going to use our
existing data set our existing
validation set and then to simplify
things I'm just going to use two columns
to start with so let's go ahead and
start writing a random forest so my way
of writing nearly all code is top-down
just let my teaching and so if I
top-down I start by assuming that
everything I want already exists
so in other words the first thing I want
to do I'm going to call this a tree
ensemble right so to create a random
forest the first question I have is
what do I need to pass in right why I
need to initialize my random first so
I'm going to need some independent
variables some dependent variable pick
how many trees I want I'm going to use
the sample size parameter from the start
here so how big you want each sample to
be and then maybe some optional
parameter of what's the smallest leaf
size okay for testing it's nice to use a
constant random seed so we'll get the
same result each time so this is just
how you set a random seed okay maybe
it's worth mentioning is for those of
you unfamiliar with it random number
generators on computers aren't random at
all now actually constitute a random
number generators and what they do is
given some initial starting point in
this case 42 a pseudo-random number
generator is a mathematical function
that generates a deterministic always
the same sequence of numbers such that
those numbers are designed to be as
uncorrelated with the previous number as
possible okay
and as unpredictable as possible and as
uncorrelated as possible with something
with a different random seed so the
second number in in the sequence
starting with 42 should be very
different to the second number starting
with 41 and generally they involve kind
of like taking you know you know using
big prime numbers and taking mods and
stuff like that it's kind of an
interesting area of math if you want
real random numbers the only way to do
that is again you can actually buy
hardware called a hardware random number
generator that'll have inside them like
a little bit of some radioactive
substance and and like something that
detects how many things it's spitting
out or you know there will be some
hardware thing
any current system time is is it a valid
random like random number generation no
sense so that would be for maybe for a
random seed right so this thing of like
what do we start the function with so
one of the really interesting areas is
like in your computer if you don't set
the random seed what is it set to and
yeah quite often people use the current
time for security like obviously we use
a lot of random number stuff for
security stuff like if you're generating
an SSH key you need some it needs to be
random it turns out like you know people
can figure out roughly when you created
a key like they could look at like oid
RSA has a timestamp and they could try
you know all the different nanoseconds
starting points for a random number
generator around that time step and
figure out your key so in practice a lot
of like really random high randomness
requiring applications actually have a
step that say please move your mouse and
type random stuff at the keyboard for a
while and so it like gets you to be a
sort that's called entropy to be a
source of entropy other approaches is
they'll look at like you know the hash
of some of your log files or you know
stuff like that it's a really really fun
area so in our case our purpose actually
is to remove randomness
so we're saying okay generate a series
of pseudo-random numbers starting with
42 so it always should be the same so if
you haven't done much stuff in Python oo
this is a basically standard idiom at
least I mean I write it this way most
people don't but if you pass in like 1 2
3 4 5 things that you're going to want
to keep inside this object then you
basically have to say self dot x equals
x self dot y equals y self that sample
equals sample right and so we can assign
to a tuple from at a port so you know
okay this is like my way of coding most
people think this is horrible but I
prefer to be able to see everything at
once and so I know in my code anytime I
see something that looks like this it's
always all of the
stuff in the method being set if I did
it a different way than half the codes
now come off the bottom of the page and
you can't see it all right so um so that
was the first thing I thought about is
like okay to create a random forest what
information do you need then I'm going
to need to store that information inside
my object and so then I need to create
some treats
I had a random forest is something that
creates and is something that has some
trees so I fit basically figured okay
list comprehension to create a list of
trees how many trees do we have or you
put n trees trees that's what we asked
for so range entries gives me the
numbers from 0 up to n trees minus 1 ok
so if I create a list comprehension that
lips through that range calling create
tree each time I now have entries trees
and also I add to write that I didn't
have to think at all
like that's all like obvious and so I've
kind of delayed the thinking to the
point where it's like well wait we don't
have something to create a tree okay no
worries but let's pretend we did if we
did we've now created a random forest
okay we'd still need to like do a few
things on top of that for example once
we have it we need a predict function so
okay well let's write a prediction
function how do you predict in a random
forest can somebody tell me either based
on their own understanding or based on
this line of code what would be like
your one or two-sentence answer how do
you make a prediction in a random forest
positive Spencer
uh you would want to over every tree for
your like the row that you're trying to
predict on average the values that your
that each tree would produce for that
book good and so you know that's a
summary of what this says right so for a
particular row right or maybe this is a
number of rows go through each tree
calculate its prediction so here is a
list comprehension that is calculating
the prediction for every tree for X I
don't know if X is one row or multiple
rows it doesn't matter right
as long as as long as trade I predict
works on it and then once you've got a
list of things a cool trick to know is
you can pass numpy dot mean a regular
non mum pie list okay
and it'll take the mean you just need to
tell it access equals zero means everage
it across the lists okay so this is
going to return the average of that
predict for each tree and so I find list
comprehensions allow me to write the
code in the way that the brain was like
you could take the word Spencer said and
like translate them into this code or
you could take this code and translate
them into words like the one Spencer
said right and so when I write code I
want it to be as much like that as
possible all right I want it to be
readable and so hopefully you'll find
like when you look at the past AI code
you can understand how to journey
through X I try to write things in a way
that you can read it and like it kind of
turn it into English in your head
so if I say correctly that predict
method is recursive it's no it's calling
trade predict and we haven't written a
tree yet so self trees is going to
contain a tree object so this is tree
Ensemble dot predict and inside the
trees is a tree not a tree ensemble so
this is called an trade product not tree
ensemble dotted it
the question okay so we nearly finished
riding around and for our seventh week
all we need to do now is write create
tree right so um based on this code here
or on your own understanding of how we
create trees in a random forest can
somebody tell me let's take a few
seconds have a raid have to think and
then I'm going to try and come up with a
way of saying how do you create a tree
in a random forest
okay who wants to tell me yes
okay let's tireless work cluster
you take your you're essentially taking
a random sample or of the original data
and then you're just it just
constructing a tree however that happens
so construct a decision tree like a non
random tree from a random sample of the
data ok so again like we've delayed any
actual thought process here we've
basically said ok we could pick some
random IDs this is a good trick to know
if you call NP random permutation
passing in an inch it'll give you back a
randomly shuffled sequence from zero to
that inch right and so then if you grab
the first : n items of that that's now a
random subsample so this is not doing
bootstrapping we're not doing sampling
with replacement here which i think is
fine you know for my random forest I'm
deciding that it's going to be something
where we do subsampling not
bootstrapping
ok so here's a good line of code to know
how to write because it comes up all the
time like I find in machine learning
most algorithms I use are somewhat
random and so often I need some kind of
random sample can you pass that tartaric
entry won't they give you 1 1 extra
because the easier it will go from 0 to
length no so this will give you if lens
self dot y is of size n this will give
you n a sequence of length n so 0 to n
minus 1 and then from that I'm picking
out : self dot sample size so the first
sample size ladies I have a comment on
bootstrapping I think this method is
better because we have transfer giving
more weights to each observation or am I
thinking wrong I think you proposed
wrapping we could also give weights I
mean we
single observations more than they are
like without one thing that weights
because I'm bootstrapping with with
replacement we can have a single
observation and dr. pitz of it yeah the
same tree
yeah it just feel weird but I think
the actual theory or empirical results
backs up higher intuition that it's
worse it'd be interesting to look look
back at that actually personally I
prefer this because I feel like most of
the time we have more data than we want
to put a tree at once I feel like back
when Bremen created random forests it
was 1999 it was kind of a very different
world you know where we pretty much
always wanted to use all the data we had
but nowadays I would say that's
generally not what we want we normally
have too much data and so what people
tend to do is they'll like fire up a
spark cluster and they'll run it on
hundreds of machines when it makes no
sense because if they had just used a
subsample each time they could have done
it on one machine and like the the
overhead of like spark is a huge amount
of i/o overhead like I know you guys are
doing distributed computing now if you
if you've looked at some of the
benchmarks yeah yeah exactly so if you
do something on a single machine it can
often be hundreds of times faster
because you don't have all this this i/o
overhead it also tends to be easier to
write the algorithms like you can use
like SK learn easier to visualize and
cheaper so forth so like I almost always
avoid distributed computing and I have
my whole life like even 25 years ago
when I was studying in machine learning
I you know still didn't use clusters
because I so I always feel like whatever
I could do with a cluster now I could do
with a single machine in five years time
so one of us focus on always being as
good as possible with the single machine
you know and that's going to be more
interactive and more iterative and work
for me so ah okay so so again we've like
delayed thinking to the point where we
have to write decision tree and so
hopefully you get an idea that this
top-down approach that goal is going to
be that we're going to keep delaying
thinking so long that that we delay it
forever
like like eventually we've somehow
written the whole thing without actually
having to think right and that's that's
kind of what I need is I'm kind of slow
right so this is why I write code this
way and notice like you never have to
design anything in
you just say hey what if somebody
already gave me the exact API I needed
how would I use it okay and then and
then okay to implement that next stage
what would be the exact API I would need
to implement that right you keep going
down until eventually you're like oh
that already exists okay so this assumes
we've got a class port decision tree so
we're going to have to create that so a
decision tree is something so we already
know what we're going to have to pass it
because we just passed it right so we're
passing in a random sample of X's a
random sample of Y's
um
uhh
indexers is actually so we know that
down the track so I've got a plan a tiny
bit we know that a decision tree is
going to contain decision trees which
themselves contain decision trees and so
as we go down the decision tree there's
going to be some subset of the original
data that we've kind of got and so I'm
going to pass in the indexes of the data
that we're actually going to use here
okay so initially it's the entire random
sample all right so I've got the whole
team I've got the whole range and I turn
that into an array so that's 0 the
indexes from 0 to the size of the sample
and then what is passed down the mean
left side so everything that we got for
constructing the random forest where to
pass down the decision tree except of
course num trees which is irrelevant for
the decision tree so again now that we
know that's the information we need we
can go ahead and store it inside this
object so I'm pretty likely to need to
know how many rows we have in this tree
which I generally call n how many
columns do I have which I generally call
C so the number of rows is just equal to
the number of indexes well given and the
number of columns is just like however
many columns there are in our
independent variables so then we're
going to need this value here
we need to know for this tree
what's its prediction right so the
prediction for this tree is the mean of
our dependent variable or those indexes
which are inside this part of the tree
alright so at the very top of the tree
it contains all the indexes right I'm
assuming that by the time we've got to
this point remember we've already done
the random sampling right so when we
talk about indexes we're not talking
about the random sampling to create the
tree we're assuming this tree now has
some random sample inside decision tree
this is this is the one of the nice
things right inside decision tree hole
random sampling things gone right that
was done by the random forest right so
at this point we're building something
that's just a plain old decision tree
it's not in any way a random sampling
anything it's just a plain old position
tree right so the indexes is literally
like which subset of the data that we
got to so far in this tree and so at the
top of the decision tree it's all the
data right so it's all of the indexes
okay so all of the indexes so this is
therefore all of the dependent variable
that are in this part of the tree and so
this is the value mean of that that
makes sense
anybody could be any questions about
about that so ah yes hey pastor Chen Qi
actually just to let you know there's a
large portion of us don't have a over B
I mean all P experiments okay yeah sure
so so quick so quick over P prenup would
be helpful
great yeah okay
who is done object-oriented programming
in some programming language okay
so you've all used actually lots of
object-oriented programming in terms of
using existing classes right so every
time we've created a random forest we've
called the random forests constructor
and it's returned an object and then
we've called methods and attributes on
that object so fit is a method you can
tell because it's got parentheses after
it right where else yeah
oh I'll be score is a property or an
attribute doesn't have parentheses after
it okay
so inside an object there are kind of
two kinds of things there the functions
that you can call so you have object dot
function parentheses arguments or there
are the properties or attributes you can
grab which is object dot and then just
the attribute name no parentheses so
when and then the other thing that we do
with objects is we create them okay we
pass in the name of a class and it
returns us the object and you have to
tell it all of the parameters necessary
to get constructed so let's just copy
this code and see how we're going to go
ahead and build this so the first step
is we're not going to go n equals random
forest regressor we're going to go M
equals tree ensemble we're creating a
classical tree ensemble and we're going
to pass in
various bits of information okay so
maybe we'll have ten trees sample size
of a thousand or maybe a min leaf of
three okay and you can always like
choose to name your admits or not so
when you've got quite a few it's kind of
nice to name them so that just so we can
see what each one means it's always
optional so we're going to try and
create a class that we can use like this
and then the notional we're going to
bother with dot fit because we've passed
in the X and the y right like in
scikit-learn they use an approach where
first of all you construct something
without telling it what they did here is
and then you pass in the day we're doing
these two steps at once
we're actually passing in the data right
and so then after that we're going to be
going and dot so we're going to go creds
equals m predict passing in maybe some
validations there okay so we that's
that's the API we're kind of creating
here so this thing here is called a
constructor something that creates an
object is called a constructor and
Python there's a lot of ugly hideous
things about Python one of which is they
it uses these special magic method names
underscore underscore init underscore
underscore is a special magic method
that's caught it's called
when you try to construct a class so
when I call tree ensemble parentheses it
actually calls tree ensemble dot they
see people say dunder init I kind of
hate it but anyway timed it you know
double underscore in it double
underscore dunder init
so that's why we've got this method
called dunder init okay so when I call
tree ensemble is going to call this
method
another hideously ugly thing about
pythons oo is that there's this special
thing where if you have a class and to
create a class you just wrecked class in
the name of us all of its methods
automatically get sent one extra
parameter when extra arguments which is
the first argument and you can call it
anything you like if you call it
anything other than self everybody will
hate you and you're a bad person so call
it anything you like as long as it's
self so so that's why you always see
this and in fact I can immediately see
here I have a bug anybody see the bug in
my predict function I should have so
right I like it always do it right so
anytime you try and call a method on
your own class and you get something
saying you're passed in two parameters
and it was only expecting one you forgot
so okay so like this is a really dumb
way to add oh okay to a programming
language but the older languages like
Python often did this because they kind
of needed to they started out not being
oo and then they kind of added oo in a
way that was hideously ugly so Perl
which predates plaything by a little bit
kind of I think really came up with this
approach and unfortunately other
languages of that era stuck with it so
you have to add in this magic self so
the magic self now when you're inside
this class you can now pretend as if any
property name you like exists so I can
now pretend there's something called
self dot X I can read from it I can
write to it right but if I read from it
and I haven't yet written to it I'll get
an error so the stuff that's passed to
the constructor gets thrown away by
default like there's nothing that like
says you need to rip this class needs to
remember what these things are but
anything that we stick inside self is
remembered for all time you know as long
as this object exists you can access it
it's remembered so now that I've gone
in fact let's do this right so that
let's create the tree ensemble class and
let's now instantiate it okay of course
we haven't got X we need to call X train
y trade ok decision tree is not defined
so let's
we had a really minimal decision tree
there we go okay so here is enough to
actually instantiate our tree ensemble
okay so we have to find the inert for it
we have to find the inert for decision
tree we need decision trees in it to be
defined because inside our ensemble in
it they're called self directory and
then self create tree called the
decision tree constructor and then
decision tree constructor basically does
nothing at all other than save some
information right so at this point we
can now go m dot okay and if I press tab
at this point can anybody tell me what I
would expect to see press it to Taylor
tension could you possibly say like we
would see a drop-down of all available
methods for that class okay it would be
in this case so if M is a tree ensemble
we would have create tree and predict
okay anything else what
oh yeah as well as earnest whispered to
variables as well yeah so that the
variable could made a lot of things well
attributes so the things that we put
inside self so if I hit tab right there
they are right as Taylor said there's
create tree there's predict and then
there's everything else we put inside so
all right so if I look at m dot min leaf
if I hit shift enter what will I see yep
the number that I just put there I put
in leaf is three so that went up the air
dam in leaf this here is a default
argument such as if I don't pass
anything it'll be five but I did pass
something right so three self dot min
leaf here is it going to be equal to min
leaf yeah so something which like
because of this rather annoying way of
doing oh oh
it does mean that it's very easy to
accidentally forget so do that right so
if I don't assign it to self dot min
leaf right then I get an error and so
here tree ensemble doesn't happen in
leaf right so how do I create that
attribute
I just put something in it okay so if
you want to like if you don't know what
a value of it should be yet but you kind
of need to be able to refer to it you
can always feel like self dot min leaf
equals none that's at least there's
something you can read check for
numbness and not have an error great now
interestingly I was able to instantiate
tree ensemble even if I predict refers
to a method of decision tree that
doesn't exist and this is actually
something very nice about the dynamic
nature of Python is that because it's
not like compiling it it's not checking
anything unless you're using it right so
we can go ahead and create decision to
predict later
and then our our instantiated object
will magically start working right it
doesn't actually look up that functions
that methods details until you use it
and so it really helps with top-down
programming
okay so when you're inside a class
definition in other words you're at that
indentation level you know indented one
in so these are all class definitions
any function that you create unless you
do some special things that we're not
going to talk about yet is automatically
a method of that class and so every
method of that class magically gets a
self passed to it so we could call since
we've got a tree ensemble we could call
em create tree and we don't put anything
inside those parentheses because the
magic self will be passed and the magic
self will be whatever M is okay so m dot
create tree returns a decision tree just
like we asked it to right so m dot
create tree dot e excess will give us
the self ID access inside the decision
tree okay which is set to NP dot a range
range self dot sample size Y is data
scientists do we care about
object-oriented programming because a
lot of the stuff you use is going to
require you to implement stuff with oo P
for example every single PI torch model
of any kind is created with olp it's the
only way to create by torch models um
good news is what you see here is the
entirety of what you need to know so you
this is all you need to know you need to
know to create some in code in it to
assign the things to the pasta in it to
something call it self and then just
stick the word self after it give your
methods okay and so the nice thing is
like now to think as an AOP programmer
is to realize you don't now have to pass
around X Y sample size and min leaf to
every function that uses them by
assigning them to attributes itself
they're now available like magic all
right so this is why our peas super
handy
if you're particularly I started trying
to create a decision tree initially
without using oot and try to like keep
track of like what that decision tree
was meant to know about it was very
difficult you know where else with our P
you can just say even side the decision
tree you know self indexes equals this
and everything displace okay okay that's
great so we're out of time I think
that's that's great timing because
there's an introduction 200 P but this
week you know next class I'm going to
assume that you can use it right so you
should create some classes instantiate
some classes look at their methods and
properties have them call each other and
so forth until you feel comfortable with
them and maybe for those of you doesn't
haven't done our P before you can find
some other useful resources you could
flop them onto the wiki thread so that
other people know what you find useful
right thanks everybody