okay so last class of part one
I guess the theme of part one is
classification and regression with deep
wading and specifically it's about
identifying and learning the best
practices for classification and
regression and we started out with the
kind of here are three lines of code to
do image classification and gradually
we've been for the first four lessons
within kind of going through NLP
structured data collaborative filtering
and kind of understanding some of the
key pieces and most importantly
understanding you know how to actually
make these things work well in practice
and then the last three lessons are then
kind of going back over all of those
topics in kind of reverse order to
understand more detail about what was
going on and understanding what the code
looks like behind the scenes and wanting
to kind of write them from scratch part
two of the course we'll move from a
focus on classification and regression
which is kind of predicting a thing like
a number or or at most a small number of
things like a small number of labels and
we'll focus more on generative modeling
generative modeling means predicting
kind of lots of things
for example creating a sentence such as
in Ural translation or image captioning
or question-answering while creating an
image such as in style transfer
super-resolution segmentation and so
forth and then in part two it'll move
away from being just here are some best
practices you know established best
practices either through people that are
written papers or through research that
last day is done and it kind of got
convinced that these are best practices
to some stuff which would be a little
bit more speculative you know some stuff
which is maybe recent papers that
haven't been fully tested yet and
sometimes in part two like pickles will
come out in the middle of the course and
will change direction with the course
and study that paper because it's just
you know interesting and so if you're
interested in kind of learning a bit
more about how to read a paper and how
to implement it from scratch and so
forth then that's another good reason to
do part two it still doesn't assume any
particular math background but it does
beyond kind of high school but but it
does assume that you're prepared to
spend time like you know digging through
the notation and understanding it and
converting it to code and so forth all
right so we're we're up to is is our
intent at the moment and I think one of
the issues I find most with teaching
iron ends is trying to ensure that
people understand they're not in any way
different or unusual or magical they're
they're just a standard fully connected
Network and so let's go back to the
standard fully connected Network which
looks like this right so to remind you
the arrows represent one or more layer
operations generally speaking a linear
followed by a nonlinear function in this
case their matrix modifications followed
by real new raw or fan and the arrows of
the same color represent the same
exactly the same weight matrix being
used and so one thing which was just
slightly different from previous fully
connected networks we've seen is that we
have an input coming in at the not just
at the first layer but also for the
second layer and also at the third layer
and we tried a couple of approaches one
was concatenating the inputs and one was
adding the airport's okay but there was
nothing at all conceptually different
about this so that code looked like this
we had a model where we basically
defined the the three arrows colors we
had as three different weight matrices
okay and by using the linear
we got actually both the weight matrix
and the bias vector wrapped up for free
for us and then we went through and we
did each of our embeddings put it
through our first linear layer and then
we did each of our we call them hiddens
being the orange orange areas and in
order to avoid the fact that there's no
orange arrow coming into the first one
we decided to kind of invent an empty
matrix and that way every one of these
rows about the same right and so then we
did exactly the same thing except we
used to loop just to refactor the cutter
okay so it's just it was just a code
refactoring there was no change of
anything conceptually and since we were
doing a refactoring we took advantage of
that to increase the number of
characters to eight because I was too
lazy to type 8 when the alias but I'm
quite happy to change the loop in that
stage
yeah so this now looked through this
exact same thing but we had eight of
these rather than three so then we
refactored that again by taking
advantage of an end errand in which
basically puts that loop together for us
and keeps track of the this.h as it goes
along for us and so by using that we
were able to replace the loop with a
single call and so again that's just a
refactoring doing exactly the same thing
okay so then we looked at something
which was mainly designed to save some
training time which was previously we
had if we had a big piece of text right
so we've got like a movie review
but we were basically splitting it up
into eight character segments and we'd
grab like segment number one and use
that to predict the next character right
but in order to make sure that we kind
of used all of the data we didn't just
put it up like that we actually said
like okay here's our whole thing let's
grab the first will be to grab this
section the second will be to grab that
section in that section then that
section and each time would predict
predicting the next one character a lot
okay and so you know I was bit concerned
that that seems pretty wasteful because
like as we calculate this section nearly
all of it overlaps with the previous
section okay so instead what we did was
we said all right well what if we
actually did split it into
non-overlapping pieces right and we said
all right let's grab this section here
and use it to predict every one of the
characters one along right and then
let's grab this section here and use it
to predict every one of the characters
went along so after we look at the first
character in we try to predict the
second character and then now if we look
at the second character we try to
predict the third character and so okay
and so that's where you've got to and
then what if you perceptive folks asked
a really interesting question or
expressed their concern which was hey
after we got through the first the first
point here after we got through the
first point here we kind of withdrew
away our H activations and started a new
one which meant that when it was trying
to use character one to predict
character - it's got nothing to go on
you know it hasn't built it's only built
it's only done one linear layer and so
that seems like a problem which indeed
it is okay
so we're going to do the obvious thing
which is let's not throw away H okay so
let's not throw away that that matrix at
all
so in code the big problem is here but
every time we call forward so in other
words every time we do a new mini-batch
we're creating our our hidden state
right which remember is the orange
circles okay we're resetting it back to
a bunch of zeros and so as we go to the
next non-overlapping section we're
saying forget everything that's come
before but in fact the whole point is we
know exactly where we are we're at the
end of the previous section and about to
start the new next contiguous section so
let's not throw it away
so instead the idea would be to cut this
out right move it up to here okay store
it away in self and then kind of keep
updating it right now so we're going to
do that and there's going to be some
minor details to get right so let's
start by looking at the model so here's
the model it's it's nearly identical and
okay
here's the model it's nearly identical
but I've got as expected one more line
in my constructor where I call something
called init hidden and as expected in it
hidden sets self dot H to be a bunch of
zeros okay so that's entirely
unsurprising and then as you can see our
R and n now takes in self garage and it
as before spits out our new hidden
activations and so now the trick is to
now store that away inside self dot H
and so here's wrinkle number one if you
think about it if I was to simply do it
like like that right and now I train
this
on a document that's I don't know a
million words million characters long
then the size of this unrolled are a 10
is has a million circles here and so
that's fine going forwards right there
when I finally get to the end and I say
here's my character and actually
remember we're doing multi output now so
multi output looks like this right or if
we were to draw the unrolled version of
multi output we would have a triangle
coming off at every point okay so the
problem is that then when we do back
propagation we're calculating you know
how much does the error at character one
impact the final answer how much does
the error character to impact the final
answer and so forth and so we need to go
back through and say like how do we have
to update our weights based on all of
those you know errors and so if there
are our million characters my unrolled R
and N is a million layers long I have a
1 million layer fully connected Network
all right and like I didn't have to
write the million layers because I have
for loop and the for loops hidden away
behind that you know the self dot R and
n but it's still there right we so so
this is actually a 1 million layer fully
connected Network and so the problem
with that is it's going to be very
memory intensive because in order to do
the chain rule I have to be able to
multiply at every step like you know
after a few times she acts right and so
like I've got that means I have to
remember that those values you the value
of every set of layers so I'm gonna have
to remember all those million layers and
I'm going to do have to have to do a
million multiplications and I'm going to
have to do that every batch okay so that
would be bad so to avoid that we
basically say all right well from time
to time I want you to forget your
history okay so we can still remember
the state right which is to remember
like what's the
values in our hidden matrix right but we
can remember the state without
remembering everything about how we got
there
so there's a little function called
repackage variable which literally is
just this right it just simply says grab
the tensor out of it
right because remember the tensor itself
doesn't have any concept of history
right and create a new variable out of
that and so this variables going to have
the same value but no no history of
operations and therefore when it tries
to back propagate it all it'll stop
there
so basically what we're going to do then
is we're going to call this in our
forward so that means it's going to do
add characters it's going to back
propagate through eight layers it's
going to keep track of the actual values
in our hidden state but it's going to
throw away at the end of those eight
it's its history of operations so this
is this approach it's called back prop
through time and you know when you read
about it online people make it sound
like like a different algorithm or some
big insight or something but it's it's
not at all right it's just saying hey
after our for loop you know just throw
away your your history operations and
start afresh so we're keeping our hidden
state but we're not keeping our hidden
States history okay so that's that's
wrinkle number one that's what this
repackage bar is doing and so what do
you see
BP BP TT that's referring to that crop
through time and you might remember we
saw that in our original errand in
Lesson we had a variable called BP t t
equals 70 and so when we set that
they're actually saying how many layers
backprop through another good reason not
to back crop through too many layers is
if you have any kind of gradient
instability like gradient explosion or
gradients
banishing you know too many more of the
more layers you have the harder the
network s to Train so smaller and less
resilient on the other hand and longer
value for VP TT means that you're able
to explicitly capture a longer kind of
memory more state okay so that's a
that's something that you get to tune
when you create your area
all right wrinkle number two is how are
we going to put the data into this right
like it's all very well the way I
described it just now where we said you
know we could do this and we can first
of all look at this section then this
section in this section but we're going
to do a mini batch at a time right we
want to do a bunch at a time
so in other words we want to say let's
do it like this
so mini-batch number one would say let's
look at this section and predict that
section and at the same time in parallel
let's look at this totally different
section and predict this and at the same
time in parallel let's look at this
totally different section and predict
this right and so then because remember
in our in our hidden state we have a
vector of hidden state for everything in
our mini batch right so it's going to
keep track of at the end of this is
going to be a you know a vector here a
vector here a vector here and then we
can move across to the next one and say
okay so this part of the mini batch use
this to predict that and use this to
predict that and use this to predict
that right so you can see that we're
moving that we've got like a number of
totally separate bits of our text that
we're moving through in parallel right
so hopefully this is going to ring a few
bells for you because what happened was
was back when we started looking at
torch texture the first time we started
talking about how it creates these mini
batches and I said what happened was we
took our whole big long document
consisting of like you know the entire
works of nature or all of the IMDB
reviews concatenated together or
whatever and a lot of a lot of you not
surprisingly because this really said
this is really weird at first a lot of
you didn't quite hear what I said
correctly what I said was we split this
into 64 equal sized chunks and a lot of
your brains when Jeremy just said we
split this into chunks of size 64 but
that's not what Theresa Jeremy said we
split it into 64 equal sized chunks
right so if this whole thing was length
64 million right which would be a
reasonable sized corpus not an unusual
size corpus then each of our 64 chunks
would have been of length 1 million
right and so then what we did was we
talked the first chunk of 1 million and
we put it here
and then we took the second chunk of 1
million and we put it here
the third chunk of 1 million we put it
here and so forth to create 64 chunks
and then H mini-batch consisted of us
going let's split this down here and
here and here and each of these is of
size BP te T which I think we had
something like 70 right and so what
happened was we said alright let's look
at our first mini batch is all of these
right so we do all of those at once and
predict everything accrue off set by one
and then at the end of that first mini
batch we went to the second chunk right
and used each one of these to predict
the next one offset by one ok so that's
that's why we did that slightly weird
thing right is that we wanted to have a
bunch of things we can look through in
parallel each of which like hopefully a
far enough away from each other you know
that we don't have to worry about the
fact that you know the truth is this
starting the start of this million
characters was actually in the middle of
a sentence but you know who cares right
because it's you know that only happens
once every million characters honey I
was wondering if you could talk a little
bit more about augmentation for this
kind of data set and how to data
augmentation of this kind of data said
yeah no I can't because I don't I really
know a good way it's one of the things
I'm going to be studying between now and
part two there have been some recent
developments particularly something we
talked about the machine learning course
and I think we've refinished in here
which was somebody for a recent careful
competition won it by doing data
augmentation by randomly inserting parts
of different rows basic
something like that may be useful here
and I've seen it I've seen some papers
that do something like that but yeah I
haven't seen any kind of recent ish
state-of-the-art new
NLP papers that that are doing this kind
of data orientation so it's something
we're planning to work on so it's
generally how the issues be PTT so
there's a couple of things to think
about when you pick your be PTT the
first is that you'll note that the the
matrix size for a mini batch has a B PTT
the the TT by batch size so one issue is
your GPU Ram needs to be able to fit
that by your embedding matrix racks
every one of these is going to have B of
length embedding length plus all of the
hidden state so one thing is to you know
if you get a cruder out of memory error
you need to reduce one of those if
you're finding your training is very
unstable like your loss is shooting off
to LAN suddenly then you could try to
decreasing your B PTT because you've got
less layers to gradient explode through
it's too slow you could try decreasing
your B PTT because it's going to kind of
do one of those steps at a time like
that for loop can't be paralyzed well I
say that there's a recent thing called
QR an N which is will hopefully talk
about in part two which kind of does
paralyze it but the versions we're
looking at don't paralyze it so there
would be the main issues I think before
look at performance look at memory and
look at stability and try and find a
number that's you know as high as you
can make it but all of those things work
for you
okay so trying to get although that
chunking and lining up and anything to
work is more code than I want to write
so for this section we're going to go
back and use torched s together okay
so when you're using AP is like fast AI
and torch text which in these case these
two API is a desire to or at least from
the first day I site designed to work
together you often have a choice which
is like okay this API has a number of
methods that expect the data in this
kind of format and you can either change
your data to fit that format or you can
write your own data set subclass to
handle the format that your data is
already in I've noticed on the forum a
lot of you are spending a lot of time
writing your own dataset classes whereas
I am way lazier than you and I spend my
time instead changing my data to fit the
data set classes I have like I that's
fine and if you realize like oh there's
a kind of a format of data that me and
other people are likely to be seen quite
often and it's not in the first day our
library then by all means write the data
set subclass it submitted as a PR and
then everybody can benefit you know but
in this case I just kind of thought I
want to have some Nietzsche data fed
into torch text I'm just going to put it
in the format that watch text kind of
already support so torch text already
has or at least the first day I wrap her
around Twitter text already has
something where you can have a training
path and a validation path and you know
one or more text files in each path
containing a bunch of stuff that's
concatenated together for your language
model so in this case all I did was I
made a copy of my nature file copied it
into training made another copy stuck it
into the validation and then in one of
the you know in the training set I did I
deleted the last twenty percent of rows
and in the validation set I deleted all
except for the last one
Center for us and I was done right so I
found this that in this case I found
that easier than writing a custom
dataset class the other benefit of doing
it that way was that I felt like it was
more realistic to have a validation set
that wasn't a random shuffled set of
rows of text that was like a totally
separate part of the corpus because I
feel like in practice you're very often
going to be saying like oh I've got I
don't know these books or these authors
I'm learning from and then I want to
apply it to these different books and
these different authors you know so I
felt like for getting a more realistic
validation of my nietzsche model I
should use like a whole separate piece
of the text so in this case it's the
last you know 20% of the rows if the
corpus so I haven't created this for you
right intentionally because you know
this is the kind of stuff I want to do
practicing is making sure that you're
familiar enough comfortable enough with
with batch or whatever that you can
create these and that you understand
what they need to look like and so forth
so in this case you can see I've now got
you know a train and a validation here
and then I could yeah okay so you can
see I've literally just got one file in
it because it's a fire when you're doing
a language model ie predicting the next
character or predicting the next word
you don't really need separate files
it's fine if you do have separate files
but they just get capped native together
anyway alright so that's my source data
and so here is you know the same lines
of code that we've seen before and let's
go over them again so it's a couple of
lessons ago right so in torch text we
create this thing called a field and the
field initially is just a description of
how to go about pre-processing the test
okay now you in this case I'm gonna say
hey lowercase it you know cuz I don't
mean now I think about it there's no
particular reason to have done this
lower case upper case would work fine
too and then how do I talk
maser and so you might remember last
time we used a tokenization function
which kind of largely spit on white
space and try to do some flavor things
with punctuation right and that gave us
a word model in this case I want to
character model so I actually want every
character put into a separate token so I
could just use the function list in
Python because list in Python does that
okay so this is where you can kind of
see like understanding how libraries
like torch text and fast ar e are
designed to be extended can make your
life a lot easier right so when you
realize that very often both of these
libraries kind of expect you to pass a
function that does something and then
you realize like oh I can write any
function I like all right okay so this
is now going to mean that each mini
batch is going to contain a list of
characters and so here's where we get to
define all our different parameters and
so to make it the same as previous
sections of this notebook I'm going to
use the same batch size the same number
of characters then they're going to
rename it to their PT t since we know
what that means
the number of the size of the embedding
and the size of our hidden state okay
remembering that size of our hidden
state simply means going all the way
back to the start right and hidden
simply means the size of the state
that's created by each of those orange
arrows so it's the size of each of those
circles yeah okay
so having done that we can then create a
little dictionary saying what's our
training validation and test set in this
case I don't have a separate test set so
I just use the same thing and then I can
say all right I want a language model
data subclass with model data I'm going
to grab it from text files and this is
my path and this is my field which I
defined earlier and these are my files
and these are my hyper parameters min
fracks not going to do anything actually
in this case because there's not I don't
think there's going to be any character
that appears less than three times
that's probably redundant okay so at the
end of that it says there's going to be
963 batches to go through and so if you
think about it that should be equal to
the number of tokens divided by the
batch size divided by B PTT because
that's like the size of each of those
rectangles
you'll find that in practice it's not
exactly that and the reason it's not
exactly that is that the authors of
torch text did something pretty smart
which I think we've briefly mentioned
this before they said okay we can't
shuffle the data like with images we'd
like to shuffle the order so every time
we see them in a different order so
there's a bit more random listed we
can't shuffle because we need to be
contiguous but what we could do is
randomize the length of you know
basically randomize be PTT a little bit
each time and so that's what PI torch
does it's not always going to give us
exactly 8 characters long 5% of the time
it'll actually cut it enough and then
it's going to add on a small little
standard deviation you know to make it
slightly bigger or smaller than for
white okay so it's going to be slightly
different to eight on average
yes just to make sure is it going to be
constant per Vinny watch yeah yeah
exactly that's right so a mini batch you
know has to kind of it needs to do a
matrix multiplication and the mini batch
size has to remain constant because
we've got this age weight matrix that
has to you know has to line up in size
with the size of the mini batch yeah but
the number you know the sequence length
can can change their problem okay so
that's why we have 963 that's so the
length of a data loader is how many mini
batches in this case it's so do it
approximate okay number of tokens is how
many unique things are in the vocabulary
and remember after we run this line text
now does not just contain in a
description of what we want but it also
contains an extra attribute called vocab
right which contains stuff like a list
of all of the unique items in the
vocabulary and a reverse mapping from
each item to its number okay so that
text object is now an important thing to
keep out all right so let's now try this
so we do we started out by looking at
the class so the class is exactly the
same as the class we've had before the
only key difference is to call in at
hidden which calls sets out so H is not
a variable anymore it's now an attribute
itself that H is a variable containing a
bunch of zeros now I've been shown that
that size remains constant H time
but unfortunately when I said that I
lied to you and the way that I lied to
you is that the very last mini batch
will be shorter okay the very last mini
batch is actually going to have less
than 60 well it might be exactly the
right size if it so happens that this
data set is exactly divisible by B PTT
times patch size but it probably isn't
so the last batch will probably has a
little bit less okay and so that's why I
do a little check here that says let's
check that the batch size inside self
dot H right and so self dot H is going
to be the height sorry the height is
going to be the number of activations
and the width is going to be the mini
batch size okay check that that's equal
to the actual sequence length sorry the
actual batch size length that we've
received okay and if they're not the
same then set it back to 0 's again okay
so this is just a minor little wrinkle
that basically at the end of each epoch
it's going to do like a little mini mini
batch right and so then as soon as it
starts the next epoch it's going to see
that they're not the same again and
it'll reinitialize it to the correct
full batch size okay so that's why you
know if you're wondering there's an
inert hidden not just in the constructor
but also inside forward it's to handle
this kind of end of each epoch start of
each epoch difference okay not an
important point by any means but
potentially confusing when you see it
okay so the last wrinkle the last
wrinkle is something which i think is
something that slightly sucks about pi
torch and maybe somebody can be nice
enough to try and fix it with a PR if
anybody feels like it which is that the
loss functions such as softmax
I'm not happy receiving a rank 3 tensor
remember a rank 3 tensor is just another
way of saying
dimension three right okay there's no
particular reason they ought to not be
happy receiving a rank 3 tensor you know
like somebody could write some code to
say hey a wreck three tensor is probably
you know a sequence length by batch size
by you know results thing and so you
should just do it for each of the two
initial axis but no one's done that and
so it expects it to be a rank two tensor
funnily enough it can handle write to or
rec for they're not right through yeah
so we've got so we've got a rank two
tensor containing you know for each time
period I can't remember which way around
the the y axes are but whatever for each
time period for each batch we've got our
predictions okay and then we've got our
our actuals for each time period for
each batch we've got our predictions and
we've got our actuals okay and so we
just want to check whether they're the
same and so at an ideal world our lost
function a loss function would check you
know item 1 1 then item 1 2 and then
item 1 3 but since that hasn't been
written we just have to flatten them
both out okay and we can literally just
flatten them out put rose - rose and so
that's why here I have to use dot view
okay and so dot view says the number of
columns will be equal to the size of the
vocab because remember we're going to
end up with a prediction you know a
probability for each letter and then the
number of rows is however big is
necessary which will be equal to batch
size times B PTT okay and then you may
be wondering where I do that
that's so that's where the predictions
you may be wondering where I do that for
the target and the answer is torch text
knows that the target needs to look like
that
so torch text has already done that for
us okay so torch text automatically
changes the target to be flattened out
as you might actually remember if you go
back to lesson 4 when we actually looked
at a mini batch that's bad out of torch
text we did we noticed actually that it
was flattened and I said we'll learn
about why later and so later is now all
right okay so they're the three wrinkles
get rid of the history ooh I guess for
wrinkles recreate the hidden state if
the batch size changes flatten out and
then you just torch text to create mini
batches that line up nicely so once we
do those things we can then create our
model create our optimizer with that
models parameters and fit it one thing
to be careful of here is that softmax
now as of hi torch 0.3 requires that we
pass in a number here saying which
access do we want to do the softmax over
so at this point this is a
three-dimensional tensor right and so we
want to do the softmax over the final
axis right so when i say which axis do
we do the softmax over remember we
divide by there we go e to the X I
divided by the sum of e to the X I so
it's saying which axis do we sum over so
which access we want to sum to one and
so in this case clearly we want to do it
over the last axis because the last axis
is the one that contains the probability
per letter of the alphabet and we want
all of those probabilities to sum to one
okay
so therefore to run this notebook you're
going to need PI torch 0.3 which just
came out this week ok so if you're doing
this on the milk you're fine I'm sure
you've got at least a 0.3 or later ok
where else the students here if you just
go Conda and update it will
automatically update you to 0.3 the
really great news is that 0.3 although
it does not yet officially support
windows it does in practice I
successfully installed 0.3 from Condor
yesterday by typing Condor install torch
PI torch in Windows are then attempted
to use the entirety of lesson 1 and
every single part worked so I actually
ran it on this very laptop so for those
who are interested in doing deep burning
on their laptop can definitely recommend
the new surface book the new surface
book 15-inch has a gtx 1066 gig GPU in
it and i was getting and it was running
about 3 times slower than my 1080 TI
which i think means it's about the same
speed as an AW sp2 the instance and as
you can see it's also a nice convertible
tablet that you can write on and it's
thin and light and so it's like I've
never seen a such a good deep learning
boss also I successfully installed Linux
on eart and all of the faster I staff
worked on Linux as well so really good
option if you're interested in a laptop
that can run deep learning stuff
[Music]
alright so that's that's going to be
aware of with this team equals minus 1
so then we can go ahead and construct
this and we can call fit and yeah we're
basically going to get pretty similar
results to what we got the ball
alright so then we can go a bit further
without RNN by just kind of unpacking it
a bit more
and so this is now again exactly the
same thing gives exactly the same
answers but I have removed the cold air
in it so I've got rid of this self to
iron in okay and so this is just
something I won't spend time on it but
you can check it out
so instead I've now to find iron in as R
and n cell and I've copied and pasted
the code above don't run it this is just
for your reference from PI torch this is
this is the color the definition of
eridan so in PI torch and I want you to
see that you can now read PI torch
source code and understand it not only
that you'll recognize it as being
something we've done before it's a
matrix modification of the weights by
the inputs plus biases so f dot linear
simply does a matrix product followed by
an addition right and interestingly
you'll see they do not concatenate the
the input bit and the hidden bit they
sum them together which is our first
approach and I'm as I said you can do
either neither one's right or wrong but
it's interesting to see this is the
definition yeah
yes you know can give some insight about
what are they using that particular
activation function firm yeah yeah I
think you might have briefly covered
this last week but very happy to do it
again if I did basically fan that's
positive 1 and negative 1
then looks like that so in other words
it's a sigmoid function double the
height minus one naturally they're
they're equal so it's it's it's a nice
function in that it's forcing it to be
you know no smaller than minus one no
bigger than plus one and since we're
multiplying by this white matrix again
and again and again and again we might
worry that our Lu because it's unbounded
might have more of a gradient explosion
problem that's basically the theory
having said that you can actually ask pi
torch for an RNN cell which uses a
different non-linearity so you can see
by default it uses then you can ask for
a value as well but yeah most people
seem to pretty much everybody still
seems to use them as far as I can tell
so you can basically see here this is
all the same except now I've got an
errand in cell which means now I need to
put my for loop back alright and you can
see every time I call my my little
linear function I just obtained the
result onto my list okay and at the end
the result is that all stacked up
together okay so like just trying to
show you how nothing inside PI torches
is mysterious right you should find you
get basically the fact you I found I got
exactly the same answer from this as the
previous one okay in practice you would
never write it like this but what you
may well find in practice is that
somebody will come up with like a new
kind of eridan cell or a different way
of kind of keeping track of things over
time or a different way of doing
regularization and so inside posterize
code you will find that we we do this
exactly this basically we have this by
hand because we use some regularization
approaches that are supported by pi
torch
all right so then another thing I'm not
going to spend much time on but I'll
mention briefly is that nobody really
uses this hour an insult in practice and
the reason we don't use that eridan so
in practice is even though the fan is
here you do tend to find gradient
explosions are still a problem and so we
have to use pretty low learning rates to
get these to train and pretty small
values for B PTT to get them to Train so
what we do instead is we replace the
eridan cell with something like this
this is called a GI u cell and a GI u so
here it is has a picture of it and
there's the equations for it so
basically I'll show you both quickly but
we'll talk about it much more in part
two we've got our input okay
and our input normally goes straight in
gets multiplied by a weight matrix to
create our new activations that's not
what happens
and then we've cost we also we add it to
the existing activations that's not what
happens here in this case our input goes
into this H tilde temporary thing and it
doesn't just get added to our
activations their previous activations
that our previous activations get
multiplied by this value R and R stands
for reset it's a reset gate okay and how
do we calculate that this this value
goes between Norton one right in our
reset gate well the answer is it's
simply equal to a matrix product between
some weight matrix and the concatenation
of our previous hidden state and our new
input in other words this is a little
one hidden layer neural net and in
particular it's a one hidden layer
neural net because we're then put it
through the sigmoid function
when you seasick but one of the things I
hate about mathematical notation is
symbols are overloaded a lot right
sometimes when you see Sigma that means
standard deviation when you see it next
to a parenthesis like this it means the
sigmoid function okay so in other words
that okay which looks like that okay so
this is like a little mini neural net
with no hidden layers or to think of it
another way it's like a little logistic
regression okay and this is I mentioned
this briefly because it's going to come
up a lot in part two and so it's a good
thing to like start learning about it's
this idea that like in the very learning
itself you can have like little mini
neural nets inside your neural nets
right and so this little mini neural net
is going to be used to decide how much
of my hidden state am I going to
remember right and so it might learn
that Oh in this particular situation
forget everything you know for example
oh there's a full-stop you know hey when
you see a full-stop you should throw
away nearly all of your hidden state
that is probably something it would
learn and that that's very easy for it
to learn using this little mini neuron
there okay and so that goes through to
create my new hidden state along with
the input and then there's a second
thing that happens which is there's this
gate here called Z and what Z says is
all right you've got your some amount of
your previous hidden state plus your new
input right and it's going to go through
to create your new state and I'm going
to let you decide to what degree do you
use this new input version of your
hidden state and to what degree where
you just leave the hidden state the same
as before so this thing here is called
the update gate right and so it's got
two choices it can make the first-years
to throw away some hidden state when
deciding how much to incorporate that
versus my new input and how much to
update my hidden state versus just leave
it exactly the same and the equation
hopefully is going to look pretty
similar
to you which is check this out here
remember how I said you want to start to
recognize some some common ways of
looking at things
well here I have a 1 - something by a
thing and a something without the 1 - by
a thing which remember is a linear
interpolation right so in other words
the value of Z is going to decide to
what degree do I have keep the previous
hidden state and to what degree do I use
the new hidden state right so that's why
they draw it here as this kind of like
it's not actually a switch but like you
can put it in any position you can be
like oh it's here or it's here or it's
here to decide how much that'll do ok so
so they're basically the equations it's
a it's a little mini neural net with its
own weight matrix to decide how much to
update little mini neural net with its
reset and then that's used to do an
interpolation between the two hidden
states so that's called giu
gated recurrent Network there's the
definition from the PI torch source code
they have some slight optimizations here
that if you're interested in we can talk
about them on the forum but it's exactly
the same for we just saw and so if you
go and NDI you that it uses this same
code but it replaces the iron in so with
this cell okay and as a result rather
than having something where we needed
where we were getting a 1.54 we're now
getting down to one point 400 and we can
keep training even more get right down
to one point three six okay so in
practice a giu or very nearly
equivalently we'll see in a moment in
lsdm in practice what pretty much
everybody always uses so the art he and
HT are ultimately scalars after they go
through the sigmoid but there are
Clyde element-wise is that correct -
mm-hmm
yeah although of course one for each
mini batch but yes the scaler yeah okay
great thanks and on the excellent colas
blog Chris Ellis blog there's an
understanding LS TM networks post which
you can read all about this in much more
detail if you're interested and also the
other one I was dealing from here is a
wild ml also have a good blog post on
this there's somebody wants to be
helpful feel free to put them in the
lesson wiki
okay so then putting it all together I'm
now going to replace my GI you with
Nellis TM I'm not going to bother
showing you the soul for this it's very
similar to GI u but the LS TM has one
more piece of state in it called the
sell state not just the hidden state so
if you do use an LS TM you're now inside
you're in it hidden have to return a
couple of matrices they're exactly the
same size as the hidden state but you
just have to return the tupple okay the
details don't matter too much but we can
talk about it during the week if you're
interested you know when you pass in you
still pass in self dot H still returns a
new value of H is to repackage it in the
usual way
so this code is identical to the code
before one thing I've done though is
I've had a drop out inside my air and in
which you can do with the height watch R
and n function so that's going to do
drop out after a time step and I've
doubled the size of my hidden layer
since I've now added point five drop out
and so my hope was that this would make
it be able to learn more but be more
resilient as it does so so then I wanted
to show you how to take advantage of a
little bit more fast AI magic without
using the layer class and so I'm going
to show you how to use Cobra
and specifically we're going to do s GDR
without without using the learner class
ok so to do that we create our model
again just a standard PI torch model ok
and this time rather than going
remember the usual pipe torch approach
is opt equals up to M naught atom and
you pass in the parameters and a
learning rate I'm not going to do that
I'm going to use the fast AI layer
optimizer class which takes my opt-in
class constructor from PI torch it takes
my model it takes my learning rate and
optionally takes weight decay ok and so
this class is tiny it doesn't do very
much at all the key reason it exists is
to do differential learning rates and
differential weight decay right but the
reason we need to use it is that all of
the mechanics inside fast AI assumes
that you have one of these right so if
you want to use like callbacks or SPDR
or whatever in code where you're not
using the learner class then you need to
use rather than saying you know opt
equals off to m dot atom and here's my
parameters you instead say lay optimizer
okay
so that gives us a layer optimizer
object and if you're interested
basically behind the scenes you can now
grab a dot opt property which actually
gives you the optimizer but you don't
have to worry about that itself but
that's basically what happens behind the
scenes the key thing we can now do is
that we can now when we call fit we can
pass in that optimizer and we can also
pass in some callbacks and specifically
we're going to use the cosine annealing
callback okay and so the cosine
annealing callback requires a layer
optimizer object right and so what this
is going to do is it's going to do
cosine annealing by changing the
learning
right inside this object okay so the
details aren't terribly important we can
talk about them on the forum it's really
the concept I wanted to get across here
right which is that now that we've done
this we can say all right
create a cosine and kneeling callback
which is going to update the learning
rates in this layer optimizer the length
of an epoch is equal to this here right
how many mini batches are there in an
epoch well it's whatever the length of
this data loader is okay so because it's
going to be it's going to be doing the
cosine annealing it needs to know how
often to reset okay and then you can
pass in the cycle more in the usual way
and then we can even save our model
automatically like you remember how
there was that cycle saved name
parameter that we can pass to learn not
fit this is what it does behind the
scenes behind the scenes it sets an on
cycle end callback and so here I have to
find that callback as being something
that saves my model okay so there's
quite a lot of cool stuff that you can
do with callbacks callbacks are
basically things where you can define
like at the start of training or at the
start of an epoch or at the side of a
batch or at the end of training or at
the end of an epoch or at the end of a
batch please call this club okay and so
we've written some for you including SGD
R which is the cosine annealing callback
and then so how I recently wrote a new
callback to implement the new approach
to decoupled weight decay we use
callbacks to draw those little graphs of
the loss over time so there's lots of
cool stuff you can do with callbacks so
in this case by passing in that callback
we're getting as JDR and that's able to
get us down to one point three one here
and then we can train a little bit more
and eventually get down to one point two
five and so we can now test that out and
so if we passed in a few characters of
text we get not surprisingly and a
after four thus let's do then 400 and
now we have our own Nietzsche so
Nietzsche tends to start his sections
with a number and a dot so 2 9 3 perhaps
that every life the values of blood have
intercourse when it senses there is
unscrupulous his very rights and still
impulse love ok so I mean it's slightly
less clear than Nietzsche normally but
it gets the tone right ok and it's
actually quite interesting like if to
play around with training these
character based language models to like
run this at different levels of loss to
get a sense of like what does it look
like like you really notice that this is
like 1.25 and like that's slightly worse
like 1.3 this looks like total junk you
know there's like punctuation in random
places and you know nothing makes sense
and like you start to realize that the
difference between you know Nietzsche
and random junk is not that far in kind
of language model terms and so if you
train this for a little bit longer
you'll suddenly find like oh it's it's
it's making more and more sense okay so
if you are playing around with NLP stuff
particularly generative stuff like this
and you're like there is also like kind
of okay but not great don't be
disheartened because that means you're
actually very very nearly there you know
the the difference between like
something which is starting to create
something which almost vaguely looks
English if you squint and something
that's actually a very good generation
it's it's not it's not far in most
motion tests okay great so let's take a
five-minute break we'll come back at
7:45 and we're going to go back to
computer vision
okay so now become full circle back to
vision so now we're looking at less than
seven so far ten that book you might
have heard of so far ten it's a really
well-known data set in academia and it's
partly it's well known it's actually
pretty old by you know computer vision
standards well before image net was
around there was sci-fi 10 you might
wonder why we're going to be looking at
such an old data set and actually I
think small data sets are much more
interesting than image net because like
most of the time you're likely to be
working with stuff with a small number
of thousands of images rather than one
and a half million images some of you
will work at one and a half million
images but most of you won't right so
learning how to use these kind of data
sets I think is much more interesting
often also a lot of the stuff we're
looking at like in medical imaging we're
looking at like the specific area where
there's a lung nodule you're probably
looking at like 32 by 32 pixels at most
as being the area where that lung nodule
actually exists right and so sci-fi 10
is small both in terms of it doesn't
have many images and the images are very
small and so therefore I think this is
like it's been in a lot of ways is much
more challenging then something like
image net and in some ways it's much
more interesting right and also most
importantly you can run stuff much more
quickly on earth so it's much better to
test out your algorithms with something
you can run quickly and they're still
challenging and so I hear a lot of
researchers complain about like how they
can't afford to study all the different
versions that their algorithm properly
because it's too expensive and they're
doing that on imagenet so like it's
literally a week of you know expensive
CP GPU work for every study they do and
like I don't understand why you would do
that kind of study on imagenet doesn't
make sense
yeah and so
this has been a particularly you know
there's been a particular a lot of kind
of debate about this this week because
I'm really interesting researcher named
Ali raha me nips this week gave a talk a
really great talk about kind of the need
for rigor in experiments in deep
learning and you know he felt like
there's a lack of rigor and I've talked
to him about it quite a bit since that
time and I'm not sure we yet quite
understand each other as to where we're
coming from but but we have very similar
kinds of concerns which is basically
people aren't doing carefully tuned
carefully thought about experiments but
instead they kind of throw lots of GPUs
or lots of data and consider that a day
and so this idea of like saying like
well you know it's my data statement
it's my algorithm meant to be good
that's moral imagers at small data sets
well if so let's study on sci-fi 10
revin studying it on imagenet and then
do more studies of different versions of
the algorithm and learning different
bits on and off understand which parts
are actually important and so forth
people also complain a lot about amnesty
which we've talked about looked at
before and I would say the same thing
about em this right which is like if
you're actually trying to understand
rich parts of your algorithm make a
difference and why using m mr that kind
of study is a very good idea and all
these people who complain about em NIST
I think they're just showing off they're
saying like oh I work at Google and I
have you know a part of TP use and I
have $100,000 a week of time just being
on it no worries but I don't know I
think that's all it is you know it's
just signalling rather than actually
academically rigorous okay so I'm so far
ten you can download from here and this
person is very kindly made it available
in image form if you google for size 510
you'll find us a much less convenient
form so please use this one it's already
in the exact form you need once you
download it you can use it in the usual
way so here's a list of the classes that
are there now you'll see here I've
created this thing called
that's normally when we've been using
pre trained models we have been seeing
transforms from model and that's
actually created the necessary
transforms to convert our data set into
a normalized data set based on the means
and standard deviations of each channel
in the original model that was trained
in our case though this time we got a
trainer model from scratch so we have no
such thing so we actually need to tell
it the mean and standard deviation of
our data to normalize it okay and so in
this case I haven't included the code
here to do it you should try and try
this yourself to confirm that you can do
this and understand where it comes from
but this is just the mean channel and
the standard deviation per channel of
all of the images alright so we're going
to try and create a model from scratch
and so the first thing we need is some
transformations so for so far 10 people
generally do data augmentation of simply
flipping randomly horizontally so here's
how we can create a specific list of
augmentations to use and then they also
tend to add a little bit of padding
black padding around the edge and then
randomly pick a 32 by 32 spot from
within that pattern image so if you add
the pad parameter to any of the fast a a
transform creators it'll it'll do that
for you okay and so in this case I'm
just going to add 4 pixels around each
size and so now that I've got my
transforms I can go ahead and create my
image classifier data from paths in the
usual way okay I'm going to use a batch
size of 256 because these are pretty
small so it's going to let me do a
little bit more at a time so here's what
the data looks like so for example
here's a boat and just to show you how
tough this is what's that
okay it is it's a not chicken prog-rock
so I guess it's this big thing whatever
the thing is called there's your frog
okay so so these are the kinds of things
that we want to look at so I'm going to
start out so our student Karen we saw
one of his posts earlier in this course
he he made this really cool log book
which shows how different optimizers
works there we go so Karen made this
really cool notebook I think it was
maybe last week in which he showed how
to create various different optimizers
from scratch so this is kind of like the
Excel thing I had but this is the Python
version of momentum and Adam and
Nesterov and Atta grad all written from
scratch it is very cool one of the nice
things he did was he showed a tiny
little general-purpose fully connected
Network generator so we're going to
start with his so so he called that
simple net so are we so here's a simple
class which has a list of fully
connected layers okay
whenever you create a list of layers in
pi torch you have to wrap it in an end
module list just to tailpipe torch to
like register these as attributes and so
then we just go ahead and flatten the
data that comes in because it's fully
connected layers and then go through
each layer and call that linear layer do
the value to it and at the end do a soft
mess okay so there's a really simple
approach and so we can now take that
model and now I'm going to show you how
to step up one level of the API higher
rather than calling the fit function
we're going to create a learn object but
we're going to create a learn object
from a custom model and so we can do
that by say we want a convolutional
learner we want to create it from a
model and from some data and the model
is this one so this is just a general
height watch model and this is a model
data object of the usual kind
and that will return a loaner so this is
a bit easier than what we just saw with
the RNN we don't have to fiddle around
with lair optimizers and cosine and
kneeling and callbacks and whatever this
is now a loaner that we can do all the
usual stuff with that we can do it with
any model that we created okay so if we
just go learn that'll go ahead and print
it out okay so you can see we've got
three thousand and seventy two features
coming in because you've got 32 by 32
pixels by three channels okay and then
we've got 40 features coming out of the
first layer that's going to go into the
second layer ten features coming out
because we've got the ten so far ten
categories okay you can call dot summary
to see that a little bit more detail we
can do LR find we can plot that and we
can then go fetch and we can use cycle
length and so forth okay so with a
simple
how many hidden layers do we have one
hidden layer right one getting layer one
output layer one hidden layer model with
and here we can see the number of
parameters we have is that over 120,000
okay we get a 47 percent accuracy so not
great all right so let's kind of try and
improve it right and so the goal here is
we're going to try and eventually
replicate the basic kind of architecture
of a resonator okay so that's where
we're going to try and get to hear it
specially built up to a resonant so the
first step is to replace our fully
connected model with a convolutional
model okay so to remind you so to remind
you a fully connected layer is simply
doing a dot product right so if we had
like all of these data points and all of
these weights right then we basically
do a sum product of all of those
together right in other words it's a
matrix multiply right then that's a
fully connected layer okay and so we
need the white matrix is going to take
contain an item for every every element
of the input for every element of the
output okay so that's why we have here a
pretty big weight matrix and so that's
why we had despite the fact that we have
such a crappy accuracy we have a lot of
parameters because in this very first
layer
we've got 3072 coming in and for T
coming out so that gives us three
thousand times forty parameters and so
we end up not using them very
efficiently because we're basically
saying every single pixel in the input
has a different weight and of course
what we really want to do is kind of
find groups of three by three pixels
that have particular patterns to them
okay and remember we call that a
convolution okay so a convolution looks
like so we have like little 3x3 section
of our image and a corresponding 3x3 set
of filters right or our filter with a
three by three kernel and we just do a
sum product of just that three by three
by that three by three okay and then we
do that for every single part of our
image right and so when we do that
across the whole image that's called a
convolution and remember in this case we
actually had multiple filters right so
the result of that convolution actually
had multiple it was a tensor with an
additional third dimension to it
effectively so let's take exactly the
same code that we had before but we're
going to replace n n dot linear with NN
com2 D okay now what I want to do in
this case though is each time I have a
layer I want to
the next layer smaller and so the way I
did that in my Excel example was I used
max Pauling right so max Pauling took
every 2x2 section and replaced it with
this maximum value right nowadays we
don't use that kind of max bowling much
at all instead nowadays what we tend to
do is do what's called a stride to
convolution
let's drag to convolution rather than
saying let's go through every single 3x3
it says let's go through every second
3x3 so rather than moving this three by
three one to the right
we move it two to the right and then
when we get to the end of the row rather
than moving one row down we move two
rows down okay so that's called a stride
to convolution and so it's tried to
convolution has the same kind of effect
as a max pooling which is you end up
having the resolution in each dimension
so we can ask for that by saying stroud
equals to okay we can say we wanted to
be three by three by saying kernel size
and then the first term parameters are
exactly the same as nn but linear
they're the number of features coming in
and the number of features coming out
okay so we create a multiple list of
those layers and then at the very end of
that so in this case I'm going to say
okay I've got three channels coming in
the first one layer will come out with
20 then a at 40 and then 80 so if we
look at the summary we're going to start
with a 32 by 32 we're going to spit out
of 15 by 15 and then a 7 by 7 and then a
3 by 3 right and so what do we do now to
get that down to a prediction of one of
10 classes what we do is we do something
called adaptive max pooling and this is
what is pretty standard now for
state-of-the-art algorithms is that the
very last layer we do a max pool but
rather than doing like a 2
go to next Paul we say like it doesn't
have you to bow to could have been 3x3
which is like replace every three by
three pixels with its maximum could have
been four by four adaptive backs Paul is
where you say I'm not going to tell you
how big an area to pull but instead I'm
going to tell you how big a resolution
to create right so if I said for example
I think my input here is like 28 by 28
right if I said do a 14 by 14 adaptive
max Paul that would be the same as a 2
by 2 max Paul because in other that's
saying please create a 14 by 14 output
if I said do a 2 by 2 adaptive max Paul
right then that would be the same as
saying do a 14 by 14 max Paul and so
what we pretty much always do in modern
cnn's is we make our per northmet layer
a 1 by 1 adaptive Max Paul so in other
words find the single largest cell and
use that as our new activation right and
so once we've got that we've now got a 1
by 1 tensor right we're actually 1 by 1
by number of features tensor so we can
then on top of that go view X dot view X
dot size comma minus 1 and actually
there are no other dimensions to this
basically right so this is going to
return a matrix of mini-batch by number
of features and so then we can feed that
into a linear layer with however many
classes we need right so you can see
here the last thing I pass in is how
many classes am I trying to predict and
that's what's going to be used to create
that last layer so it goes through every
convolutional layer does a convolution
does arel you does an adaptive max pool
this dot view just gets rid of those
trailing unit backsies
one comma one axis which is not
necessary that allows us to fit that
into our final linear layer that spits
out something of size C which here is
ten so you can now see how it works
it goes 32 to 15 to 7 by 7 to 3 by 3 the
adaptive next pull makes it 80 by 1 by 1
right and then our dot view makes it
just a mini batch size by 80 and then
finally a linear layer which makes it
from 80 to 10 which is what we wanted
okay so that's our like most basic you
would call this a fully convolutional
network so a fully convolutional network
is something where every layer is
convolutional except for the very last
so again we can now go Li dot find and
now in this case when I did ll find it
went through the entire data set and
we're still getting better and so in
other words even a the default final
learning rate rises 10 and even at that
point it was still like pretty much
getting better so you can always
override the final learning rate by
saying n del R equals that and that will
get it just to get it to try morphine's
okay and so here is the learning rate
finder and so I picked 10 to the minus 1
trained that for a while and that's
looking pretty good
so I try to put the cycle length of 1
and it's starting to flatten out at
about 60% right so you can see here the
number of elements the number of
parameters I have here are 500 7000
28,000 about 30,000 right so I have
about a quarter of the number of routers
that my accuracy has gone up from 47% to
60% right and the time per epoch here is
under 30 seconds and here also so the
time period box about the same and
that's not surprising because when you
use small simple architectures most of
the time is the memory transfer the
actual time during the compute is
is trivial okay so I'm going to refactor
this slightly because I want to try and
put less stuff inside my forward and so
calling RAL you every time you know it
doesn't seem ideal so I'm going to
create a new class called conf lair okay
and the conf lair class is going to
contain a convolution with a kernel size
of three and a stride of two one thing
I'm going to do now is I'm going to add
padding
did you notice here the first layer went
from 32 by 32 to 15 by 15 not 16 by 16
and the reason for that is that at the
very edge of your convolution right here
see how this first convolution like
there isn't a convolution where the
middle is the top left point right
because there's like nothing outside it
where else if we had put a row of zeros
at the top and a row of zeros at the
edge of each column we now could go all
the way to the edge alright so pad
equals 1 adds that little layer of zeros
around the edge for us ok
and so this way we're going to make sure
that we go 32 by 32 to 16 by 16 to 8 by
8 it doesn't matter too much when you've
got these bigger layers but by the time
you get down to like say 4 by 4 you
really don't want to throw away a whole
piece right so padding becomes important
so by refactoring it to put this with
its defaults here and then in the
forward I put the value in here as well
it makes by confident you know a little
bit smaller and you know more to the
point it's going to be easier for me to
make sure that everything is correct in
the future by always using this common
player class ok
so now you know not only how to create
your own neural network model but how to
create your own neural network layer so
here now I can use conf layer right and
this is such a cool thing about pi torch
is a layer definition and a neural
network definition are literally
identical okay they both
have a constructor and a forward and so
anytime you've got the lair you can use
it as a neural net anytime you have a
neural net you can use it as a lair
okay so this is now the exact same thing
as we had before one difference is I now
have padding okay and another thing just
to show you you can do things
differently back here my max pool I did
as as an object likely I use the class n
n dot adaptive max pool and I stuck it
in this attribute and then I called it
but this actually doesn't have any state
there's no weights inside max pooling so
I can actually do it with a little bit
less code by calling it as a function
right so everything that you can do as a
class you can also do as a function it's
inside this capital F which is n n dot
functional okay so this should be a tiny
bit better because this time I've got
the padding I didn't trade it for as
long to actually check so let's skip
over that all right so one issue here is
that in the end this is having I when I
tried to add more layers
I had travel training it okay and the
reason I was having trouble training it
is it was you know if I used larger
learning rates it would go off to NI N
and if I use smaller learning rates that
are kind of takes forever and doesn't
really have a chance to explore properly
so it wasn't resilient so to make my
model more resilient I'm going to use
something called batch normalization
which literally everybody calls bachelor
and bachelorettes a couple of years old
now and it's been pretty transformative
since it came along because it suddenly
makes it really easy to train deeper
networks alright so the network I'm
going to create is going to have more
layers right I've got one two three four
five convolutional layers plus a fully
connected layer right so like back in
the old days that would be considered a
pretty deep network and we considered
pretty hard to train nowadays super
simple thanks to vaginal
now to use batch norm you can just write
in end on that to learn about it we're
going to write it from scratch okay so
the basic idea of batch norm is that
we've got some vector of activations
anytime I draw a vector of activations
obviously I mean you can repeat it for
the mini batch so I pretend it's a mini
batch with one so we've got some veteran
activations and it's coming into some
layer right so so probably some
convolutional matrix multiplication and
then something comes out the other side
so imagine this this is just a matrix
multiply which was like I don't know say
it was a identity matrix right then
every time I'd multiply it by that
across lots and lots of layers my
activations are not getting bigger
they're not getting smaller they're not
changing at all okay that's all fine
right but imagine if it was actually
like 2 2 2 right and so if every one of
my weight matrices or filters was like
that then my activations are doubling
each time right and so suddenly I've got
as exponential growth and that in deep
models that's going to be a disaster
right because my gradients are exploding
at an exponential rate and so the
challenge you have is that it's it's
very unlikely unless you try carefully
to deal with it that your matrices your
weight matrices on average are not going
to cause your activations to keep
getting smaller and smaller or keep
getting bigger and bigger right you have
to kind of carefully control things to
make sure that they stay you know at a
reasonable size you want to you know
keep them at a reasonable scale so we
start things off with zero mean standard
deviation one by normalizing the inputs
really like to do is to normalize every
layer not just the inputs all right and
so okay fine
let's do that right so here I've created
a BN layer which is exactly like my
Kampf layer it's got my common 2d with
my stride my padding right I do my
condom I value right and then I
calculate the mean of each channel or of
each filter and the standard deviation
of each channel or each filter and then
I subtract the means and divide by the
standard deviations right so now I don't
actually need to normalize my input at
all because it's actually going to do it
automatically
right it's normalizing it per channel or
and for later layers its normalizing it
per filter so it turns out that's not
enough right
because SGD is bloody-minded right and
so if sgt decided that it what's the
weight matrix to be you know like so
where that matrix is something which is
going to you know increase the values
overall repeatedly then trying to divide
it by the subtract domains and divide by
the standard deviations just means the
next mini-batch it's going to try and do
it again and they were try and do it
again it'll try and do it again so it
turns out that this actually doesn't
help like it literally does nothing
because SGD is just going to go ahead
and undo it
the next mini batch so what we do is we
create a new multiplier for each channel
and a new added value for each Channel
literally just and we just start them
out as the addition and addition is just
a bunch of zeros so for the first layer
three zeros and the multiplier for the
first layer is just three ones okay so
number of filters for the first layer is
just three and so we then like basically
undo exactly what we just did or
potentially we undo them right so by
saying this is an addenda parameter that
tells PI torch you're allowed
to learn these as weights right so
initially it says okay so check the
means divided by the standard deviations
multiplied by one add on zero
okay that's fine nothing much happened
there but what it turns out is that now
rather than like if it wants to kind of
scale the layer up it doesn't have to
scale up every single value in the
matrix it can just scale up this single
trio of numbers self dot M if it wants
to shift it all Apple down a bit doesn't
have to shift the entire weight matrix
they can just shift this trio of numbers
self dot a so I will say this I'm at
this talk I mentioned at nips Alley
Rahim ease talk about rigor he actually
pointed to this paper this batch norm
paper as being a particularly useful
particularly interesting paper where a
lot of people don't necessarily we quite
quite know why it was right and so if
you're thinking like okay subtracting
out the means and then adding some
learned weights of exactly the same rank
and size sounds like a weird thing to do
there are a lot of people that feel the
same way right so at the moment I think
the best is I can say like intuitively
is what's going on here is that we're
normalizing the data and then we're
saying you can then shift it and scale
it using far fewer parameters than would
have been necessary if I was asking you
to actually shift and scale the entire
set of convolutional filters right
that's the kind of basic intuition more
importantly in practice what this does
is it adds is it basically allows us to
increase our learning rates and it
increases the resilience of training and
allows us to add more layers so once I
added
a PN layer rather than a common flower I
found I was able to add more layers to
my model and it still trained
effectively generally are we worried
about anything that maybe we are divided
by something very small or anything like
that once we do this probably I think in
the pie chart
version it would probably be divided by
itself dudes plus Epsilon or something
yeah this worked fine for me but yeah
that is definitely something to think
about if you were trying to make this
more reliable I mentioned poplar so the
self dot m and self dot a getting it's
getting updated through back propagation
as well yeah so by putting like saying
it's an N n dot parameter that's how we
flag to pi torch to learn it through
that probe exactly right the other
interesting thing it turns out the batch
norm does is it regularizes in other
words you can often decrease or remove
drop out or decrease or remove weight
okay when you use batch normal and the
reason why is if you think about it each
mini batch is going to have a different
mean and a different standard deviation
to the previous mini batch so these
things keep changing and because they
keep changing it's kind of changing the
meaning of the filters in this subtle
way and so it's adding a regularization
effect because it's noise that when you
add noise of any kind it regularizes
your model all right I'm actually
cheating a little bit here in the real
version of batch norm you don't just use
this batches mean and standard deviation
but instead you take an exponentially
weighted moving average standard
deviation and
and so if you wanted to exercise to try
a during the week that would be a good
thing to try but I will point out
something very important here which is
if self-training when we are doing our
training loop this will be true when
it's being applied to the training set
and it will be false when it's being
applied to the validation set and this
is really important because when you're
going through the validation set you do
not want to be changing the meaning of
the model okay so this is this really
important idea is that there are some
types of layer that are actually
sensitive to what the mode of the of the
network is whether it's in training mode
or as plight which calls it evaluation
mode or we might say a test mode right
and actually we actually had a bug a
couple of weeks ago when we did our mini
net for movie lens the collaborative
filtering we actually had F dot dropout
in our forward pass without protecting
it with a F self training F dot dropout
as a result of which we were actually
doing dropout in the validation piece as
well as the training piece which
obviously isn't what you want okay
so I've actually gone back and fixed
this by changing it to using n n dot
dropout and n n dot dropout has already
been written for us to check whether
it's being used in training mode or not
that or alternatively I could have added
a if self dot training before I use the
dropout yeah okay so it's important to
think about that you know any and the
main the main true or pretty much the
only two built-in two pi torch where
this happens is dropout and and so
interestingly this is also a key
difference in fast AI which no other
library does is that these means and
standard deviations get updated in
training mode in every other library as
soon as you basically say I'm
training regardless even of whether that
layer is set to trainable or not and it
turns out that with a pre trained
network that's a terrible idea
if you have a pre trained network for
specific values of those means and
standard deviations in batch norm if you
change them it changes the meaning of
those pre trained layers right and so in
fast AI always by default it won't touch
those means and standard deviations if
your layer is frozen okay as soon as you
I'm freezing it'll start updating them
unless you've set won't be and freeze
true if you set learned up being freeze
true it says never touch these met means
and standard deviations and you know
I've found in practice that that often
seems to work a lot better for
pre-trained models particularly if
you're working with data that's quite
similar to what the pre trained model
was trained with you know as you look
like I did a lot of work did you say
sorry like quite a lot of code here well
you're doing more work than you would
normally do essentially you're
calculating all these aggregates as you
go through each each each layer yes
wouldn't this mean you're training like
your epoch time like now this is like
super fast like if you think about what
a cone has to do a cones has to go
through every 3x3 you know with a stride
and do this multiplication and then
addition like that is a lot more work
than simply calculating the per channel
mean so this is so and that's a little
bit of time but it's it's less time
intensive than the convolution would it
be like right after like decomposition
yeah
we'll talk about that in a moment so at
the moment we have it after the rally
and in the original batch norm paper I
will
that's where they put it so this this
idea of something called an ablation
study and an ablation study is something
where you basically try kind of turning
on and off different pieces of your
model to see like which bits make which
impacts and one of the things that
wasn't done in the original batch norm
paper was any kind of really effective
ablation study and one of the things
therefore that was missing was this
question which you just asked which is
like where do you put the vaginal before
the early year after the earlier
whatever and so since that time you know
that oversight has caused a lot of
problems because it turned out the
original paper didn't actually put it in
the best spot and so then other people
since then have now figured that out
and they're like every time I show
people code where it's actually in the
spot that turns out to be better people
always say your bedrooms in the wrong
spot and I have to go back and say no I
know that's what the paper said what
they're doing now that's what I thought
and so it's kind of causes confusion so
there's there's been a lot of question
about that
so a little bit of a higher-level
question so we started out with cipher
data yes it's the basic reasoning that
you use a smaller data set to quickly
train a new model and then you take it
the same model and you're using much
much much bigger data set to get a
higher accuracy level is that the basic
maybe so if you want to you know if you
had a large data set or if you were like
interested in the question of like how
good is this technique on a large data
set then yes what you just said would be
what I would do I would do lots of
testing on a small data set which I had
already discovered had the same kinds of
properties as my larger data set and
therefore my conclusions would likely
carry forward and then our test them at
the end
having said that personally I matched
be more interested in actually studying
small datasets for their own sake
because I find most people I speak to in
the real world don't have a million
images they have you know somewhere
between about two thousand and twenty
thousand images seems to be much more
common so I'm very you know very
interested in having fewer rows because
I think it's more valuable in factors
I'm also pretty interested in small
images not just for the rest you
mentioned which is it allows me to test
things out more quickly but also as I
mentioned before often a small part of
an image actually turns out to be what
you're interested in that's certainly
true in in medicine I have two questions
the first is on what you mentioned in
terms of small datasets particular
middle medical imaging you've you've
heard of I guess is it vicarious to
start up in the specialization and
one-shot learning so your opinions on
that and then this second being this is
related to I guess Ali's talk at nips so
it was I don't say its controversial but
like young laocon there was like a
really
I guess controversial thread attacking
you in terms of what you're talking
about as a baseline of theory just not
keeping up with practice and so I mean I
guess I was siding with the on where's
all he actually he tweeted at me quite a
bit trying to defend like he wasn't
attacking yawn at all but in fact he was
you know trying to support him but I
just kind of feel like a lot of theory
as as you go is just sort of at it they
even it's hard to keep up whether then
you know no archive from on Draco party
to keep up but if the theory isn't
keeping up but industry is the one
that's actually sitting in the standard
then doesn't that mean that you know
people who are actual practitioners are
the ones like young lacunae are
publishing the theory that are keeping
up to date or is like academic research
institutions are actually behind so I
don't have any comments on the vicarious
papers because I haven't read them I'm
not aware of any of them have as
actually showing you know better results
than the papers but I think they've come
a long way in the last twelve
so that might be wrong yeah yeah I
viewed the discussion between yarn
lacunae and a lyric Jimmy is very
interesting because they're both smart
people who have interesting things to
say unfortunately a lot of people talk
Ally's talk as meaning something which
he says it didn't mean and when I
listened to his talk I'm not sure he
didn't actually made it at the time but
he clearly doesn't mean it now which is
he's he's now said many times he didn't
he was not talking about theory he was
not saying we need more theory at all
actually he thinks we need more
experiments and so specifically he's
he's also now saying he wished he hadn't
used the word rigour which I also wish
because rigour is it's kind of
meaningless and everybody can kind of
say when he says rigor he means the
specific thing I study you know so a
lots of people have kind of taken his
talk as being like oh yes this proves
that nobody else should work in neural
networks unless they are experts at the
one thing I'm an expert in so yeah so
I'm going to catch up with him and talk
about more about this in January and
hopefully we'll pick up some more stuff
out together but basically what would we
can clearly agree on and I think you and
also agrees on is careful experiments
are important just doing things on
massive amounts of data using massive
amounts of TP use or GP users not
interesting of itself and we should
instead try to design experiments that
give us the maximum amount of insight
into what's going on so Jeremy is it a
good statement to say something like so
drop out and bash norm are very
different things drop out is the
realization technique bash norm has
maybe some realization effect but it's
actually just about convergence of the
optimization method yeah yeah and and I
would further say like I can't see any
reason not to use pattern or
there are versions of batch norm that in
certain situations turned out not to
work so well that people have figured
out ways around that for nearly every
one of those situations now so I would
always seek to find a way to use batch
norm it may be a little harder in our
own ends
at least but even there there are ways
of doing batch norm in our attenders as
well so you know try try and always use
batch norm on every layer if you can and
the question that somebody asked is does
it mean I have to I can stop normalize
in my data yeah yeah it does
although do it anyway because it's not
at all hard to do it and at least that
way the people using your data I don't
know they kind of know how you've
normalized it and particularly with
these issues around a lot of libraries
in my opinion at least warm not my
opinion my experiments don't deal with
batch norm correctly for pre-trained
models just remember that when somebody
starts retraining those averages and
stuff are going to change for your data
set and so if your new data set has very
different input averages it could really
cause a lot of problems so so yeah I
went through a period where I actually
stopped normalizing my data and you know
things kind of worked but it's probably
not worth it okay so so the rest of this
is identical right all I've done is I've
changed conf layer to BN layer but I've
done one more thing which is I'm kind of
trying to get closer and closer to
modern approaches which I've added a
single convolutional layer at the start
with a bigger kernel size and a stride
of one why have I done that so the basic
idea is that I want my first layer to
kind of have a richer input right so
before my first layer had an input of
just three because there's just three
channels right but if I start with my
image right and and I kind of take a
bigger area few different color I kind
of take a bigger area right and I do a
convolution using that bigger area in
this case I'm doing five by five right
then that kind of allows me to try and
find more interesting richer features in
that 5x5 area and so then I spin out a
bigger output this case I spit out a
filter size good about ten five by five
filters and so the idea is like pretty
much every state of the art
convolutional architecture now starts
out with a single con flare with like a
five by five or seven by seven or
sometimes even like 11 by 11 convolution
with like quite a few filters you know
something like you know thirty two
filters coming out and it's just just a
way of kind of trying to and like
because I use the straight of one and
the padding of kernel size minus one
over two
it means that my outputs going to be
exactly the same size as my input but
just got more filters now this is just a
good way of trying to create a richer
starting point for my sequence of
convolutional layers
okay so that's the basic theory of why
I've added this single convolution which
I just do once at the start and then I
just go through all my layers and then I
do my adaptive max pooling and my final
classifier okay so it's a minor tweak
but it helps right and so you'll see now
I kind of can go for a Moodle I have 60%
and after a couple is 45% now after a
couple that's 57% and after a few more
I'm out for 68% okay
so you can see it's you know the the
batch norm and you know tiny bit the
conveyor at the start it's helping now
what's more you can see this is still
increasing right so that's looking
pretty encouraging okay so given that
this is looking pretty good an obvious
thing to try might be to see is to try
increasing the depth of the model and
now I can't just add more of most dried
to layers because remember how it half
the size of the image each time I'm
basically down to two by two at the end
right so I can't add much more so what I
did instead was I said okay here's my
original layers so you must trade two
layers for everyone also create a
straight one layer so astrayed one layer
doesn't change the size and so now I'm
saying zip my stride two layers and my
stride one layers together and so first
of all do the straight too and then do
the straight one so this is now actually
twice as deep okay so this is so this is
now twice as deep but I end up with the
exact same you know two by two that I
had before and so if I try this you know
here after one two three four epochs is
at sixty-five percent after one two
three epochs I'm still at 65% it hasn't
helped right and so the reason it hasn't
helped is I'm now too deep
even for batch norm two handlers now my
depth is now one two three four five
times two is ten eleven kampf 112 okay
so 12 layers deep it's possible to train
a standard confident 12 layers deep but
it starts to get difficult to do it
properly right and it certainly doesn't
seem to be really helping much if at all
so that's where I'm instead going to
replace this with a ResNet all right so
a rest net is our final stage
what a resin it does is I'm going to
replace our BN layer right I'm going to
inherit from BN layer and replace our
forward with that and that's it
everything else is going to be identical
except now I'm going to do like way lots
of layers I'm going to make it four
times deeper right and it's going to
Train beautifully just because of that
so why does that help so much so this is
called a ResNet block and as you can see
I'm saying that's not what I meant to do
I'm saying my predictions equals my
input plus some function you know in
this case a convolution of my input
alright that's that's that's what I've
written here and so I'm now going to
shuffle that around a little bit and I'm
going to say I'm going to say f of X
equals y minus X ok so there's the same
thing shuffled around right that's my
prediction within the previous layer
right and so what this is then doing is
it's trying to fit a function to the
difference between these two right and
so the difference is actually the
residual
so if this is what I'm trying to
calculate my actual Y value and this is
the thing that I've most recently
calculated then the difference between
the two is basically the error in terms
of what I've calculated so far and so
this is therefore saying that okay try
to find a set of convolutional weights
that attempts to fill in the the amount
I was off by so in other words if we
let's clear this out if we have some
inputs coming in right and then we have
this function which is basically trying
to predict the error it's like how much
are we off by right and then we add that
on so we basically add on this
additional like prediction of how much
will be wrong by and then we add on
another prediction of how much were we
wrong by that time and add on another
prediction of how much we wrong by that
time then that each time we're kind of
zooming in getting closer and closer to
our correct answer and each time we're
saying like okay we've got to a certain
point but we still got an error you've
still got a residual so let's try and
create a model that just predicts that
residual and add that on to our previous
model and then let's build another model
that predicts the residual and add that
on to our previous model and if we keep
doing that again and again we should get
closer and closer to our answer and this
is based on a theory called boosting
which people that have done some machine
learning will certainly come across
right and so basically the trick here is
that by specifying that as being the
thing that we're trying to calculate
then we kind of get boosting for free
right it's like because we couldn't just
juggle that around to show that actually
it's just calculating a model on the
wrist Jill so that's kind of amazing and
you know it totally works as you can see
here I've now got my standard batch norm
layer okay which is something which is
going to reduce my size by two because
it's got the stride too and then I've
got a resident layers dried one and
another resident layer astride one right
and sorry I think I said that was four
of these is actually three of these so
this is now three times deeper I zipped
through all of those and so I've now got
a function of a function of a function
so three layers per group and then my
con at the start and my linear at the
end so this is now three times bigger
than my original and if I fit it you can
see it's just keeps going up and up and
up and up I keep fitting it more he's
going up and up and it's still going up
when I kind of got bored okay so the
rest net has been a really important
development and it's allowed us to
create these really deep networks right
now the full risk net does not quite
look the way I've described it here the
full res net doesn't just have one
convolution right but it actually has
two convolutions right so the way people
normally draw resident blocks is they
normally say you've got some input
coming in to the layer it goes through
one convolution to convolutions and then
gets added back to the original input
right that's the full version of a
ResNet block in my case I've just done
one convolution okay and then you'll see
also in every block
right one of them it's actually the
first one does he it's actually the
first one here is not a resident block
but a standard convolution with a stride
of two right this is called a bottleneck
layer right and the idea is this is not
a ResNet block so from time to time we
actually change the geometry right we're
doing this trade to in resident we don't
actually use just a standard
convolutional layer there's actually a
different form of bottleneck block that
I'm not going to picture in this course
I'm going to teach you in part two okay
but as you can see even this somewhat
simplified version of a resin it still
works pretty well and so we can make it
a little bit bigger all right and so
here I've just increased all of my sizes
I have still got my three and also I've
had it drop out right so at this point
I'm gonna say this is other than the
minor simplification of ResNet you know
a reasonable approximation of a good
starting point for a modern architecture
okay and so now I've added in my point
to drop out I've increased the size here
and if I train this you know I can treat
it for a while it's going pretty well I
can then add in gta at the end
eventually I get 85% and you know this
is at a point now where like literally I
wrote this whole notebook in like three
hours right we can like create this
thing in three hours and this is like an
accuracy that in kind of 2012-2013 was
considered pretty much data the art for
say pocket right so this is actually no
this is actually pretty damn good to get
you know nowadays the most recent
results are like 97% you know there are
there's plenty of room we can still
improve but they're all based on these
techniques like there isn't really
anything you know when we start looking
in in part to it like how to get this
right up to state of the art you'll see
it's basically better approaches to data
augmentation better approaches to
regularization some tweaks on ResNet
but it's all basically the circuit okay
so so is the residual training on the
residual method is that only looks like
it's a generic thing that can be applied
non image problems oh great question
yeah yes it is but it's like being
ignored everywhere else in NLP something
called the transformer architecture
recently appeared and you know was shown
to be the state of the art for
translation and it's got like a simple
resonance structure you know first time
I've ever seen it in NLP I haven't
really seen anybody else take advantage
of it yeah this general approach we call
these skip connections this idea of like
skipping over a layer and kind of doing
an identity it's yeah it's been
appearing a lot in computer vision and
nobody else much seems to be using it
even though there's nothing computer
vision specific about it so I think it's
a big opportunity okay so final stage I
want to show you is how to use an extra
feature of Pi torch to do something cool
and it's going to be a kind of a segue
into part two it's going to be our first
little hint as to what else we can build
on these neural nets and so and it's
also going to take us all the way back
to lesson 1 which is we're going to do
dogs and cats ok so going all the way
back to dogs and cats we're going to
create a resin at 34 ok so these
different ResNet 3450 101 they're
they're basically just different numbers
of different sized blocks it's like how
many of these kind of pieces do you have
before it bottleneck block and then how
many of these sets of super blocks do
you have right that's all these
different numbers mean so if you look at
the torch vision source code you can
actually see the definition of these
different resonates you'll see they're
all just different parameters right ok
so we're going to use rest at 34
and so we're going to do this a little
bit more by hand okay so if this is my
architecture this is just the name of a
function then I can call it to get that
model right and then true look at the
definition is do I want the pre-trained
so in other words is it going to load in
the pre-trained imagenet weights
okay so M now contains a model and so I
can take a look at it like so okay and
so you can see here what's going on
right is that inside here I've got my
initial two deconvolution
and here is that kernel size of seven by
seven okay and interestingly in this
case it actually starts out with a seven
by seven strobe - okay there's the
padding that we talked about to make
sure that we don't lose the edges all
right there's our batch naught okay
there's our Lu you get the idea right
Kong and then so here you can now see
there's a layer that contains a bunch of
blocks all right so here's a block which
contains a cons fetch norm rally you con
Bethnal you can't see it printed but
after this is where it does the addition
all right so there's like a whole ResNet
block and then another resident block
and then another ResNet block okay and
then you can see also sometimes you see
one where there's a stripe - right so
here's actually one of these bottleneck
layers okay
so you can kind of see how this is this
is structure so in our case sorry I
skipped over this a little bit but the
approach that we ended up using for real
you was to put it before our before our
Bashan on which see what they do here
we've got fetch norm railing you cons
that
no I'm really okay okay so you can see
the order that they're using it here
okay
and you'll find like there's two
different versions of ResNet in fact
there's three different versions of
ResNet floating around the one which
actually turns out to be the best it's
called the pre-act ResNet which has a
different ordering again but you can
look it up it's basically a different
order of where the value and where the
batch norm yeah okay so we're going to
start with a standard resident 34 and
normally what we do is we need to now
turn this into something that can
predict dogs versus class right so
currently the final layer has a thousand
features because imagenet has a thousand
features right so we need to get rid of
this so when you use confer owner from
pre-trained in fast AI it actually
deletes this layer for you and it also
deletes this layer and something that as
far as I know is unique to fast AI is we
replace this see this is an average
pooling layer of size seven by seven
right so this is the basically the
adaptive pooling layer but whoever wrote
this didn't know about adaptive pooling
so they manually said oh I know it's
meant to be seven by seven so in first
AI we replaced this with adaptive
pooling but we actually do both adaptive
average pooling and adaptive max pooling
and we then concatenate them two
together which it's it is something we
invented but at the same time we
invented it somebody wrote a paper about
it
so it's you know we don't get any credit
but I think we're the only library that
provides it and certainly only one that
does it by default we're going to for
the purpose of this exercise though
we're going to do a simple version where
we delete the last two layers so we'll
grab all the children of the model will
delete the last two layers and then
instead we're going to add a convolution
which just has two outputs right I'll
show you why in a moment
right then we're going to do our average
pooling and then we're going to do
soft mess okay so that's a model which
is going to have you'll see that there
is no this one has a fully connected
layer at the end this one does not have
a fully connected layer yet but if you
think about it this convolutional layer
is going to be two filters only right
and it's going to be two by seven by
seven and so once we then do the average
pooling it's going to end up being just
two numbers that it produces so this is
a different way of producing just two
numbers I'm not going to say it's better
it's going to say it's different okay
but there's a reason we do it I'll show
you the reason we can now train this
model in the usual way right so we can
say transform stock model image
classifier data from paths and then we
can use that Kampf learner from model
data we just learnt about I'm now going
to freeze every single layer except for
that one and this is the fourth last
layer
so we'll say freeze to minus four right
and so this is just training the last
layer okay so we get 99.1 percent
accuracy so that you know this
approaches working fine and here's what
we can do though we can now do something
called fast comm last activated Maps
fast activation is what we're going to
do is we're going to try to look at this
particular cat and we're going to use a
technique called class activation Maps
where we take our model and we ask you
which parts of this image turned out to
be important and when we do this it's
going to feed out this is got the
picture it's going to create alright and
so as you can see here it's found the
cat so how did it do that well the way
it did that will kind of work backwards
is to produce this matrix now you'll see
in this matrix there's some pretty big
numbers around about here which
correspond to our cat so what is this
matrix this matrix is simply
or to the value of this feature matrix
times this py vector the py vector is
simply equal to the predictions which in
this case said I am 100% confident it's
a cat right so this is just equal to the
value of if I just call the model
passing in our cat this is our cat
that's an X then we got our predictions
right so it's just the value of our
predictions so py is just the value of
our predictions
what about feet what's that equal to
feet is equal to the values in this
layer right in other words the value
that comes out of the final in facts
come out of this ladder coming out of
the final convolutional layer right so
it's actually the seven by seven by two
and so you can see here let's see feet
the shape of features is two filters by
seven by seven right so the idea is if
we multiply that vector by that tensor
right then it's going to end up grabbing
all of the first channel because that's
a 1 and none of the second channel
because that's a 0 and so therefore it's
going to return the value of the last
convolutional layer for the for the
section which lines up with being a cat
but if you think about it this the first
section lines up with being a cat the
second section lines up with being a dog
so if we multiply that tensor by that
tensor we end up with this matrix and
this matrix is which parts most like a
cat or to put it another way in our
model the only thing that happened after
the convolutional layer was an average
pooling layer so the average pooling
layer talked that 7x7 grid and said
average
how much each part is cat Lake that
answered my final value my final
prediction was the average cattiness
there's the whole thing right and so
because it had to be able to average out
these things to get the average
cattiness that means I could then just
take this matrix and resize it to be the
same size as my original cat and just
overlay it on top you get this heat map
right so the way you can use this
technique at home is to basically
calculate this matrix right on some like
really you've got some really big
picture you can calculate this matrix on
a quick small little cognate and then
zoom into the bit that has the highest
value and then rerun it just on that
part that so it's like oh this is the
area that seems to be the most like a
hat or most like a dog that zoom in to
that bit right so I skipped over that
pretty quickly because we ran out of
time and so we'll be learning more about
these kind of approaches in part two and
we can talk about it more on the forum
and hopefully you get the idea the one
thing that totally skipped over was how
do we actually ask for that particular
layer okay and I'll let you read about
this during the week but basically
there's a thing called a hook so we said
we called save features which is this
little class that we wrote that goes
register forward hook and basically a
forward hook is a special PI torch thing
that every time it calculates a layer it
runs this function it's like a callback
basically it's like a callback that
happens every time it calculates a layer
and so in this case it just saved the
value of the particular layer that I was
interested in okay and so that way I was
able to go inside here and grab those
features out look after I was done okay
so I call save features that gives me my
pork and then later on I can just grab
the value that I saved okay so I skipped
over that pretty
quickly but if you look in the pipe or
docks they have some more information
and help about that yes Jeremy can you
spend five minutes talking about your
journey into deep learning
yeah and finally how can we keep up with
important research that is important to
practice sure yeah so it's gonna that's
good I think I'll close more on the
latter bit which is like what now okay
so for those of you are interested you
should aim to come back for part two if
you're aiming to come back for part two
how many people would like to come back
to part two okay that's not bad I think
almost everybody so if you want to come
back to part two be aware of this by
that time you're expected to have
mastered all of the techniques we've
learnt in part one and there's plenty of
time between now and then okay even if
you haven't done much or any ml before
but it does assume that you're going to
be working you know at the same level of
intensity for now until then that you
have been with practicing right so
practicing so generally speaking the
people who did well in part two last
year had watched each of the videos
about three times right and some of the
people actually I knew had actually
discovered they learnt some of them off
by heart by mistake so they're like
watching the video is again is helpful
and make sure you get to the point that
you can recreate the notebooks without
watching the videos all right and so
other men make more interesting
obviously try and recreate them
notebooks using different data sets you
know and definitely then just keep up
with the forum and you'll see people
keep on posting more stuff about recent
papers and recent advances and over the
next couple of months you'll find
increasingly less and less of it seems
weird mysterious and more and more of it
makes perfect sense and so it's a bit of
a case with just thing staying tenacious
you know there's always going to be
stuff that you don't understand yet and
but you'll be surprised if you go back
to lesson one and two now you'll be like
oh that's all trivial right
so you know that's kind of hopefully a
bit of your learning journey and yeah I
think the main thing I've noticed is
that people who succeed are the ones who
just keep keep working at it you know so
not coming back here every Monday you're
not going to have that forcing function
I've noticed the forum suddenly gets
busy at 5:00 p.m. on a Monday you know
it's like Oh course is about to start
and suddenly these questions start
coming in so now that you don't have
that forcing function you know try and
use some other technique to you know
give yourself that little kick maybe you
can tell your partner at home
you know I'm going to try and produce
something every Saturday for the next
four weeks or I'm going to try and
finish reading this paper or something
you know anyway so I hope to see you all
back in March and even I regardless
whether I do or don't it's been a really
great pleasure to get to know you all
and I hope to keep seeing on the forum
thanks very much
[Applause]