okay well welcome to part two of deep
learning for coders part one was
practical deep learning for coders that
too is not impractical deep learning for
coders but it is a little different as
well discuss this is probably a really
dumb idea that last year I started like
not starting part two with part two
lesson one but part two lesson 8 because
it's kind of out of the same sequence so
I've done that again but sometimes I'll
probably forget and call things lesson
one
so clap to lesson one in part two less
than eight or the same thing if you ever
make that mistake so we're going to be
talking about object detection today
which refers to not just blending out
what a picture is a picture of but also
where abouts the thing is but in general
the idea of each lesson in this part is
not so much because I particularly want
you to care about say object rotation
but rather because I'm trying to pick
topics which allow me to teach you some
foundational skills that you haven't got
yet right so for example object
detection is going to be all about
creating much richer convolutional
network structures which have kind of a
lot more interesting stuff going on and
a lot more stuff going on in the first
day I library that we have to customize
to get there so like at the end of these
seven weeks I can't possibly cover the
hundreds of interesting things that
people are doing with deep learning
right now but the good news is that all
of those hundreds of things are you'll
see once you later read the papers like
minor tweaks on a reasonably small
number of concepts and so we covered a
bunch of those concepts in part one and
we're going to go a lot deeper into
those concepts and build on them to get
just in deeper concepts in part two so
in terms of what we covered in part one
there's a few key takeaways we'll go
through each of these takeaways into it
one is the idea and you might have seen
recently Young Buck Owens been promoting
the idea that we don't call this deep
learning but differentiable programming
and the idea is that you've noticed all
the stuff we did in part one was really
about setting up a differentiable
function and a loss function that
describes how good the parameters are
and then pressing go and it kind of
makes it work you know and so this is
kind of I think it's quite a good way of
thinking about it differentiable
programming this idea that if you can
configure a loss function that does but
you know describes you have scores how
good something is it doing your task and
you have a reasonably flexible neural
network architecture you're kind of done
okay so that's one key way of thinking
about this this example here comes from
playground tensorflow dot org which is a
cool website where you can play
interactively with creating your own
little differentiable functions manually
the second thing then we learnt is about
transfer learning and it's basically
that transfer learning is like the most
important single thing to be able to do
to use deep wound effectively nearly all
courses nearly all papers nearly
everything in deep learning education
and research focuses on starting with
random words which is ridiculous because
you almost never would want to or need
to do that you would only want to or
need to do that if nobody had ever
trained and model on a vaguely similar
set of data with an even remotely
connected kind of problem to solve as
what you're doing now you know which
almost so this is where kind of the
faster library and the stuff we talk
about in this class is vastly different
too
any other library or course is that it's
all focused on transfer learning and it
turns out that you do a lot of things
quite differently so the basic idea of
transfer learning is here's a network
that does thing a remove the last layer
or so replace it with a few random
layers at the end fine-tune those layers
to do things be taking advantage of the
features at the original network word
and then optionally find you in the
whole thing into end and you've now got
something which probably uses orders of
magnitude less data and if you start
with random weights it's probably a lot
more accurate and probably trained a lot
faster you know we didn't talk a hell of
a lot about architecture design in part
one and that's because kind of
architecture design is getting less and
less interesting there's a pretty small
range of architectures that generally
works pretty well quite a lot of the
time we've been focusing on using CNN's
for generally fixed size somehow ordered
data era tins for sequences at some
state fiddling around a tiny bit with
activation functions I soft maps if
you've got a single categorical outcome
or sigmoid if you've got multiple
outcomes and so forth
some of the architecture design we'll be
doing in this part gets kind of more
interesting particularly this first
session about object detection but you
know on the whole I think we probably
spend less time talking about
architecture design than most courses or
papers because it's it's not it's you
know it's generally not too happy okay
so the third thing is we looked at was
out of word overfitting and so did the
general idea that I tried to explain is
is the way I like to build a model is to
of all create something that's
definitely terribly over parameterised
will massively overfit for sure trainer
and make sure it does over the it
factors at that point you know okay I've
got a model that is capable of
reflecting the training set and then
it's as simple as doing these things to
then reduce that overfitting and if you
can't start if you don't start with
something's overfitting then you you're
kind of lost right so you start with
something else overfitting and then to
make it over fit less you can add more
data you can add more data augmentation
you can do things like more batch norm
layers or dense Nets or you know various
things that can handle those a few nice
data you can add regularization like
weight decay and drop out and then
finally this is often the thing people
do first but this should be the thing
you do last is reduce the complexity of
your architecture have less layers or
less activations we talked quite a bit
about
betting's both for NLP and the general
idea of any kind of categorical data as
being something you can now model with
neural nets and it's been interesting to
see how since part one came out at which
point there were almost no examples of
kind of papers or blogs or anything
about using kind of tabular data at
categorical data in deep learning
suddenly it's kind of taken off and it's
it's kind of everywhere so this is
becoming a more and more popular
approach it's it's still little enough
known that when I say to people like oh
you know we use neural nets for time
series and tabular data analysis is
often like wait really but it's
definitely not such a far-out idea yeah
and there's more and more resources
available including casual competition
recent capital competition winning
approaches using this technique okay so
the part one you know which kind of
particularly had those five messages
really was all about introducing you to
best practices in deep learning and so
it's like trying to show you techniques
which were mature enough that they
definitely work reasonably reliably for
practical real world problems
and that I had researched and tuned
enough over quite a long period of time
that I could kind of say okay here's the
sequence of steps and architectures and
whatever that if you use this you'll
almost certainly get pretty good results
and then had kind of put that into the
first day I bring into a way that you
could do that pretty quickly and easily
so that's kind of what practical deep
learning pakodas was designed to do so
this part two is cutting edge deep
learning for coders and what that means
is I often don't know the exact best
parameters architecture details and so
forth to solve Euler problem we don't
necessarily know if it's going to solve
a problem well enough to be practically
useful it almost certainly won't be
integrated well enough in too fast AI or
any library that you can just press a
few buttons it'll start working it's
it's all about stuff which I'm not going
to teach it unless I'm very confident
that you know there is now or will be
soon very practically useful technique
so like I don't kind of take stuff which
just appeared and I don't know enough
about it to kind of know like what's a
trajectory gonna be so if I'm teaching
it in this course and saying like you
know this is you know either works well
in the research literature now and it's
gonna be well worth learning about or
we're pretty close to being there
it's got to take a lot of freaking often
and experimenting to get it to work on
your particular problem because we don't
know you know the details well enough to
know how to kind of make it work for
every dataset or every example so it's
kind of exciting to be working at this
point it means that rather than fast AI
and pi torch being obscure black boxes
which you just know these recipes for
you're going to learn the details of
them well enough that you can customize
them exactly the way you want that you
can debug them that you can read the
source code or to see what's happening
and so if you're not pretty confident of
you know object-oriented Python and
stuff like that then that's something
you don't want to focus on studying
during this course because we we assume
that I'm not going to spending time on
that but I will be trying to introduce
you to some some tools that I think are
particularly helpful like the Python
debugger like how to use your editor to
kind of jump through the code stuff like
that and in fact in general there'll be
a lot more detailed specific code
walkthroughs coding technique
discussions and stuff like that as well
as more detailed walkthroughs of papers
and stuff and so anytime we cover one of
these things if you notice something
where you're like you know this is
assuming some knowledge that I don't
have that's fine
you know it just means like that's
something you could ask from the forum
and say hey you know Jeremy kind of was
talking about whatever static methods in
Python I don't really know what a static
method is or like he was using it here
because only some resources like you
know these are kind of things at all
they're not rocket science it's just
just because you don't happen to have
come across it yet doesn't mean it
ha it's just something you learn I will
mention that as I cover these research
level topics and develop these courses I
often refer to code that academics have
put up you know to go along with it
papers or kind of example code that
somebody else is written on github I
nearly always find that there's some
massive critical flaw so be careful of
like taking code from you know online
resources and just assuming that if it
doesn't work for you that you've made a
mistake or something you know this kind
of like research level code it's it's
just good enough that they were able to
run their particular experiments you
know every second Tuesday so you should
you know you should be ready to kind of
do some debugging so on that that's
since I just wanted to remind you about
something from our old course wiki that
we sometimes talk about which is like
people often ask what should I do after
the less and like had away how do I know
if I've got it right and we basically
have this thing called how to use the
provided notebooks and the idea is this
part don't open up the notebook and I
know I said this in part one as well but
I'll say it again and go shift and a
shift and a shift enter until a bag
appears and then go to the forums and
say it notebooks broken right the idea
of the notebook is to kind of be like a
little crutch to help you get through
step the idea is that you start with
like an empty notebook and think like
okay I now want to complete this process
right and and that might be initially
require you op tabbing to to the
notebook and reading it figuring it out
what it says but whatever you do don't
copy and paste it your notebook type it
out yourself right back
so try to make sure you can repeat the
process and as you're typing it out and
you'd be thinking like well what am i
typing why don't i okay so if you can
get to the point where you can you know
solve an object detection problem
yourself in a new empty notebook even if
it's using the exact same data set we
used in the course that's a great sign
that you're getting it right and that'll
take a while but the idea is that by
practicing you know the second time you
try to do it the third time you try to
do it your check the notebook glass yes
right and if there's anything in the
notebook where you think if you think I
don't know what it's doing I hope to
teach you enough techniques in this
course in this past that you'll know how
to experiment to find out what it's
doing right so you shouldn't have to ask
that but you may well want to ask like
why is it doing that you know that's the
conceptual bit and that's something
which you may need to go to the forums
and say like you know before this tip
jeremy had done this after this tip
jeremy had done that this is bit in the
middle way who does this other thing I
don't quite know why you know so then
you can try and say like here my
policies as to why like try and work
through it as much as possible and that
way you'll both be helping yourself and
other people will help you fill in the
gaps right if you wish and you have the
financial resources now is a good time
to build a deep learning box for
yourself when I say a good time I don't
mean a good time in the history of the
pricing of GPUs GPUs are currently by
far the most expensive they've ever been
as I say this because of the
cryptocurrency mining boom I mean it's a
good time in your study cycle I mean the
fact is if you're paying somewhere
between 60 cents and 90 cents an hour
for doing your deep learning on a cloud
provider particularly if you're still on
a k80 like an Amazon p2
or google collab actually I haven't come
across it now let's you train on a kad
for free but those are very slow jeez
you know you can buy one it's gonna be
like three times faster for maybe six
hundred seven hundred dollars you need a
box to put it in of course but you know
the example in the bottom right here
from the forum was something that
somebody put together in last year's
cost so like a year ago they were able
to put together a decent box referred
over five hundred dollars
generally speaking your problem I
created a veneer forum thread where you
can talk about you know options and
parts and ask questions and so forth
afford it right now that gtx 980ti is
almost certainly what you want in terms
of the best price performance MIPS if
you can't afford it at ten seventy is
fine if you can't afford that you should
probably be looking for a secondhand 980
or a second Amazonia something like that
if you can afford to spend more money
it's worth getting a second GPU so you
can do what I do which is to have one
GPU training and another GPU which I'm
running an interactive Cupid in the
clock session Ram is very useful try and
get 32 gig if you can Ram is not
terribly expensive a lot of people find
that their vendor or person to buy one
of these business classes they on CPUs
that's a total waste of time you can get
one of them into our eye five or I seven
consumers to CPUs far far cheaper but
actually a lot of them are faster often
you're here CPU speed doesn't matter
that's if you're doing computer vision
that's definitely not true
it's very common now with these like
1080 TRS and so forth to find that the
speed of the data augmentation is
actually this mo bit that's happening on
the CPU so it's worth getting a decency
to you your again your GPU if it's
running quickly but the hard drives got
fast enough to give it data then that's
a waste as well so if you can afford an
nvme drive they're super super fast you
don't have to get a big one you can just
get a little one you just copy your
current set of data onto and have some
big raid array that sits there for the
rest of your data when you're not using
it
there's a slightly arcane thing about
PCI lanes which is basically like
they're kind of the size of the highway
that connects your GPU to your computer
and a lot of people claim that you need
to have a 16 lanes to feed your GPU it
actually turns out based on some
analysis that I've seen recently that
that's not true you need you need eight
lanes GPU so again so like hopefully
help you save some money on your
motherboard if you've never heard of PCI
lanes before trust me by the end of
putting together this bus you'll be sick
of hearing about you can buy all the
parts and put it together yourself it's
not that hard can be a useful learning
experience it can also be kind of
frustrating and annoying so you can
always go to like central computers and
they'll put it together for you there's
lots of online and vendors that will do
the same thing now generally like make
sure it turns on and runs properly
generally not much of a markup so it's
not a bad idea we're going to be doing a
lot of reading papers basically each
week we'll be implementing a paper or a
few papers and if you haven't looked at
papers before they look something like
on the left that thing on the left is an
extract from the paper that implements
atom you may also have seen atom as a
single excel formula on the spreadsheet
that are in there the same thing okay
the difference is in academic papers
people love to use Greek letters they
also hate to refactor so you'll often
see like like a page long formula where
when you actually look at it carefully
you'll realize like the same and a sub
equation of his eight times you know
they didn't know if they didn't think to
say about it like that T equal like this
that equation announced one I don't know
why this is a thing but
I guess all this is to say like once
you've read and understood a paper you
then go back to it and you look at it
you just like wow how did they make such
a simple feeling so complicated like
Adam Wright is like momentum and
momentum on this momentum on the
gradient and momentum on the squared
already that's it right and and speak
long things and the other reason it's a
big long thing is because they have
things like this where they have like
theorems and calories and stuff where
they're kind of saying like here's or
our theoretical reasoning behind why
this ought to work or whatever and for
whatever reason you know a lot of
conferences and journals don't like to
accept papers that don't have a lot of
this theoretical justification Geoffrey
Hinton's talked about this a bit how
particularly you know a decade or two
ago when no conferences would really
accept any neural network papers then
there was this like one abstract
theoretical result that came out where
suddenly they could show this you know I
don't like practically unimportant but
theoretically interesting thing and then
suddenly they could then start
submitting things to journals because
they have this like theoretical
justification so it's kind of yeah
academic papers are a bit weird but in
the end it's the way that the research
community communicates their their
findings and so we need to learn to read
them but something that could be a great
thing to do is to take a paper put in
the effort to understand it and then
write a blog where you explain it in you
know code in normal English and lots of
people who do that you know end up
getting quite a following end up getting
some pretty great job offers and so
forth because you know it's such a
useful skill to show like okay I can I
can understand these papers I can
implement code I can explain them in
English
one thing I will mention is it's very
hard to read or understand something
which you can't localize which means if
you don't know the names of the Greek
letters like it sounds weird but it's
actually very difficult to understand
remember take in a formula that appears
again and again that's got like squiggle
right you need to know that that
squiggle is called Delta or that screw
or the Sigma or whatever so like just
spending some time learning the names of
the Greek letters is like sounds like a
strange thing to do but suddenly you
don't look at these things anymore and
go like squiggle iovers people beat us
other weird squiggle looks like a why
thing right they've all got notes
okay so now that we're kind of at the
cutting edge stage a lot of the stuff
we'll be learning this class is stuff
that almost nobody else knows about so
that's a great opportunity for you to be
kind of like it's the first person to
create an understandable and
generalizable code library that
implements it or the first person to
write a blog post explains it in clear
English for the first person to try
applying it to this slightly different
area but it's obviously going to work
just as well or so so when we say
cutting-edge research that doesn't mean
you have to come up with like the next
batch norm or the next atom or the next
five liter convoluted convolution it can
mean like okay take this thing that was
used for translation and apply it to
this very similar other parallel and LP
task or take this thing that was tested
on skin lesions and trusted on this data
set of this other clarifications that
kind of stuff is super great learning
experience and incredibly useful because
the vast majority of the world that
knows nothing about this whole field it
just looks like magic you know you're
like a I've for the first time shown
greater than 90 percent accuracy at you
know finding this kind of lesion in this
kind of data
[Music]
so you know when I say here experiment
in your area of expertise you know one
of the things we particularly look for
in this class is to kind of bring in
people who are pretty good at something
else you know pretty good at meteorology
or pretty good at denovo drug design or
pretty good at goat dairy farming or
whatever you know examples people we had
in the class so probably the thing you
can do the best would be to take that
thing you're already pretty good at and
that on these new skills right because
otherwise if you try to go into some
different domain you're gonna have to
figure out how do I get data for that
domain problems are solved in that
domain
where else often it'll seem pretty
trivial to you to take this technique
apply to this data set that you've
already got sitting on your hard drive
but that's often going to be that super
interesting thing you know for the rest
of the world to see like oh that's
interesting you know when you apply it
to meteorology data and you use this
eridan or whatever
and allows you to forecast over larger
areas or a longer time periods so
communicating what you're doing is super
helpful we've we've talked about that
before but I know something that a lot
of people in the forum's ask people who
have already written is that when
somebody's written a blog often people
on the forum will be like how did you
get up the guts to do that or what did
you what up the process you got to
before you decided to start publishing
something or whatever and the answer is
always the same it's always just you
know
I was sure I wasn't good enough to do it
I felt terrified and intimidated of
doing it but I wrote it and posted it
anyway but you just like never a time I
think any of us actually feel like we're
not total frauds and imposters but we
know more about what we're doing then us
of six months ago right and there's
somebody else in the world
who knows as much as you did six months
ago so if you act something now that
would have helped you at six months ago
you're helping some people and honestly
if you wait another six months then the
you of 12 months ago probably won't even
understand that any more offices to
advanced it know so Mike it's great to
communicate wherever you're up to in a
way that you think could be helpful to
the person you were before you knew that
thing um and of course something that
the forum's have been useful for is
getting feedback about drafts you know
and if you post a draft of something
that you're thinking of releasing and
the folks here can point out things that
they find clear or they think need some
Corrections whatever so
the kind of overarching theme with part
two I've described as generative models
but unfortunately then Rachel asked me
this afternoon exactly what I meant by
generative models and I realize I don't
really know so what I really mean is in
part one that the output of our neural
networks was generally like like a
number you know our category where else
the outputs a lot of the stuff in part
two are going to be like a whole lot of
things you know like the top left and
bottom right location of every object in
an image along with what the object is
or a complete picture with the class of
every single pixel in that picture or an
enhanced super resolution version of the
input image or the entire original input
paragraph translated into fish or you
know it's kind of like often it just
requires some different ways of thinking
about things and some kind of different
architectures and and so forth and so
that's kind of like I guess the main
theme of the kind of techniques we'll be
looking at the vast majority possibly
all of the data we'll be looking at will
be either text or image data the it
would be fairly trivial to do most of
these things with audio as well it's
just not something I've spent much time
on myself yet somebody asked on the
forum about like welcoming doing more
stuff with time-series and tabular data
and my answer was like I've already
taught you everything I know about that
and I'm not sure there's much else to
say particularly if you check out the
machine learning course which goes into
a lot of that in a lot more detail so I
don't feel that there's more stuff to
tell you I think that's a super
important area
but I think we're done we're done with
that we'll be looking at some larger
data sets both in terms of the number of
objects in the data search and the size
of each of those objects for those of
you that are working with limited
computational resources please don't let
that put you off
feel free to replace it with something
small at the simpler in fact when I was
designing this course so did quite a lot
of it in Australia when I went to visit
my mom and my mom decided to book a nice
holiday house for us with fast Wi-Fi and
we turned up to the holiday house with
fast Wi-Fi and indeed it did have Wi-Fi
that was fast
but the Wi-Fi was not the internet so I
caught up the agent and I said like I
found thee a DSL router and it's got an
ADSL thing plugged in and I followed the
cable down and the other end of the
cable has nothing to plug into so she
called the she called the people you
know renting the house ona and called me
back the next day and she said actually
the tambaran is quite quickly I actually
point leo has known internet wait what
and so the good old Australian
government had decided to replace ADSL
in point Leo with a new National
Broadband Network and therefore they had
disconnected
ADSL that had not yet connected and
after brought that down so we had fast
Wi-Fi which we could use to Skype chat
from one side of the house to the other
but I had no internet
luckily I did have a news surface book
fifteen-inch which has a gtx 1070 in it
and so I wrote a live German of this
course entirely on my laptop which means
I had to practice with relatively small
resources I mean not tiny like 16 gig
ram and
six gig GP here so I can definitely you
know III definitely and it was all in
Windows so I can tell you that most of
this you know much one where this course
works well on Windows on a laptop so you
can always use smaller batch sizes you
could use a cut-down version of the data
set whatever but if you have the
resources you'll get better results if
you can use the bigger data sets when
they're available okay now it's a good
time I think to take a somewhat early
break so we can fix the floor so the
forum's chill down okay so it was it
okay let's come back at 7:25 so let's
start talking about object detection and
so here is an example object detection
and so hopefully you'll see two main
differences from what we're used to when
it comes to classification the first is
that we have multiple things that were
classifying which is not unheard of we
did that in the planets satellite data
for example but what is kind of unheard
of is that as well as saying what we see
we've also got what's called bounding
boxes around what we see a bounding box
has a very specific definition which is
it's a box all right it's a rectangle
and the rectangle has the object
entirely fitting within it but it's no
bigger than it has to be okay you'll see
this bounding box is perhaps for the
horse at least slightly imperfect in
that this looks like there's a bit of
tail here so it probably should be a bit
wider and maybe there's leaving a little
bit of hoof here maybe there should be a
bit longer so like the bounding box this
won't be perfect but they're generally
pretty good in most data
so our job will be to take data that has
been labeled in this way and on data
that was unlabeled to generate their
classes of the objects and each one of
those their bounding losses one thing
I'll note to start with is that labeling
this kind of data is generally more
expensive it's generally quicker to say
horse person person horse car dog
jumbo jet than it is to say you know if
there's a whole like horse race going on
to label the exact location of every
rider and a very horse and then of
course it also depends like what classes
do you want to label you know if you
want to label everything fence post or
whatever so generally always just like
in like imagenet it's not like tell me
any object you see in this picture it's
an image notice like here are the
thousand classes that we asked you to
look for tell us which one of those
thousand classes you find just tell me
one thing for these object detection
datasets
it's here's a list of object classes
that we want you to tell us about you
know find every single one of them at
any time in the picture along with where
they are so in this case why isn't there
tree or jump labeled that's because for
this particular data set they weren't
one of the classes that the annotators
were asked to find and therefore not
part of this particular problem okay so
that's kind of the specification of the
object detection problem
so let me describe stage 1 and stage 1
is actually going to be surprisingly
straightforward and we're going to start
at the top and work down we're going to
start out by classifying the largest
object in each image so we're going to
try and say the person actually this one
is wrong dog is not the largest object
sofa is the largest object all right so
here's an example of a misclassified one
bird correct person correct okay that'll
be the first thing we try to do that's
not going to require anything new so
it'll just be a bit of a warm-up for us
the second thing will be to tell us the
location of the largest object at each
image again here this is actually
incorrect it should have labeled the
sofa but you can see where it's coming
from and then finally we will try and do
both at the same time which is to label
what it is and where it is for the
largest thing and this is going to be
obviously straightforward actually so to
be kind of good warm-up to get us going
again but what I'm going to do is I'm
going to use it as an opportunity to
show you some useful coding techniques
and a couple of little faster I Andy
details before we then get on to
multi-label classification and then
object specification so let's start here
the logbook that we're using is Pascal
notebook and it's all of the notebooks
are in the DL too
one thing you'll see in some of my
notebooks is torch Dakota dot set device
you may have even seen it in the last
part just in case you're wondering why
that's there I have four GPUs on the
university server that I use and so I
can put a number from North to three in
here to pick one this is how I prefer to
use multiple GPUs rather than run a
model on multiple GPUs which doesn't
always beat it up that much and it's
kind of awkward I generally like to have
different GPUs running different things
so I in this case I was running
something in this on device one and
doing something else another booking
device to obviously if you see this in a
notebook left behind that was a mistake
if you don't have more than one GPU
you're going to get an error done so you
just change it to zero or delete that
line entire so there's a number of
standard object detection data sets
just like imagenet kind of a standard
object classification data set and kind
of the the old classic kind of image net
equivalent if you like is Pascal vo see
visual object class and it's something
like that yeah the actual main website
for it is like I don't know it's running
on somebody's coffee warmer or something
it goes down all the time every time he
makes coffee I don't know so some folks
with mrida it's very kind of thin so
you might find it easier to grab from
the mirror you'll see when you
downloaded that there's a 2007 dataset
of 2012 data set that there basically
were like academic competitions in those
different years just like the Internet
data set we tend to use is like actually
the image net 2012 competition producer
now we'll be using the 2007 version in
this particular notebook feel free to
use of 2012 and stared it's a bit bigger
you might get better results a lot of
people in fact most people now in
research papers actually combine the two
you do have to be careful because
there's some leakage between the
validation sets between the two so if
you do decide to do that make sure you
do some reading about the data set to
make sure you know how to combine them
correctly the first thing you'll notice
in terms of coding here is this we
haven't used this before I'm going to be
using this all the time now this is part
of the Python 3 standard library called
path Lib and it's super handy
it's basically gives you an
object-oriented access to directory or a
file so you can see if I go path dot
something it there's lots of things I
can do one of them is iterative
directory however path iterate directory
returns that hopefully you've come
across generators by now because we do
quite a lot of stuff that use them
behind the scenes without talking about
them too much but basically a generator
is something in in Python 3 which you
can iterate over right so basically you
go for oh in that grid Oh for instance
right ok
or of course you could do the same thing
as a list comprehension right or you can
just stick the word list around it to
turn a generator into the list ok so
anytime you see me put mist around
something that's normally because it
pretend a generator it's not
particularly interests
ding the reason that things generally
return generators is that like what if
the directory had 10 million items in
you don't necessarily 1 to 10 million
long list so we were the for loop just
grep 1 do the thing thrown over wait a
second
throw it away and lets you do things
lazily you'll see that the things that's
returning aren't actually strings but
they're some kind of object
if you're using Windows it'll be a
Windows path of Linux would be a POSIX
path most of the time you can use them
as if they're strings so most like if
you pass it you know any of the OS path
dot whatever functions in Python it'll
just work at some external libraries it
won't work so that's fine if you grab
one of these let's say let's say o
equals let's just grab one of these so
in general you can change data types in
Python just by naming the data type that
you want and treating it like a function
and that will cast it I had so many time
you try to use one of these paths Lib
objects and you pass it to something
which says like I was expecting a stream
this is not a string that's okay so
you'll see there's quite a lot of
convenient things you can do one kind of
fun thing is the slash operator is not
divided by but its path slash so like
they've overwritten the slash operator
in Python so that it works so you can
say path slash whatever and that gets
you you'll see like see how that's not
inside a stream right so this is
actually applying not the division
operator but the overridden slash
operator which means get the child thing
in that path that makes sense and you'll
see if you run that it doesn't return a
string it returns a pathway object okay
and so part one of the things the path
the object can do is it has an open
method
right so this it's it's kind of it's
actually pretty cool once you start
getting the hang of it and you'll also
find that like the open method takes all
the kind of arguments you're familiar
with it's a right for binary your
encoding order so in this case I want to
load up these these JSON files which
contain not the images but the bounding
boxes and the classes of the objects and
so in Python the easiest way to do that
is with the JSON library or there's some
faster API equivalent versions but this
is pretty small so you won't need them
and you go json dot load and you pass it
and open file object and so the easy way
to do that since we're using path live
is just go path open
so these JSON files that we're going to
look inside in a moment if you haven't
used it before JSON is JavaScript object
notation it's kind of the most standard
way to pass around hierarchical
structure don't yet know obviously not
just with JavaScript you'll see I've got
some JSON files in here they actually
did not come from the mirror I mentioned
the the original pascal annotations were
an xml format but cool kids club uses
email anymore we have to use JSON so
somebody's converted them all to JSON
and so you'll find the second link here
has all the JSON files so if you just
pop them in the same location that I've
put them here everything will so these
annotation files
jaison's basically contain a dictionary
once you open up the JSON it becomes a
Python dictionary and they've got a few
different things in the first is we can
look at images it's got a list of all of
the images how big they are and the
unique ID for each one one thing you'll
notice here is
taken the word images and put it inside
a constant court images that may seem
kind of weird but if you're using you
can a notebook or any kind of IDE or
whatever this down means I can tap
complete all of my strings and I won't
accidentally type it slightly wrong so
it's just a handy trick okay so here's
the contents first few things and the
images more interestingly here are some
of the annotations right
so you'll see basically an annotation
contains a bounding box and the bounding
box tells you the column and row if the
top left and it's height and width and
that it tells you that that particular
bounding box is for this particular
image so you'd have to join that up to
over here to find it sexually Oh to top
jpg okay and it's of category ID 7 um it
also some of them at least has a polygon
segmentation not just a bounding box
we're not going to be using that some of
them have an ignore flag so we'll ignore
the ignore flags and some of them have
something telling you it's a crowd of
that object not just one of them right
so that's that's what these annotations
look like so then you saw here there's a
category ID so then the categories for
examples they're basically each ID he
has a name here we go okay so what I did
then was turned the his categories list
into a dictionary from ID to name
I created a dictionary from ID to name
of the image file names and I created a
list all of the image IDs just to make
life easier so you know generally like
when you're working with a new data set
at least when I work with a new dataset
I try to make it look the way I would
want it to if I designed that data set
so
kind of do a quick manipulation and so
like the the steps you see here and
you'll see an h-class
basically like the sequence of steps I
talk as I started working with is this
bead onus it except like without the
thousands of screw-ups that I did I find
like the the one thing people most
comment on when they see me working in
real time having seen my classes is like
wow you actually don't know what you're
doing it's like 99 some of the things I
do don't work more percentage of the
things that do work end up here so like
this is like I mentioned that because
machine learning and particularly deep
learning is kind of incredibly
frustrating because you know in theory
you just to find the correct must
function and flexible enough
architecture and you press train and you
don't all right but if that was actually
all a talk then like nothing would take
any time the problem is that all the
steps along the way until what works it
doesn't work you know like it it goes
straight to infinity or crashes with an
incorrect answer size or whatever and I
will endeavour to show you some kind of
debugging techniques as we go but it's
one of the hardest things to teach
because like I don't know maybe I just
have quite a few get it out yet but it's
like the main thing it requires is
tenacity I find like the biggest
difference between the people I've
worked with who are super effective and
the ones who don't seem to go very far
has never been about intellect it's
always been about you know sticking with
it basically never never giving up so
it's particularly important with this
kind of deep learning stuff because you
don't get that continuous reward cycle
like with normal programming
you've got like 12 things to do until
you've got your Flash endpoints staged
up you know in at each stage it's like
okay we have successfully processing the
JSON and now we successfully you know
I've got the callback from that promise
and now I successfully created the
authentication system like you know it's
this constant sequence of like stuff
that works where else generally with
training the model it's a constant
stream of life it doesn't work it
doesn't work it does
okay so let's see a look at the images
so you'll find inside the GOC dev kit
there's 20 toy 2007 and 2012 directories
and in there there's a bunch of stuff
that's mainly these XML files the one we
care about the JPEG images and so again
here you've got path tips slash operator
and inside there's a few examples of the
images okay so what I wanted to do was
to create a dictionary where the key was
the image ID and the value was a list of
all of its annotations so basically what
I wanted to do was go through each of
the annotations that doesn't say to
ignore it and append it the bounding box
and the class to the appropriate
dictionary item where that dictionary
item is a list but the annoying thing is
of course is that if that dictionary
item doesn't exist yet then there's no
list to the pen too so one super handy
trick in Python is that there's a class
called collections default depth which
is just like a dictionary but if you try
and access a key that doesn't exist it
magically makes itself exist and it sets
itself equal to the return value
this function now this could be the name
of some function that you've defined or
it can be a lambda function a lambda
function simply means it's a function
that you define in place we'll be seeing
lots of them so here's an example of a
function all the arguments to the
function are listed on the left so
there's no arguments to the function and
lambda functions a special you don't
have to write return as there a return
is assumed so in this case this is a
lambda function that takes no arguments
and returns an empty list so in other
words every time I try and access
something in train annotations that
doesn't exist now does exist it as an
empty list which means I can go into it
okay one comment on variable naming is
when I read through these notebooks I'll
generally try and like speak out the
English words that the variable name is
a limit for a reasonable question would
be well why didn't I write the full name
of the variable in English rather than
using a short demonic
it's a personal preference I have based
on a number of programming communities
where the basic kind of thesis is that
the more that you can see in a single
kind of I grab of the screen the more
you can like understand intuitively that
won't go every time you have to your eye
has to jump around it's kind of like a
context change that reduces your
understanding it's a style of
programming I found super helpful and so
generally speaking I try to I
particularly try to reduce the vertical
height so things don't scroll off the
screen but I also try to reduce the size
of things so that there's a mnemonic
there which if you know it's training
annotations it doesn't take long view to
see the patient's you know
throughout the whole thing yet so I'm
not saying you have to do it this way
I'm just saying there's some very light
programming communities some of which
have been around for 50 or 60 years
which refused this approach and it's
interesting to compare like I guess my
philosophy is somewhere between math and
Java
you know like in math everything is a
single character the same single
character can be used in the same paper
for five different things and depending
on whether it's in italics or bold faced
with capitals another fire in Java you
know variable names sometimes require a
few pages well so for me I personally
like names which are you know short
enough to not take too much of my you
know perception to see it once but long
enough to have a mnemonic also however a
lot of the time the variable will be
describing a mathematical object as it
exists in the paper and there isn't
really an English name for it and so in
those cases I will use the same like
often single letter that the paper uses
right and so if you see something called
Delta or a or something and it's like
something inside an equation from a
paper I generally try to use the same
thing just to explain that yeah and by
no means do you have to do the same
thing I will say however if you
contribute to first day I I'm not
particularly fastidious about coding
style or whatever but if you write
things more like the way I do than the
wage are but people do okay so by the
end of this we now have a dictionary
from file names to at Apple and so
here's an example of looking up that
dictionary and we get back a bounding
box
and a-plus you'll see when I create the
bounding box I've done a couple of
things the first years I've switched the
X&amp;Y coordinates and the reason for this
I think we mentioned this briefly in the
last course the kind of computer vision
world when you say like oh my screen is
640 by 480
that's width by height or else the math
world when you say my array is 640 by
480 it's rows by colors so you'll see
that a lot of things like pil pillow
image library in Python tend to do
things in this kind of width by height
or columns by rows way numpy is the
opposite way around so I again my view
is don't put up with it's kind of
incredibly annoying inconsistency fix it
right so I've decided fast AI is you
know the lump I PI torch way is the
right way so I'm always rows by cons so
you'll see here I sketched my rows of
columns I've also decided that we're
going to do things by describing the top
left XY coordinate and the bottom right
XY coordinate the bounding box rather
than the XY and the eye width okay so
you'll see here I was converting the the
height and width to the top so you know
again it's kind of like I often find
dealing with junior programmers and
particular junior data scientists that
they kind of get given datasets that are
in shitty formats or happy api's and
they just act as if everything has to be
that way but your life would be much
easier if you take a couple of moments
to make things consistent make them the
way you want to be okay so earlier on I
took all of our classes and created a
categories list and so if we look up
category number 7 which is what this
year's veteran on the 7 is car
let's have a look at another example
image number 17 has two bounding boxes
one of them is of type 15 one some type
13 that is a person and a horse so this
would be much easier to understand if we
can see a picture of these things so
let's create some pictures so having
just turned our height width stuff into
top left bottom right stuff we're now
going to create a method to do the exact
opposite because anytime I want to call
some library that expects the opposite
I'm going to need to pass it in the
opposite so here is something that
converts a bounding box to a hiking with
B bhw
the bounding box - okay so it's again
reversing the order and credit and
giving us the height width so we can now
open an image in order to display it and
where we going to get to is we're going
to get it to show that sets that car we
just sorts it out right so one thing
that I often get asked on the forums or
through github is like well how do I
find out about this open image thing
where did it come from what does it mean
who uses it and so I wanted to just to
take a moment because what other things
are going to be doing a lot and although
a lot of you aren't professional coders
you have backgrounds in statistics or
you know meteorology your physics or
whatever and I apologize for those of
you that are professional coders you
know this already you need because we're
gonna be a lot doing about a stuck with
the fast AI library and other libraries
you need to go to navigate very quickly
through them okay and so let me give you
a quick overview of how to navigate
through code and for those of you that
haven't used an editor properly before
this is going to blow your months right
for those of you that have you're going
to be like so for the demo I'm going to
show you in Visual Studio code
personally my view is that
on pretty much every platform unless
you're prepared to put in the decades of
your life to learn beer more in apps
well Visual Studio code is probably the
best editor out there it's free it's
open source there are other perfectly
good ones as well okay also if you
download a recent version of anaconda it
will offer to install Visual Studio code
for you it integrates with anaconda sets
it up with your Python interpreter and
comes with the Python extensions and
everything so it's it's a it's a good
choice if you're not sure if you've got
some other editor you like you know
search for the right keywords in the
health so if I fire up Visual Studio
code the first thing to do of course is
do a git loan of the faster I library to
your laptop you'll find in the root of
the repo as well as the environment yml
file that sets up a condor environment
52 you one of the students has been kind
enough to create an environment - CPU
yml file and perhaps one of you that
knows how to do this can add some notes
to the wiki but basically you can use
that to create a local CPU only fast AI
installation and the reason you might
want to do that is so that as you
navigate the code you know you'll be
able to navigate into PI torch you'll
see all the status is there anyway so I
open up visual studio code and it's as
simple as saying open folder right and
then you can just point it out the
faster I get hub folder that you just
downloaded and so the next thing you
need to do is to set up visual studio
code to say I want to use the fast AI
Condor environment place so the way you
do that is with the select interpreter
command and there's a really nice idea
which is kind of like the best of both
worlds between a command-line interface
and a GUI which is you hit this is the
only command in each mode ctrl shift P
you hit ctrl shift P and then you start
typing what you want to do and watch
what happens
Joseph P I want to changed my
interpreter in
okay and it appears if you're not sure
you can kind of try a few different
things right so here we are Python
select interpreter and you can see
generally you can type stuff in it'll
give you a list of things if it can and
so here's a list of all of the
environments interpreters I have set up
and here's my fast AI environment okay
so that's basically the only setup that
you have to do the only other thing you
might want to do is to know there's an
integrated terminal and so if you hit
ctrl backtick it brings up the terminal
and you can the first time you do it
it'll ask you what terminal do you want
if you're in Windows
it'll be like PowerShell or command
prompt or - if you're on Linux you've
got more shells installed and asked so
as you can see I've got it set up to use
- okay
and you'll see it automatically goes to
the directory alright so the main thing
we want to do right now let's find out
what I couldn't understand is so the
only thing you need to know to do that
is control teeth if you hit ctrl T you
can now type the name of a class
function pretty much anything and you
find out about it so open image you can
see it appears and it's kind of cool if
there's something that's got like
camelcase capitalized or something that
underscore you can just type the first
few letters of each pitch so I could be
like open image for example look I do
that and it's found the function it's
also found some other things that match
oh there it is okay so that's kind of a
good way you can see exactly where it's
come from when you can find out exactly
what it is and then the next thing I
guess would be like well what's it used
for so if it's used inside fast AI you
could say find references which is shift
o smoke set up should say shift
open image shift f12 and it brings up
something saying oh it's used twice in
this codebase and I can go and I can
have a look at each of those examples
okay if it's used in multiple different
files it'll tell you the different files
that it's used in it another thing
that's really handy then is as you look
at the code you'll find that certain
bits of the code call other parts of the
code so for example if you're inside
files data set and you're like oh this
is calling something called open image
what is that well you can wave your
pointer over it and it'll give you the
doc string or you can hit f12 and it
jumps straight to its definition right
so like often it's easy to get a bit
lost in like things call things cool
things and if you have to manually go to
each bit it's if you're ready for us
this way it's always one button way
right ctrl T to go to something that
you're specific you know the name of or
f12 to jump to the name the definition
of something that you're clicking on and
when you're done you probably want to go
back where you came from
so alt left takes you back to where you
were okay so whatever you use BM Emacs
Adam whatever they all have this
functionality as long as you have an
appropriate extension installed if you
use pycharm
you can get that for free that doesn't
need any exchange it's Python you know
whatever you're using you want to know
how to do this stuff finally I mentioned
there's a nice thing called sin mode
ctrl K Z which basically gets rid of
everything else so you can focus but it
does keep this nice little thing on the
right hand side which kind of shows you
whele
okay so that's something that you should
practice if you haven't played around
with it before during the week because
we're increasingly going to be you know
digging deeper and deeper into faster
iron pipe or fibers as I say if you're
already a professional coders know all
this stuff
apologies for telling you stuff you know
okay so we're going to well actually
since we did that let's just talk about
open image you'll see that we're using
cv 2 cv 2 is the library is actually the
opencv library you might wonder why
we're using open CV and I want to
explain some of the units of fast AI to
you because some of them are kind of
interesting and might be helpful to the
torch vision like the standard kind of
Pi torch vision library actually uses
apply torch tensors for all of its you
know data augmentation and stuff like
that a lot of people use pillow Pio a
standard of Python imaging library I
found I did like a lot of testing of all
of these I found open CV was about 5 to
10 times faster than to watch vision so
early on actually teamed up with one of
the students from an earlier class to do
the planetlab satellite competition back
when that was on and we used to watch
vision and because it was so slow we
could only get like 25% GPU utilization
because we were doing a lot of data
augmentation and so then I use the
profiler to find out what's going on and
realized it was all in in to watch
vision pillow or PIL is quite a bit
faster but it's not as fast as open CV
it also is not nearly as threadsafe so I
actually talked to the guy who developed
the the thing that python has this thing
called the global interpreter lock this
before the GI L which basically means
that true
fred's can't do do pythonic things at
the same time yes but it makes python a
really shitty language actually the
modern programming but they're stuck
with it
so I spoke to the guy on Twitter who
actually made it so that open CV
releases the GIM
so one of the reasons the faster your
library is so amazingly fast is because
we don't use multiple processors like
every other library does for our data
organization we actually do multiple
threats and the reason we can do
multiple threads is because we use it
and see bit unfortunately OpenCV is like
a really shitty API it's kind of
inscrutable a lot of stuff it does this
point documented as they're poorly
documented it's documented but like in
really obtuse kind of ways so that's why
I try to make it so like no one using
fast AI needs to know that it's using a
CD you know like if you want to open an
image do you really need to know that
you have to pass these flags to open to
actually make it work do you actually
need to know that if the reading fails
it doesn't show an exception it just
silently returns now you know it's these
kinds of things that we try to do to
actually make it work
lastly right but as you start to dig
into it you'll find yourself in these
places and you're kind of want to know
you want to know what and I mentioned
this in particular to say don't start
using you know height or your data
orientation don't start bringing in
pillow you'll find suddenly things slow
down horribly or the body threatening
won't work anymore or whatever I try to
stick to using OpenCV for your
processing okay so so we've got our
image we're just going to use it to to
demonstrate the pascal library and so
the next thing I wanted to show you in
terms of like important coding stuff
we're going to be using throughout this
course is is using matplotlib a lot
better so matplotlib is so named because
it was a rich
a clone of matlab's flooding later
unfortunately MATLAB matlab's plotting
library is awful but at the time it was
what everybody knew so at some point the
matplotlib folks realized or they
probably always view that the MATLAB
plotting library is lawful so they added
a second API to it which was an
object-oriented API
unfortunately because nobody who
originally learned that plot let let the
OO API they then taught the next
generation of people the old MATLAB
style API and now there's basically no
examples or tutorials online I'm aware
of that use the much much better easier
to understand simpler ago so one of the
things are going to try and show you
because plotting is so important in deep
learning is how to use this API and I've
discovered some simple little tricks one
simple little trick is plot subplots is
just a super handy wrapper I'm going to
use it lots right and what it does is it
returns two things one of the things you
probably won't care about the other
thing is an axes object and basically
anywhere where you used to say PLT dot
something you now say ax dot something
and it will now do that plotting to that
particular sub bike so a lot of the time
you'll use this or I'll use this during
this course to kind of plot multiple
plots that we can compare next to each
other but even in this case I'm I'm
creating a single plot alright but it's
just it's just nice to only know one
thing rather than lots of things so
regardless of whether you doing one plot
and lots of plots
I always start now with with this that I
was right and the nice thing is that
this way I can pass in an access object
if I want to plot it into a figure I've
already created or if it hasn't been
passed you know I can create
so this is also a nice way to make your
matplotlib functions like really
versatile and you're kind of see this
used throughout this course so now
rather than plot that I am show it's a
yesterday on show okay and then rather
than kind of weird stateful setting
things in in the old-style API you can
now use ooohs you know get access that
returns an object except visible that's
a property it's all pretty normal
straightforward stuff so once you start
getting the hang of a small number of
these oo matplotlib things hopefully
you'll find life a little easier so I'm
going to show you a few right now
actually so let me show you a cool
example what I think is a cool example
so one thing that kind of drives me
crazy with people putting text on images
whether it be subtitles on TV or people
doing stuff with computer vision is that
it's like white text on a black
background or black text on a black
background you can't read it and so a
really simple thing that I like to do
every time I draw on an image is to
either make my text in boxes white with
a little black border or vice versa and
so here's a like cool little thing you
can do in matplotlib is you can take a
matplotlib plotting object and you can
go set path effects and say add a black
stroke around it and you can see that
then when you draw that like it doesn't
matter that here it's white on a white
background right or here at some black
background it's equal and like it's just
I know it's a simple little thing but it
kind of just makes life so much better
when you can actually see your bounding
boxes and actually read the text so you
can see rather than just saying add a
rectangle
I get the object that it creates and
then pass that object to draw outline
now everything I do that again this nice
path effect runner
you can see matplotlib is perfectly
convenient way of drawing stuff alright
so when I want to draw a rectangle
matplotlib calls that a patch and then
you can pass it all different kinds of
patches so here's again you know rather
than having to remember all that every
time please take another function
alright now you can use that function
every time you know you don't have to
put it in a library somewhere I always
put lots of functions inside my notebook
if I use it in like three notebooks then
I know it's useful enough that I'll
stick it in a separate library you can
draw text and notice all of these take
an axis object right so this is always
going to be added to whatever thing I
want to add it to right so I can add
text and outline around it so having
done all that I can now take my show
image which and notice here the show
image if you didn't pass it an axis it
returns the axis it created right so
show image returns returns the axis that
image is on I then turn my bounding box
into height width for this particular
images bounding box I can then draw the
rectangle I can then draw the text in
the topple in the top left corner so
remember the bounding box x and y are
the first two coordinates right so the
column to the top left this is the
remember the top all contains two things
the bounding box and then the class so
this is the class and then to get the
text of it I just pass it into my
categories list and there we go okay so
now that I've kind of got all that set
up I can use that for all of my object
detection stuff from here all right what
I really want to do though is to kind of
package all that up so here it is
packaging it all it up so here's
something that draws an image with some
annotations right so it shows the image
that goes through each annotation turns
it into height and width draws the
rectangle
Roza test okay if you haven't seen this
before
each annotation remember contains a
bounding box and a class so rather than
going for o in a and n and going o 0 or
I can D structure it okay this is a D
structuring assignment so if you put
something on there something on the left
then that's going to put the two parts
of a top-off or a list into those two
things to bandy so for the bounding box
and the class in the annotations go
ahead and do that
and so then I can then say ok draw a
image of particular index by grabbing
the image ID opening it up and then
calling that draw and so let's test it
out and there it is okay so you know
that kind of seems like quite a few
steps but to me when you're working with
a new data set like getting to the point
that you can rapidly explore it it pays
off right you'll see as we start
building our model we're going to keep
using these functions now to kind of see
how things go
alright so step one from our
presentation is to do a classifier okay
and so I think it's always good like for
me I didn't really have much experience
before I started preparing this course a
few months ago in doing this kind of
object detection stuff so I was like
alright I want I want to get this
feeling of even though it's deep
learning of continual progress all right
so like what could I make work all right
well why don't I find the biggest object
in each image and classifier I know how
to do that all right so it's like this
is one of the biggest problems I find
today with the younger students if they
figure out the whole big solution they
want generally which involves a whole
lot of new speculative ideas
I tried before and they spend six months
doing it and then the day before the
presentation none of it works and this
roof right where else like I've talked
about my approach to Kabul competitions
before I was just like half an hour if
you go at the end of that half an hour
submit something right and try and make
it a little bit better than yesterday's
so I kind of tried to do the same thing
in preparing this lesson right which is
try to create something that's bit
better than lasting okay so the first
thing was like the easiest thing I could
come up with was my largest item
classifier so the first thing I needed
to do was to go through each of those
each of the bounding boxes in an image
and get the largest one right so I
actually didn't write that first I
actually wrote this first right so
normally I like pretend that somebody
else has created the exact API I want
and then go back and write right so I
kind of I wrote this phone first and
it's like okay I need something which
takes all of the bounding boxes for a
particular image and finds the largest
and well that's pretty straightforward I
can just sort the bounding boxes and
here again we've got a lambda function
so again if you haven't used lambda
functions before this is something you
should study during the week right
they're used all over the place to
quickly define a function or like a
once-off function and in this case the
pythons dead the Python built-in sorted
function lets you pass in a function to
say how do you decide whether
something's earlier or later in the sort
order and so in this case I took the
product of the last two items of my
bounding box list ie the bottom right
hand corner - the
two items of my bounding box vest a the
top left corner so bottom right - couple
left is the size the two sizes and if
you take the product of those two things
you get the size of any boss and so then
that's the function do that in
descending order I mean often um often
you can take something it's gonna be a
few lines of code and turn it into one
line of code and sometimes you can take
that too far but for me I like to do
that you know where I reasonably can
because again it means like rather than
having to understand a whole big chain
of things my brain can just say like I
can just look at that at once and say
okay there it is and also I find it over
time my brain kind of builds up this
little library of idioms you know and
like more and more things I can look at
a single line and know what's going on
okay so this bill is a dictionary and
it's a dictionary because this is a
dictionary comprehension a dictionary
comprehension is just like a list
comprehension I'm gonna use it a lot in
this part of the course except it goes
inside curly brackets and it's got a key
colon value all right so here the key is
going to be the image ID and the value
is the largest angles okay so now that
we've got that we can look at an example
and here's an example of the largest
bounding box for this image okay so
obviously there's a lot of objects here
there's three bicycles and three people
okay but here's the largest bus and I
feel like this ought to go without
saying but it definitely needs to be
said because so many people don't do it
you need to look at every stage when
you've got any kind of processing
pipeline if if you're as bad at coding
as I am
everything you do will be wrong the
first time you do it right but like
there's lots of people that are as bad
as be according and yet lots of people
write lines minds of code assuming
they're all correct and then at the very
end they've got a mistake and they don't
know where it came from
right so particularly when you're
working with images write or text like
things that humans can look at and
understand keep looking at it right so
here I have it yep that looks like the
biggest thing and that certainly looks
like this so let's move on
here's another nice thing in path Lib
make directory okay method so I'm going
to create a path called CSB which is a
path to my large objects CSV file why am
I going to create a CSV file pure
laziness right we have an image
classifier dot from CSV but I could go
through a whole lot of work to create a
custom data set and blah blah blah to
use this particular format I have but
why you know it's so easy to create the
CSB check it inside a temporary folder
and then use something they already have
right so this is kind of a something
I've seen a lot of times on the forum is
people will say like how do I convert
this weird structure into a way that
first day I can accept it and then
normally somebody on the forum will say
like print it to a CSV file so that's a
good simple tip and the easiest way to
create a CSV file is to create a panda's
data frame all right so here's my
panda's data frame I can just give it a
dictionary with the name of a column and
the list of things in that column so
there's the file name
there's the category and then you'll see
here why do I have this I've already
named the columns in the dictionary why
is it here because the order of columns
matters all right and a dictionary does
not have an order okay so this says the
file name comes first in the category
list all right so that's a good trick to
creating a CSV
so now it's just dogs and cats right I
have a CSV file it contains a bunch of
file names and for each one it contains
the plus of that object so this is the
same two lines of code 15,000 times what
we will do though is to like take a look
at this the one thing that's different
is crop type so you might remember the
default strategy for creating whatsis is
here to 24 a to 24 by to 24 image in
fast AI is to first of all resize it so
the largest side sorry the smallest side
is to 24 and then to take a random crop
assuming it's rectangular a random
square run during training and then
during validation we take the center
crop unless we use data augmentation in
which case we do a few ran across for
bounding boxes we don't want to do that
because unlike an image net where the
thing we care about is pretty much in
the middle and it's pretty big a lot of
the stuff in object detection is quite
small and close to the edge so we could
crop it out and that would be bad so
when you create your transforms you can
choose crop type equals crop type got no
and no means don't crop and therefore to
make it square instead it squishes it so
you'll see this guy now looks kind of a
bit strangely wide right and that's
because he's been squished like this
okay and generally speaking a lot of
computer vision models work a little bit
better if you crop rather than squish
but they still work pretty well if you
squish right and in this case we
definitely don't want to crop so this is
perfectly fine right so we you know if
you had like very long or very
or images that you know such that if a
human looked at the squashed version if
you like that looks really weird then
that difficult but in this case we're
just like so the computer whoa okay so
I'm going to kind of quite often just
dig a little bit into some more depths
of fast AI and pipe torch in this case I
want to just look at data loaders a
little bit more so you already know that
let's just make sure this is all run so
you already know that inside a model
data object when there's lots of model
data subclasses like image classifier
data we have a bunch of things which
include training data loader and the
training data set all right and we'll
talk much more about this so but the
main thing to know about training about
a data loader is that it's an iterator
that each time you grab the next
iteration of stuff from it you get a
mini batch okay and the mini that you
get is of whatever size you asked for
and by default the batch size is 64 okay
you can pass below um however so in
Python the way you grab the next thing
from an iterator is with next right you
can't just do that right and why can't
you just do that the reason you can't do
that is because you need to say like
start a new epoch now right in general
like this isn't just in pi choice but
for any Python iterator you're kind of
need to say start at the beginning of
the sequence please all right and so the
way you do that and this is a general
Python concept is you write it up and it
says please grab an iterator out of this
object right specifically as we will
learn later
it means this class has to have to find
an underscore underscore header
underscore underscore method
which returns some different object
which then has an underscore underscore
next underscore underscore yes right so
that's how I do that right and so if you
want to grab just a single batch this is
how you do it X comma y equals next in a
data load that Y X comma Y because our
our lab data loader is our data sets
behind the daily loaders always have an
X you know the independent in the Y the
dependent variable so here we can grab a
mini batch of X's and Y's and now I'm
going to pass that to that show image
command we had earlier but we can't send
that straight to show image for example
here it is for one thing it's not an
umpire right it's not on the CPU and its
shape is all wrong it's not to 24 by 2
24 3 it's 3 by 2 3 4 30 24 furthermore
these are not numbers between 0 &amp; 1
why not because remember all of the
standard imagenet pre-trained models
expect our data to have been normalized
to have a 0 mean and a 1 standard
deviation so if you look inside see
let's use Visual Studio code for this
that's what we've been doing so if you
look inside transform the strong model
so ctrl T transforms from model TFM egg
alright which in turn calls transforms
ashle transports model calls
transport stats and here you can see
normalize and it normalizes with some
set of image statistics and the set of
image statistics they're basically
hard-coded this is the image snap
statistics this is statistics user
insertion models right so there's a
whole bunch of stuff that's been done to
the input to get it ready to be passed
to a pre train model so we have a
function called denim for denormalize it
doesn't only do normalize it also fixes
up the dimension order and all that
stuff right and they look the
denormalization depends on the transport
okay and the data set knows what
transform was used to create it so
that's why you have to go model data dot
and then some data set dot d norm and
that's a function that it's stored for
you that will undo that all right and
then you can pass that a mini batch but
you have to turn it into non bio first
okay so this is like all the stuff that
you need to be able to do to kind of
grab batches and unlock them and so
after you've done all that you can show
the image and we've got that catalyst so
that's looking good so in the end we've
just got this to end of four lines of
code we've got our transforms we've got
our model data come learn about
pre-trained we're using your resna 34
here I'm gonna add accuracy as a metric
fix some optimization function to an LR
find and that looks kind of weird not
particularly helpful normally we would
expect to see a uptick on the right the
reason we don't see it is because we
intentionally remove the first few
points in the last few points the reason
is that often the last few points shoots
so high up towards infinity that you
basically can't see anything so the vast
majority of the time removing the last
few points is a good idea however
when you've got very few mini batches
sometimes it's not a good idea and so a
lot of people asked us on the forum
here's how you fix it all right just say
skip by default it skips 10 at the start
so in this case we just say 5 by default
it's gives 5 at the end we'll just say 1
and so now we can see that the shape
properly um if your data sets really
tiny he made it he's a smaller batch
size like if you only have like three or
four batches worth this one is not going
to see that in this case so it's it's
fine we just have to plot a little bit
more okay so we pick a learning rate we
say fit after 1 Apoc just training the
last player it's a descent
let's unfreeze a couple of players do
another epoch 2% and freeze the whole
thing not really improving why are we
stuck at 80% kind of makes sense right
like unlike imagenet or dogs versus cats
where each image has one major thing
they were kicked because they have one
major thing and the one major thing is
what they're asked to look for a lot of
the Pascal data set has lots of little
things and so a largest classifier is
not necessarily going to do great but of
course we really need to be able to see
the results to kind of see like whether
it makes sense so we're going to write
something that creates this and in this
case I'm kind of like I after working
with this a while I know what the 20
Pascal classes are so I know there's a
person and a bicycle class I know
there's a dog and I so for class so I
know this is wrong it should be so
forever that's correct yes yes chair
that's wrong I think the tables bigger
motorbikes correct because there's no
cactus there should be a bus person's
correct that's correct Kasper if plants
great cars correct so that's looking
pretty good all right so um
when you see a piece of code like this
if you're not familiar with all the
steps to get there it can be a little
overwhelming
alright and I feel the same way when I
see a few lines of code in something I'm
not familiar with I feel like a 1 as
well but it turns out there's two ways
to make it super super simple to
understand the code or there's one high
level where the high level way is run
each line of code step yeah step
printout the inputs print out the
efforts most of the time that'll be
enough if there's a line of code where
you don't understand how the outputs
relate to the inputs go and have a look
for the sauce so now all you need to
know is what are the two ways you can
step through the lines of code one at a
time um the way I use paths the most
often is to take the contents of the
loop copy it create a cell above it
paste it out dent it right I equals
naught and then put them all in separate
cells and then run each one one at a
time
printing out the inputs now I mean I
know that's obvious but the number of
times I actually see people do that when
they asked me for help is basically zero
because if they had done that they
wouldn't be asking for help another
method that's super handy and there's
particular situations where a super
super super handy is to use the Python
debugger
who here is used a debugger before so
after two thirds so for the other half
of here this would be life-changing
actually a guy I know this morning is
actually a deep learning researcher
wrote on Twitter and his his message on
Twitter was how come nobody told me
about the Python debugger before my life
has changed and like this guy's an
expert but because like nobody
teaches basic software engineering
skills in academic courses you know
nobody thought to say to him hey Mark
you know what there's something that
shows you everything your code does one
stair at a time so I replied on Twitter
and I said good news mark not only that
every single language in existence in
every single operating system also has a
debugger and if you google for language
named debugger it will tell you Harry's
right so there's a metal piece of
information point in Python the standard
debugger is called PDB ok and there's
two main ways to use it
the first is to go into your code and
the reason I'm mentioning this now is
because during the next few weeks if
you're anything like me 99% at the time
you'll be in a situation where your
codes not working right and very often
it all have been on the fourteenth
mini-batch inside the forward method of
your custom module that it's like what
do you do
right and the answer is you go inside
your module and you wrap that right and
if you know it was only happening on the
14th iteration you type if I equals 13
right so you can set a conditional
breakpoint that's put a breakpoint PDB
is the Python debugger fast AI imports
it for you if you get the message that
PDB spots there then you can just say
import PD Lee ok so let's try that and
justly it's not the most user-friendly
experience it just pops up a boss right
but the first cool thing to notice is
holders should the debugger even works
in a notebook all right so that's pretty
nifty you can also work in the terminal
plus and so what can you do you can type
a trip right and there are plenty of
tutorials here and the main thing to
know is this is one of these situations
where you definitely want to know the
one letter mnemonics right so you could
type next but you definitely want to
talk right you could type continue
you're definitely less
I've listed the main ones you need so
what I can do now that I'm sitting here
is like it shows me the line I'm Kara
it's about to run okay so one thing I
might want to do is to print out
something and I can write any Python
expression and hit them up and find it
okay so that's that's a useful thing to
do a might want to find out like more
about like well where am I in the code
more generally I just want to see this
line but what's the before it and after
it okay so I want a whole forest right
and so you can see I'm about to run that
line these are the lines above it in the
blower okay um so I might be like okay
let's run this line and see what happens
so go to the next line is ten okay and
you can see now it's about to run the
next one one handy tip you don't even
have to type n if you just hit enter it
repeats the last thing you did
so that's okay so I now should have a
thing called beep right
unfortunately single letters are often
used for debugger commands so if I just
type B it'll run the big man rather than
print B for me that's so to force it to
print use P print okay so there's bird
all right fine let's do next again right
at this point if I hit next it'll draw
the text but I don't want to just draw
the text I want to know how it's going
to draw the text so I don't put no next
over it I want to ask step into it so if
I now hit s to step into it I'm now
inside draw test and I now hit n I
concede your text and so forth okay and
then I'm like okay I know everything I
want to know about this I will continue
until I hit the next breakpoint so C
will continue what if I was zipping
along
this happens quite often that like let's
step into Dean on here I am inside Dean
on and what will often happen is if
you're debugging something in your PI
torch module and it's hidden exception
and you're trying to debug you'll find
yourself like six layers deep inside pi
torch but you want to actually see
backup what's happening when you called
it from right so in this case I'm inside
this property but I actually want to
know what was going on up the call stack
I just hit you and that doesn't actually
run in a thing it just changes the
context of the debugger to show me what
called it and now I can type you know
things to find out about that
environment
okay and then if I'm gonna go down again
it's deep okay so like I'm not gonna
show you everything about the debugger
but I just showed you all of those
commands right yes there's a Oh
something that we found helpful as we've
been doing this is using from ipython
court a debugger imports a trace and
then you get a all prettily colored it's
usually excellent tip let's learn about
some of our students here is it tell us
I know you were doing an interesting
project can you tell us about it okay
hello everyone I mean is a here with my
uh my collaborator Britt and we're using
this kind of stuff to try to build a
Google Translate for animal
communication yeah so that involves
playing around a lot with like
unsupervised machine neural translation
and doing it on top of audio where do
you get data for that from ah that's
sort of the hard problem so there you
have to go and like we're talking to a
number of researchers to try to collect
and collate large data sets but if we
can't get it that way we're thinking
about building a living library of the
audio of the species of Earth that
involves going out and like collecting a
hundred thousand hours of like gelada
monkey vocalization so
all right that's great here okay so
let's get rid of that set trace um the
other place that the debugger comes in
particularly handy is as I say if you've
got an exception
all right particularly if it's deep
inside pipes watch so if I like when I
times 100 here obviously that's gonna in
exception I've got rid of the set trace
so if I run this now okay something's
wrong
now in this case it's easy to see what's
wrong right
but like often it's not so what do I do
percent debug pops open the debugger at
the point the exception that okay so now
I can check like okay creds
Len crits 64 5 times 100 I've got a
print that size and 100 oh no one okay
and you can go down the list okay so I
do all of my development both with the
library end of the lessons in G but a
notebook I do it all interactively and I
use you know percent debug you know all
the time along with this idea of like
copying stuff out of a function of
putting in a desert of cells running it
step by step
there are similar things you can do
inside for example Visual Studio code
there's actually Jupiter extension which
lets you select any line of code inside
Visual Studio code and it'll and say run
in Jupiter and it will run it in Jupiter
and create a little window showing you
the output
there's neat little stuff like that
personally I think Jupiter notebook is
better and perhaps by the time you watch
this on the video you know the lab or me
the main thing give it a lab selection
in the next version of Jupiter notebook
pretty similar Wow I just broke it
totally
okay well we know exactly how to fix it
so we were worried about that another
time hey debug it this evening okay so
to kind of do the next stage we want to
create the bounding box okay and now
creating the bounding box around the
largest object may seem like something
you haven't done before but actually
it's totally something you've done
before okay and the reason is something
you've done before is we know that we
can create a regression rather than a
classification here all right in other
words a classification year on there is
just one that has a sigmoid or soft
mapped out port and that we use across
entropy or binary cross entropy loss
function like that's basically what
makes it if we don't have the softmax it
boys at the end and we use means Guidera
as a loss function it's now our
regression model right and so we can now
use it to predict a continuous number
rather than the category we also know
that we can have multiple outputs like
in the planet competition we did a
multiple object classification what if
we combine the two ideas and to a
multiple column regression so in this
case we've got four numbers top left out
and why bottom-right X&amp;Y yeah and we
could create a neural net with four
activations we could have no softmax or
sigmoid and use a mean squared error
loss function and this is kind of like
where you're thinking about it like
differentiable programming it's not like
how do I create a bounding box model
it's like all right what do I need I
need four numbers therefore I need a
neural network with four activations
okay that's traffic what I need to know
the other half I need to know is a loss
function in other words what's a
function that when it is lower means
that the four numbers are better because
if I can do those two things I'm going
okay well if the X is close to the first
activation and the wires close to the
second so forth then I'm done so that's
it I just need to create a model with
four activations with a mean squared
error loss function and that should be
it right like we don't need anything new
so let's try it so again we'll use a CSV
right and if you remember from part one
to do a multiple label classification
your multiple labels have to be spaced
separated okay and then your file name
is comma separated so I'll take my
largest item dictionary create a bunch
of bounding boxes for each one separated
by a space no use you know this
comprehension I'll then create a data
frame like I did before I'll turn that
into a CSV and now I've got something
that's got the file name and the four
bounding box corners I will then pass
that to from CSV again I will use crop
type equals crop type dot no real next
week we'll look at transform type dot
coordinate for now just realize that
when we're doing scaling and data
augmentation that needs to happen to the
bounding boxes not just images image
classifier data dot CSV gets us to a
situation where we can now grab one mini
batch of data we can do normalize it we
can turn the bounding box back into a
height width so that we can show it and
here it is okay remember we're not doing
classification so I don't know what kind
of thing this is it's just a thing but
there is the thing okay so I now
to create a comic debt based on
President 34 but I don't want to add the
standard a set of fully connected layers
that create a classifier I want to just
add a single linear layer with four
outputs so first AI has this concept of
a custom head if you say my model has a
custom head the head being the thing
that's added to the top of the model
then it's not going to create any of
that fully connected Network for you
it's not going to add the adaptive
average pooling for you but instead
it'll add whatever model you asked for
so in this case I've created a tiny
model it's a model that flattens out the
previous layer so remember I'm normally
would have a seven by seven by I think
512 previous layer in risen at 34 so it
has flattens that out into a single
vector of length 2508
fat and then I just add a linear layer
that goes from 2508 eight to four
there's my four yeah so like that's the
simplest possible kind of final layer
you could add I stick that on top of my
pre-trained risen at 34 model so this is
exactly the same as usual except I've
just got this custom here all right
optimize it with atom user criteria I'm
actually not going to use MSC I'm going
to use l1 loss so I can't remember
recover this last week we can revise it
next week if we did it but l1 loss means
rather than adding up the squared errors
add up the absolute values of years so
it's like it's it's normally actually
what you want adding up the squared
errors really penalize --is bad misses
by too much so l1 loss is generally
better to work with okay I'll come back
to this next week but basically you can
see what we do now is we do our ela find
find our learning rate learn for a while
freeze - - to learn a bit more freeze -
- three learn a bit more and you can see
this validation loss which remember is
the absolute value mean of
absolute value with pixels were off by
gets lower and lower and then when we're
done we can print out the bounding boxes
and lo and behold it's done a damn good
job okay so well revise this a bit more
next week but like you can see this idea
of like if I said to you before this
class do you know how to create a
bounding box model you might have said
no nobody's taught me that all right
but the question actually is can you
create a model with for continuous
outputs yes can you create a loss
function that is lower if those poor
outputs are near to four other numbers
yes then you're done
okay now you'll see if I scroll a bit
further down it starts looking a bit
crappy anytime we've got more than one
object and that's not surprising right
because like how the hell do you decide
which birds so it's just said I'll just
pick the middle which cow I'll pick the
middle how much of this is actually
potted plant right this one it could
probably improve but you know it's got
close to the car but it's pretty weird
right but nonetheless you know for the
ones that are reasonably clear I would
say it's done a pretty good job
okay all right so that's time for this
week I think J you know it's been a kind
of gentle introduction for the first
lesson if you're a professional coder
there's probably like not heaps of new
stuff here for you and so you know in
that case I would suggest like
practicing learning you know about
bounding boxes and stuff if you answer
experienced with things like debuggers
and that flat live api and stuff like
that there's gonna be a lot for you to
practice because we're going to be
really assuming you know well from next
week okay thanks everybody see you next
Monday
[Applause]