welcome to lesson 13 where we're going
to be talking about image enhancement
and image enhancement we'll cover things
like this painting that you might be
familiar with however you might not have
noticed before that this painting
actually has a picture of an eagle in it
the reason you may not have noticed that
before is this painting actually didn't
used to have an eagle in it by the same
token actually on that first page this
painting did not used to have Captain
America's shield on it either and this
painting did not used to have a clock in
it either
this is a cool new paper actually that
just came out a couple of days ago
called deep painterly harmonization and
it uses almost exactly the technique
we're going to learn in this lesson with
some minor tweaks but you can see the
basic idea is take one picture pasted on
top of another picture and then use some
kind of approach to combine the two and
the basic approach is something called a
style transfer before we talk about that
though I wanted to mention this really
cool contribution by William Horton who
added this stochastic weight averaging
technique to the first library that is
now all merged and ready to go and he's
written a whole post about that which I
strongly recommend you check out not
just because stochastic weight averaging
actually lets you get higher performance
from your existing neural networks with
basically no extra work it's as simple
as adding these two parameters to your
fit function but also he's described his
process of building this and how he
tested it and how it contributed to the
library so I think it's interesting you
know if you're interested in doing
something like this I think William had
not built this kind of library before so
he describes how he did it
another very cool contribution to the
faster a library is a new train phase
API and I'm going to do something I've
never done before which are
actually going to present somebody
else's notebook and the reason I haven't
done it before is because I haven't
liked any notebooks enough to think
they're worth presenting but so has done
a fantastic job here of not just
creating this new API but also creating
a beautiful notebook describing what it
is and how it works and so forth and the
background here is as as you guys know
we've been trying to train networks
faster partly as part of this dawn bench
competition and also for a reason that
you'll learn about next week and I
mentioned on the forums last week it
would be really handy for our
experiments if we had an easier way to
try out different learning rate
schedules and stuff and I basically laid
out an API that I had in mind as it'd be
really cool if somebody could write this
because I'm going to bed now
and I kind of need it by tomorrow and so
when I replied on the forum well that
sounds like a good challenge and by 24
hours later it was done and it's been
super cool I wanna I want to take you
through it because it's it's going to
allow you to do research into things
that nobody's tried before so it's
called the Train phase API and the
easiest way to show it is to show an
example of what it does which is here
here is a iteration against learning
rate chart as you're familiar with
seeing and it this is one where we train
for a while at the learning rate of 0.01
and then we train for a while a learning
rate of 0.001
I actually wanted to create something
very much like that learning rate chart
because most people that trained
imagenet use this stepwise approach and
it's actually not something that's built
into fast AI because it's not generally
something we recommend but in order to
replicate existing papers I wanted to do
it the same way and so rather than
writing a number of fit-- fit-- fit--
calls with different learning rates so
it'd be nice to be able to basically say
train for n
at this learning rate and then M epochs
at that learning rate and so here's how
you do that you can say phases so a
phase is a period of training with you
know particular optimizer parameters and
it consists of a number of training
phase objects a training phase objects
is how many epochs to train for what
optimization function to use and what
learning rate amongst other things that
we'll see and so here you'll see the two
training phases that you just saw on
that graph so now rather than calling
were not fit you say low n dot fit with
an optimizer scheduler with these phases
get op
and then from there most of the things
you pass in can just get sent across to
the fit function as per usual so most of
the usual parameters will work fine but
in this case generally speaking actually
we can just use these training phases
and you'll see it fits in the usual way
and then when you say plot LR there it
is alright and not only does it plot the
learning rate it also plots momentum and
for each phase it tells you what
optimizer it used you can turn off the
printing of the optimizers you can turn
off the printing of momentum x' and you
can do other little things like a
training phase could have an LR decay
parameter so here's a fixed learning
rate and then a linear decay learning
rate and then a fixed learning rate
which gives us that picture and this is
like might be quite a good way to Train
actually because we know at high
learning rates you get to kind of
explore better and they're not low
learning rates you get to fine-tune
better and it's probably better to
gradually slide between the two so you
know this actually isn't a bad approach
I suspect you can use other decay types
not as linear so cosine this probably
makes even more sense as a genuinely
potentially useful and learning rate an
ailing shape exponential which is super
popular
approach polynomial which isn't terribly
popular but actually in the literature
works better than just about anything
else but seems to have been largely
ignored so polynomials could to be aware
of and what surveillance done is he's
given us the formula for each of these
curves and so with a polynomial you get
to pick what polynomial to use so here
it is with a different size and I
believe a P of 0.9 is the one that I've
seen really good results for fYI if you
don't give a couple of learning rates
when there's an LR decay then it will
decay all the way down to zero right and
as you can see you can happily start the
next cycle at a different point so the
cool thing is now we can replicate all
of our existing schedules using nothing
but these training phases so here's a
function called phases s JDR which does
SJD are using the new training phase api
and so you can see if he runs this
schedule and here's what it looks like
but he's even done the little trick I
have where you're training a little
really low learning rate just for a
little bit and then pop up and do a few
cycles and the cycles are increasing in
length and that's all done in a single
in a single function so the new one
cycle we can now implement with again a
single little function alright and so if
we run if we fit with that we get this
triangle all followed by a little
flatter bit and the momentum is a cool
thing the momentum has a momentum decay
right and then here we've got a fixed
momentum at the end so it's doing the
momentum and the learning rate at the
same time
so something that I haven't tried yet
but I think would be really interesting
is to use he's calling a differential
learning rates we've changed the name
now to discriminative learning rates to
use oops yes what fix it just scream
inactive learning race so a combination
of discriminative learning rates and one
cycle no one's tried yet
so that would be really interesting
there's actually a the only paper I've
come across which has discriminative
learning rates is called uses something
called Lars lar s and it was used to
Train imagenet with very very large
batch sizes by basically looking at the
ratio between the gradient and the mean
at H layer and using that to change the
learning rate of each layer
automatically and they found that they
could use much larger batch sizes that's
the only other place I've seen this kind
of approach used but there's lots of
interesting things you could try with
combining discriminative learning rates
and different interesting schedules so
you can now write your own LR finder of
different types specifically because
there's now this stop div parameter
which basically means that it'll you
know use whatever schedule you asked for
but when the loss gets too bad at all
stop training so here's one with no
learning rate versus loss and you can
see it stops itself automatically one
useful thing that's been added is the
linear parameter to the plot function if
you use linear schedule rather than an
exponential schedule and your learning
rate finder which is a good idea if
you've kind of fine-tuned into roughly
the right area then you can use linear
to find exactly the right area and then
you probably want to plot it with a
linear scale so that's why you can also
pass linear to plot now as well
you can change the optimizer HBase and
that's more important than you might
imagine because actually the current
state-of-the-art for training on really
large batch sizes really quickly for
imagenet actually starts with rmsprop
for the first bit and then they switch
to SGD for the second vid and so that
could be something interesting to
experiment more with is like because at
least one paper has now shown that that
can work well and again it's something
that isn't well appreciated as yet and
then the bit I find most interesting is
you can change your data and why would
we want to change our data because you
remember from lessons 1 and 2 you could
use small images at the start and later
bigger images later and the theory is
the theory is that you could use that to
kind of train the first bit more quickly
with smaller images and remember if you
like have half the height and half the
width and you've got a quarter of the
activations basically every layer so it
can be a lot faster and it might even
generalize better so you can now create
a couple of different for example it's
because he's got 28 and then 32 sized
images this is just so far 10 so there's
only so much you can do and then if you
pass in an array of data in this data
list parameter when you call fit pop
shared it'll use a different data set
for each face so that's really cool
because we can use that now like we
could use that in our dorm bench entries
and see what happens when we actually
increase the size with very little code
so what happens when we do that well the
answer is here in Dorn bench training on
imagenet and you can see here that
Google is one this with half an hour on
a cluster of TP use the best non cluster
of TPU result is fast AI plus students
under three hours
beating out Intel on 128 computers where
else we ran on a single computer we also
beat Google running on a TPU so using
this approach we've shown the fastest
GPU result the fastest single machine
result the fastest publicly available
infrastructure result these TPU pods you
can't use unless your Google and the
cost is tiny like this Intel one cost
them $1,200 worth of compute they
haven't even written it here but that's
what you get a few user sorry 128
computers in parallel each one with 36
cause each one with 140 gig compared to
our single AWS instance so this is you
know a kind of a breakthrough in in what
we can do like the idea that we can
train imagenet on a single publicly
available machine and this $72 by the
way it was actually $25 because we used
a spot instance so one of our students
Andrew Shaw built this whole system to
allow us to throw a whole bunch of spod
instance experiments up and run them
simultaneously and pretty much
automatically but dawn binge doesn't
quote the actual number we used so it's
actually 25 bucks not 72 bucks so this
data list idea is super important and
helpful and so our sci-fi 10 results
also now up there officially and you
might remember the previous best was a
bit over an hour and the trick here was
using one cycle basically so all this
stuff that's in silver has training
phase API is really all the stuff that
we used to get these top results and
really cool another fast AI student who
goes by the name here bkj has has taken
that and done his own version he took a
resonant 18 and added the concat polling
that you might remember that we learnt
about on top and used leslie cycles once
leslie smith's one cycle and so he's got
on the leaderboard so all the top three
first day i students which is wonderful
and same for cost the top three
and you can see paper space so brett ran
this on paper space and got the the
cheapest result just ahead of dkj
been his name is i believe okay so so i
think you can see like a lot of the kind
of interesting opportunities at the
moment for the training stuff more
quickly and cheaply you're all about
kind of the learning rate annealing and
size annealing and like training with
different parameters at different times
and I still think we buddies scratching
the surface I think we can go a lot
faster and a lot cheaper and that's
really helpful for people you know in
resource constrained environments which
is basically everybody except Google
maybe Facebook architectures interesting
as well though and one of the things we
looked at last week was just like
creating a simpler architecture which is
basically state of the art you know like
the really basic kind of dark net
architecture but there's a piece of
architecture we we haven't talked about
which is necessary to understand the
inception network
the inception network is actually pretty
interesting because they use some tricks
to to actually make things more
efficient and we're not currently using
these tricks and I kind of feel that
maybe we should try it and so this is
the the most interesting most successful
inception network is their inception
resident to network and most of the
blocks in that looks something like this
and it looks a lot like a standard
ResNet block in that there's an identity
connection here and then there's a conv
confirmation is so a one by one conf is
simply saying for each grid cell in your
input you've got a basically it's a
vector write a 1x1 by number of filters
tensor is basically a vector right so
for each grid cell in your input you're
just doing a dot product with that
tensor right and then of course it's
going to be one of those vectors for
each of the hundred and ninety two
activations we're creating soon
basically do 192 dot products with grid
cell 1 1 and then 192 with good 0 1 2 or
1 3 and so forth and so you'll end up
with something which has got the same
grid size as the input and 192 channels
in the output so that's a really good
way to you know either reduce the
dimensionality or increase the
dimensionality of an input without
changing the grid size that's normally
what we use 1x1 cons for so here we've
got a 1x1 conf and then we've got
another one-by-one conf and then they
add it together and then there's a third
path and this third path is not added
this third path it's not actually
explicitly mentioned but it's
concatenated right and so actually there
is a form of ResNet which is basically
identical to resonate but we don't do
plus we do concat right and that's
called a dense net alright so it's just
a resonate where we do concat instead of
plus and that's an interesting approach
because then the kind of the identity
path is literally being copied right so
you kind of get that that that flow
through all the way through and so as
we'll see next week that tends to be
good for like segmentation and stuff
like that where you really want to kind
of keep the original pixels and the
first layer of pixels and the second
layer of pixels and touched so
concatenate another than adding branches
is is a very useful thing to do and so
here we're concatenate in this branch
and this this branch is doing something
interesting which is it's doing first of
all the 1x1 con and then a 1 by 7 and
then a seven by one so what's going on
there so what's going on there is
basically what we really want to do is
do a seven by seven conch the reason we
want to do a seven by seven con is that
if you've got multiple paths each of
which has different kernel sizes then
it's able to look at you know different
amounts of the image and so like the
original inception network had like a
1x1 or 3x3 a 5x5 seven by seven kind of
getting concatenated in together
something like that and so if we can
have a seven by seven filter then we get
to kind of look at a lot of the image at
once and create a really rich
representation and so actually the stem
of the inception network that is the the
first few layers of the inception
network actually also used you know this
kind of seven by seven cond because you
start out with this 224 by 224 by three
and you want to turn it into something
that's like 112 by 112 by 64
so by using a 7x7 Conniff you can get a
lot of information in each one of those
outputs to get those 64 filters but the
problem is that 7x7 conv is a lot of
work you've got 49 kernel values 2 x 49
inputs for every input pixel across
every channel so the compute is crazy
you know you can kind of get away with
it maybe for the very first layer and in
fact the very first layer the very first
con was reza net is a seven by seven con
but i'm not so for inception for
inception they don't do a seven by seven
comma instead they do a one by seven
followed by a seven by one and so to
explain the basic idea of the inception
networks or all the different versions
of it that you have a number of separate
paths which have different convolution
widths in this case conceptually the
idea is this is a one-by-one convolution
with and this is going to be a seven
convolution with and so they're looking
at different amounts of data and then we
combine them together but we we don't
want to have a seven by seven plunge
throughout the network because it's just
too computationally expensive but if you
think about it if we've got some input
coming in right and we have some big
filter that we want and it's it's too
big to deal with and what could we do
right so let's say let's just to make it
a little bit less drawing that's two
five by five what we can do
is to create two filters one which is 1
by 5 1 which is 5 by 1 or 7 or whatever
on line so we take our activations the
previous layer and we put it through the
1 by 5 we take the activations out of
that and put it through the 5 by 1 and
something comes out the other end now
what comes out the other end well rather
than thinking of it as first of all we
take the activations then we put it
through the 5 by 1 then we put it
through the 5 but then we put it through
the 1 by 5 1 by 5 then the 5 by 1 what
if instead we think of these 2
operations together and say what is a 5
by 1 dot production of one by five dot
product do together right and
effectively right you could take a 1 by
5 and a 5 by 1 and the outer product of
that is going to give you a 5 by 5 right
now that you can't create any possible 5
by 5 matrix by taking that product right
but there's a lot of 5 by 5 matrices
that you can create and so the basic
idea here is you know when you think
about the order of operations and I'm
going to go into the detail of this if
you're interested in more of the theory
here you should check out Rachel's
numerical linear algebra course which is
basically a whole course about this
stuff but conceptually the idea is that
very often the the computation you want
to do is actually more simple than an
entire 5x5 convolution very often that
the term we use in linear algebra is
that there's some lower rank
approximation in other words that the 1
by 5 and the 5 by 1 combined together
that 5 by 5 matrix is nearly as good as
the 5 by 5 matrix you really ideally
would have computed
if you were able to and so this is very
often the case in practice right just
because the nature of kind of the real
world is that the real world tends not
to be is you know it tends to have more
structure you know than kind of
randomness so the cool thing is if we
replace our seven by if we replace our
seven by seven conf where the one by
seven and a seven by one right then this
has basically for each cell it's got 14
by input channel by output Channel dot
products to do whereas this one has 49
to do okay so it's just going to be a
lot faster and we have to hope that it's
going to be nearly as good it's
certainly capturing as much widths of
information by definition so if you're
in student learning more about this
specifically in a deep learning area you
can google for factored convolutions the
idea was come up with three or four
years ago now it's probably been around
for long river that was when I first saw
it and yeah it turned out to work really
well and the inception network uses it
quite widely they actually use it in
their in their stem it's it's
interesting actually we've talked before
about how we tend to kind of add-on we
tend to say like this it's main like
backbone you know like when we have
ResNet 34 for example we kind of say oh
this is main backbone which is all of
the convolutions and then we've talked
about how we can add on to it a custom
head right and that tends to be like a
mac spalling layer and a fully connected
layers and whether the you know it's
actually kind of better to talk about
the the backbone is containing kind of
two pieces one is the stem and then the
other is kind of the main backbone
and the reason is that the thing that's
coming in remember it's only got three
channels and so we want some sequence of
operations it's going to expand that out
into something richer generally
something like 64 channels and so in
ResNet the stem is just super simple
it's a seven by seven cons straight to
one followed by a Strad to Emax port
yeah I think that's it if memory serves
correctly an inception they have a much
more complex stem with multiple paths
getting combined and cabin aided
including factoid comms as one by seven
and seven by one and now I'm kind of
interested in what would happen if you
stopped like a resident standard
resonate on top of an inception instead
for instance like I think that would be
a really interesting thing to try
because like an inception stem is kind
of quite a carefully engineered thing
and this thing of like how do you take
your three channel input and turn it
into something richer seems really
important and all of that work seems to
have got thrown away for ResNet we like
ResNet it works really well but what if
we put you know or a dent in it what if
we put the dense net backbone on top of
an inception stem or what if we replaced
the seven by seven cons with a 1 by 7
and 7 by 1 factored conf you know
standard business I don't know there's
lots of things we could try and I think
it'd be really interesting so there's
some more thoughts about potential
research directions ok so that was kind
of my little bunch of random stuff
section moving a little bit closer to
the actual main topic of this which is
what I used image enhancement
I'm going to talk about a new paper
briefly because it's it really connects
what I just discussed with what we're
going to discuss next and the new paper
well it's not that new is it no it's a
year old it's a paper on progressive
dance which came from Nvidia and the
progressive Ganz paper is really neat it
basically sorry Rachel yes we have a
question one-by-one Kampf is usually
called a network within a network in the
literature what is the intuition of such
a name know networking network is more
than just a one by one time it's part of
it I am and we don't I don't think
there's any particular reason to look at
that said I'm aware of okay so the the
progressive can basically takes this
idea of actually gradually increasing
the image size it's the only other
direction I'm aware of where people have
actually gradually increase the image
size and it kind of surprises me because
this paper is actually very popular and
very well known and very well liked and
yet people haven't taken the basic idea
of gradually increasing the image size
and use it anywhere else which shows you
the general level of creativity you can
expect to find in the deep learning
research community perhaps so they start
with four by four like they really go
back start with a four by four again
like literally they're trying to create
like replicate four by four pixel and
then eight by eight and so here's the 8
by 8 pixels this is the celeb a data set
so we're trying to recreate pictures of
celebrities and then they go 65 16 and
then 32 and then 64 and then 128 and
then 256 and one of the really nifty
things they do is that as they increase
size they also add more layers to the
network right which kind of makes sense
right
because if you're doing a more of a
resin Ettie type thing you know then
you're spitting out something which
hopefully makes sense at each grid cell
size and so you should be able to kind
of layer stuff on top and they do
another nifty thing where they kind of
add a skip connection when they do that
and they gradually change the linear
interpolation parameter that moves it
more and more away from the old 4x4
Network and towards the new 8x8 Network
and then once this totally moved it
across they throw away that extra
connection so it's it the details don't
matter too much but it it uses the basic
ideas we've talked about gradually
increasing the image size it's kind of
skip connections and stuff but it's a
great paper to study because a you know
it's like one of these rare things where
they've like good engineers actually
built something that just works in a
really sensible way now it's not
surprising this actually comes from
Nvidia themselves right so in video
don't do a lot of papers and it's
interesting that when they do they build
something that's so thoroughly practical
and sensible and so I think it's a great
paper to study you know if you want to
kind of like put together lots of the
different things we've learned you know
and there aren't many re-implementation
of this so like it's an interesting
thing you know to project and you maybe
you could build on and find something
else so here's what happens next we
eventually go up to 102 4 by 1 or 2 4
and you'll see that the images are not
only getting higher resolution but
they're getting better and so when I
prove 1 or 2 4 by 184 I'm going to see
if you can guess which one of the next
page is fake they're all fake that's the
next stage right you go up up up up up
up up and then BOOM okay so like dance
and stuff they're getting crazy and some
of you may have seen this during the
week
yeah so this video just came out and
it's a speech by Barack Obama and let's
check it out so my Jordan Peele this is
a dangerous time moving forward we need
to be more vigilant with what we trust
from you nourish it's time we need to
rely on trusted news sources they sound
basic but how we before so as you can
see they've used this kind of technology
to literally move Obama's face in the
way that Jordan peels face was moving
and like you basically have all the
techniques you need now to do that so is
that a good idea
so this is the bit where we talk about
what's most important which is like now
that we can like do all this stuff what
should we be doing and how do we think
about that and the Tod our version is I
actually don't know recently a lot of
you saw the founders of this the spacy
prodigy folks founders of explosion a I
had to to talk and Matthew and Ennis I
went to dinner with them afterwards and
we basically spent the entire evening
talking debating arguing about you know
what does it mean they're companies like
ours of building tools that are
democratizing access to tools that can
be used in harmful ways and you know
they're incredibly thoughtful people and
we I wouldn't say we didn't agree we
just couldn't we just couldn't come to a
conclusion ourselves so I'm just going
to lay out some of the questions and
point to some of the research
and when I say research most of the
actual literature review and putting
this together was done by Rachel so
thanks Rachel
let me start by saying the models we
build are often pretty shitty in ways
which are not immediately apparent and
you won't know how shitty they are
unless the people that are building them
with you a range of people and the
people that are using them with you or a
range of people so for example a couple
of wonderful research is Chemnitz at
Stanford and rest joy is she oh she's at
Microsoft now she wasn't Stanford okay
joy is it from PhD from MIT so joy and
Timna did this really interesting
research where they looked at some
basically off-the-shelf face recognizes
one from face plus plus which is a huge
Chinese company IBM's
and Microsoft's and they looked for a
range of different face types I'm
generally speaking you know the
Microsoft one in particular was
incredibly accurate and last the face
type happened to be dark-skinned when
suddenly it went you know 25 times worse
you know got it wrong nearly half the
time and for somebody to a big company
like this to release a product that for
like a very very large percentage of the
world basically doesn't work is more
than a technical failure right it's a
really deep failure of understanding
what kind of team needs to be used to
create such a technology and to test
such a technology or even an
understanding of who your customers are
yeah some of your customers have dark
skin yes Rachel I was also gonna add
that the classifier is all did worse on
women than on men shocking yeah
yeah as funny like actually Rachel
tweeted about something like this the
other day and some some guy was like
what's this all about you know like what
are you saying that we like you know
don't you know about like people people
made cards for a long time you saying
you need women to make cars - and Rachel
pointed out like well actually yes for
most of the history of car safety women
in cars have been far far more at risk
of death than men in cars because the
men created male looking feeling sized
crash-test dummies and so car safety was
literally not tested on women size
bodies so the fact you know like you
know shitty product management with a
total failure of diversity and
understanding is not new to our field
and I would say that was comparing
impacts of similar strength men and
women mm-hmm yeah I don't know why like
whenever you say something nice on
Twitter like Rachel has to say this
because anytime you say something like
some Twitter there's like 10 people
who'll be like all you have to compare
all these other things is if like we
didn't know that so yeah I mean yeah
other things you know our very best most
famous systems do like Microsoft's face
recognizer or Google's language
translator you turn she is a doctor he
is a nurse into Turkish and quite
correctly both the pronouns become Oh
because there's no gendered pronouns in
Turkish so go the other direction
I'll be a doctor I don't know how to say
that one for Christmas and what does it
get turned into he is a doctor she is a
nurse so like we've got these kind of
like biases built into tools that we're
all using every day and again people
they go it's just showing us what's in
the world and well okay there's lots of
problems with that basic assertion but
as you know machine learning algorithms
love to generalize right and so because
they love to generalize this is one of
the cool things about you guys knowing
the technical details now because they
love to generalize when you see
something like 60% of people cooking our
in the pictures they used to build this
model and then you actually run the
model on a separate set of pictures then
84 percent of the people they choose as
cooking women rather than the correct 67
percent but which is like a really
understandable thing for an algorithm to
do as it took a biased input and created
a more biased output because you know
for this particular loss function you
know that's kind of where it ended up
and this is a really common kind of a
really common kind of model
amplification okay so this stuff matters
right it matters in ways more than just
you know awkward translations or like
you know black people's photos not being
classified correctly or you know maybe
there's some there's some wins too as
well like you know horrifying
surveillance everywhere and maybe won't
work on black people right but yes or
it'll be even worse because it's
horrifying surveillance and it's
flat-out racist and wrong okay that sir
but but let's go deeper right like what
hat like that the four always say about
human failings humans such generally you
know that there's there's a long history
of civilization and societies creating
kind of layers of human judgment which
avoid hopefully the most horrible things
happening and sometimes companies which
love technology think let's throw away
the humans and replace them with
technology like Facebook did right so
let's let two or three years ago a
couple years ago Facebook literally got
rid of their human editors like this is
in the news at the time and they were
replaced with algorithms and so now as
algorithms that put all the stuff on
your on your newsfeed and human editors
right at the loop what happened next
many things happen next one of which was
a massive horrifying genocide Menma
babies getting torn out of their mothers
are
right under fires mass rape murder and
an entire people exiled from their
homeland okay I'm not gonna say that was
because Facebook did this but what I
will say is that when the leaders of
this horrifying project are interviewed
they regularly talk about how everything
they learnt about the disgusting animal
behaviors of Rangers that need to be
thrown off the earth they learnt from
Facebook right because the algorithms
just want to feed you more stuff that
gets you clicking and so if you get told
these people that don't look like you
and you don't know a bad people and
here's what the story's about the bad
people and then you start clicking on
them and then they feed you more of
those things and next thing you know you
have this like extraordinary cycle and
people have been studying this right so
for example some we've been told a few
times people click on our first AI
videos and then the next thing
recommended to them is like conspiracy
theory videos from Alex Jones and then
you know continues there because you
know humans click on things that shocked
us and surprise us and horrify us right
and so at so many levels
you know this decision has had
extraordinary consequences which we're
only beginning to understand and again
this is not to say this particular
consequence is because of this one thing
but to say it's entirely unrelated would
be clearly ignoring all of the evidence
and information that we have right so
this is really kind of the key takeaway
is to think like what are you building
and how could it be used right so lots
and lots of effort now being put into
face detection including in our course
right we've been spending a lot of time
thinking about how to recognize stuff
and where
and there's lots of good reasons to want
to be good at that
you know for improving crop yields and
agriculture for improving diagnostic and
treatment planning and medicine for
improving your logo sorting robot system
whatever right but it's also being
widely used in in surveillance and
propaganda and disinformation and you
know again it's like the question is
like well what do I do about that
I don't exactly know right but it's just
definitely at least important to be
thinking about it talking about it and
sometimes you can do really good things
for example meetup comm did something
which I would put in the category of
really good thing which is they
recognized early a potential problem
which is that more men who are tending
to go to their meet us and that was
causing their collaborative filtering
systems which you're all familiar
building now to recommend more technical
content to men and that was causing more
men to go to more technical content
which was causing the recommendation
systems to suggest more technical
content to men right and this kind of
runaway feedback loop is extremely
common when we interface the algorithm
and the human together so what it made
up do they intentionally made the
decision to recommend more technical
content to women right not because of
some you know highfalutin idea about how
the world should be but just because
that makes sense right that the runaway
feedback loop was a bug right there are
women that want to go to tech meetups
but when you turn up for a tech make up
and it's all men and you don't go and
then it recommends more to men and so on
and so forth right so so I made up made
us a really strong product management
decision here which was too
not do what the algorithm said to do
unfortunately this is rare
most of these runaway feedback loops for
example in predictive policing where
algorithms tell policemen where to go
which very often is more black
neighborhoods which end up crawling with
more policemen which leads to more
arrests which has assistance job more
policemen to go to more black
neighborhoods and so forth so this
problem of algorithmic bias is now very
widespread and as algorithms become more
and more widely used for specific policy
decisions judicial decisions day-to-day
decisions about just who to give what
offer to this just keeps becoming a
bigger problem right and so and some of
them are really things that the people
involved in the product management
decision should have seen at the very
start didn't make sense and were
unreasonable under any definition of the
term for example this stuff that I'd
gone pointed out these were questions
that were used to decide which was the
sentencing guidelines this software is
used for both pretrial so who it was
required to post bail so these are
people that haven't even been convicted
as well as for sentencing and for who
gets parole and this was upheld by the
Wisconsin Supreme Court last year
despite all the flaws okay so whether
you have to stay in jail because you
can't pay the bail and how long your
sentences for and how long you stay in
jail for depends on what your father did
whether your parents stayed married who
your friends are and where you live
right now
turns out these algorithms are actually
terribly terribly bad so some recent
analysis showed that they're basically
worse than chance but even the
the company's building them were
confident on these were statistically
accurate correlations
does anybody imagine there's a world
where it makes sense to decide like what
happens to you based on what your dad
did you know so a lot of this stuff you
know at the basic level is obviously
unreasonable and a lot of it just fails
in these ways that you can see
empirically that these kind of runaway
feedback loops must have happened and
these over generalizations must have
happened you know for example these are
the kind of cross tabs that anybody
working in these fields in any field is
using algorithm should be preparing
right so prediction of likelihood of
reoffending for black versus white
defendants like we can just calculate
this very simply of the people that were
labeled high-risk but didn't reopen
there were twenty three point five
percent white but about twice that
african-american where else those that
were labeled law risk but did riaf end
was like half the white people and only
twenty percent of the african-american
right so like this is the kind of stuff
we're least you know if you're taking
the technologies we've been talking
about and putting the production in some
kind of in any way right or building a
an API for other people or providing
training for people or or whatever right
then at least make sure that the that
what you're doing can be tracked in a
way that people know if some things you
know people know what's going on that's
at least they're informed okay I think
it's a mistake in my opinion to assume
that people are our evil you know and
and trying to break society right like I
think I would I prefer to start with an
assumption of like okay if people are
doing dumb stuff it's because they don't
all right so you know at least make sure
that they have this information and I
find very few ml practitioners thinking
about what is the information they
should be presenting in their interface
you know and then often I'll talk to
data scientists who will kind of say
like oh the stuff I'm working one
doesn't have a societal impact it's like
really like like a number of people who
think that what they're doing is
entirely pointless come on you know
otherwise you think people are paying
you to do it for a reason that's going
to impact people in some way okay so
think about what that is the other thing
I know is a lot of people involved here
are hiring people and so if you're
hiring people you know I guess you're
all very familiar with the first day I
philosophy now which is the basic
premise that and I think it comes back
to this idea that I don't think about
people on the whole were evil I think
they need to be informed and have tools
right so we're trying to have us give as
many people the tools as possible that
they need and particularly we're trying
to put those tools in the hand of a more
the hands of a more diverse range of
people so if you're involved in hiring
decisions perhaps you can keep this kind
of philosophy in mind as well that if
you're if you're not just hiring a wider
range of people but also promoting a
wider range of people and providing like
really appropriate Career Management for
a wider range of people well apart from
anything else your company will do
better it actually turns out that more
diverse teams are more creative and tend
to solve problems more quickly and
better than most diverse teams but also
you know you might avoid these kind of
awful screw-ups which you know that one
level are bad for the world and another
level if you ever get found out they can
also destroy your company also they can
destroy you or at least make you look
pretty bad in history a couple of
examples one is you know going right
back to
the Second World War IBM basically
provided all of the infrastructure
necessary to track the Holocaust so they
had a these are the forms that they used
and they say had different code for you
know Jews were Asian gypsies for 12
death and the gas chambers were six and
they all went on these punch cards you
can go and look at these punch cards and
museums now and this has actually been
reviewed by a Swiss judge who said that
IBM's technical assistance facilitated
the task of the Nazis and the commission
of the crimes against humanity and you
know it's interesting to read back the
history you know from these times to see
like what was going through the minds of
people at IBM at that time and you know
what what was clearly going through the
minds was like the opportunity to show
technical superiority the opportunity
that I test out their you know their new
systems it's it's it's you know and the
course the extraordinary amount of money
that they were making um you know and
when when you do something which at some
point down the line turns out to be a
problem even if you were told to do it
that can turn out to be a problem for
you personally for example you will
remember the diesel emissions scandal in
VW know who is the one guy that went to
jail it was the engineer right just
doing his job
okay so if all of this stuff about
actually you know not sucking up the
world isn't enough to convince you they
can up your life too right so if
you if you do something that turns out
to cause problems even though somebody
told you to do it you can absolutely be
held criminally responsible and you're
certainly like look at the but there's
no Cogan
you know I think a lot of people now
know the name Aleksandr Cogan he was the
guy that handed over the Cambridge
analytic er data
he's a Cambridge academic now a very
famous Cambridge academic the world over
for doing his part to destroy the
foundations of democracy right so you
know this is probably not how we want to
go down in history all right so let's
have a break before we do read short
question on a different topic yes in one
of your tweets you said drop out is
patented I think this is about wavenet
patent from Google what does it mean can
you please share more insight on this
subject does it mean that will help to
pay to use drop out in the future yeah
okay good question let's talk about that
after the break and so let's come back
at 7:40 the question before the break
was about patents what does it mean so
so I guess the reasons coming up was
because I wrote a tweet this week which
I think was like three words and said
drop out is patented - the patent
holders is Geoffrey Hinton so what isn't
that great inventions all of our patents
right and so you know my answer is no
you know patents have gone wildly crazy
the amount of things that are patentable
that we talk about every week would be
dozens like it's so easy to come up with
a little tweak and then you know if you
turn that into a patent to stop
everybody from using that little tweak
for the next 14 years and you end up
with a situation we have now where
everything is patented in 50 different
ways and so then you get these patent
trolls who have made a very very good
business out of looking better basically
buying lots of shitty little patents and
then suing anybody who accidentally
turned out did that thing you know like
putting rounded corners on buttons you
know so who was it oh this there's Apple
suits Samsung or something I don't
remember so yeah so what does it mean
for us that a lot of stuff is patented
in deep learning I don't know
it's like one theory like a lot of the
one of the main people doing this is
Google and people from Google who
replied to this patent tend to assume
that on Google's doing it because they
wanted to have it defensively so if
somebody Sue's them they'll be like
don't sue us we'll see you back because
we have all these patents
the problem is that as far as I know
they haven't signed what's called a
defensive patent pledge so basically you
can sign a legally binding document that
says our patent portfolio will only be
used in defense and not offense and even
if you believe all the management of
Google would never turn into a patent
troll
you've got to remember that you know
management changes right and like to
give a specific example I know the you
know the somewhat recent CFO of Google
you know has a much more you know kind
of aggressive stance towards the PNL and
I don't know maybe maybe she might
decide that they should start monetizing
their patents or maybe the you know the
group that made that patent might get
spun off and then sold to another
company that might end up in private
equity hands and decide to monetize the
patents or whatever like so I think it's
a problem there has been a big shift
legally recently away from software
patents actually having any legal
standing so it's possible that these
will all end up thrown out of court but
you know the reality is that anything
but a big company is unlikely to have
the financial ability to defend
themselves against one of these huge
patent trolls
so I think it's a problem I don't know
like it you you can't you can't avoid
using patented stuff if you write code
like most I wouldn't be surprised if
most lines of code you write have
patents on them
so actually funnily enough the best
thing
to do is not to study the patents
because if you do and you infringe
knowingly then it's the penalties are
worse so the best thing to do is to like
put your hands in your ears sing a song
you know and get back to work so that
thing about it said about dropouts
patented forget I said that you don't
you don't know that he's given that bit
okay this is super fun artistic style
we're gonna kind of go a bit retro here
because this is actually the kind of
original artistic style paper and
there's been a lot of updates to it a
lot of different approaches and I
actually think kind of in many ways the
original is the best we're going to look
at some of the newer approaches as well
that I actually think the original is a
terrific way to do it even with
everything that's gone since let's just
jump to the code so this is the style
transfer no four so the idea here is
that we want to take a photo we've got
to take a photo of this bird and we want
to create a painting that looks like van
Gogh painted the picture of the bird
thank off then go quite a bit of the
stuff that I'm doing by the way uses an
image net you don't have to download the
whole of image net for any of the things
I'm doing there's an image net sample on
file start fast today I slash data which
has like I don't know a couple of gig
and it should be plenty good enough for
everything we're doing if you want to
get really great results you can grab
image net you can download it from cab
all the I'm Carol it's the localization
competition actually contains all of the
classification data as well
all right so and you know if you've got
room it's good to have a copy of
imagenet because it comes in handy all
the time so I just grab the bird out of
my imagenet folder and there is my
Buddha and so what I'm going to do is
I'm going to start with this picture and
I'm going to try and make it more and
more like a picture of this bird painted
by Van Gogh and the way I do that is
actually very simple you're all familiar
with it we will create a loss function
which we'll call f yeah and the loss
function is going to take as input a
picture and spit out as output a value
and the value will be lower if the image
looks more like a the bird photo painted
by Van Gogh having written that loss
function we will then use the PI torch
gradient and optimizers gradient times
the learning rate and we're not going to
update any weights we're going to update
the pixels of the input image to make it
a little bit more like a picture which
would be a bird painted by Van Gogh and
we'll stick it through the loss function
again to get more gradients and do it
again and again and that's it so it's
like identical to how we solve every
problem like you know I'm a one-trick
pony right this is my only trick ok tap
create a loss function use it to get
some gradients x learning rates
to update something always before we've
updated weights in a model but today
we're not going to do that they're going
to update that pixels in the input but
it's no different at all
all right we're just taking the gradient
with respect to the input rather than
respect to the weights okay that's it so
we're nearly done let's do a couple more
things let's mention here that there's
going to be two more inputs to our loss
function one is the picture of the bird
birds look like this okay and the second
is an artwork by Van Gogh they look like
this oh and of course go okay so and by
having those as inputs as well that
means we all be able to rerun the
function later to make it look like you
know a bird painted by money or a jumbo
jet painted by van Gogh or whatever
right so those are going to be the three
three inputs and so initially as we
discussed input here this is going to be
the first time I've ever found the
rainbow pen useful there's going to be
that there's also okay
some random noise okay so we start with
some random noise use the loss function
get the gradients make it a little bit
more like a bird painted by Van Gogh and
so forth okay so the only outstanding
question which you know I guess we can
talk about briefly is how we calculate
how much our image looks like a bird
this bird painted by Van Gogh okay so
let's split it into two parts let's put
it into a part called the content loss
and that's going to return a function a
value that's lower if it looks more like
the bird not just any bird the specific
bird that we have coming in okay and
then let's also create something called
the style loss and that's going to be a
lower number if the the image is more
like van goths style okay so there's one
way to do the content loss which is very
simple we could look at the pixels of
the output compare them to the pixels of
the bird and to a mean square error
addemup
so if we did that I ran this for a while
eventually our image would turn into an
image of the bird you should try it
right you should try this as an exercise
try to use the optimizer implied torch
to start with a random image and turn it
into another image by using mean squared
error pixel loss okay not terribly
exciting but that would be step one the
problem is even if we already had our
style loss function working beautifully
and then presumably what we're going to
do is we're going to add these two
together right and then one of them will
multiplied by some lambda so like adjust
some number we'll pick to adjust how
much style versus how much content right
so assuming we had a style loss or we
picked some sensible lambda if we use
two pixel wise content loss then
anything that makes it look more like
Van Gogh and less like the exact photo
the exact background the exact contrast
lighting everything
will decrease the content was which is
not what we want right we wanted to look
like the bird but not in the same way
right it's still gonna have the same two
eyes in the same place and be the same
kind of shape and so forth but not the
same representation so what we're going
to do is this is going to shop here
we're going to use a neural network all
right they're going to use a neural
network I totally meant that to be black
and a came out green it's always a black
box ever mind and we're going to use the
vgg neural network because that's what I
used last year and I didn't have time to
see if other things worked so you can
try that yourself during the week and
the vgg network is something which takes
in an input and sticks it through a
number of layers and I'm just going to
treat these as just the convolutional
layers there's obviously value there and
if it's a bgg with batch norm which most
are today then it's it's also got better
on men there's some X pulling and so
forth but that's fine what we could do
is we could take one of these
convolutional activations and then
rather than comparing the pixels of this
bird we could instead compare the vgg
layer five activations of this to the
vgg layer five activations of our
original birth or layer six or layer
seven or whatever so why might that be
more interesting well for one thing it
wouldn't be the same bird right it
wouldn't be exactly the same because
we're not checking the pixels we're
checking some later set of activations
and so what are those latest sets of
activations contained right well
assuming that's after some max pooling
they contain a small agree
right so it's less specific about where
things are and rather than containing
pixel color values they're more like
semantic things like is this kind of
like an eyeball or is this kind of furry
or is this kind of bright or is this
kind of reflective or is this laying
flat whatever right so we would hope
that there's some level kind of semantic
features through those layers where if
we get something a picture that that
matches those activations then any
picture that matches those activations
looks like the bird but it's not the
same representation of the bird
so that's what we're going to do that's
what our content loss is going to be and
people generally call this a perceptual
loss right which because like it's
really important in deep learning that
you always create a new name for every
obvious thing you do right so if you
compare two activations together you're
doing a perceptual was okay so so that's
it a Content loss is going to be a
perceptual loss and then we'll do the
style loss later so let's start by
trying to create a bird that initially
is random noise and we're going to use
perceptual loss to create something that
is bird-like but it's not this better
okay so let's start by saying they don't
do 28 by 288 like we've because pretty
good to do one bird there's going to be
no GPU memory problems right so I was
actually disappointed that I realized
that I picked a rather small important
image it'd be fun to try this with
something much bigger to create a really
grand scale piece the other thing to
remember is if you are like production
izing this you could like do a whole
batch at a time so people sometimes
complain about this this approach
gaddy's is the lead author the gaddy's
style transfer approaches being slow and
I don't agree it's low it takes a few
seconds and you can do a whole batch in
a few seconds anyway
so we're going to stick it through some
trance
as per usual transforms for vgg 16 model
and so remember the transform class has
a dunder call method so we can treat it
as if it's a function right so if you
pass an image into that then we get the
transformed image right so like try not
to treat the fast AI and ply torch
infrastructure as a black box because
like it's all designed to be like really
easy to use in a decoupled way all right
so this idea of that transforms are just
callable x' ie things that you can do
with parentheses comes from pipe torch
and we totally plagiarized the idea so
with with torch vision or with fast AI
you basically you're transforms are just
color balls and the whole pipeline of
transforms is just a callable so now we
have something of 3 by 2 88 by 2 88
because PI torch likes the channel to be
first and as you can see it's been
turned into a square for us it's being
normalized to 0 1 or that normal stuff
ok now we're creating a random image ok
and here's something I discovered trying
to turn this into a picture of anything
it's actually really hard I found it
very difficult to actually get an
optimizer to get reasonable gradients
that went anywhere and just as I thought
I was going to run out of time for this
class and really embarrassed myself I
realized the key issue is that pictures
don't look like this they have more
smoothness so I turned this into this by
just kind of blurring it a little bit I
used a median filter that basically it's
like a like a median pooling effectively
right and as soon as I change it from
this to this it immediately started
training really well ok so it's like a
number of little tweaks you have to do
to get these things to work is kind of
insane but there's that here is a little
booty alright so we start with a random
image which is at least somewhat smooth
okay and I found that my bird image had
a standard deviation of pixels that was
about half of this
so I mean about half of this mean so I
divided it by two just trying to make it
a little bit easier for it to match I
don't know if it matters turn that into
a variable because this image remember
we're going to be modifying those pixels
with an optimization algorithm so
anything that involved in the loss
function needs to be a variable and
specifically it requires a gradient
because we're actually updating the
image okay all right so we now have a
mini batch of one three channels 288 by
288 random noise we're going to use for
no particular reason the thirty-seventh
layer of vgg if you print out the vgg
Network you can just type in their
member score vgg and prints it out
you'll see that this is a you know kind
of mid to late stage layer so we can
just grab the first 37 layers and turn
it into a sequential model and so now
we've got a subset of heg that will spit
out some mid layer activations and so
that's that's what the models going to
be so we can take our actual bird image
right and we want to create a mini batch
of one so remember if you slice in numpy
with none also known as NP you axis it
introduces a new unit axis in that point
so in here I want to create an axis of
size one to say this is a mini batch of
size one alright so slicing with none
just like I did here has sliced with
none to get this one's one unit axis at
the front okay sis so then we turn that
into a variable and this one doesn't
need to write big be updated so it's we
use DV to say you don't need gradients
for this guy and so that's going to give
us our our target activations
okay so we've basically taken our bird
image turn it into a variable stuck it
through our model to grab the thirty
seventh layer activations and that's our
target right is that we want our content
loss to be this set of activations here
so then we're going to create an
optimizer we'll go back to the details
of this in a moment but we're going to
create an optimizer and we're going to
step a bunch of times going 0 the
gradients call some loss function loss
top backward
no so that's the high-level version and
I'm going to come back to the details in
a moment but the key thing is that the
loss function we're passing in that
randomly generated image the
optimization image or actually the
variable of it right so we passed that
to our loss function and so it's going
to update this using the loss function
and the loss function is the mean
squared error loss comparing our current
optimization image passed through our
vgg to get the intermediate activations
and comparing it to our target
activations okay just like we discussed
okay and we'll run that a bunch of times
and we'll print it out and we have our
bird but not the representation of the
boat okay so there it is so a couple of
new details here one is we had optimizer
lb-ft yes anybody who's done I don't
know exactly what courses they're in but
certain parts of math and computer
science courses comes into deep learning
discovers we use all this stuff like
Adam and the SGD and always assume that
nobody in the field knows the first
thing about computer science and
immediately says oh of any of you guys
tried using the FDS
there's basically a long history of a
totally different kind of algorithm for
optimization that we don't use to train
neural networks and of course the answer
is actually the people who have spent
decades studying neural networks do know
a thing or two about computer science
and it turns out these techniques on the
whole don't work very well but it's
actually going to work well for this and
it's a good opportunity to talk about an
interesting algorithm for those of you
that haven't studied this type of
optimization algorithm at school so BFGS
is one of the names Broyden favor I
can't remember anyway initials are for
different people
at the L stands for limited memory so
it's really just quote VFDs
limited memory BFGS and it's an
optimizer so as an optimizer that means
that there's some loss function and it's
going to use some gradients to I mean
not all optimizes use gradients but all
the ones we use do
here's gradients to find a direction to
go and try to make the loss function go
lower and lower by adjusting some
parameters yeah this just an optimizer
but it's an interesting kind of
optimizer because it does a bit more
work than the ones we're used to on each
step and so specifically
okay Facebook okay so the way it works
is it starts the same way that we used
to which is we just kind of pick
somewhere to get started and in this
case we've picked like a random image as
we saw and as per usual we we calculate
the gradient but we then don't just take
a step but what we actually do is as
well as finding the gradient we also try
to find the second derivative so the
direct second derivative says how fast
is the gradient change so the gradient
is how fast of the function change the
second derivative is how fast as a
gradient change in other words how curvy
is it right and the basic idea is that
if you know that it's like not very
curvy then you can probably jump further
but if it's very curvy then you probably
don't want to jump as far and so in in
higher dimensions the gradients called
the Jacobian and the second derivative
is called the Hessian you'll see those
words all the time that that's what they
mean okay again mathematicians have to
invent your words for everything as well
they're just like deep learning
researchers so it may be a bit more
snooty so with BFGS we're going to try
and calculate the second derivative and
then we're going to use that to figure
out kind of what direction to go and and
how far to go all right so it's less of
a kind of a wild jump into the unknown
now the problem is that actually
calculating the hessian the second
derivative is almost certainly not a
good idea because in each possible
direction that you can add for each
direction that you're measuring the
gradient in you also have to calculate
the hessian in every
direction it gets ridiculously big so
rather than actually calculating it we
take a few steps and we basically look
at how much the gradients changing as we
do each step and we approximate the
Hessian using that little function right
and again this seems like a really
obvious thing to do but nobody thought
of it until someone well surprisingly a
long time later keeping track of every
single step you take takes a lot of
memory so duh don't keep track of every
step you take just keep the last ten or
twenty and the second bit there that's
the L to the l-bfgs so a limited memory
BFGS means keep the last ten or 20
gradients use that to approximate the
amount of curvature and then use the
curvature in gradient to estimate what
direction to travel and how far
and so that's normally not a good idea
in deep learning for a number of reasons
you know it's obviously more work to do
than a kind of an atom or an SGD update
number Z more memory memory is much more
of a big issue when you've got a GPU to
store it on an hundreds of millions of
weights but more importantly the
mini-batches super bumpy so figuring out
like curvature decide exactly how far to
travel is kind of polishing turds as we
say is that an American expression or
just an Australian Australian thing a
bit English there to do in a certain
sense yeah obviously
yeah oh yeah yeah polishing turns you
get the idea and also interestingly
actually take using the second
derivative information it turns out is
like a magnet for saddle points so
there's some interesting theoretical
results that basically say it's actually
sends you towards nasty flat areas of
the function if you use second
derivative information so normally not a
good idea but in this case we're not
optimising weights we're optimizing
pixels so all the rules change and
actually turns
our BFGS does make sense and because it
does more work each time you know it's a
kind of a different kind of optimizer
the API is a little bit different in
plight watch as you can see here when
you say optimizer dot step you actually
pass in the loss function okay
and so my log so my loss function is to
call step with a particular loss
function which is my activation loss
right and as you can see you don't so
you don't inside the loop you don't say
step step-step right but rather it looks
like this so it's a little bit different
and you're welcome to try and rewrite
this to use SGD it'll still work it'll
just take a bit longer I haven't tried
it with SGD I'd be interested to know
how much longer it takes okay so you can
see the loss function going down the
mean squared error between the you know
activations at layer 37 of our vgg model
for our optimized image versus the
target activations and remember the
target activations were the vgg applied
to our Albert so make sense right so
we've okay so we've now got a Content
loss now one thing I'll say about this
content loss is we don't know which
layer it's going to work best so it'd be
nice if we were able to experiment a
little bit more and the way it is here
is annoying maybe we even want to use
multiple layers okay so rather than like
lopping off all of the layers are for
the one we want wouldn't it be nice if
we could somehow like grab the
activations of a few layers as it
calculates now we already know one way
to do that back when we did SSD we
actually wrote our own network which had
a number of outputs remember like the
different convolutional layers we spat
out a different like icon
thing but I don't really want to go and
like add that to the torch vision ResNet
model especially not if like later on I
want to try you know then I want to try
the torch vision vgg model and then I
want to try an S and at a model I don't
to go into all of them and like change
their outputs right besides which I'd
like to easily be able to turn certain
activations on and off with demand so we
briefly touched before this idea that PI
torch has these fantastic things called
hooks you can have forward Hawks that
let you plug anything you like into the
forward path of a calculation or a
backward walk so that's you plug
anything you like into the backward pass
so we're going to create the world's
simplest forward hook and this is one of
these things that like almost nobody
knows about so like almost any code you
find on the internet that implements
style transfer will have all kinds of
horrible hacks rather than using forward
walks but with four books it's really
easy so to create a forward hook you
just create a class right and the class
has to have something called hook
function okay and your hook function is
going to receive the module that you've
hooked it's going to receive the input
for the forward pass and it's going to
receive the target and then you do
whatever the hell you like so what I'm
going to do is I'm just going to store
the output of this module in some
attribute that's it all right so this
can actually be called anything you like
but hook function seems to be the
standard because you can see what
happens here in the constructor is I
store inside some attribute the result
of this is going to be the layer that
I'm gonna hook you go module register
forward hook and pass in the function
that you want to be called when this
module when it's when it's forward
method is called so when it's forward
method is called it will call self dot
hook function
which will store the output in an
attribute cord features okay so now what
we can do is we can create a vgg as
before right and let's set it to not
trainable so we don't waste time and
memory calculating gradients for it and
let's go through and find out let's find
all of the max pool layers alright so
let's go through all of the children of
this module and if it's a max pool layer
let's spit out index minus one so that's
going to give me the layer before the
map sport and so in general the layer
before and that's pool or the layer
before us dry to cons is a very
interesting layer but because it's like
it's the most you know complete
representation we have at that grid cell
size back because the very next layer is
changing the grid okay so that seems to
me like a good place to grab the for
content loss from is you know the best
most semantic most interesting content
we have at that grid size so that's why
I'm going to pick those indexes so Helia
those are the indexes of the last layer
before each max poor in vgg so I'm going
to grab this one here 22 just no
particular reason just to try something
else so I'm going to say sorry this one
here 32 so I'm going to say block ends 3
that's maybe 32 so children vgg indexed
to block ends 3 will give me the 30
second layer of vgg as a as a module
right and then if I call the save
features constructor it's going to go
self cork equals 30 second layer of the
GG register forward hook hook function
ok so now every time I do a forward pass
on this bjg model it's going to store
the 30 second layers output inside
sf dot features so we can now say see
here I'm calling my vgg Network but I'm
not strong it anywhere I'm not saying
you know activations equals vgg of my
image I'm calling it throwing away the
answer and then grabbing the features
that we stored in our SF in our safe
features object right so that way this
is now going to contain one so like I've
done if this is a forward plus now
that's how you do a forward pass and ply
torch you don't say dot forward you just
use it as a callable and using as a
callable on an NN dot module
automatically calls forward that's how
plat watch modules what okay so we call
it as a koala ball that ends up calling
our forward hook that forward hook
stores the activations in SF dot
features and so now we have our target
variable just like before but in a much
more flexible way these are the same
four lines of code we had earlier I've
just stuck them into a function okay and
so it's just giving me my popped up my
random image to optimize and an
optimizer to optimize that image this is
exactly the same code as before so that
gives me these and so now I can go ahead
and do exactly the same thing right but
now I'm going to use a different loss
function activation lost number two
which doesn't say out equals mV GG again
the calls MV chuchita to a forward pass
throws away the results and grabs SF top
features okay and so that's now my 30
second layer activations which I can
then do my MSA loss on you might have
noticed the last time the last loss
function in this one both multiplied by
a thousand why are they multiplied by a
thousand again this was like all the
things that were trying to get this
lesson to not work correctly I didn't
used to have the a thousand yeah it
wasn't training by lunchtime today
nothing was working
after days of trying to get this thing
to work and finally kind of just
randomly noticed like gosh the last
functions like the numbers are really
low you know like 10 e neg 7 and I just
kind of thought well what if they
weren't so low so I multiplied them by a
thousand and instead of working so why
did it not work because we're doing
single precision floating point right
and single precision floating point
ain't that precise and particularly once
you're kind of getting gradients that
are kind of small and then you're
multiplying around the learning rate can
be kind of small and you end up with a
small number and if it's so small they
could get rounded to zero and that's
what was happening and my model wasn't
ready okay so I'm sure there are better
ways I'm multiplying by a thousand
whatever it works fine like it doesn't
matter what you multiply a loss function
by because all you care about is its is
its direction it's relative size right
and interestingly like this is actually
something similar we do for when we were
training imagenet we were using half
precision floating point because the
Volta tents of course require that and
it's actually a standard practice if you
want to get the half precision floating
point to Train you actually have to
multiply the loss function by a scaling
factor and we were using a thousand and
twenty four or five twelve and I think
fast AI is now the first library that
has all of the tricks necessary to train
in half precision floating point
built-in so if you now if you have a
lucky enough to have a Volta or you can
pay for a p3 if you've got a learner
object you can just say learned half and
it'll now just magically train correctly
position floating point that built into
the model data objects as well it's all
automatic and pretty sure no other
library does that okay
so this is just doing the same thing on
a slightly earlier layer and you can see
that the bird looks you know the later
layer you know doesn't look very
bird-like at all but you can kind of
tell it's bird slightly earlier layer
more bird-like right
and hopefully that makes sense to you
that earlier layers are getting closer
to the they're getting closer to the
pixels you know it's a it's a smaller
grid size well there's this little more
grid cells each cell is smaller smaller
receptive field less complex semantic
features so the earlier we get the more
it's going to look like a bit and in
fact the paper has a nice picture of
that showing various different layers
and kind of zooming into this house
they're trying to make this house look
like this picture and you can see that
later on it's pretty messy and earlier
on it looks like this okay
so this is just doing what we just did
and I will say like one of the things
I've noticed in our study group is
anytime I say to somebody to answer a
question yes if we're anytime I say read
the paper there's a thing in the paper
that tells you the answer to that
question there's always this shock look
okay read the paper me the paper but
seriously the papers have like they've
done these experiments and drawn the
pictures like there's all this stuff in
the papers like it doesn't mean you have
to read every part of the paper right
but at least look at the pictures right
so check out the gaddy's paper it's got
nice pictures okay so they've done the
experiment for us they basically did
this experiment okay but it looks like
they didn't go as deep they just got
some earlier ones okay the next thing we
need to do is to create style loss all
right so we've already got the loss
which is how much like the bird is it
now we need how like this painting style
is it and we're going to do nearly the
same thing okay we're going to grab the
activations of somewhere now the problem
is that the activations of some layer
let's say it was a five by five layer
way of course there are no five by five
layers up to 24 by 24 bit corporate head
five by five I whatever nine to say
totally unrealistic sizes but never mind
so there here's some activations and we
could get these activations both per
hour the image we're optimizing and for
our van Gogh thank you and let's look at
our van Gogh painting there it is night
I downloaded this from Wikipedia and I
was wondering what is taking so long to
load it turns out that the the Wikipedia
version I downloaded was thirty thousand
by thirty thousand pixels okay that's
pretty cool they've got this like
serious gallery quality archive stuff
there I didn't know it existed so don't
try and run a neuron in on that totally
killed my Jupiter notebook okay so yeah
so we can do that for our van Gogh image
and we can do that for our optimizer
image and then we can compare the two
and we would end up creating an image
that looks you know content like the
painting but it's not the painting
that's not what we want we want
something with the same style but it's
not the painting it doesn't have the
contrary so we actually want to throw
away all of the spatial information
right we're not trying to create
something that looks that has a moon
here and stars here and because it's a
church here and whatever right we don't
want any of that so how do we throw away
all the spatial information what we do
is let's grab so there are like in this
case they're like nineteen faces on this
right like nineteen slices so let's grab
this top slice
okay let's grab that top slice so that's
going to be a five by five matrix okay
and now let's flatten it so now we've
got a twenty five long vector now in one
stroke we've thrown away the you know
the bulk of the spatial information by
flattening it all right now let's grab a
second slice alright so another another
Channel and do the same thing
okay so here's channel one flattened
here's channel two flattened and they've
both got $25 and now let's take the dot
product which we can do with at in dump
I and so the nine the dot products going
to give us one number what's that number
what is it telling us well assuming this
is kind of somewhere around the middle
activation you know the activations are
somewhere around the middle layer of the
vgg network we might expect some of
these activations to be like how
textured is the brushstroke and some of
them to be like how bright is this area
and some of them to be like is this part
of a house or a part of a circular thing
or other parts to be you know how dark
is this part of the painting and so this
a dot product
remember it's basically a correlation
right if if if this element and this
element are both highly positive or both
highly negative it gives us a big result
right
we're also if they're the opposite gives
a small result if they're both close to
zero it gives no result so it's
basically a dot product as a measure of
how similar these two things are
right and so if the activations of
channel 1 and channel 2
you know how similar that it basically
says let's give an example let's say
this first one was like how textured are
the brushstrokes and this one here that
say was like how kind of diagonally
oriented are the brushstrokes right and
if and if both of these were high
together and both of these were high
together then it's basically saying oh
anywhere that there's more textured
brush strokes they tend to be diagonal
right or another interesting one is what
would be the dot product of c1 with c1
so that would be basically the the two
normal that the sum of the squares of
that channel which in other words is
basically just on average how so let's
go back I screwed this up
channel 1 might be texture and channel
two might be diagonal and this one here
would be cell 1 comma 1 and this cell
here would be like cell say 4 comma 2
and so sorry what I was should have been
saying is if these are both high at the
same time and these are both high at the
same time then it's saying grid cells
would have texture tend to also have
diagonal so sorry I drew that all wrong
the idea was right it has drew it all
wrong so yeah so this number is going to
be high when grid cells that have
texture also have diagonal and when they
don't they don't so that's C 1 dot
product C 2 where else C 1 dot product C
1 right is basically as we said like the
two norm effectively squared or the sum
of the squares of C 1
sum over I of c1 squared and this is
basically saying how in how many grid
cells is the textured channel active and
how active is it so in other words see
one dot product see one tells us how
much textured painting is going on and
see two dot product see two tells us how
much diagonal paint strokes is going on
and you know maybe see three is you know
is it bright colors so see three dot
product see three would be you know how
often do we have bright colored cells so
what we could do then is we could create
a 25 by 25 matrix containing every one
channel 1 channel 2 channel 3 channel 1
channel 2 channel 3 so you're not
channel man it's been a long day 19
there are 19 channels 19 by 19 okay
channel 1 channel 2 channel 3 channel 19
channel 1 channel 2 channel 3 did it do
it channel 19 okay and so this would be
the dot product of channel 1 or channel
1 this would be the drug product of
channel 2 with channel 2 and so forth
after flattening yeah and like we
discussed mathematicians have to give
everything a name so this particular
matrix where you flatten something L out
and then do the doctrine all the dot
products is called a gram matrix
and I'll tell you a secret like most
deep learning practitioners either don't
know or don't remember all these things
like what is a grand matrix if they ever
did study at university they probably
forgot it because they had a big night
afterwards and the way it works in
practice is like you realize oh I could
create a kind of non spatial
representation of how the channels
correlate with each other and then when
I write up the paper I have to go and
ask around and say like does this thing
have a name and somebody be right isn't
it the gram matrix and you go and look
it up that it is right so don't think
like you have to go and study all of
math first you use your intuition and
common sense and then you worry about
what the math is called later normally
sometimes it works the other way not
with me because I can do a mess okay so
this is called the gram matrix and of
course if you're a real mathematician is
very important that you you say this as
if you already always knew it was a gram
matrix and you kind of just go oh yes we
just calculate the gram matrix that's
really important so the grand matrix
then is this kind of map of the diagonal
is perhaps the most interesting right
the diagonal is like which channels are
the most active and then the off
diagonal is like which channels tend to
appear together and overall if two
pictures have the same style right then
we're expecting that some layer of
activations they will have similar Gramm
matrices because if we found the level
of activations that capture a lot of
stuff about like paint strokes and
colors and stuff then the diagonal alone
might even be enough and like that's
another interesting homework assignment
if somebody wants to take it is try
doing gaddy's style transfer not using
the ground matrix but just using the
diagonal of the gray matrix and that
would be like a single line of code to
change that I haven't seen it tried and
I don't know if it would work at all but
it might work fine Christine Christine
okay yes Christine you've tried it and
it works most of the time except when
you have funny pictures where you need
two styles to appear in the same spot so
it sounds like grass in one half and
like a crowd in one half and you need
the two styles ah cool
you're still gonna take your homework is
that okay Christine says she'll do it
for you okay
so let's do that so here's our painting
I've tried to resize the painting so
it's the same size as my bird picture so
that's all this is just doing so I make
the yeah so there it is it doesn't
matter too much which bit I use as long
as it's got lots of a nice style in it I
grab my optimizer and my random image
just like before and this time I call
save features for all of my block ends
and that's going to give me an array of
save features objects one for each
module that appears the layer before
IMAX Paul so now because because this
time I want to play around with
different activation layer styles or
more specifically I want to let you play
around with it okay so now I've got a
whole array of them so now I call my vgg
module on my my image again yeah I'm not
going to use that yeah okay ignore that
line.i style image sorry style images my
van Gogh painting so I take my style
image put it through my transformations
to create my transform style image I
turn that into a variable put it through
the forward pass of my vgg module and
now I can go
through all of my save features objects
and grab each set of features and notice
I call clone right because I don't I've
caused like later on if I call my vgg
object again it's going to replace those
contents I haven't quite thought about
whether this is necessary if you take it
away and it's not that's fine but us as
being careful
so here's now an array of the
activations at every block and player so
here you can see all of those shapes and
you can see like being able to like whip
up a list comprehension really quickly
it's really important in your Jupiter
fiddling around because you really want
to be able to like immediately see you
know here's my channel sixty four one
four six five twelve and you can see
here the grid size having as we would
expect because all of these appear just
before M export so so do a Graham MSC
loss it's going to be the MSE loss on
the ground matrix of the input versus
the gram matrix of the target and the
ground matrix is just the matrix
multiply of X with X transpose where X
is simply equal to my input where I've
flattened the batch and channel axes all
down together and I already got one
image so you can kind of ignore the
batch part right it's basically channel
and then everything else which in this
case is the height and width is the
other dimension because there's now
it'll be channel by width and then as we
discussed we can then just do the matrix
multiply of that by its transpose and
just to normalize it we'll divide that
by the number of elements it would
actually be more elegant if I had said /
import dot Nam elements that were in the
same thing okay
and then again this kind of keep me tiny
numbers so I multiply it by a big number
to make it something more sensible okay
so that's basically my loss right so now
my style loss is to take my image to
optimize throw it through vgg forward
pass grab an array of the features in
all of the safe features objects and
then call my Graham MSC loss on every
one of those layers okay and that's
going to give me an array and then I
just add them up now you could add them
up with different weightings you could
add up subsets whatever right in this
case I'm just grabbing all of them pass
that into my optimizer as before and
here we have a random image in the style
of Van Gogh which i think is kind of
cool and again gaddy's has done it for
us here is different layers of random
image in the style of Van Gogh and so
that the first one as you can see the
activations are simple geometric things
not very interesting at all the later
eight layers are much more interesting
so we kind of have a suspicion that we
probably want to use later layers
largely for our style laughs if we
wanted to look good all right I added
this what was it this save features dot
close which just calls remember I stored
the hook here and so Hawk don't remove
gets rid of it and it's a good idea to
get rid of it because otherwise you know
you can potentially just keep using
memory all right so at the end I go
through each of my so features objection
was it so style transfer is
adding the two together with some weight
so there's not much to show
grab my optimizer grab my image and now
my combined loss is the MSE loss at one
particular layer my style loss set all
of my layers sum up the stay losses add
them to the content loss the content
lost so I'm scaling actually the style
loss a scaled already by 1e6
and this one is one two three four five
six okay so actually they're they're
both the scaled exactly the same add
them together and again you could try
weighting the different style losses or
you could maybe remove some of them
whatever so this is the simplest
possible version train that and like
holy it actually looks good so I
think that's yeah I think that's pretty
awesome you know again you know the main
takeaway here is if you want to solve
something with a neural network all you
got to do is set up a loss function and
then optimize something all right and
the loss function is something which a
lower number is something that you're
happier with because then when you
optimize it it's going to make that
number as low as you can and it'll do
what's your what did its do okay so here
we can't what we didn't come up with
Gettys came up with a loss function that
does a good job of being a smaller
number when it looks like the thing we
want it to look like and it looks like
the style of the thing we want to be in
the style of that's all we had to do
right we like what it actually comes to
it you know apart from implementing gram
MSE loss which was like six lines of
code if that that's our loss function
pass it to our optimizer wait about five
seconds
and we're done and remember we could do
a batch of these at a time so we could
wait five seconds and sixty-four of
these will be done yeah so I think
that's really interesting and and since
this paper came out you know it's really
inspired a lot of interesting work to me
though most of the interesting work
hasn't happened yet because to me the
interesting work is the work where you
combine human creativity with these
kinds of tools you know and you know I
haven't seen much in the way of tools
that you can download or use where you
know that the artist is in control and
can kind of do things interactively it's
interesting talking to the guys at the
Google Magento project which is kind of
their creative value project all of the
stuff they're doing with music is
specifically about this it's building
tools that musicians can use to perform
in real time and so you'll see much more
of that on the music space thanks to
magenta if you go to their website
there's all kinds of things where you
can like press the buttons to like
actually change the drum beats or
melodies or keys or whatever and you can
definitely see like Adobe an Nvidia it's
kind of starting to release you know
little prototypes and started you
through this spit you know this kind of
like creative AI explosion hasn't
happened yet I think we have pretty much
all the technology we need but no one's
like put it together into a thing and
said like look at the thing I built and
look at the stuff that people built with
my thing you know so that's just a huge
area of opportunity so the paper that I
mentioned at the start of class in
passing the one where we can add Captain
America's shield to arbitrary paintings
basically used this technique right that
the trick was though some minor tweaks
to make the kind of the pasted Captain
America shield
blending nicely right but like that
would that papers only a couple of days
old so like that would be a really
interesting project to try because you
you can use all this code you know it
really does leverage this approach and
then you could start by you know making
the content image be like the painting
with the shield and then the style image
could be the painting without the shield
and like that would be a good start and
then you could kind of see what specific
problems they try to solve and there's
painting in this paper to make it better
but you know you could you could have a
start on it right now
okay so let's make a quick start on the
next bit which is yes Rachel say two
questions earlier there are a number of
people that expressed interest in your
thoughts on pyro and probabilistic
programming yeah so you know tensor
flows now but this particular tends to
flow probability or something there's
yeah there's a bunch of probabilistic
programming frameworks out there I I
think they're intriguing you know but as
yet unproven in the sense that like I
haven't seen anything done with any
probabilistic programming system which
hasn't been done better without them the
basic premise is that it allows you to
create more of a moral of how you think
the world works and then like plug in
the parameters so back when I used to
work in management consulting 20 years
ago we used to do a lot of stuff where
we would use a spreadsheet and then we
would have these Monte Carlo simulation
and plugins at risk and one crystal ball
I don't know if there still exists
decades later but basically they would
let you like change a spreadsheet cell
to say this is not a specific value but
it actually represents a distribution of
values with this mean and the standard
deviation or it's got this distribution
and then you would like hit a button and
the spreadsheet would recalculate a
thousand times pulling random numbers
from those distributions and show you
like the distribution of your outcome
that might be some you know profit or
market share or whatever and we used
them all the time back there apparently
think that feel that a spreadsheets a
more obvious place to do that kind of
work because you can kind of see it all
much more naturally but I don't know
we'll see at this stage I I hope it
turns out to be useful because I find it
very appealing and it kind of appeals to
as I say the kind of work I used to do a
lot of there's actually whole practices
around this stuff they used to call
systems dynamics which really was built
on top of this kind of stuff but no it's
it's not quite gone anywhere hey then
there is a question about pre training
for generic style transfer yes I don't
think you can pre train for a generic
style but you can pre train for a
generic photo for a particular style
which is where we're going to get to
although it may end up being a homework
I haven't decided but I'm going to do
all the pieces and one more question is
please ask him to talk about multi-gpu
oh yeah I haven't had a slide about that
it's events actually we're about to
about to get it
so yes okay so before we do just another
interesting picture from the Geddes
paper they've got a few more just didn't
fit in mice in my slide here but
different convolutional layers for the
style different style to content ratios
and here's the different images
obviously this isn't
then go anymore there's a different
combination so you can see like if you
just do like wall style you don't see
any image if you do all you know lots of
content that you use low enough
convolutional layer it looks okay but
the backgrounds kind of dumb so you kind
of want somewhere around here or here
I guess anyway so you can play around
with it and experiment but also use the
paper to help guide you actually I think
I might work on the math now and we'll
talk about multi GPU and and super
resolution next week because I think
that this is from the the paper and like
one of the things I really do want you
to do after we talk about a paper is to
read the paper and then ask questions on
the forum anything that's not clear but
there's kind of like a key part of this
paper which I wanted to talk about and
discuss how to interpret it so we're
going to be the paper says we're going
to be given an input image X and this
little thing means it's whatnot it means
it's a vector Rachel but this one's a
matrix I guess it could mean either yeah
I don't know maybe it's anyway so
normally small letter bulk means vector
or a small letter with Dubey on top
means vector they can both mean vector
and normally big letter means matrix or
small letter with two doobies on top
means matrix in this case our image is a
matrix we are going to basically treat
it as a vector so maybe we're just
getting ahead of ourselves so we've got
an input image X and it can be encoded
in a particular layer of the CNN by the
filter responses so the activations your
responses are activations right so
hopefully that's something you all
understand that's basically what a CNN
does is it produces layers of
activations Alea has a bunch of filters
right which produce a number of channels
right and so this year says that layer
number L has capital
our filters and again this capital does
not mean matrix so I don't know math
notation is so inconsistent so capital
NL distinct filters that layer L which
means it has that also that many feature
Mouse right so make sure you can see
that this letter is the same as list
letter that's you've got to be very
careful to read the letters and
recognize it's like snap you know that's
the same letter as that okay so
obviously NL feature maps are in our
filters filters create and our feature
maps or channels h1 is of size M okay so
I can see this is where the this is
where the unrolling is happening each
map is of size M little L right so this
is like you know m square bracket L in
numpy notation it's the elf layer so m
for the elf layer and the the size is
height times width okay so we flattened
it out so the responses at that layer L
can be stored in a matrix F and now the
old grows at the top for some reason so
this it's not f ^ else it's just another
indexing we're just moving around fun
and this thing here where we say it's an
element of R this is a special I mean in
the real numbers n times M this is
saying that the dimensions of this is n
by M right so this is really important
like you don't move on it's just like
with PI torch making sure that you
understand the rank and size of your
dimensions first same with math right
you did these are the bits where you
stop and think why is it n by M right
okay so n is a number of filters M is
height by width right so do you remember
that thing where we did viewer batch x
channel comma minus 1 right here that is
okay so try to map the code to the math
so f is
f is X if I was nicer to you I would
have used the same letters as the paper
but I was too busy getting this damn
thing working to do that carefully so
you can go back and rename it as capital
F okay and this is why we moved the L to
the top is because we're now going to
have some more indexing right so like
where else your numpy or apply torch we
index things by square brackets and then
lots of things with commas between the
approach in math is to like surround
your letter by little letters all around
it okay and just throw them up there
everywhere so here F L is the elf layer
of F and then I J is the activation of
the I filter at position J of layer yeah
right so position J is cut up to size M
which is up to size height by width this
is the kind of thing that be easy to get
confused like often you'd see an IJ and
assume that's like indexing into a
position of an image like height by
width but it's totally not is it okay
it's indexing into channel by flattened
image right and it even tells you it's
the I filter the earth channel in the
J's position in the flattened out image
in layer L right so you you're not gonna
be able to get any further in the paper
unless you know unless you understand
what F is okay so that's why like these
are the bits where you stop and make
sure you're comfortable all right so now
the content lost so I'm not going to
spend much time on but basically we're
going to just check out the values of
the activations versus the predictions
squared right so there's our content
loss okay and the style loss will be
much the same thing but using the grande
matrix G okay and I really wanted to
show you this ones I think it's super
this is sometimes I really like things
you can do in math note
and they're things that you can also
generally do in J and APL which is this
kind of this implicit loop going on here
right what this is saying is there's a
whole bunch of values of I and a whole
bunch of values of J and I'm going to
define G for all of them and there's a
whole bunch of values of L as well I'm
going to define G for all of those as
well right and so for all of my G at
every L of every I at every J it's going
to be equal to something and you can see
that something has an i and a J and an L
right
so matching these and it also has a K
and that's part of the sum
so what's going on here well it's saying
that my grand matre --ks in layer l for
the eighth channel
well there's out channels anymore in the
eighth position in one axis and the j DH
position and another axis is equal to my
F matrix so my flattened out matrix for
the eighth channel in that layer versus
the jafe channel and the same layer and
then I'm going to sum over I'm going to
say see this K in this case are the same
letter right so we're going to take the
k DH position and multiply them together
and then add them all up all right so
that's exactly what we just did before
when we calculated our own matrix right
so like this there's a lot going on
because of some like to me very neat
notation right which is there are three
implicit loops or going on at the same
time plus one explicit loop in the Sun
and then they all work together to
create this grand matrix for every layer
that's so let's go back and see if you
can match this yeah so so oh that's kind
of happening all at once which i think
is pretty great okay so that's it so
next week we're going to be looking
at a very similar approach basically
doing style transfer all over again but
in a way where we were actually going to
train a neural network to do it for us
rather than having to do the
optimization and we'll also see that you
can do the same thing to do super
resolution and we're also going to go
back and revisit some of that SSD stuff
as well as doing some some segmentation
so if you're if you've forgotten SSD
might be worth doing a little bit of
revision this week all right thanks
everybody see you next week
[Applause]