so we're going to be talking about Ganz
today who has heard of Ganz
yeah most of you very hot technology but
definitely deserving to be in the
cutting edge deep learning part of the
course because they're not quite proven
to be necessarily useful for anything
but they're nearly there they're
definitely going to get there and we're
going to focus on the things where
they're definitely definitely going to
be useful in practice and there's a
number of areas where they may turn out
to be useful in practice but we don't
know yet so I think the area that we're
going to be that they're definitely
going to be useful in practice is the
kind of thing you see on the left here
which is for example turning drawings
into rendered pictures this comes from a
paper that's just came out two days ago
so there's a very active research going
on right now before we get there though
let's talk about some interesting stuff
from the last class this was an
interesting thing that one of our
diversity fellows Christine Payne did
Christine has a master's in medicine
from Stanford and so she OC had an
interest in thinking what would it look
like if we built a language model of
medicine and one of the things that we
briefly touched on back in less than
four but didn't really talk much about
last time is this idea you can actually
seed a generative language model which
basically means you've trained a
language model on some corpus and then
you're going to generate some text from
that language model and so you can start
off by feeding it a few words you know
to basically say here's the first few
words to create the hidden state in the
language model and then generate from
there please and so when Christine so
Christine did something clever which was
to kind of pick up was to seed it with a
question and then repeat the question so
it's 3 times Christine three times and
then where'd it generate
from there and so she fed a language
model lots of different medical texts
and then fed at this question what is
the prevalence of malaria and the model
said in the US about 10 percent of the
population has the virus but only about
one percent is infected with a virus
about 50 to 80 million infected she said
what's the treatment for ectopic
pregnancy and it said it's a safe and
safe treatment for women with the
history or symptoms may have a
significant impact and clinical response
most important factor is development and
management of ectopic privacy etc and so
what I find interesting about this is
you know it's it's pretty close to it
being a to me as somebody who doesn't
have a masters in medicine from Stanford
are pretty kind of close to being a
believable answer to the question but it
really has no bearing on reality
whatsoever and I kind of think it's an
interesting kind of ethical and user
experience quandary so actually I'm
involved also in a company called dr. a
that's trying to basically doing a
number of things but in the end provide
an app for doctors and patients which
can help kind of create a conversation
or user interface around helping them
with their medical issues and I've been
kind of continually saying to the
software engineers on that team please
don't try to create a generative model
using like an LST em or something
because they're going to be really good
at creating bad advice that sounds
impressive you know kind of like you
know political pundits or tenured
professors you know people who can say
with great Authority so I think
yeah so I thought it was really I
thought it was a really interesting
experiment and great to see you know
what what about diversity fellows doing
I mean this is why we have this program
I suppose I should just say masters in
medicine actually a Juilliard trained
classical musician or on actually also a
Princeton valedictorian in physics so
also a
woman's a computing expert yeah okay so
she does a bit of everything so yeah
really impressive group of people and
great to see such exciting kind of ideas
coming out and if you're wondering you
know I've done some interesting
experiments should I let people know
about it
well I Kristin mentioned this in the
forum I went on to mention it on Twitter
too which I got this response you are
you looking for a job you may be
wondering whose AVM aerotrain is well he
is the founder of a hot new medical AI
startup he was previously the head of
engineering at Quora before that he was
the guy net flips around the data
science team and built their recommender
systems and so this is what happens if
you do something cool let people know
about it and get get noticed by awesome
people like stevia
so let's talk about sci-fi 10 and the
reason I'm going to talk about so far 10
is that we're going to be looking at
some more you know bare-bones PI torch
stuff today to build these generative
adversarial models there's there's no
really fast AI support to speak up at
all Dan's at the moment I'm sure there
will be soon enough apparently there
isn't so we're going to be building a
lot of models from scratch now it's been
a while since we've done much you know
serious model building a little bit of
model building I guess for our bounding
box staff but really all the interesting
stuff there was the loss function so we
looked at sci-fi 10 in the plat 1 of the
course and we built something which was
getting about 85% accuracy and I
remember a couple of hours to Train
interestingly there's a competition
going on now to see who can actually
train sci-fi turn the fastest going
through this earth Stepford Dawn bench
and currently so the goal is to get it
to train to 94% accuracy so everything
to see if we can build an architecture
then can get
four percent accuracy because that's a
lot better than our previous attempt and
so hopefully in doing so we'll learn
something about creating good
architectures that will be then useful
for looking at these gams today but I
think also it's useful because I've been
kind of looking much more deeply into
the last few years papers about
different kinds of CN n architectures
and realize that a lot of the insights
in those papers are not being widely
leveraged and clearly not widely
understood so I want to show you what
happens if we can leverage some of that
understanding so I've got this note book
called sci-fi 10 darknet that's because
the the particular architecture we're
going to look at is it's quite is really
very close to the darknet architecture
but you'll see in the process that the
darknet architecture has in not the
whole euro version three end-to-end
thing but just the part of it that they
pre trained on imagenet to do
classification it's almost like the most
generic simple architecture almost you
could come up with and so it's a really
great starting point for experiments so
we're going to call it dark net but it's
not quite that net and you can fiddle
around with it to create things that
definitely aren't dark now it's really
just the basis of nearly any modern
ResNet based architecture so so far 10
remember is a fairly small data set the
images are only 32 by 32 in size and I
think it's a really great data set to
work with because it's you can you can
train it you know relatively quickly
unlike image net it's a relatively small
amount of data
unlike image net now it's actually quite
hard to recognize the images because 32
by 32 is it's kind of too small to
easily see what's going on so it's it's
somewhat challenging so I think it's a
really underappreciated data set because
it's old you know and you know who a
deep mind or even an AI wants to work
with a small old data set when they
could use their entire server room to
process something much bigger but you
know to me I think this is a really
great
data set to focus on so so go ahead and
and kind of import our usual stuff and
we're going to try and build a network
from scratch to train this with one
thing that I think is a really good
exercise for anybody who's not a hundred
percent confident with their kind of
broadcasting and pi torch and so forth
basic skills is figure out how I came up
with these numbers okay so these numbers
are the averages for each channel and
the standard deviations for each channel
insofar cap so try and that's a bit of a
homework just make sure you can recreate
those numbers and see if you can do it
and you know no more than a couple of
lines of code you know no loops all
right ideally I want to kind of do it in
one go Ken alright because these are
fairly small we can use a larger batch
size unusual 256 and the size of these
images is 32 transformations normally we
kind of have this standard set of sidon
transformations we used for photos of
normal objects we're not going to use
that here though because these images
are so small that trying to rotate a 32
by 32 image a bit is going to introduce
a lot of you know blocky kind of
distortions so the kind of standard
transforms that people tend to use is a
random horizontal flip and then we add
size divided by 8 so 4 pixels of padding
on each side and one thing which I find
works really well is by default fast AI
doesn't add black padding which
basically every other library does we
actually take the last 4 pixels of the
existing photo and flip it and reflect
it and we find that we get much better
results by using this reflection padding
by default so now that we've got a 36 by
36 image this sort of transforms in
training will randomly pick a 32 by 32
crop so we got a little bit of variation
but not he's all right so we can use a
normal from past
grab our data so we now need an
architecture and what we're going to do
is we've got to create an architecture
which fits in one screen okay so this is
from scratch as you can see the only you
know I'm using the predefined come 2d
veteran onto a daily key value modules
but I'm not using any blocks or anything
they're all being defined so the entire
thing is here on one screen so if you're
ever wondering can I understand a modern
good quality architecture absolutely
let's study let's study this one okay so
my basic starting point with an
architecture is to say okay it's it's
it's a stacked bunch of layers and
generally speaking there's going to be
some kind of hierarchy of layers so at
the very bottom level there's things
like a convolutional layer and a batch
nom layer but generally speaking any
time you have a convolution you're
probably going to have some standard
sequence and normally it's going to be
con fetch norm then a nonlinear
activation like a value right so you
know I try to start kind of right from
the top by saying okay what are my basic
units going to be and so by defining it
here that way I don't have to worry
about I don't have to worry about kind
of trying to try to keep everything
consistent it's going to make everything
a lot simpler so here's my con flavor
and so anytime I say come flare
I mean cons batch norm rally now I'm not
quite saying
value I'm saying leaky value and that's
I think we've briefly mentioned it
before but the basic idea is that
normally Lu looks like that right
hopefully you all know that now a leaky
rail you looks like that right so this
part as before has a gradient of 1 and
this part has a gradient of it can vary
but something around point one or point
zero one is common now and the idea
behind it is that when you're in this
negative zone here you don't end up with
a zero gradient which makes it very hard
to update it in practice people have
found leaky value more useful on smaller
datasets and less useful and big
datasets but it's interesting that for
the Yola version 3 paper they did use
early key value and got great
performance from it so it really makes
things worse and it often makes things
better so it's probably not bad if you
need to create your own architecture to
make that your default go to is to use
leaky value ok you'll notice I don't
define a pipe launch module here I just
go ahead and go sequential this is
something that if you read other
people's height watch code it's really
underutilized people tend to write
everything is applied watch module with
an inert and a forward but if you're if
the thing you want is just a sequence of
things one after the other
it's much more concise and easy to
understand to just make it a sequential
right so I just got a simple plain
function it just returns a sequential
model alright so I mentioned that
there's generally kind of a number of
hierarchies of kind of units in most
modern networks and I think we know now
that the the kind of next level in this
unit hierarchy for rez nets and kind of
this this is a type of resin it is the
is the the res block or the residual
block I quoted here as Leia and back
when we lasted sci-fi 10 I over simplify
this I cheated a little bit
we had X coming in and we put that
through a conf and then we added it back
up to X to go out okay so we ended up so
but in general you know we've got your
output is equal to your input plus some
function of your input right and the
thing we did last year was we meant we
made F was a 2d conf okay
but actually the in the real res block
is actually two of them okay so it's
actually Khan of Khan's of X okay and
when I say conf I'm using this as a
shortcut for outcome flare in other
words in other words calm Vectren on
real you okay so you can see here I've
created two coms and here it is I take
my ex put it through the first com put
it through the second con and add it
back up to my input again to get my
basic Reds block okay so one kind of
interesting approach or one interesting
insight here is kind of what are the
number of channels in these convolutions
right so we've got coming in some ni
some number of input channels number of
inputs well number of input filters okay
the way that the darknet folks set
things up is they said okay we're going
to make every one of these rez layers
spit out the same number of channels
that came in and I kind of liked that
that's why I used it here because it
makes life simpler right and so what
they did is they said okay let's have
the first cons have the number of
channels and then the second con double
it again
so ni goes to ni / - and then ni / -
goes to ni right so you've kind of got
this like funneling thing where if
you've got like 64 channels coming in
you kind of get squished down with a
first come down to 32 channels and then
taken back up again to 64 channels
coming out
yes retro why is in place equals true in
the leaky rally oh thanks for asking a
lot of people forget this I don't know
about it but this is a really important
memory technique if you think about it
this cone flower it's like the lowest
level thing so pretty much everything in
our resin it once it's all put together
is going to be complex complex complex
if you don't have in place equals true
it's going to create a whole separate
piece of memory for the output of the
value so like it's gonna allocate a
whole bunch of memory that's that's
totally unnecessary and actually since I
wrote this I come up came up with an
another idea the other day which I'll
now implement which is you could do the
same thing for the res layer rather than
going let's just reorder this to say X
plus that you can actually do the same
thing here yeah hopefully some of you
might remember that in PI torch pretty
much every function has an underscore
suffix version which says do that in
place so plus there's also a add and so
that's add in place and so that's now
suddenly reduced my memory there as well
so these are these are really handy
little tricks and I actually forgot the
in place equals true at first for this
in my literally he was having to
decrease my batch size to much lower
amounts and I mean you should be
possible and it was driving me crazy and
then I realized that that was missing
you can also do that with drop out by
the way if you have dropped out so drop
out and
all the activation functions you can do
in place and then generally any
arithmetic operation you can do in place
as well
why is bias usually like in ResNet set
to false in the conflate yeah so if
you're watching the video pause now and
see if you can figure this out right
because this is a really interesting
question is like why don't we need bias
okay so I wait for you to pause okay
welcome back so if you figured it out
here's the thing right
immediately after the Kahn is a batch
not and remember batch norm has to learn
herbal parameters for each activation
the the kind of the thing you multiply
by and the thing you add so since we're
if we if we had bias here to add and
then we add another thing here we're
adding to you things which is totally
pointless like that's two weights where
one would do right so if you have a
batch norm after a cons then you can you
can either say in the batch norm don't
don't include the add bit there please
or easier is just to say don't include
the bias in it there's no particular
harm but again it's it's it's gonna take
more memory because that's more
gradients that it has to keep track of
so best to avoid also another thing
little trick is most people's comm
players have padding as a parameter but
generally speaking you should be able to
calculate the padding basically enough
right and I see people like trying to
like implement you know special same
padding modules and all kinds of stuff
like that but like if you've got a
stride one and you've got or pretty much
any strategy and you've got padding of
oh sorry and kernel size of three right
then obviously that's going to overlap
by kind of one unit on each side so we
want padding of one or else if its
stride one then we don't need any
padding so in general padding of kernel
size integer divided by two
that's what you need there's some tweaks
sometimes but in this case this works
perfectly well so again trying to
simplify my code by having the computer
calculates stuff for me rather than me
having to do it myself another thing
here with the two common players so we
we kind of have this idea of a
bottleneck this idea of reducing the
channels and then increasing them again
is also what kernel size we use so
here's a one by one conf right and so
this is again something you might want
to pause the video now and think about
what's the one by one con really what
actually happens in a one by one con so
if we've got you know a little 4x4 grid
here right and of course there's a
filters or channels access as well maybe
that's like 32 okay and we're going to
do a one by one cons so what's the
kernel for a one by one Kong's gonna
look like it's gonna be 1 by 32 right so
remember when we talked about the the
kernel size we never mention that last
piece but let's say it's 1 by 1 by 32
because that's part of the filters in
and filters out so in other words then
what happens is this this one thing gets
placed first of all here on the first
cell and we basically get a dot product
of that 32 deep bit with this 32 bit
deep bit and that's going to give us our
first oops and that's going to give us
our first output alright and then we're
going to take that 32 bit bit and put it
with the second one to get the second
output right so it's basically going to
be a bunch of little dot pallets ok for
each point in the grid so it's what it
basically is then is a
it's basically something which is
allowing us to to to kind of change the
dimensionality in whatever way we want
in the in the channel dimension and so
that would be that would be one of our
filters right and so in this case we're
creating an AI divided by two of these
right so we're going to have ni divided
by two of these dot products always
different basically different weighted
averages of the input channels okay so
it basically lets us you know with very
little computation at this additional
step of calculations and nonlinearities
so that's what that's a cool trick you
know this idea of taking advantage of
these one by one cons creating this
bottleneck and then pulling it out again
with three by three comms so that's
actually going to take advantage of the
you know the 2d nature of the input
properly real so one by one comm doesn't
take advantage of that at all so these
two lines of code there's not much in it
but it's a really great test of your
understanding and kind of your intuition
about what's going on why is it that a
one by one cond going from ni to NI over
two channels followed by a three by
three conferring from ni over to de and
i and i channels like why does it work
why do the tensor ranks line up why do
the dimensions or line up nicely why is
it a good idea what's it really doing
like it's a really good thing to fiddle
a fiddle around with maybe create some
small ones in jupiter notebook you know
run them yourself see what inputs now
let's come in and out you know really
get a feel for that once you've done so
you can then play around with different
things right and there's actually one of
the really unappreciated papers
is this one wide residual networks okay
and it's really quite a simple paper but
what they do is they basically fiddle
around with with these two lines of code
right and what they do is they say well
what if this wasn't 2/2 but what if it
was times two like that'd be totally
allowable all right that's going to line
up nicely or what if we had another
comfrey
after this and so this was actually ni
over to - ni / - and then this is an AO
to again that's going to work right
kernel say is one three one going to
half the number of kernels leave it at
half and then double it again at the end
and so they come up with this kind of
simple notation for basically defining
what this can look like and then they
show lots of experiments and basically
what they show is that this approach of
a bottlenecking
of decreasing the number of channels
which is like almost universal and
resinates is probably not a good idea in
fact from the experiments definitely not
a good idea because what happens is it
lets you create really deep networks
right and the guys who created resinates
got particularly famous recruiting a
1001 bio network
ok but the thing about a thousand and
one layers is you can't calculate layer
two until you're finished layer 1 from
jakarta calculate layer 3 until you
finish calculating where - so it's
sequential GPUs don't like sequential so
what they showed is that if you have
less layers fat with more active with
more calculations per layer and so one
easy way to do that would be to remove
the / - no other changes all right like
try this at home
try running sci-fi and see what happens
right or make even more apply it back to
you or fiddle around and that basically
lets your GPU do more work and it's very
interesting because the vast majority of
papers that talk
about performance of different
architectures never actually time how
long it takes to run a batch throat like
they literally say this one requires X
number of floating-point operations per
batch but then they never actually
bother to run the damn thing like a
proper experimentalist and find out
whether it's faster or slower and so a
lot of the architectures that are really
famous now turn out to be slow as
molasses and take crap loads of memory
and just totally useless because the
that the research has never actually
bothered to see whether they're fast and
to actually see whether they fit in RAM
with normal size batch batch sizes so
the wide ResNet paper is unusual in that
it actually times how long it takes as
does the yellow version 3 paper which
which made the same insight I'm not sure
they might have missed the wide
resonance paper because that the yellow
version 3 paper came to a lot of the
same conclusions but I'm not even sure
they cited the wide resinous paper so
they might not be aware that all that
works being done but they're both both
great to see people actually timing
things and noticing what actually makes
sense
yes which cell you looked really hot in
the paper which came out but I noticed
that you don't use it what's your
opinion on cell you so sell you is
something largely for fully connected
layers which allows you to get rid of
batch norm and the basic idea is that if
you use this different activation
function it's it's kind of self
normalizing that's what yes and so it
stands for so self normalizing means
that all always remain at a unit
standard deviation and zero mean and
therefore you don't need that pattern on
it hasn't really gone anywhere and the
reason it hasn't really gone anywhere is
because it's incredibly finicky you have
to use a very specific initialization
otherwise it doesn't start with exactly
the right standard deviation of mean
very hard to use it with things like
embeddings if you do then you have to
use a particular kind of embedding
initialization which doesn't necessarily
actually make sense for embeddings
so you know and you do all this work
very hard to get it right
and if you do finally get it right
what's the point well you've managed to
get rid of some batch norm layers which
weren't really hurting you anyway and
it's interesting because that paper that
sell me a paper I think one of the
reasons people noticed it or in my
experience the main reason people
noticed it was because it was created by
the inventor of LST m/s and also it had
a huge mathematical appendix and people
were like lots of maths from a famous
guy this must be great you know but in
practice I don't see anybody using it to
get any state-of-the-art results or win
any competitions or anything like that
okay so this is like some of the tiniest
bits of code we've seen but there's so
much here and it's fascinating to play
with so now we've brought this block
which is built on this block and then
we're going to create another block on
top of that block okay so we're going to
call this a group layer and it's going
to create a bucket it's going to contain
a bunch of rez layers and so a group
layer it's going to have some number of
channels or filters coming in okay and
what we're going to do is we're going to
double the number of channels coming in
by just using a standard comm flare
optionally we'll have the grid size by
using a stride of two okay and then
we're going to do a whole bunch of rez
blocks a whole bunch of rez layers we
can pick how many that could be two or
three or eight back because remember
these rez layers don't change the grid
size and they don't change the number of
channels so you can add as many as you
like anywhere you like without causing
any problems and this is going to use
more computation and more RAM but
there's no reason other than that you
can't add as many as you like so a group
layer therefore it's going to end up
doubling the number of channels because
if this initial convolution which
doubles the number of channels
its initial convolution doubles the
number of channels
and depending on what we pass in a
stride it may also have the grid size if
we put straight equals to and then we
can do a whole bunch of res block
computations as many as we like all
right so then to define our darknet or
whatever we want to call this thing
we're just going to pass in something
that looks like this
and what this says is create five group
layers the first one will contain one of
these extra rez layers the second will
contain two then 4 then 6 then 3 and I
want you to start with 32 filters
alright so the first one of these res
res layers will contain 32 filters and
they'll just be one extra rez layer the
second one it's going to double the
number of filters because that's what we
do each time we have a new group layer
we double the number so the second one
will have 64 and then 128 then 256 and
then 512 and then that'll be it all
right so that's going to be like nearly
all of the network is going to be those
bunches of layers and remember every one
of those group layers also has one
convolution of this data okay
and so then all we have is before that
all happens we're going to have one
convolutional layer at the very start
and at the very end we're going to do
our standard adaptive average pooling
flatten and a linear layer to create the
number of classes out at the edge
alright so one convolution at the end
that we're pulling and one linear layer
at the other end and then in the middle
these group layers each one consisting
of a convolution or layer followed by n
number of resumes and that's that's it
again I think we've mentioned this a few
times but I'm yet to see any code out
there any any exam
Falls anything anywhere that uses
adaptive average cooling everyone I've
seen rats it like this and then spits a
particular number here right which means
that it's now tied to a particular image
size which definitely isn't what you
want
so most people even the top researchers
I speak to most of them are still under
the impression that a specific
architecture is tied to a specific size
and that's a huge problem when people
think that because it really limits
their ability to like use smaller sizes
to kind of kick-start their modeling or
to use smaller sizes for doing
experiments and stuff like that again
you'll notice I'm using sequential here
rather than a nice way to create
architectures is to start out by
creating a list in this case this is a
list with just one comp layer in and
then my function here make group layer
it just returns another list right so
then I can just go plus equals patter
pending that list to the previous list
and then I could go plus equals to a pen
this bunch of things to that list and
then finally sequential of all those
layers right so there's a very nice
thing so now my forward is just self dot
layers okay so here's a kind of you know
this is a nice kind of picture of how to
make your architectures as simple as
possible okay so you can now go ahead
and create this and as I say you can
fiddle around you know you could even
parameterize this too to make it a
number that you kind of pass in here's
to pass in different numbers so it's not
too maybe it's times two instead you
could pass in things that change the
kernel size or change the number of
convolutional layers you know fiddle
around with it and maybe you can create
something I've actually got a version of
this which I'm about to run for you
which kind of implements all of the
different parameters that's in that wide
ResNet paper so I could fiddle around
let's see what worked well so once we've
got that we can use confluent from
bottle data to take our pipe watch model
module and that a model data object and
turn them into a learner give it a
criterion that's a metric so if we like
and then we can call fit in a way
go could you please explain adaptive
average pooling how does setting to one
work sure before I do I just want to
like since we've only got a certain
amount of time in this class I wanted to
see I do want to see how we go you know
with this simple network against these
state-of-the-art results so to make life
a little easier so we can reconstruct
later so I've got the command ready to
go so we've basically take taken all
that stuff and put it into a simple
little Python script and I've modified
some of those parameters I mentioned to
create something I've caught of wrn 22
Network which doesn't officially exist
but it's got a bunch of changes to the
parameters we talked about based on my
experiments we're going to use the new
leslie smith one cycle thing so there's
quite a bunch of cool stuff here so the
one cycle implementation was done by our
students yoga i think i don't know how
to pronounce his name exactly so where
this the trains life our experiments
were largely done by brett currents and
stuff like getting the half position
floating-point implementation integrated
into fast AI was done by Andrew Shaw
so it's been a cool kind of bunch of
different student projects coming
together to allow us to run this so this
is going to run actually on a AWS Amazon
AWS p3 which has eight GPUs the p3 has
these newer Volta architecture GPUs
which actually have special support for
half precision floating point first AI
is the first library I know of to
actually integrate the volatile
optimized
half position floating point into the
library so we can just go learn half now
and get that support automatically and
is also the first one to integrate one
cycle so these are the parameters for
the one cycle so we can go ahead and get
this running so what this actually does
is it's
using PI torches multi-gpu support since
there are eight GPUs it's actually going
to fire off eight separate Python
processors and each one's going to train
on a little bit and then at the end it's
going to pass the gradient updates back
to kind of the master process that's
going to integrate them all together so
you'll see here they are right lots of
progress bars will pop up together and
you can see it's training you know three
or four seconds when you do it this way
where else when I had where else when I
was training earlier I was getting let's
see 30 epochs in I was getting about 30
seconds per clock so doing it this way
we can kind of train things like 10
times faster or so which is pretty cool
okay so we'll leave that running so you
are asking about adaptive average
pooling and I think specifically is
what's the number one doing so normally
when we're doing average pooling let's
say we've got four by four let's say we
did average pooling - comma - okay then
that creates a 2x2 area and takes the
average of those four right and then we
can pass in the stride all right so if
we said stride one then the next one is
we look at this block of 2x2 and take
that average and so forth right so
that's like what a normal to go to
average pooling would be and so that
would in that case if we didn't have any
parting that would spit out a 3x3 okay
because it's true here to here to here
okay and if we added padding we can make
it three by three as well that's right
so if we wanted to spit out something we
didn't want 3x3 what if we wanted one by
one right then we could say average pull
four comma four right and so that's
gonna do 4 comma 4 and average the whole
lot right and that would spit out one by
one but that's just one way to do it
rather than saying the size of the the
kind of appalling filter
why don't we instead say well I don't
care what the size of the input grid is
I always want one by one right so that's
where then you say adaptive average Hall
and now you don't say what's the size of
the palling filter you instead say
what's the size of the app what I want
and so I want something that serve one
by one and if you already put a single
int it assumes you mean one by one so in
this case adaptive average pooling one
with a four by four grid coming in is
the same as average pooling for Hummer
four if it was a 7x7 grid coming in it
would be the same as 7 comma 7 right so
it's the same operation it's just
expressing it in a way that says
regardless of the input I want something
of that sized output please okay
how's our little thing going along oh
okay well we got 294 and it took three
minutes and 11 seconds and the previous
state of the art was one hour and seven
minutes so was it worth fiddling around
with those parameters and learning a
little bit about how these architectures
actually work and not just using what
came out of the box well holy we
just used a publicly available instance
we use the spot instance so it's cost
you that so that cost us like $8 per
hour for three minutes cost us a few
cents to train this from scratch
20 times faster than anybody's ever done
it before so that's like the most crazy
state at the at result I think we see
we've seen many but this one just blew
it out of the water right and so you
know this is kind of partly thanks to
just fiddling around with those
parameters of the architecture mainly
frankly about using Leslie Smith's one
cycle thing and swampers implementation
of that and remember not only so does to
remind you of what that's doing it's
basically saying this is batches right
and this is mining right okay
it creates an upward path that's equally
long as the downward path right so it's
a true clr triangular cycle called
learning rate as per usual you can pick
the ratio between those two numbers
right so X divided by Y in this case is
is a lumber that you get to pick in this
case we picked 50 okay so we started out
with a much smaller one here and then
it's got this cool idea which is you get
to say what percentage of your epochs
then is spent going from the bottom of
this down all the way down pretty much
to zero and that's what this second
number here is so 15 percent of the
batches are spent going from the bottom
of our triangle even further so
importantly though with that's not the
only thing one cycle does we also have
momentum right and momentum goes from
point nine five to 0.85 like this
in other words when the loading rates
really low
we use a lot of momentum and when the
learning rates really high we use very
little momentum which makes a lot of
sense but until Leslie Smith showed this
in that paper I've never seen anybody do
it before so it's a really really cool
trick so you can now use that by using
the UCLA beta parameter in in first AI
and you should be able to basically
replicate this state-of-the-art result
you can use it on your own computer or
your paper space obviously the only
thing you won't get is the multi-gpu
piece but that makes it a bit easier to
Train anyway so in a single GPU you
should be able to beat this this this on
a single GPU yeah make group layer
contains stride equals two so this means
stride is one for layer one and two for
everything else what's the logic behind
it usually the strides I have seen our
odd no strides are either one or two I
think you're thinking of kernel sizes so
strata calls to means that I jump to
across and so stride of two means that
you have your grid size so I think you
might've cos got confused between stride
and kernel size there and so if we have
a stride of one the grid size doesn't
change if you have a stride of two then
it does and so in this case because this
is for say fire 10 32 by 32 is small and
we don't get to have the grid size very
often right because pretty quickly we're
going to run out of cells and so that's
why the first layer has a stride of one
so we don't decrease the grid size
straightaway as you play and it's kind
of a nice way of doing it because that's
why we kind of have a low number here so
we can we can start out with you know
not too much computation on the big grid
and then we can gradually doing more and
more computation as the grids get
smaller and smaller but because the
smaller grid
the computation will take less time okay
so I think so that we can do all of our
gaining in one go let's take a slightly
early break and come back at 7:30 okay
so we're going to talk about generative
adversarial networks also known as ganz
and specifically we're going to focus on
the Vasa Stein gang caper which included
some guy called seumas chintala who went
on to create some piece of software
called hide watch the Vasa Stein Gann
was heavily influenced by the Sun is
going to call this w again that's the
time the DC gain or deep convolution
deep convolutional generative
adversarial networks paper which also
seemeth was involved with so it's a
really interesting paper to read a lot
of it looks like this the good news is
you can skip those bits because there's
also a bit that looks like this which
says do these things all right now I
will say though but like a lot of papers
have a theoretical section which seems
to be they're entirely to get past the
reviewers need for theory that's not
true with a W again paper the theory bit
is actually really interesting like you
don't need to know what to use it but if
you want to learn about like some some
cool ideas and see the thinking behind
why this particular algorithm it's
absolutely fascinating and almost nobody
before this paper came out I didn't know
literally I'd Lou knew nobody who had
studied the math that it's based on so
like everybody had
the method is based on ins and so the
paper does a pretty good job of laying
out all the pieces you have to do a
bunch of reading yourself so if you're
interested like in digging into the
deeper math behind some paper to see
what it's like to study it I would pick
this one because at the end of that
theory section you'll come away saying
like okay I can see now why they made
this algorithm the way it is okay and
then having come up with that idea like
the other thing is often these
theoretical sections are very clearly
added after they come up with the
algorithm they'll come up the algorithm
based on intuition and experiments and
then later on post hoc justify it or
else this one you can clearly see it's
like okay let's actually think about
what's going on in Ganz and think about
what they need to do and then come up
with the algorithm so the basic idea of
a began is it's a generative model okay
so it's something that is going to
create sentences or create images kind
of generate stuff right and it's going
to try and create stuff which is very
hard to tell the difference between
generated stuff and real stuff
that's what generative model could be
used to face what a video you know a
very well-known controversial thing of
deep fakes and fake pornography and
stuff happening at the moment could be
used to fake somebody's voice it could
be used to fake the answer to a medical
question but in that case it's not
really a fake right it could be a
generative answer to a medical question
that's actually a good answer right so
you like generating language you could
generate a caption to a to an image for
example so generative models have lots
of apple interesting adaptations but
generally speaking they're they need to
be good enough that for example if
you're using it too you know
automatically create a new scene for
Carrie Fisher in the next Star Wars
movies and she's not around to play that
part anymore you want to you know try
and generate an image of her that looks
the same then it has to fool the Star
Wars audience into thinking like okay
that that doesn't look like some weird
Carrie Fisher that looks like the real
Carrie Fisher or if you're trying to
generate an answer to a medical question
you want to generate English that reads
you know nicely and clearly and it
sounds authority of meaningful so the
idea of a generative adversarial Network
is we're going to create not just a
generative model to create say the the
the the generated image that a second
model that's going to try to pick which
ones are real and which ones are
generated and we're going to call them
fake okay so which ones are real and
which ones are fake so we've got a
generator that's going to create our
fake content and a discriminator that's
going to try to get good at recognizing
which ones are real and which ones are
fake so they're going to be two models
and then they're going to be adversarial
meaning the generator is going to treat
a tree trying to keep getting better at
falling the discriminator into thinking
that fake is real and the discriminator
is going to try to keep getting better
at discriminating between the real and
the fake and they're going to go head to
head like that right and it's basically
as easy as I just described it really is
but it's going to build two models in
play torch we're going to create a
training loop that first of all says the
loss function for the discriminator is
can you tell the density real and fake
and then update the weights of that and
then we're going to create a loss
function for the generator which is just
going to say can you generate something
which pulls the discriminator and update
the weights true from that loss and
we're going to look through that a few
times and see what happens and so let's
come back to the pseudo code here if the
algorithm and let's read the real code
first
so there's lots of different things you
can do with Gans and we're going to do
something that's kind of boring but easy
to understand and and it's kind of cool
that it's even possible
which is we're just going to generate
some pictures from now we're just going
to get it to draw some pictures okay and
specifically we're going to get it to
draw pictures of bedrooms right you'll
find if you hopefully get a chance to
play around of this during the week with
your own data sets
if you pick a dataset that's very varied
like imagenet and then get again to try
and create image net pictures it tends
not to do so well because it's it's not
really clear enough what do you want a
picture of alright so it's better to
give it for example the there's a data
set called celeb a which has pictures of
celebrities faces that works great with
dance you create really clear celebrity
faces that don't actually exist the
bedroom data set also a good one right
lots of things pictures of the same kind
of thing okay so that's just a
suggestion so there's something called
the L son same classification data set
you can download it using these steps
I've also it's pretty huge and so I've
actually created a kegel data set of a
20% sample right so unless you're really
excited about generating bedroom images
you might prefer to grab the 20% sample
so then we do the normal steps of
creating some different paths and in
this case you know I as we do before I
find it much easier to kind of grow the
CSV route when it comes to handling our
our data so I just generate a CSV with
the list of files that we want and a
fake label of 0 because we don't really
have labels for these at all and I
actually create two part two CSV files
one that contains everything in that
bedroom data set and one that just
contains a random 10% that's just nice
to do that because then I can most of
the time use the sample when I'm
experimenting because like because
there's well over a million files
just reading in the list takes a while
okay
so this will look pretty familiar so
here's a con block this is before I
realized that sequential models are much
better so if you compare this to my
previous con lock with a sequential
model there's just a lot more lines of
code here but you know it does the same
thing of doing con rally better on okay
and we calculate our padding and here's
a bias pulse so this is the same as
before basically but with a little bit
more code alright so the first thing
we're going to do is we're going to
build a discriminator so a discriminator
is going to receive as input an image
okay and it's going to spit out a number
and the number is meant to be lower if
it thinks this image is real okay now of
course the what does it do for a lower
number thing doesn't appear in the
architecture that'll be in the loss
function so what we have to do is create
something that takes an image and spits
out a number okay so a lot of this code
is borrowed from the original authors of
this paper of the paper so some of the
naming scheme and stuff is different to
what we're used to so sorry about that
but hopefully I've tried to make it look
at least somewhat familiar I probably
should have renamed things a little bit
but it looks very similar to actually
what we had before we start out with a
convolution so in become block is
conquering a veteran on okay and then we
have a bunch of extra comm flares this
is not gonna use a residual right so it
looks very similar to before a bunch of
extra layers but these are going to
become players rather than res layers
and then at the end we need to append
enough stride to
enough strive to calm players that we
decrease the size the grid size down to
be no bigger than 4x4 right so it's
going to keep using straight to divide
the size by twos tried to divide by
those by two and till our grid size is
no bigger than four and so this is quite
a nice way of like creating as many
layers as you need in a network to
handle arbitrary sized images and turn
them into a fixed loan grid size yes
Rachel does again need a lot more data
than say dogs versus cats or NLP or is
it comparable you know honestly I'm kind
of embarrassed to say I am NOT an expert
practitioner in games so you know the
stuff i teach in part one is stuff I'm
happy to say I know the best way to you
know pretty close the best way to do
these things and so I can show you
stayed at the out results like I just
did with safe at ten with the help of
some of my students of course I'm not
there at all with Ganz
so I'm not quite sure how much you need
like in general Pitt seems unique quite
a lot but remember the only reason we
didn't need too much and dogs and cats
is because we had a pre trained model
and could we leverage pre-trained and
models and fine-tune them probably I
don't think anybody's done it as far as
I know that could be really interesting
thing for people that are kind of think
about an experiment with maybe people
have done it and there's some literature
there I haven't come across so I'm
somewhat familiar with the main pieces
of literature and Gans but I don't know
all of it so maybe I've missed something
about transfer learning in games but
that would be the trick to not needing
too much data and so it's the huge
speed-up a combination of one cycle
learning rate and momentum annealing
plus the eight GPU parallel training in
the half precision is that only possible
to do the half precision calculation
with consumer GPU another question why
is the calculation eight times faster
from single to half precision while from
double the single is only two times fast
okay so the SyFy ten result it's not
eight times faster from single to half
it's about two or three times as fast
from single to half the Nvidia claims
about the about the flops performance of
the tensor cause are academically
correct but in practice meaningless
because it really depends on what calls
you need for what pieces so about two or
three X improvement for half
so yeah the half precision helps a bit
the the extra GPUs helps a bit the one
cycle helps an enormous amount then
another key piece was the playing around
with the parameters that I told you
about so kind of ten reading the wide
ResNet paper carefully identifying the
kinds of things that they found there
and then writing a version of the
architecture you just saw that made it
really easy for me to fiddle around with
prep one action for me for Brett pans to
fiddle around with parameters staying up
all night trying every possible
combination of different kernel sizes
and numbers of kernels and numbers of
layer groups and size of layer groups
and the amount of remember we did a
bottleneck but actually we tended to
focus not on bottlenecks bonds instead
on widening so we actually like things
that increase the size and then decrease
it because it takes better advantage of
the GPU so though all those things
combined together I'd say the one cycle
was perhaps the most critical but but
every one of those resulted in a big
speed-up that's why we were able to get
this 30x improvement over the
state-of-the-art so factor and we got
some ideas for other things like after
this Dorn bench finishes and you know
maybe we'll try and go even further see
if we can beat one minute one day
that'll be fun okay so so here's okay so
here's our discriminator right I mean
that the important thing to remember
about an architecture is it doesn't do
anything
rather than have some input tensor size
and rank and some output tensor size and
range so this is going to spit out you
see the last calm here has one channel
right this is a bit different to what
we're used to right because normally our
last thing is a linear block right but
our last thing here is a common block
right and it's only got one channel but
it's got a grid size of something around
4 by 4 it's no more than 4 by 4 so we're
gonna spit out a let's say it's provoke
or a 4 by 4 by 1 cancer so what we then
do is we then take the mean of that fat
so it goes from 4 by 4 by 1 to the
scalar right so this is kind of like the
ultimate adaptive average pulling right
because we've got something with just
one channel we take the mean so this is
a bit yeah a bit different normally we
first do average pooling and then we put
it through a fully connected layer to
get our one thing out in this case
though but getting one channel out and
then taking the mean of with that I
haven't fiddled around with like why did
we do it that way what would instead
happen if we did the usual average
Pauling followed by a fully connected
layer would it work better would it not
I I don't know I rather suspect it would
work better if we did it like the normal
way but I haven't tried it and I don't
really have a good enough intuition to
know whether I'm missing something
finished the experimenter truck if
somebody wants to stick an adaptive
average Pauling layer here and a fully
connected layer afterwards with a single
output it should keep working you know
we should do something the loss will go
down to see whether it works okay so
that's the discriminator right so it's
gonna be a training loop let's put let's
assume we've already got a generator
somebody says okay Jeremy here's a
generator it generates bedrooms ok I
want you to build a model that can
figure out which ones are real and which
ones aren't
so I'm going to take the data set and
I'm going to basically label a bunch of
images which are fake bedrooms from the
generator and a bunch of images of real
bedrooms from my else I'm data set to
stick a 1 or a 0 and h1 and then I'll
try to get there discriminator to tell
the difference ok so
that's gonna be simple enough but I
haven't been given a generator I need to
build one so a generator and we haven't
talked about the last function yet okay
we're just going to assume that there's
some loss function that does this thing
okay so a generator is also an
architecture which doesn't do anything
by itself until we have a loss function
and data but what are the ranks and
sizes of the tenses well the input to
the generator is going to be a vector of
random numbers okay and in the paper
they call that the prior but it's going
to be a vector of random numbers how big
I don't know some big 64 128 right and
the idea is that a different bunch of
random numbers will generate a different
bedroom okay so that's the idea so our
our gann generator sorry has to take as
input a vector and it's going to take
that vector so here's our import all
right and it's going to stick it through
in this case so sequential model and the
sequential models going to take that
vector it's going to turn it into a 2 by
2 sorry a turn it into a well I rank for
tensor or if we take off the batch bit
around three tensor height by width by
three okay so you can see at the end
here our final step here NC number of
channels so I think that's going to have
to end up being 3 equals going to create
a 3 channel image of some size yes
Rachel in coms block forward is there a
reason my batch dorm comes after Lu ie
self dot batch norm dot self dot right
no that's not it's just what they had in
the code I borrowed from I think that
the order is reversed yeah so
again unless my intuition about Dan's is
all wrong and say some some reason need
to be different to what I'm used to I
would normally expect to yeah I would
actually no sorry I would normally
expect to go rally your then batch norm
that this is actually the order that
makes more sense to me but I think the
order I had in the darknet was what they
used in the darknet paper so I don't
know everybody seems to have a different
order of these things and in fact most
people for sci-fi 10 have a different
order again which is they actually go
bien
then rally then conf which is kind of a
quirky way of thinking about it but it
turns out that for often for residual
blocks that works better
that's called a pre activation ResNet so
if you google for pre activation ResNet
you can see that so yeah there's there's
a few not so much papers but more blog
posts out there where people will have
experimented with different orders of
those things and yeah it seems to depend
a lot on what specific data said it is
and what you're doing with although in
general the difference in performance is
small enough you won't care unless it's
through a competition okay
so the generator needs to start with a
vector and end up with a rank three
tensor we don't really know how to do
that yet so how do we do that how do we
start with a vector and turn it into a
rank three tensor we need to use
something called a deconvolution and a
deconvolution
is or as they call it an fie torch
transposed convolution same name
that's right same same thing different
name and so a deconvolution is something
which rather than decreasing the grid
size it increases the grid size so as
with all things
it's easiest to see in an Excel
spreadsheet so here's a convolution
right we start let's say with a four by
four grid cell okay with a single
channel a single photo and let's put it
through a three by three kernel again
with a single output filter okay so
we've got a single channel in a single
filter kernel and so if we don't add any
padding we're going to end up with two
by two right because that three by three
you can go in
one two three four places right can go
in one of two places across some one of
two places down if there's no padding
okay so there's our there's our
convolution right remember the
convolution is just the sum of the
product of the kernel and the
appropriate grid cell so there's a
there's our standard 3x3 upon one
channel one filter so the idea now is I
want to go the opposite direction I want
to start with my 2x2 and I want to
create a 4x4 and specifically I want to
create the same 4x4 that I started with
and I want to do that by using a
convolution so how would I do that well
if I have a 3x3 convolution then if I
want to create a 4x4 output I'm going to
need to create this much padding that
goes with this much padding I'm going to
end up with one two three four by one
two three four you see why that is so
this filter can go at any one of four
places across from four places up and
down so let's say my convolutional
filter was just a bunch of zeros then I
can calculate my my error for each cell
just by taking this attraction and then
I can get the sum of absolute values
they are one loss later summing up the
absolute values of those errors all
right
so now I could use optimization so in
Excel that's called solver to do a
gradient descent okay so I'm going to
set that cell equal to a minimum try and
reduce my loss by changing my filter
okay and I'll go solve okay and you can
see it's come up with a filter such that
you know fifteen point seven compared to
sixteen seventeen that's right seventeen
point it so it's not perfect right and
in general you can't assume that a
deconvolution can exactly create the
same you know the exact thing that you
want because there's just not enough you
know there's only nine things here and
there's sixteen things you're trying to
create right but it's it's made a pretty
good attempt okay so this is what a
deconvolution looks like asteroid one
3x3 deep deconvolution on a 2x2 grid
cell input did you have a question how
difficult is it to create a
discriminator to identify fake news
versus real news well you don't need
anything special that's just a
classifier right so you would just use
the NLP classifier from previous
previous to previous class and listen
for right it's there's nothing like it
and in that case there's no generative
piece right so you just need the data
set that says these are the things that
we believe are fake news and these are
the things we consider to be real news
and it should actually work very well
you know like as to the best of our
knowledge if you if you try it you
should get a you know as good a result
as anybody else has got whether it's
good enough to be useful to practice I
don't know as I say that it's very hard
very hard there's not a good solution
that does that well but I don't think
anybody in our course has tried and
nobody else outside our cause knows of
this technique right so like there's
beaners we've
as we've learned we've just had a very
significant jump in NLP classification
capabilities and yeah I mean I think
it's obviously the best you could do I
think at this stage would be to generate
a kind of a triage that says these
things look pretty sketchy based on how
they're written and then you know some
human could go and in fact check them
you know I mean an NLP classifier and I
run in kind of fact-check things but it
could recognize like all these these are
written in that kind of you know that
kind of highly popularized style which
often fake news is written in and so
maybe these ones are worth paying
attention to
I think that would probably the best you
could hope for without drawing on some
kind of external data sources yeah but
it's important to remember you know the
discriminator is basically just a
classifier and you don't need any
special techniques beyond what we've
already learned to do an LP
classification ok so to to do that kind
of deconvolution in in pi torch just say
chrome transporters 2d and in the normal
way you say the number of input channels
the number of output channels the kernel
size the stride the padding the bias so
these parameters are all the same right
and the reason it's called a comm
transpose is because actually it turns
out that this is this is the same as the
calculation of the gradient of
convolution that's that's that's
basically why they call it that so this
is a really nice example back on the
older Theano website that comes from a
really nice paper which actually shows
you some visualizations so this is
actually the one we just saw of doing a
2x2 deconvolution
if there's a stride to then you don't
just have padding around the outside but
you actually have to put padding in the
middle as well okay they're not actually
quite implemented this way because this
is slow to do in practice you in a
different way but it all happens behind
the scenes we don't have to worry
better okay yeah this we've we've talked
about this convolution arithmetic
tutorial before and if you're still not
comfortable with convolutions and in
order to get comfortable with D
convolutions this is a great site to go
to if you want to see the paper just
Google for convolution arithmetic it'll
be the first thing that comes up let's
do it now so you know you've found it
here it is
and so that Theano tutorial actually
comes from this paper but the paper
doesn't have the animated gifs okay so
it's interesting there no decomp block
looks identical to a comp lock except
it's got the word transpose written here
okay we just go comb for Elliot better
on this before it's about input filters
output fit filters the only difference
is that stride 2 means that the grid
size will double rather than half both
nn comp transpose to D and n n dot up
sample seemed to do the same thing
ie expand grid size height and width
from the previous layer can we say that
Kampf transpose to D is always better
than up sample since up sample is merely
resizing and filling unknown unknowns by
zeros or interpolation no you can't so
there's a fantastic interactive paper on
distilled pub called deconvolution and
checkerboard artifacts which points out
that what we're doing right now is
extremely suboptimal but the good news
is everybody else does it if you have a
look here could you see these
checkerboard architect artifacts like
it's all like that blue light blue dark
blue light blue you know you kind of and
so these are all from from actual papers
right and basically they noticed every
one of these papers with generative
models has these checkerboard artifacts
and what they realized
is it's because when you have a stride
to convolution of size three kernel they
overlap right and so you basically get
like some pixels get twice as much kind
of active some grid cells I guess wise
as much activation and so even if you
start with random weights you end up
with a check of what artifact so you can
kind of see it here right and so the
deeper you get kind of the worse it gets
their advice is actually less director
than it ought to be I've found that for
most generative models up sampling is
better right so all if you do end up
sample then all it does is it's it's
basically doing pooling right basically
but it's kind of its kind of the
opposite of Pauline right it says let's
replace this one pixel or this one grid
cell with four two by two and there's a
number of ways to up sample one is just
to kind of copy it across to those four
and other is to use kind of lit by
linear or bicubic interpolation there
are various techniques to kind of try
and create a smooth off sample version
and you can pretty much choose any of
them in pi torch so if you do a two by
two up sample and then a regular stride
one three by three khans that's like
another way of doing the same kind of
thing as a commons plus well it's it's
doubling the grid size and doing some
convolutional arithmetic on it
and i found for generative models and it
pretty much always works better and in
that distorter pub publication they kind
of indicate that maybe that's a good
approach but they don't just come out
and say just do this whereas i would
just say just do this having said that
for gains i haven't had that much
success with it yet and I think it
probably requires some tweaking to get
it to work as I'm sure some people have
got it to work the the issue I think is
that in the earliest
ages it doesn't create enough noise
ahead I don't have it here
I had a version actually where I tried
to do it within an up sample and you
could kind of see that the noise didn't
look very noisy so anyway it's an
interesting question but um next week
when we look at style transfer and
super-resolution and stuff I think
you'll see and ended up sample really
comes into its own okay so the generator
we can now basically start with the
vector we can decide and say like okay
does not think of it as a vector but
actually it's a one by one grid cell and
then we can turn it into a four by four
and they by eight and so forth and so
that's why we have to make sure it's a
it's a suitable multiple so that we can
actually create something of the right
size and so you can see it's doing the
exact opposite as before right it's
making the cell size smaller and smaller
by two at a time as long as it can sorry
bigger and bigger so this cell size
bigger and bigger as long as it can
until it gets to half the size that we
want and then finally we add one more on
at the end sorry we add n more on at the
end of just with no stride and then we
add one more calm transpose to finally
get to the size that we wanted and we're
done finally we put that through a fan
and that's got a force us to be in the
zero to one range because of course we
don't want to spit out arbitrary size
pixel values okay so that's so we've got
to generate our architecture which spits
out an image of some given size with the
correct number with the correct whatever
a readout of all correct number of
channels and with values between zero
and one so at this point we can now
create our model data object
these things take a while to train so I
just made it 128 by 128 so this is just
a convenient way to make it a faster and
that's going to be the size of the input
but then we're going to use
transformations to turn it into 64 by 64
okay
there's been more recent advances which
have attempted to really increase this
up to kind of like high resolution sizes
but they still tend to require either
like a batch size of 1 or like lots and
lots of GPUs or whatever so we're kind
of trying to do things that we can do 1
conceal all consumer GPUs yeah so here's
an example of one of the 64 by 64
bedrooms okay so we're gonna do if
pretty much everything manually so let's
go ahead and create our two models our
generator and our discriminator and as
you can see they're DC can so in other
words they're the same modules that came
up were appeared in this paper so if
you're interested in reading the papers
you it's well worth going back and
looking at the DC gain paper to see what
these architectures are because it's
assumed that when you read the vasa
stein gain paper that you already know
that yes you don't we use a sigmoid if
we want values between 0 and 1
I always forget which ones which okay so
sick yes so sigmoid is 0 to 1 fan is 1
to minus 1 I think what will happen is
I'm gonna have to check that I beg you
remember thinking about this when I was
writing this notebook and realizing that
1 2 minus 1 made sense for some reason
but I can't remember what that reason
was now so let me get back here about
that during the week and remind me if I
forget it's good question thank you ok
so we've got our generator in a
discriminator so we need a function that
returns a prior vector so a bunch of
noise
so we do that by creating a bunch of
zeros NZ is the size of Zed so like very
often in our code if you see a
mysterious letter it's because that's
the letter they used in the paper that
says ed is the size about noise vector
okay so there's the size of our noise
vector and then we use a normal
distribution to generate random numbers
inside that and that needs to be a
variable because it's going to be
participating in the in the gradient
updates so here's an example of creating
some noise and so here are four
different pieces of noise okay so we
need an optimizer in order to update our
gradients in the vasa stein game paper
they told us to use rmsprop
so that's fine that's so when you see
this thing saying do an rmsprop update
in a paper that's nice we can just do an
rmsprop update with pipe watch okay and
they suggested a learning rate of five
Enid five I think I found one a nigga
four seem to work so I was made a little
bit bigger so now we need a training
loop and so this is the thing that's
going to implement this algorithm so a
training loop is going to go through
some number of epochs that we get to
pick so that's going to be a parameter
and so remember when you do everything
manually you've got to remember all the
manual steps to do so one is that you
have to set your modules into training
mode when you're training them and into
evaluation mode when you're evaluating
them because in training mode batch norm
updates happen and dropout happens in
evaluation mode those two things get
turned off okay so it's basically
difference so put it into training mode
we're going to grab a iterator from our
training data loader we're going to see
how many steps we have to go through and
then we'll use two qdm to give us a
progress bar and then we're going to go
through that many steps okay
so the first step of this algorithm is
to update the is to update the
discriminator so in this one I'm just
trying to remember yes they don't call
it a discriminator they call it a critic
right so W are the weights of the of the
critic so the first step is to train our
critic a little bit and then we're going
to train our generator a little bit and
then we go go back to the top of the
loop right so this inner so we got a
while loop on the outside okay so here's
our while loop on the outside and then
inside that there's another loop for the
critic and so here's a little loop
inside that for the critic okay we call
it a discriminator so what we're going
to do now is we're going to try we've
got we've got a generator and at the
moment it's random right so our
generator is going to generate stuff
that looks something like this right and
so we need to first of all teach our
discriminator to tell the difference
between that and a bedroom right which
shouldn't be too hard you would hope so
we just do it in basically the usual way
but there's a few little tweaks so first
of all we're going to grab a mini batch
of real bedroom photos so we can just
grab the next batch from our iterator
turn it into a variable okay then we're
going to calculate the loss for that
right so this is going to be how much
does the discriminator think this looks
this looks fake right through the real
ones book fake and then we're going to
create some fake images and to do that
will create some random noise and we'll
stick it through our generator which at
this stage is just a bunch of random
weights okay and that's going to create
a mini batch of fake images
okay and so then we'll put that through
the same discriminator module as before
okay to get the loss for that so how
fake to the fake ones look remember when
you do everything manually you have to
zero the gradients in in your loop and
if you've forgotten about that go back
to the part one lesson where we do
everything from scratch so now finally
the total discriminator loss is equal to
the real loss - the fake loss okay and
so you can see that here they don't talk
about the loss they actually just talk
about one of the gradient updates so
this here is a symbol for get the
gradients alright so inside here is the
loss right and like trying to like learn
to throw away in your head all of the
boring stuff
so when you see sum over m / M that
means take the average so just throw
that away and replace it with NP don't
mean in your head there's another NP
domain right so you want to get quick at
like being able to see these common
idioms so anytime you see one over m sum
over m you go okay and peed on me right
so we're taking the mean of and we're
taking the mean of so that's all fine X
I what's X I it looks like it's next to
the power of I but it's not right the
math notation is very overloaded they
showed us here what X I is and it's a
set of M samples from a batch of the
real data so in other words this is a
mini batch right so when that when you
see something same sample it means just
grab a row grab a row grab a row and you
can see here grab it m times and we'll
call the first row X parentheses 1 the
second row X parentheses 2 one of the
annoying things about math notation is
the the way that we index into arrays is
everybody uses different approaches
subscript superscript things in brackets
combinations commas square brackets
whatever right so you've just got to
look in the paper and be like ok at some
point they're going to say
take the I throw from this matrix or the
ithe image in this batch how are they
going to do it in this case let's say
superscript in parentheses okay so
that's all sample means and curly
brackets means it's just a set of them
this little squiggle followed by
something here means according to some
probability distribution and so in this
case like and very very often in papers
it simply means hey you've got a bunch
of data right grab a bit from it at
random okay so that's like that's the
the probability distribution of the data
you have is the data you have right
so this says grab em things at random
from your real data this says grab em
things at random from your prior samples
and so that means in other words call
create noise to create m random vectors
so now we've got em real images each one
gets put through our discriminator we've
got em bits of noise each one gets put
through our generator to create em
generated images each one of those gets
put through look FW that's the same
thing so these ones of those gets put
through our discriminator to try and
figure out whether they're fake or not
and so then it's this minus this and the
mean of that and then finally get the
gradient of that in order to figure out
how to use our own s prop to update our
weights using some learning rate okay so
in height or CH we don't have to worry
about getting the gradients we can just
specify their last bit okay and then
just say lost stop backward
discriminator optimizer diet step okay
now there's one key step right which is
that we have to keep all of our
activations
so all of our weights which are the
parameters in a page horch module in
this small range between 0.01 negative
0.01 and point out one why because the
mathematical assumptions that make this
algorithm work only only apply in like a
small ball all right so I'm not going to
tell I don't I think it's kind of
interesting to understand the math of
why that's the case but it's very
specific to this one paper and
understanding it won't help you
understand any other paper so only study
it you know if you're interested in you
know I think it's nicely explained I
think it's fun but it won't be
information that you're reuse elsewhere
unless you get super into dance I'll
also mention after the paper came out
and improved froster stein Gann came out
that said hey there are better ways to
ensure that your that your weight space
is in this tight ball which was
basically that kind of penalize
gradients that are too high so actually
nowadays they're at there is slightly
different ways to do this anyway that's
why this line of code there it's kind of
the key contribution this you know this
one line of code actually is the one
line of code you add to make it a versus
time again basically that the work was
all in knowing like that that's the
thing that you can do that makes
everything work better ok so at the end
of this we've got a discriminator that
can recognize an industry in real
bedrooms and our totally random crappy
generated images so let's now try and
create some better images so now set
trainable discriminator to false set
trainable the generator to true zero out
the gradients of the generator and now
our loss again is fw that's the did that
remember that's the discriminator of the
generator applied to some more random
noise okay so here's our random noise
here's our generator here's our
discriminator
I think I can remove that now because I
think I've put it inside the
discriminator but I won't change it now
because it's going to confuse me so it's
exactly the same as before where we did
generator on the noise and then pass a
discriminator but this time the thing
that's trainable is the generator not
the discriminator so in other words in
this pseudocode the thing they update is
theta which is the generators parameters
rather than W which is the
discriminators parameters and so
hopefully you'll see now that this this
W down here is telling you these are the
parameters of the discriminator this
theta down here is telling you these are
the actually better these this theta
here is telling you these are the
parameters of the generator okay
again it's not as universal mathematical
notation it's a thing they're doing in
this particular paper but it's kind of
nice when you see some some suffix like
that there's like try to think about
what it's telling you okay so it takes
noise generate some images try and
figure out if they're fake or real and
use that to get gradients with respect
to okay the generator as opposed to
earlier we got them with respect to the
discriminator and use that to update our
weights with our s prop with an alpha
learning rate okay you'll see that it's
kind of unfair that the discriminator is
getting trained and critic times which
they set to five for every time that we
train the generator once and the paper
talks a bit about this but the basic
idea is like there's no point making the
generator better if the discriminator
doesn't know how to discriminate yet
okay so that's why we've got this while
loop and here's that v right and
see something which was added I think in
the later paper or maybe a supplementary
material is the idea that from time to
time and a bunch of times at the start
you should do more steps at the
discriminator so kind of make sure that
the discriminator is pretty capable from
time to time okay so do a bunch of
epochs of training the discriminator a
bunch of times to get better at telling
the dentistry in real and fake and then
do one step of making the generator
being better at generating and that is
an epoch and so let's train that for one
epoch and then let's create some noise
so we can generate some examples
actually going to do that later let's
first of all decrease the learning rate
by 10 and do one more pass so we've now
done two epochs and now let's use our
noise to pass it to our generator okay
and then put it through our
denormalization to turn it back into
something we can see and then plot it
and we have some bedrooms okay there's
not real bedrooms and some of them don't
particularly like bedrooms but some of
them look a lot like bedrooms so that's
that's the idea okay that's again and I
think like the best way to think about
again is it's like an underlying
technology that you'll probably never
use like this but you'll use in lots of
interesting ways for example they're
going to use it to create now a cycle
game
and we're going to use the cycle Gann to
turn horses into zebras you could also
use it to turn mono prints into photos
or to turn photos of Yosemite in summer
into winter so it's gonna be pretty yes
Rachel two questions one is there any
reason for using rmsprop specifically as
the optimized optimizer as opposed to
Adam I don't remember it being
explicitly discussed in the paper I
don't know if it's just experimental or
the theoretical reason yeah have a look
in the paper and see what it says I
don't recall and which could be a
reasonable way of detecting overfitting
while training or of evaluating the
performance of one of these Gann models
once we are done training in other words
how does the notion of train validation
test sets translate to Ganz that's an
awesome question and there's a lot of
people who make jokes about how Cannes
is the one field where you don't need a
test set and people take advantage of
that by making stuff up and saying it
looks great there are some pretty famous
problems with with ganz one of the
famous problems with ganz is called mode
collapse and mode collapse happens where
you look at your bedrooms and it turns
out that there's basically only three
kinds of bedrooms that every possible
noise vector mapped or you look at your
gallery and it turns at all that turns
out they're all just the same thing
or there's just three different things
mode collapse is easy to see if you
collapse down to a small number of modes
like you know three or four but what if
you have a mode collapse down to 10,000
modes
so there's only 10,000 possible bedrooms
that all of your noise vectors collapse
to that's not like you wouldn't be able
to see it here right because it's pretty
unlikely you would have two identical
bedrooms out of 10,000 or what if every
one of these bedrooms is basically a
direct copy of what if the basically had
never memorized some input you know
could that be happening and the truth is
most papers don't do a good job or
sometimes any job of checking those
things so the question of like how do we
evaluate ganz and even like the point of
like hey maybe we should actually
evaluate games properly is something
that is not widely enough understood
even now and some people are trying to
you know really push so Ian Goodfellow
who a lot of you will know because he
came and spoke here at a lot of the book
club meetings last year and of course
was the first author on the most famous
deep learning book he is the inventor of
games and he's been sending a continuous
stream of tweets reminding people about
the importance of testing dance properly
so yeah if you see a paper that claims
exceptional gaen results then this is
definitely something to look at you know
is have they talked about mode collapse
have they talked about memorization okay
so um this is going to be really
straight forwards because it's just a
neural net right so all we're going to
do is we're going to create an input
containing lots of zebra photos and with
each one we'll pair it with an
equivalent horse photo and we'll just
train a neural net that goes from one to
the other or you could do the same thing
for every Monet painting create a
dataset containing the photo of the
place oh wait that's not possible
because the places that Monet painted
aren't there anymore and there aren't
exact zebra versions of horses and oh
wait how the hell is this kind of work
this seems to break everything we know
about what neural nets can do and how
they do them alright make sure you know
ask me a question just spoil a whole
train of thought come on very good
can Ganz be used for data augmentation
yeah absolutely you can use a gain for
data augmentation should you I don't
know like there are some papers that try
to do semi-supervised learning with ganz
I haven't found any that are like
particularly compelling showing
state-of-the-art results on really
interesting data sets that have been
widely studied I'm a little skeptical
and the reason I'm a little skeptical is
because in my experience if you train a
model with synthetic data the neural net
will become fantastically good at
recognizing the specific problems of
your synthetic data and that'll be ended
up what it's learning from and there are
lots of other ways of doing
semi-supervised models which do work
well there are some places that can work
for example you might remember Octavio
gawd created that fantastic
visualization in part one of like the
zooming ComNet where it kind of showed
or let her go through em list he at
least at that time had the was the
number one autonomous remote-controlled
car okay I mean in in autonomous remote
control car competitions and he trained
his model using synthetically augmented
data where he basically took real videos
of a car driving around the circuit and
added like fake people and fake other
cars and stuff like that and I think
that worked well because well a because
he's kind of a genius and B because I
think he had a kind of a world to find
kind of little subset that he had to
work in but yeah in general it's really
hard it's really really hard to use
synthetic data I've tried using
synthetic data and models for decades
now obviously not ganz cuz they're
pretty new but in general it's very hard
to do very interesting research question
all right so somehow these folks at
Berkeley created a model that can turn a
horse into a zebra despite not having
any photos unless they went out there
and painted horses and took
before-and-after shots but I believe
they didn't right
so how the hell did they do this it's
it's kind of it's kind of genius
I will say the person I know who's doing
the most interesting practice of cycle
Gann right now is one of our students
Elena
sarin she's the only artist I know of
who was a psychic an artist here's an
example I love she created this little
doodle in the top of left and then
trained a psycho Gann to turn it into
this beautiful painting in the bottom
row here's some more of her amazing
works and I think it's really
interesting like I I mentioned at the
start of this class that like Dan's are
in the category of like stuff that's not
there yet but it's nearly there and in
this case like there's at least one
person in the world now who's creating
beautiful and extraordinary artworks
using gas and there's lots of pairs
specifically cycle games and there's
actually like at least maybe a dozen
people I know of who are just doing
interesting creative work with neural
nets more generally and the field of
creative area is going to expand
dramatically and I think it's
interesting with Elena right I mean I
don't know her personally but from what
I understand of her background she's a
you know she's a software developer you
know it's her full-time job and an
artist as her hobby and she's kind of
started combining these two by saying
gosh I wonder what this particular tool
could bring to my art and so if you
follow her Twitter account we'll make
sure we add it on the wiki somebody can
find it as for Lena sarin sarin
she basically posts a new
almost every day and they're always
pretty amazing so here's the basic trick
okay and this is from the cycle Gann
paper we're going to have to kind of two
images assuming we're doing this with
images right but the key thing is
they're not paired images so we're not
we don't have a data set of horses and
the equivalent zebras we've got bunch of
horses bunch of zebras grab one horse
grab one zebra okay we've now got an X
so X let's say X is horse and Y is zebra
we're going to train a generator and
what they call here a mapping function
that turns horse into zebra we'll call
that mapping function G and we'll create
one mapping function generator that
turns a zebra into a horse and we'll
call that F well create a discriminator
just like we did before which is going
to get as good as possible at
recognizing real from fake horses so
that'll be DX and then another
discriminator which is going to be as
good as possible and recognizing real
from fake zebras I'll call that dy okay
so that's kind of our starting point but
then the key thing to making this worse
work okay so we're kind of generating a
loss function here right here's one bit
of the loss function here the second bit
of the loss function we're going to
create something called cycle
consistency loss which says after you
turn your horse into a zebra with your G
generator and check whether or not I can
recognize that it's real so I keep
forgetting which one's false and which
one zebra I apologize I forget my X's
and Y's backwards though my horse into a
zebra and then going to try and turn
that zebra back into the same horse that
I started with okay and so then I'm
going to have another function that's
going to check whether my this horse
which are generated knowing nothing
about
generated entirely from this zebra is
similar to the original horse or not
right so the idea would be if your
generated zebra doesn't look anything
like your original horse you've got no
chance of turning it back into the
original horse so a loss which compares
X hat to X is going to be really bad
unless you can go into Y and back out
again and you're probably only going to
be able to do that if you're able to
create a zebra that looks like the
original horse so that you know what the
original horse looked like and vice
versa take the original take your zebra
turn it into a fake horse and check that
you can recognize that and then try and
turn it back into the original zebra and
check that it looks like the original so
notice here this F right is our zebra
two horse this G is our horse two zebra
right so so the G and the F are kind of
doing two things they're both turning
the original horse into the zebra and
then turning the zebra back into the
original horse okay so notice that
there's only two generators right there
isn't a separate generator for the
reverse mapping you have to use the same
generator that was used for the original
mapping okay
so this is the cycle consistence you
lost and I just think this is like this
is genius you know like the idea that
this is a thing that could be even be
possible
honestly when this came out it just
never occurred to me as a thing that I
could even try and solve it seems so
obviously impossible and then the idea
that you can solve it like this I just
think it's it's so damn smart so it's
good to look at the equations in this
paper because they're just good example
like they're written pretty simply I you
know there's it's not like some of the
stuff in the fastest time game paper
which is just like lots of theoretical
proofs and whatever else in this case
they're you know they're just equations
that just lay out what's going on and
you really want to get to a point where
you where you can read them and
understand
so like let's kind of start talking
through them so we've got a horse and a
zebra okay so for some mapping function
G okay which is our horse - zebra
mapping function then there's AG and
loss right which is the bit we're
already familiar with it says I've got a
horse a zebra a fake zebra recognizer
and a horse - zebra generator okay and
the loss is except it's what we saw
before it's our ability to draw one
zebra out of our zebras okay and
recognize whether it's real or fake okay
and then generate a take a horse and
turn it into a zebra and recognize
whether that's real or fake okay and
then you're you then do one minus the
other and in this case they've got a log
in there the logs not terribly important
so this is this is the thing we just saw
that's that's why we did for sustained
gain first is this is just a standard
gann loss in math form did you have a
question right wrong all of this sounds
awfully like translating in one language
to another then back to the original
have gans or any equivalent been tried
in translation not that I'm not that I
know of
[Music]
yeah yeah because there's the Unversed
is this this unsupervised machine
translation which does kind of do
something like this but I don't I
haven't looked at it closely enough to
know if it's nearly identical or if it's
just vaguely similar yeah did so to kind
of back up to what I do know normally
with translation you require this kind
of paired input you require parallel
text so you know this is the French
translation of this English
I dunno there's been a couple of recent
papers that show the ability to create
good quality translation models without
paired data
I haven't implemented them and I don't
understand anything I haven't
implemented but yeah they may well be
doing the same basic idea we'll look at
it during the week and get back to you
okay all right so we're going to again
loss the next piece is the cycle
consistency loss right and so the basic
idea here is that we start with our
horse use our zebra generator on that to
create a zebra use our horse generator
on that to create a horse and then
compare that to the original horse and
this double lines were the one we've
seen this before this is the l1 loss
okay so this is the sum of the absolute
value of differences where else if this
was a turn it would be the l2 loss or
the two norm which would be the sum of
squared differences the square root of
it actually and again we now know this
squiggle idea okay which is from our
horses grab a horse okay that's so this
is what we mean by sample from a
distribution there's all kinds of
distributions but most commonly in these
papers were using an empirical
distribution in other words we've got
some rows of data grab a row okay so
when you see this thing squiggle other
thing this thing here when it says P
data that means grab something from the
data and we're going to call that thing
X so from our horses pictures grab a
horse turn it into a zebra turn it back
into a horse compare it to the original
and some of the absolute values okay do
that for horse to zebra do it for zebra
to horse as well add the two together
and that is our cycle consistency you
lost
okay so now we get our loss function and
the whole loss function depends on our
horse generator a zebra generator our
horse recognizer our zebra recognizer
discriminator and we're going to add up
the gain loss for recognizing horses the
gain loss for recognizing zebras and the
cycle cycle consistency loss for our two
generators okay and then we've got a
lambda here which hopefully we're kind
of used to this idea now that is when
you've got two different kinds of loss
you chuck in a parameter there you can
multiply them by so they're of account
about the same scale okay and we did a
similar thing with our bounding box loss
compared to our classifier loss when we
did that localization stuff okay
so then we're going to try to for this
map for this loss function maximize the
capability of the discriminators are to
discriminate discriminating whilst
minimizing that for the generators so
the generators and the discriminators
are going to be facing off against each
other
so when you see this min max thing in
papers you'll see it a lot that means it
basically means this idea that in your
training loop one thing is trying to
make something better the other is
trying to make something worse and you
generally there's lots of ways to do it
but most commonly you'll alternate
between the two and you'll often see
this just referred to in math papers as
minnows okay so we see min max you think
you should immediately think okay
adversarial training so let's look at
the code and we're only going to
probably might be able to finish this
today but we're going to do something
almost unheard of which is I started
looking at somebody else's code and I
was not so disgusted that I threw the
whole thing away and did it myself I
actually said I quite like this I like
it enough I'm going to show it to my
students
so this is where the code comes from so
this is one of the people that created
the original code for cycle games and
they've created a high-torque version
and I had to clean it up a little bit
but it's actually pretty damn good it's
I think the first time I found code that
I didn't feel the need to rewrite from
scratch before I showed it to you and so
the cool thing about this is one of the
reasons I liked doing it this way of
like finally finding something that's
not awful is that you're now going to
get to see almost all the bits of fast
AI or like all the relevant bits of fast
AI written in a different way about
somebody else right and so you're going
to get to see like oh how they do data
sets and data loaders and models and
training loops and so forth okay so
you'll find there's a C game directory
which is basically nearly this with some
cleanups which I hope to submit as a PR
sometime - it was written in a way that
unfortunately made it a bit over
connected to how they were using it as a
script but I so cleaned it up a little
bit so I could use it as a module but
other than that it's pretty similar so C
can is basically their code copied from
their from their github repo with some
minor changes so the way the second mini
library has been set up is that the
configuration options they're assuming
are being passed into like a script so
they've got this train options parser
method and so you can see I'm basically
past passing in an array of like script
options okay where's my data how many
threads do I want to drop out how many
iterations what am I going to call this
model rich GPU
okay so that gives me a opt object which
you can then see well you know what it
contains you'll see that it contains
some things I didn't mention that's
because it's got defaults for everything
else that I didn't mention okay so we're
going to rather than using fast AI stuff
we're going to largely use CG and stuff
so the first thing we're going to need
is a downloader and so this is also a
great opportunity for you again to
practice your ability to navigate
through code with your editor or IDE of
choice so we're going to start with
create data loader so you should be able
to go find symbol or in vim tag to jump
straight to create data loader and we
can see that's creating a custom data
set loader and then we can see custom
data set loader is a base data loader
okay so that doesn't really do anything
it creates okay so basically we can see
that it's going to use a standard PI
torch data loader so that's good and so
we know if you're to use a standard
plate or data loader you have to pass it
a data set and we know that a data set
is something that contains a length and
a an indexer so presumably when we look
at create data set it's going to do that
here is create data set okay so this
library actually does more than just
cycle gain it handles both aligned and
unaligned image pairs
we know that our image pairs are
unaligned so we're going to an online
data set okay here it is
and as expected it has a get item and a
length good and so the main obviously
the main the length is just whatever of
our so a and B is our horses and zebras
got two sets so whichever one is longer
is the length of the data loader and so
getitem is just going to go ahead and
randomly grab something from each of our
two
horses and zebras open them up with
pillow or PIL run them through some
transformations and then we could either
be turning horses into zebras or zebras
into horses so there's some direction
and then I'll just go ahead and then
return our horse and our zebra and our
path to the boss and the path of zebra
so yeah hopefully you can kind of see
that this is looking pretty similar to
the kind of stuff that fast AI does
first day I obviously does quite a lot
more when it comes to transforms and
performance and stuff like this but you
know remember this is like research code
for this one thing like it's pretty cool
that they did all this work so we've got
a data loader so we can go and load our
data into it and so that'll tell us how
many mini batches are in it that's the
length of the data loader in Piper watch
next step we've got a data loader is to
create a model so you can go to go tag
for create model there it is okay same
idea we've got different kinds of models
so we're gonna be doing a cycle gain so
here's our cycle gain model okay so
there's quite a lot of stuff in a cycle
gain model so let's go through and find
out what's going to be used but
basically at this stage we've just
called initializer and so when we
initialize it you can see it's going to
go through and it's going to define two
generators we're just not surprising a
generator for our horses and a generator
for a zebras here okay there's some way
for it to generate a pool of fake data
and then here we're going to grab our
our Dan loss and as we talked about our
cycle consistency loss is an l1 loss
that's interesting they're going to use
Adam so
sleepy recycle cans can Adam works
pretty well and so then we're going to
have an optimizer for our horse
discriminator and optimizer for our
zebra discriminator and an optimizer for
our generator okay the optimizer for the
generator is going to contain the
parameters both for the horse generator
and the zebra generator all in one place
so okay so the initializer is going to
set up all of the different networks and
wasp functions we need and they're all
going to be stored inside this model and
so then it prints out and shows us
exactly the piped watch bottles we have
and so it's interesting to see that
they're using resonance and so you can
see the resinates look pretty familiar
we've got con vet norm rally you can
fetch norm so instance norm is just the
same as batch norm basically but it
applies it to one image at a time and
the difference isn't particularly
important okay and you can see they're
doing on reflection padding just like we
are so you can kind of see like when you
when you try to build everything from
scratch like this it is a lot of work
and you know you can kind of forget the
little you know the nice little things
that fast AI does automatically for you
you kind of have to do all of them by
hand and only you end up with a subset
of them so you know over time hopefully
soon we'll get all of this Gans stuff
into fast AI and it'll be nice and easy
okay so we've got our model and remember
the model contains the loss functions
it contains the generators it contains
the discriminators all in one convenient
place so I've gone ahead and kind of
copied and pasted and slightly
refactored the training loop from their
from their code so that we can run it
inside the notebook so this one a lot
pretty familiar right loop to go through
each epoch and a loop to go through
the dealer before we did this we set up
a tower this is actually not a play
torch data set I think this is what they
used slightly confusingly to talk about
their you know their combined what we
would call a model data object I guess
all the data that they need whip through
that with TQ DM to get a progress bar
and so now we can go through and see
what happens in the model right so set
input so set input so so it's kind of a
different approach to what we do in fast
AI this is kind of neat you know it's
quite specific to cycle games but
basically internally inside this model
is this idea that we're going to go into
our data and grab you know we're knowing
when we're either going horse to zebra
or zebra to horse depending on which way
we go we are the you know a is over the
horse or the zebra and vice versa and if
necessary put it on the appropriate GPU
and then grab the appropriate paths okay
so the model now has a mini batch of
horses and a mini batch of zebras and so
now we optimize the parameters okay so
it's kind of nice to see it like this
you can see each step right so first of
all try to optimize the generators then
try to optimize the horse discriminator
then try to optimize the zebra
discriminator zero grad is part of pipe
torch step is part of pi torch so the
interesting bit is the actual thing that
captain twitch does the backpropagation
on the generator so here it is and let's
jump to the key pieces there's all the
bits or the formula that we basically
just saw yeah
the paper so let's take a horse and
generate a zebra so we know what a fake
zebra and let's now use the
discriminator to see if we can tell
whether it's fake or not okay so it
spread fake and then let's pop that into
our loss function which we set up
earlier to see if we can basically to
get a loss function based on that
prediction then let's do the same thing
to do the gain loss so take a go in the
opposite direction and then we need to
use the opposite discriminator and then
put that through the loss function again
and then let's do the cycle consistence
you loss okay so again we take our fake
which we created up here okay and try
and turn it back again into the original
and then let's use that last function of
cycle consistency loss function we
created earlier to compare it to the
real original and here's that lambda
right so there's some weight that we
used and that would set up actually we
just use the default that I suggested in
there options and then do the same for
the opposite direction and then add them
all together do the backward step and
that's it so we can then do the same
thing for the first discriminator and
since basically all the works being done
now there's much less to do here okay so
there that is so I won't step all
through it but it's basically the same
same basic stuff that we've already seen
so optimized parameters basically is
calculating the losses and doing the
optimizer step from time to time save
and print out some results and then from
time to time update the learning rate so
they've got some learning rate annealing
built in here as well isn't very
exciting but okay so they've basically
got some kind of like fast AI they've
got this idea of schedulers which you
can then use to update your learning
rates so I think kind of like you know
for those of you are interested in
better understanding deep learning api's
or interested in contributing more to
fast AI or interested in like creating
you know your own version of some of
this stuff in some different back-end
it's cool to like look at a second kind
of API that covers some subset that some
of the similar things to get a sense for
how are they solving some of these
problems and what are the similarities
and what are the differences so we train
that for a little while and then we can
just grab a few examples and here we
have them so here are horses here they
are a zebras and here they are back as
horses again here's a hot zebra into a
horse back of a zebra it's kind of
thrown away its head for some reason but
not so much a quick get it back again
this is a really interesting one like
this is obviously not what zebras look
like but if it's going to be a zebra
version of that horse it's also
interesting to see it's foliar
situations I guess it doesn't very often
see basically just an eyeball have no
idea how to do that one so some of them
don't work very well this one's done a
pretty good job this one's interesting
it's done a good job with that one in
that one but for some reason the one in
the middle didn't get go yeah this one's
a really weird shape but it's done a
reasonable job of it this one looks good
this one's pretty sloppy again for just
a head up there so you know I didn't it
took me quite a bit for me like 24 hours
to train it even that far so it's kind
of slow and I know Hellena is constantly
complaining on Twitter about how long
these things take
I don't know how she's so productive
with them so yeah I will mention one
more thing that just came out yesterday
which is there's now a multi-modal image
to image translation of unpaired and so
you can basically now create different
cats for instance from this dock so this
is basically not just creating one
example of the output that you want but
creating multiple ones so here's a house
cat - a big cat and here's a big cap -
house cat this is the paper yeah so this
came out like yesterday or the day
before I think I think it's pretty
amazing captain - dog so you can kind of
see how this technology is developing
and I think you know if you oh there's
so many opportunities to you know maybe
do this with music or speech or writing
or to create kind of tools for artists
or alright thanks everybody and see you
next week
[Applause]