so welcome to lesson 10 or is somebody
on the forum described at lesson 10 not
seven which is probably a clearer way to
think about this we're going to be
talking about NLP before we do let's do
a quick review of last week because last
week you know there's quite a few people
who have kind of flown here to San
Francisco for this inverse of course I'm
seeing them pretty much every day
they're working full time on this and
quite a few of them are still struggling
to understand the material from last
week right so if you're finding it
difficult that's that's fine one of the
reasons I kind of put it up there up
front is so that we've got something to
cogitate about and think about gradually
work towards for the by lesson 14 mod 7
your you'll get a second crack at it
okay but it's it's world work that
there's so many pieces and so hopefully
you can keep developing a better
understanding to understand the pieces
you'll need to understand you know the
shapes of convolutional layer outputs
and receptive fields and loss functions
and and everything right so it's all
stuff that you're going to understand
need to understand for all of your deep
learning studies anyway right so
everything you do to develop an
understanding of last week's lesson is
going to help you everything else so one
key thing I wanted to mention is we
started out with something which is
really pretty simple which is single
person classifier a single object class
player single object bounding box
without a classifier and then single
object classifier and darling box and
anybody who's hopefully spent some time
studying since lesson 8 mod seven has
got to the point where they understand
this bit right now the reason I mention
this is because the bit where we go to
multiple objects is actually almost
identical to this except we first have
to solve the matching problem we ended
up creating far more activations than we
need for our number of bounding boxes
ground truth bounding boxes and so we
match each ground truth object
to a subset of those activations right
and once we've done that the loss
function that we then do to which
matched pair is almost identical to this
loss function right so if you're feeling
stuck go back to lesson eight right and
make sure you understand the data set
the data loader and most importantly the
loss function from the end of lesson
eight or the start of lesson nine okay
okay
so once we've got this thing which can
predict the class and bounding box for
one object we went to multiple objects
by just creating more activations we had
to then deal with the matching problem
having done with the dealt with a
matching problem we then basically moved
each of those anchor boxes in and out a
little bit and around a little bit so
they tried to line up with a particular
ground truth objects and we talked about
how we took advantage of the
convolutional nature of the network to
to try to have activations that had a
receptive field that was similar to the
ground truth object we were predicting
and khloé sultan provided this fantastic
picture I guess for her own notes but
she shared it with everybody which is
lovely to talk about like what is SSD
mode he had to forward do line by line
and I apparently wanted to show this to
help you with your revision but I also
can't you wanted to show through this
show this to kind of say doing this kind
of stuff is very useful for you to do
like walk through and in whatever way
helps you make sure you understand
something and you can see what Chloe's
done here is she's focused particularly
on the dimensions of the tensor at each
point and the in the in the path has be
kind of gradually down sampling using
these tragic convolutions making sure
she understands why those grid sizes
happen and then understanding how the
outputs come out of those okay and so
one thing you might be wondering is well
how did Chloe calculate these numbers so
I don't know
the answer I have spoken to her but
obviously one approach would be like
from first principles just thinking
through it but then you want to know
what am i right
right and so this is where you've got to
remember this pdb dot set trace idea
right so I just went in just before
class and went into SSD multi-head dot
forward and entered pdb dot set trace
and then I ran a single batch right and
so at that so I put the trace at the end
and then I could just print out the size
of all of these guys right so which by
the way reminds me last week there may
have been a point where I said 21 plus 4
equals 26 which is not true in most
universes and like by the way when I
code I do that stuff like that's the
kind of thing I do all the time so
that's why we have debuggers and know
how to check things and do things in
small little bits along the way anyway
so this idea of putting a debugger
inside your forward function and
printing out the sizes is something
which is damn super or you could just
put a print statement here as well so I
actually don't know if that's how Khloe
figured it out but that's how I would if
I was her and then we talked about
increasing K which is the number of
anchor boxes for each convolutional grid
cell which we can do with different
zooms and different aspect ratios and so
that gives us a plethora of activations
and therefore predicted bounding boxes
which we then went down to a small
number using non maximum suppression and
I'll try and remember to put a link
there's a really interesting paper that
one of our students told me about that I
hadn't heard about which is attempting
to like you know I've mentioned on
maximum suppression it's like kind of
hacky kind of leads totally heuristic
you know didn't even talk about the code
because it seems kind of hideous so
somebody actually came up with a paper
recently
attempts to do an end-to-end ComNet to
replace that NMS piece so I'll I'll put
that paper up nobody's created a torch a
pipe torch implementation yeah so be an
interesting project if anyone wanted to
try that um one thing I've noticed in
our study groups during the week is not
enough people reading papers the the
what we are doing in class now is
implementing papers the papers are the
real ground truth right and I think you
know from talking to people a lot of the
reason people aren't reading papers is
because a lot of people don't think
they're capable of reading papers they
don't think they're the kind of people
that read papers but you are you're here
right and like we started looking at a
paper last week and we read the words
that were in English and we largely
understood them right so it's like if
you actually look through this picture
from SSD carefully you'll realize SSD
multi-head but forward is not doing the
same as this and then you might think oh
well I wonder if this is better you know
and my answer is probably right because
that's his team all he had up forward
was like the first thing I tried just to
get something out there you know but you
know that there are between this and the
yellow vert and three paper and stuff
they're probably much better ways one
thing you'll notice in particular is
they use a smaller K but they have a lot
more sets of grids one by one three by
three five by five ten by ten 19 by 19
and 38 by 38 8700 per class right so a
lot more then the we hats they've been
interesting thing to experiment with
another thing I noticed is that where
else we had four by four two by two one
by one which means there's a lot of
overlap like every set fits within every
other set in this case where you've got
one three five there's that you don't
have that overlap right so it might
actually make it easier to learn so
there's lots of interesting things you
can play with based on stuff that's out
you know either trying to make it closer
to the paper or
think about other things you could try
that aren't in the paper or whatever
perhaps most important thing I would
recommend is to put the code and the
equations next to each other yes Rachel
there was a question of whether you
could speak about the used cyclic
learning rate argument and the fit
function we broke it there so put the
code and the equations from the paper
next to each other and draw in one of
two groups you are either a code person
like me who's not that happy about math
in which case I start with a code and
then I look at the math and I learn
about how the math master the code and
end up eventually understanding the math
all your PhD in stochastic differential
equations like Rachel whatever that
means in which case you can look at the
math and then learn about how the code
implements the math right then either
way unless you're one of those rare
people who is equally comfortable in
either world you'll learn about one or
the other now learning about code is
pretty easy because there's
documentation and we know how to it's
indexed up and so forth sometimes
learning the math is hard because the
notation might seem how to look up but
there's actually a lot of resources for
example list of mathematical symbols on
Wikipedia is amazingly great it has
examples of the explanations of what
they mean and tells you what to search
for to find out more about it really
terrific and if you google for math
notation cheat sheet you'll find more of
these kinds of terrific resources ok so
over time you do need to learn the
notation but as you'll see from the
Wikipedia page there's not actually that
much division right obviously there's a
lot of concepts behind it but once you
know the notation you can then quickly
look at the concept as it pertains to a
particular thing you're studying nobody
learns all of math and then starts
learning machine learning right
everybody even top researchers I know
when they're reading a new paper will
very often come to bits of math they
haven't seen before and they'll have to
go away and what that that bit of math
another thing you should try doing is to
recreate things that you see in the
papers right so here was the key most
important figure one from the focal loss
paper the retina paper so recreate it
right and like very often I put these
challenges up on the forums right so
like keep an eye on the lessons register
either put on the forums and so I put
this challenge up there and within about
three three minutes serrata had said
done it in Microsoft Excel
naturally along with actually a lot more
information within the original paper
the nice thing here is that she was
actually able to draw a line showing at
a point five ground truth probability
what's the loss for different amounts of
gamma I'm just kind of cool and if you
want to cheat
she's also provided Python code to I did
discover a reminder bug in my code last
week the way that I was flattening out
the convolutional activations did not
line up with how I was using them in the
loss function and fixing that actually
made it quite a bit better so my
motorbikes and cows and stuff we're
actually in the right place
so when you go back to that notebook
you'll see it's a little less bad than
it was okay
so there's some there's some quick
coverage of what's gone before yes quick
question are you gonna put the
PowerPoint on github I'll put a subset
of it on okay and then secondly usually
when we down sample we increase the
number of filters or depth when we're
doing sampling from 77 to 44 why are we
decreasing the number from 512 to 256
why not decrease dimension and SSD head
is it performance-related 77
well seven by seven two four by four I
guess they've got star it's it's it's
because well my treats because that's
kind of what the papers tend to do is is
we've got a number of well we have a
number of our paths and we kind of want
each one to be the same so we don't want
each one to have a different number of
filters and also this is what the the
papers did so I was trying to match up
with that and having these 256 it's it's
a different concept because we're taking
advantage of not just the last layer but
the layers before that as well life's
easier if we make them more consistent
okay so we're now going to move to NLP
and so let me kind of lay out where
we're going here we we've seen a couple
of times now this idea of lab taking a
pre trained model in fact we've seen it
in every lesson take a pre trained model
whip off some stuff on the top replace
it with some new stuff get it to do
something similar right and so what
we're going to do so and so we've kind
of dived in a little bit deeper to that
to say like okay with convolute a dot
pre-trained it had like a standard way
of like sticking stuff on the top which
does a particular thing which with some
classification okay and then we learn
actually we have we can stick any PI
torch module we like on the end and have
it do anything we like with a in a
custom here and so suddenly you discover
wow there's there's some really
interesting things we can do in fact
that reminds me
reminds me young Lou said well what if
we did a different kind of custom in
here and so the different custom hit was
well let's take the original pictures
and rotate them and then make our
dependent variable the op you know the
opposite of that rotation basically and
see if it can learn to unrotated and
this is like a super useful thing
obviously in fact I think Google photos
nowadays has this option that it'll
actually automatically rotate your
photos for you but the cool thing is as
young lord shows here you can build that
Network right now by doing exactly the
same as our previous lesson but your
custom had is one that spits out a
single number which is how much to
rotate by and your data set has a
dependent variable which is how much did
you rotate though yeah so like you
suddenly realized with this idea of a
backbone plus a custom head you can do
almost anything you can think about so
today we're going to look at the same
idea and say like okay well how does
that apply to NLP and then in the next
lesson we're going to go further and say
like well if NLP in computer vision kind
of lets you do the same basic ideas how
do we combine the two and we're going to
learn about a model that can actually
learn to find word structures from
images or images from word structures or
images from images and that will form
the basis if you wanted to go further of
doing things like going from an image to
a sentence that's called image
captioning for going from a sentence to
an image which will kind of have to do a
phrased image and so from there you know
we've got to go deeper then into
computer vision to think
like okay what other kinds of things we
can do with this idea of a pre-trained
network plus a custom head and so we'll
look at various kinds of image
enhancement like increasing the
resolution of a low-res photo to guess
what was missing or adding artistic
filters on top of photos or changing
photos of horses into photos of zebras
and stuff like that and then finally
that's gonna bring us all the way back
to bounding boxes again and so to get
there we've got a first of all that
about segmentation which is not just
learnt figuring out where a bounding
boxes but figuring out what every single
pixel in an image is part of so this
pixel is part of a person this pixel is
part of a car and then we're going to
use that idea particularly an idea court
unit it turns out that this idea from
unit we can apply to bounding boxes
where it's called feature pyramids
everything has to have a different name
in every slightly different area and
we'll use that to hopefully get some
better better results and really good
results actually it bounding boxes so
that's kind of our path from here um so
it's all gonna kind of build on each
other that take us into lots of
different areas now for NLP last part we
relied on a pretty great library called
torch text but as pretty great as it was
I've since then found the limitations of
it too problematic to keep using it as a
lot of you complained on the forums it's
pretty damn slow partly that that's
because it's doing parallel not doing
parallel processing and partly it's
because it doesn't remember what you did
last time and it does it all over again
from scratch and then it's kind of hard
to do fairly simple things like a lot of
you were trying to get into the toxic
comment competition on cattle which was
a multi-label problem and trying to do
that with torch text I eventually got it
working but it took me like a week of
hacking away
which is kind of ridiculous so to fix
all these problems we've created a new
library called fast AI blood test
fast AI dot text is a replacement for
the combination of torch text and fast
AI NLP yeah so don't use fast I don't
NLP anymore okay that's like that's
obsolete it's it's slower it's more
confusing it's less good in every way
right but there's a lot of overlaps okay
like intentionally a lot of the classes
have the same names all of the functions
have the same names but this is the non
torch text okay okay so we're going to
work with IMDB again alright so for
those of you have forgotten go back and
check out lesson 4
that basically this is a data set of
movie reviews and you remember we used
it to find out whether we might enjoy
some be getting or not
and we thought probably my kind of thing
so we're going to use the same data set
and by default it it calls itself a co
IMDB so this is just that the raw data
set that you can download and as you can
see I'm doing from fast AI dot text
import star there's no torch text and
I'm not using faster I don't an LP
I'm going to use path Lea but as per
usual we're going to learn about what
these tags are later so you might
remember the basic paths for NLP is that
we have to take sentences and turn them
into numbers and there's a couple of
steps to get there okay so at the moment
somewhat intentionally fast AI dot text
doesn't provide that many helper
functions it's really designed more to
let you handle things in a fairly
flexible way right so as you can see
here I wrote something called get texts
which goes
each thing in classes and these are the
three classes that they have in IMDB
negative positive and then there's
another folder unsupervised that stuff
they haven't gotten around to labeling
yet so I'm just going to call that class
now and so I just go through each one of
those classes and then I just find every
file in that folder with that name and I
open it up and read it and check it into
the end of this all right
okay and as you can see with path lab
it's super easy to grab stuff and pull
it in and then the label is just
whatever class or not - so right so I'll
go ahead and I'll do that for the Train
bit and I'll do that for the test fit so
there's 70,000 and Tre and 25,000 in
test talk about 50,000 if the Train ones
are unsupervised we won't actually be
able to use them when we get to the
classification piece okay so I actually
find this much easier than the kind of
torch text approach of having lots of
layers and wrappers and stuff because in
the end reading text files is not it's
not that hard okay
one thing that's always good idea is to
sort things randomly
it's useful to know this simple trick
for sorting things randomly particularly
when you've got multiple things you have
to sort the same way in this case you've
got labels and texts NP dot random block
permutation if you give it an integer it
gives you a random list from 0 up to and
not including the number you give it in
some random order and so you can then
just pass that in as a indexer right to
give you a list that's sorted in that
random order so in this case it's going
to sort train texts and train labels in
the same random way okay so that's a
useful little idiom to use so now I've
got my texts and my labels sorted I can
go ahead and create a data frame from
them why am I doing this well the reason
I'm doing this is because there is
a somewhat standard approach starting to
appear for text classification datasets
which is to have your training set as a
CSV file with the with the labels first
and the text of the NLP documents second
you know trained on CSV and a test or
CSB so it basically looks like this you
have your labels and your texts and then
a file called classes text which just
lists the classes I think somewhat
standard is just in a reasonably recent
academic paper yarn lakorn and a team of
researchers looked at quite a few data
sets and they use this format for all of
them and so that's what I've started
using as well for my recent paper so
what I've done is you'll find that this
notebook if you put your data into this
format the whole notebook will work
every time and so far than having a
thousand different classes or formats
and readers and writers or whatever have
you said let's just pick a standard
format and your job your coders you can
do it perfectly well is to put it in
that format which is the CSV file okay
the CSV files have no header okay
by default all right now you'll notice
at the start here that I had two
different paths one was the
classification path one was the language
model of path in NLP you'll see LM all
the time L M means language model so the
classification path is going to contain
the information that we're going to use
to create a sentiment analysis model the
language model path is going to contain
the information we need to create a
language model so they're a little bit
different one thing that's different is
that when we create the train dot CSV in
the classification path we
move everything that has a label of two
because label of two is unsupervised
okay so we remove the unsupervised data
from the classifier we cannot use it so
that means that this is going to have
actually 25,000 positive 25,000 negative
and the second difference is the labels
for the classification path the labels
are the actual labels but for the
language model there are no labels so we
just use a bunch of zeros and that just
makes it a little bit easier because we
can use a consistent data frame format
or CSV format okay now the language
model we can create our own validation
set and so you've probably come across
by now SK learn but model selection dot
train test split which is a really
simple little function that grabs a data
set and randomly splits it into a
training set and the validation set
according to whatever proportion you
specify and so in this case I
concatenate my classification training
and validation together so that's got to
be a hundred thousand altogether split
it by ten percent and so now I've got
90,000 training ten thousand validation
for my language model so I'll go ahead
and save that
so that's my basic you know get the data
in a standard format for my language
model in my classifier right so the next
thing we need to do is tokenization so
tokenization means at this stage we've
got for a document for a movie review
we've got a big long string and we
wanted to pretend it into a list of
tokens which are kind of a list of words
but not quite right for example don't we
want to be door hmm you probably want
full stop to be a token and so forth
right so tokenization is something that
we passed off to a terrific library
called spacey partly terrific because in
australian wrote it and partly terrific
because it's
good at what it does we put a bit of
stuff on top of Spacey but the vast
majority the works being done by Spacey
before we pass it to Spacey I've written
this simple fix-up function which is
basically each time I don't put a
different data set and I've looked at
about a dozen in building this everyone
had different weird things that need to
be replaced so here all the ones I've
come up with so far hopefully this will
help you out as well so I HTML and
escape all the entities and then there's
a bunch more things I replace have a
look at the result of running this on
text that you put in and make sure
there's not more weird tokens in there
it's amazing how many weird things
people do to test
so basically I've got this function
called get all which is going to go
ahead and call get texts and texts is
going to go ahead and do a few things
one of which is to apply that fix up
that we just mentioned so let's kind of
look through this because there's some
interesting things to point out so I got
to use pandas to open our train CSV from
the language model path but I'm passing
in an extra parameter you may not have
seen before called chat sighs Python and
pandas can both be pretty inefficient
when it comes to storing and using text
data and so you'll see that very few
people in NLP are working with large
corpuses and I think part of the reason
is that traditional tools have just made
it really difficult you ran out of
memory all the time so this process I'm
showing you today I have used on
corpuses of over a billion words
successfully using this exact code right
and so one of the simple tricks is to
use this thing called Chuck size with
pandas what that means is that pandas to
not return a data frame but it returns
an iterator that we can iterate through
chunks of a data frame and so that's why
I don't say truck train equals get texts
because here is a finger texts but
instead I call get all which loops
through the data frame but actually what
it's really doing is its looping through
chunks with the data frame so each of
those chunks is basically a data frame
representing a subset of the data when
I'm working with NLP data many times I
come across data with foreign text or
characters
is it better to discard them or keep
them no no definitely keep them and this
whole process is is Unicode and I've
actually used this on Chinese text this
is designed to work on pretty much
anything yeah yeah in general most of
the time it's not a good idea to remove
anything like old-fashioned NLP
approaches tend to do all this like
limit ization and all these kind of
normalization steps to kind of get rid
of you know that lower case everything
blah blah blah but you know that's
throwing away information which you
don't know ahead of time whether it's
useful or not so don't throw away
information ok so we go through each
chunk each of which is a data frame and
we call get texts get texts is going to
grab the labels and makes them into ants
it's going to grab then the the texts
and I'll point out a couple of things
the first is that before we include the
text we have this beginning of stream
token which you might remember we used
way back up here there's nothing special
about these particular strings of
letters they're just once I figured
don't appear in normal text it's very
often so every text is going to start
with X POS now why is that because it's
often really useful for your model to
know when a new text is starting for
example if it's a language
model right we are going to concatenate
all the text together and so it'd be
really helpful for it to know all this
articles finished and a new one started
so I should probably like forget some of
their context yeah Devo is quite often
texts have multiple fields like a title
and abstract and then the main document
and so by the same token I've got this
thing here which alerts us actually have
multiple fields in our CSV okay so this
really this process is designed to be
very flexible and again at the start of
each one we put a special field starts
here token followed by the number of the
field that's starting here for as many
fields as we have okay then we apply our
fix up to it and then most importantly
we tokenize it and we tokenize it by
doing a process or multiprocessor multi
processing I guess I should say and so
tokenizing tends to be pretty slow but
we've all got multiple cores and our
machines now and some of the better
machines on AWS and stuff can have
dozens of course here on a university
computer we've got 56 cause so Spacey is
not very amenable to multi processing
but I finally figured out how to get it
to work and the good news is it's all
wrapped up in this one function now and
so all you need to pass to that function
is a list of things to tokenize which
each part of that list will be tokenized
on a different core and so i've also
created this function called partition
by cause which takes a list and splits
it into sub lists the number of sub
lists is the number of cores that you
have in your computer ok so on on my
machine without more-- processing this
takes about an hour and a half and with
more processing it takes about two
minutes
alright so it's a really handy thing to
have and now that this codes here you
know feel free to look inside it and
take advantage of it for your own stuff
right remember we all have multiple
processes
protocol cause even in our laptops and
very few things in place that and take
advantage of it unless you make a bit of
an effort to make it work so there's a
couple of tricks to get things working
quickly and reliably as it runs it
prints out how it's going and so here's
the result at the end right
beginning of stream token beginning of
field number one token here's the
tokenized text you'll see that the
punctuation is on the whole now a
separate token you'll see there's a few
interesting little things one is this
what's this t up t up MGM for MGM
obviously was originally capitalized
right but the interesting thing is that
normally people are the lowercase
everything or they leave the case as is
now if you leave the case as is then
screw you or caps and screw you lower
case are two totally different sets of
tokens that have to be learned from
scratch or if you love a case them all
then there's no difference at all
between screw or you and right so how do
you fix this so that you both get a
semantic impact of like I'm shouting now
right but not have every single word
have to learn the shouted version versus
the normal version and so the idea I
came up with and I'm sure other people
have done this too is to come up with a
unique token to mean the next thing is
all uppercase so then I lowercase it so
now whatever used to be up case it's now
lowercase it's just one token and then
we can learn the semantic meaning of all
uppercase and so I've done a similar
thing if you've got like 29 exclamation
marks in a row we don't learn a separate
token for 29 exclamation marks instead I
put in a special token for the next
thing repeats lots of times and then I
put the number 29 and then I put the
explanation mark okay and so there's a
few little tricks like that and if
you're interested in LP have a look at
the code
tokenizer for these little tricks that
I've added in because some of them are
kind of fun okay so the nice thing with
doing things this way is we can now just
NP dot save that and load it back up
later like we don't have to recalculate
all this stuff each time like we tend to
have to do with with torch text or a lot
of other libraries
okay so we've now got it
tokenized the next thing we need to do
is to turn it into numbers which we call
numerical Eisinger and the way we
numeric lies it is very simple we make a
list of all the words that appear in
some order and then we replace every
word with its index into that list the
list of all the words that appear or all
the tokens that we call the vocabulary
so here's an example of some of the
vocabulary the counter class in in
plaque that is very handy for this it
basically gives us a list of unique
items and their counts okay so here are
the 25 most common and things in the
vocabulary you can see there are things
like apostrophe s and double quote and
end of paragraph and also stuff like
that now generally speaking we don't
want every unique token in our
vocabulary if it doesn't appear at least
two times then might just be a spelling
mistake or a word I mean we can't learn
anything about it if it doesn't appear
that often also the stuff that we're
going to be learning about at least so
far in this part gets a bit clunky once
you've got a vocabulary bigger than
60-thousand time permitting we may look
at some work I've been doing recently on
handling larger vocabularies otherwise
that might have to come in a in a future
class okay but actually for
classification I've discovered that
doing more than about 60,000 words
doesn't seem to help anyway so we're
going to limit our vocabulary to 60,000
words things that appear at least twice
and so here's a simple way to do that
use that dot most common pass in the
mass vocab size that'll sort it by the
frequency by the way
and if it appears less often than a
minimum frequency then don't bother at
all okay so that gives us Ida s that's
the the same name that torch text used
remember it means that into string so
this is just the list of tokens unique
tokens in the vocab I'm going to insert
two more tokens a token for unknown
evoke a bite of your unknown and vocab
item for padding okay then we can create
the dictionary which goes in the
opposite direction so string to end and
that won't cover everything because we
intentionally truncated it down to
60,000 words right and so if we come
across something that's not in the
dictionary we want to replace it with
zero for unknown and so we can use a
default dick for that with a lambda
function that always returns Europe okay
so you can see all these things were
using the kind of kick coming coming
back up so now that we've got our s to a
dictionary defined we can then just call
that for every word for every sentence
right and so there's an Americanized
version and there it is okay and so of
course the nice thing is again we can
save that step as well that's so each
time we get to another step we can save
it and these are not very big files
compared to what you used to with with
images text is generally pretty small
very important to also save that
vocabulary but because the this this
list of numbers means nothing unless you
know what each number refers to and
that's what I to restaurants you okay so
you save those three things and then
later on you can load them back up so
now our vocab size is 60,000 and term
and training language model has 90,000
documents you know okay so
that's the pre-processing you do we can
probably rap a little bit more of that
in little utility functions if we want
to but it's all pretty straightforward
and basically that exact code will work
for any data set you have once you've
got it in that CSV format so here is a
kind of a new insight that's not new at
all which is that we'd like to pre train
something like we know from lesson four
that if we pre train our classifier by
first creating a language model and then
fine-tuning that as a classifier that
was helpful do you remember it actually
got us a new start at the out result we
got the best IMDb classifier result that
had ever been published but quite a bit
well we're not going that far enough
though right because IMDB movie reviews
are not that different to any other
English document you know compared to
how different they are to a random
string or even to a Chinese document so
just like imagenet allowed us to train
things that recognized stuff that kind
of looks like pictures and we could use
it on stuff that was nothing to do with
image net like satellite images
why don't we train a language model
that's just like good at English and
then fine tune it to be good at major
reviews so this basic insight Leadbeater
try building a language model on
Wikipedia so my friend Steven marady has
already processed Wikipedia found a
subset of nearly you know the most of it
but throwing away the stupid little
articles so most of the bigger articles
and he calls that wiki text 103 so I
grabbed wiki text 103 and I trained a
language model honor
and we and I used exactly the same
approach I'm about to show you for
trading an IMDB language model but
instead I trained a wikitext 103
language model and then I saved it and
I've made it available for anybody who
wants to use it at this URL so this is
not a URL for wikitext 103 the documents
this is the wiki text 103 the language
model and so the idea now is let's train
an IMDB language model which starts with
these words there hopefully to you folks
this is a extremely obvious extremely
non-controversial idea because it's
basically what we've done in nearly
every class so far but when I first when
I first mentioned this to two people in
the NLP community I guess like June July
of last year there couldn't have been
less interest you know I asked on
Twitter where a lot of the top thread of
research is kind of people that I follow
and they'll be back I was like hey what
if we like pre-trained like a general
language model like no old language is
different you know you can do that or
like I don't know why you would bother
anyway I've talked to people at
conferences and they're like pretty sure
people have tried that and it stupid
like there was just this like I don't
know this weird like frank past and you
know I guess because I am arrogant in
obstreperous I ignored them even though
they know much more about NLP than I do
and just trade it anyway and let me show
you what happened so here's how we do it
right
grab the wiki text models right and if
you use double you get minus R it'll
actually recursively grab the whole
directory it's got a few things or not
we need to make sure that our language
model has exactly the same embedding
size number of hidden and number of
layers as my wiki text one did otherwise
you can't load the way it's in here so
here's our pre-trained path here's our
preteen language model path let's go
ahead and torch dot load in those
weights from the forward wickety text
103 model okay we don't normally use
torch dot load but that's that's that's
the you know the pi torch way of
grabbing a file and it basically gives
you a dictionary containing the name of
the layer and a tensor of those weights
or an array of those words now here's
the problem that wiki text language
model was built with a certain
vocabulary which was not the same as
this one was built on right so my number
40 was not the same as wiki text 103
models number 40 so we need to map one
to the other
okay that's very very simple because
luckily I saved the I to s for the wiki
text okay right so here's the list of
what each word is when I trained the
wiki text 103 model and so we can do the
same default dict trick to map it in
Reverse right and I'm going to use minus
1 to mean that it's not in the wiki text
dictionary and so now I can just say
okay my new set of weights is just a
whole bunch of zeros with vocab sighs by
embedding size so we're going to create
an embedding matrix I'm then going to go
through every one of the words in my
IMDB vocab room okay I am going to look
it up in s - I - so a string to int for
the wiki text 103 vocabulary and see if
it's words there okay and if that is
word there then I'm not going to get
this minus one right so I will be
greater than or equal to zero so in that
case I will just set that row of the
embedding matrix two to the weight that
I just looked
that which was stored inside this this
named element and so these these names
you can look at you can just look at
this dictionary and it's pretty obvious
what each name corresponds to it looks
very similar to the names that you gave
it when you set up your module so here
are the encoder weights
okay so I grabbed it from the encoder
weights if I don't find it then I will
use the row mean in other words here is
the average imbedding weight across all
of the wikitext what are three things
okay so that's pretty simple so I'm
going to end up with an embedding matrix
for every word that's in both my vocab
room for IMDB and the week in text 103
vocab I will use the wiki text 103
embedding matrix weights for anything
else I will just use whatever was the
average weight from the wiki text 103
embedding matrix okay and then I'll go
ahead and I will replace the encoder
weights with that turn into a tensor
we haven't talked much about weight
tying we might do so later but basically
the decoder so the thing that turns the
final prediction back into a word uses
exactly the same weights so I pop it
there as well and then there's a bit of
a weird thing with how we do embedding
dropout that ends up with a whole
separate copy of them for a reason that
doesn't matter much anyway so we just
popped the weights back where they need
to go so this is now something that a
dictionary we can now or a set of torch
state which we can load in so let's go
ahead and create our language model okay
and so the basic approach we're going to
use and I'm going to look at this in
more detail in a moment but the basic
approach are going to use is I'm going
to concatenate all of the documents
together into a single a single list of
tokens of length twenty four point nine
nine eight million okay so that's going
to be what I pass in as my trainings
so the language model right we basically
just take all our documents and just
concatenate them back to that okay and
we're going to be continuously trying to
predict what's the next word after these
words what's the next word after these
words have a look at these details in a
moment I'm going to set up a whole bunch
of drop out look at that in detail
moment
once we've got a model data object we
can then grab the model from it so
that's going to give us a learner okay
and then as per usual we can call lo not
fit so we first of all as per usual just
do a single epoch on the last layer just
to get that okay and the way I've set it
up is the last layer is actually the
embedding words because that's obviously
the thing that's going to be the most
wrong because like a lot of those
embedding weights didn't even exist in
the vocab so we're just gonna train a
single epoch of just the inventing
weights and then we'll start doing a few
epochs of the full model and so how is
that looking well here's lesson four
which was our academic world's best ever
result and after 14 he parks we had a
four point two three loss here after one
epoch we have a four point one two loss
right
so by pre-training on wikitext 103 in
fact let's go and have a look
we kept training and training at a
different rate eventually we got to four
point one six so by pre training on
wikitext 103 we have a better loss after
one époque than the best loss we got for
the language model otherwise yes Rachel
what is the wikitext 103 model is it a
double UDL STM again yeah and we're
about to dig into that it's the way I
trained it was literally the same lines
of code that you see here but without
pre-training it only takes one two three
okay so let's take a 10-minute break
come back at 7:40 and
dig in and have a look at these models
okay welcome back before we go back into
language models and NLP classifiers a
quick discussion about something pretty
new at the moment which is the faster I
dock project so the goal of a fast IO
dock project is to create documentation
that makes readers say wow that's the
most fantastic document documentation
I've ever read and so we have some
specific ideas about how to do that but
it's the same kind of idea of like top
down you know thoughtful take full
advantage of the medium approach you
know interactive experimental code first
that we're all familiar with if you're
interested in getting involved
the basic approach you can see in in the
docs directory so this is the this is
the readme in the docs directory
in there there is a amongst other things
a transforms template dot a doc what the
hell is a doc hey Doc is asciidoc how
many people here have come across sq doc
that's awesome ASCII table is people are
laughing because there's one hand up and
it's somebody who was in our study group
today who talked to me about ask you dog
ask you doc is the most amazing project
it's like markdown but it's like what
markdown needs to be to create actual
books and like a lot of actual books are
written in ASCII doc and so it's as easy
to use this back down about there's way
more cool stuff you can do with it in
fact here is an ASCII doc file here
right and as you'll see it looks very
normal there's headings right and this
is pre formatted text and there's yeah
there's lists and whatever else it looks
pretty standard and actually I'll show
you a more complete sq doc thing more
standard after doc thing but you can do
stuff like say put a table of contents
here please
you can say : : means put a definition
list here please plus means this is a
continuation of the previous list item
and so there's just like little things
that you can do which are super handy or
like put this thing make it slightly
smaller than everything else so it's
like turbocharged markdown and so this
asciidoc creates this HTML and I didn't
add any CSS or do anything myself like
we literally started this project like
four hours ago so this is like just an
example basically right and so you can
see we've got a table of contents we can
jump straight to here we've got a cross
reference we can click on to jump
straight to the cross reference each
method kind of comes along with its
details and so on and so forth right and
to make things even easier rather than
having to know that this is meant to be
like the argument list is meant to be
smaller than the main part or how do you
create a cross reference or how you
meant to format the arguments to the
method name and list out each one of its
arguments we've created a special
template where you can just write
various stuff in curly brackets like
please put the arguments here and here
is an example of one argument and here
is a cross reference and here is a
method and so forth so we're in the
process of documenting the documentation
template that there's basically like
five or six of these little curly braket
things you'll need to learn but for you
to create the documentation of class or
a method you can just copy one that's
already there basically and so the idea
is we're going to have like it'll almost
be like a book you know there'll be
tables and pictures little videos
segments and hyperloop throughout and
all that stuff you might be wondering
what about docstrings but actually I
don't know if you've noticed but if you
look at the Python standard library and
look at the doc string for example for
reg X compile it's
single-line nearly every dock string in
Python is a single line and Python then
does exactly this they have done a
website containing the documentation
that says like hey this is what regular
expressions are and this is what you
need to know about them and if you want
them to grow fast to unity his compile
and here's what some information about
compile and his examples it's not in the
dog stream and that's why we're doing it
as well our dog strings will be one line
unless you need like two sometimes it's
going to be very similar to Python but
even better
so everybody is welcome to help
contribute to the documentation and
hopefully by the time if you're watching
this on the MOOC it'll be reasonably
fleshed out and we'll try to keep a list
of things to do
all right so I'm going to do one first
so one question that came up in the
break was how does this compare to word
to vet and this is actually a great
thing for you to spend time thinking
about during the week is how does this
compare to work lévesque I'll give you
the summary now but it's a very
important conceptual difference the main
conceptual difference is what is word to
vet word Tyvek is a single embedding
matrix each word has a vector and that's
it so in other words it's a single it's
a single layer from a pre-trained model
and specifically that layer is the input
layer and also specifically that
pre-trained model is a linear model okay
that is free trained on something called
a co-occurrence matrix so we have no
particular reason to believe that this
model has learned anything much about
the English language or that it has any
particular capabilities because it's
just a single linear layer and that's it
so what's this wikitext 103 model it's a
language model and it has a four hundred
dimensional embedding matrix
three hidden layers with 1,150
activations per layer and regularization
and all that stuff tied input output
matrix equator sees it's basically a
state-of-the-art AWD ASTM so like what's
the difference between a single layer of
a single linear model versus a three
layer recurrent neural network
everything you know they're they're very
different levels of capability and so
you'll see when you try using a pre
trained language model this is a what
Vic layer you'll get very very different
results to the vast majority of tasks
what if the numpy array does not fit in
memory is it possible to write a PI
torch data loader directly from a large
CSV file it almost certainly won't come
up so I'm not going to spend time on it
like these things are tiny these they're
just hints think about how many
Institute would need to run out of
memory that's not gonna happen
they don't have a kitten's jpg memory
just in your memory so I've actually
done a another Wikipedia model which I
called Giga wiki which was on all of
Wikipedia and even that easily fits in
there and the reason I'm not using it is
because it turned out not to really help
very much business wiki text 103 but you
know I've built a bigger model than
anybody else I've found in the academic
literature pretty much and it fits in
memory on a single machine what is the
idea behind averaging the weights of
embeddings they're going to be set to
something you know like there are words
that weren't there so other options is
we could leave them a zero but that
seems like a very extreme thing to do
like zero is a very extreme number why
would it be zero we could set it equal
to some random numbers but if so what
would be the mean and standard deviation
of those random numbers or should they
be uniform if we just average the rest
of the you know the embeddings then we
have something that's reasonable scale
I just declare
this is how you're initializing words
that didn't appear in the training yeah
that's right and then I think you've
pretty much kind of just answered this
one but someone had asked if there's a
specific advantage to creating our own
pre-trained embedding over using glob or
word - back yeah I think I know we're
not creating a preacher and embedding
we're putting a pre training model okay
so um let's talk a little bit more with
this is a ton of stuff we've seen before
but it's changed a little bit it's
actually a lot easier than it was in
part one but I want to go a little bit
deeper into the language model loader
okay so this is the language model
loader and I really hope that by now
you've learned in your editor or IDE how
to jump to symbols okay yeah I don't
want it to be a burden for you to find
out what the source code of language
model loader is alright and if it's
still a burden please you know go back
and try and learn those keyboard
shortcuts in vs code you know like if
your editor doesn't make it easy
don't use that editor anymore okay
there's lots of good free editors that
make this easy okay so so here's the
source code for language model loader
and yeah it's it's it's interesting to
notice that it it's not doing anything
particularly tricky it's not deriving
from anything at all right what makes it
something that's capable being a data
loader is that it's something you can
iterate over okay and so specifically
okay
so specifically here's the fit function
inside foster yo model this is like
whatever where everything ends up
eventually which goes to each epoch and
then it creates an iterator from the
data loader and then just does a for
loop through it
alright so anything you can do a for
loop through can be a data loader
specifically it needs to return tuples
of mini-batches independent and
dependent variable for mini batches so
anything with a
Dunda in a method is something that can
act as an iterator and yield is a neat
little Python keywords you probably
should learn about if you don't already
know it
but it basically spits out a thing and
wets for you to ask for another thing
normally in like a for loop or something
so in this case we start by initializing
the language model passing it in the
numbers so this is the numerical eyes
big big long list of all of our
documents concatenated together and the
first thing we do is to batch of fudge
and this is the thing which quite a few
of you got confused about last time
right if our batch size is 64 and our we
have 24 25 million numbers in our list
we are not creating items of length 64
we're not doing that we're creating 64
items in total so each of them is of
size T divided by 64 which is three
hundred and ninety thousand okay so
that's what that's what we do here when
we reshape it so that this axis here is
of length 64 and then this minus one is
everything else so that's three hundred
and whatever a thousand three hundred
ninety thousand blob okay and then we
transpose it so that means that we now
have 64 columns three hundred ninety
thousand rows and then what we do each
time we do an iterate is we grab one
batch of some sequence length we'll look
at that in a moment but basically it's
approximately equal to VP TT which we
set to 70 stands for back prop through
time and we just grab that many rows
okay so from i to i plus 70 rows and
then we try to predict that plus one
remember so we're trying to predict when
past where a wrap - so we've got 64
columns and each of those is one
sixty-fourth of our 25 million or
whatever it was
tokens you know hundreds of thousands
long and we just grab you know 17 at a
time so each of those columns each time
and Gravatt is going to kind of hook up
to the previous column okay and so
that's why we get this consistency this
language model is it's stateful which is
really important pretty much all the
cool stuff in the language model is is
stolen from Steven Mara T's AWD LS TM
including this little trick here which
is if we always grab 70 at a time and
then we go back at me to a new epoch
we're going to grab exactly the same
batches every time there's no randomness
now normally we shuffle out data every
time we do an epoch or every time we
grab some data we grab it at random you
can't do that with a language model
because this set has to join up to the
previous set because it's fun to trying
to learn the sentence right and if you
suddenly jump somewhere else then that
doesn't make any sense as a sentence so
Stevens idea is to say okay well since
we can't shuffle the order let's step
randomly change the size the sequence
length okay and so basically he says all
right 95% of the time we'll use vacate
80 70 but 5% of the time we'll use half
that right and then he says you know
what I'm not even going to make that the
sequence length I'm going to create a
normally distributed random number with
that average and a standard deviation of
5 and I'll make that the sequence length
right so the sequence length is seventy
ish and that means every time we go
through we're getting slightly different
batches so we've got that little bit of
extra randomness I asked him Steven
marady where he came up with this idea
did he think of it
and he was like I think I thought of it
but it seemed so obvious and I bet I
didn't think of it which is like true of
like every time I come up with an idea
or deke why I think it always seems so
obvious that um somebody else is thought
of it but I think he thought of it so
yeah so this is like a nice thing to
look at if you're trying to do something
a bit unusual with the data motor it's
like okay here's a simple kind of role
model you can use as to creating a data
loader from scratch something that spits
out batches of do so so our language
model loader just took in all of the
documents concatenated together along
with a batch size and the VPT
now generally speaking we want to create
a learner and the way we normally do
that is by getting a model data object
and they're calling some kind of method
which have various names but sometimes
you don't often we call that method get
model and so the idea is that the model
data object has enough information to
know what kind of model to give you so
we have to create that model data object
which means we need that that class and
so that's very easy to do right so here
are all of the pieces we're going to
create a custom learner a custom model
data class and a custom class so a model
data class again this one doesn't
inherit from anything so you really see
it is there's almost nothing to do right
you need to tell it most importantly
what's your training set give it a data
loader
what's the validation set give it a data
loader and optionally give it a test set
data loader plus anything else that
needs to know right so it might need to
know the VPT
it needs to know the number of tokens
that's the vocab size it needs to know
what is the padding index and so that it
can save temporary files and models
model data as always need to know the
path ok and so we just grab all that
stuff and we dump it right
and that's it that's the entire
initializer there's no logic there at
all okay so then all of the work happens
inside get model right and so get model
calls something we'll look at later
which just grabs a normal pie torch and
end module architecture okay and Chuck's
it on the GPU note with PI torch
normally we would save cuda with faster
i it's better to say to GPU and the
reason is that if you don't have a GPU
it'll leave it on the cpu and it also
provides a global variable you can set
to choose whether it goes on the GPU or
not so it's a it's a better approach so
we wrapped the model in a language model
and the language model is this basically
a language model is a subclass of basic
model it basically almost does nothing
except it defines layer groups and so
remember how when we do like
discriminative learning rates where
different layers have different learning
rates or like we freeze different
amounts we don't provide a different
learning rate for every layer because
there can be like a thousand layers we
provide a different learning rate for
every layer group right so when you
create a custom model you just have to
override this one thing which returns a
list of all of your layer groups and so
in this case my last layer group
contains the last part of the model and
one bit of drop out and the rest of it
this star here means Paul is apart so
this is basically going to be one layer
per RNN layer okay so that's all that is
and then finally turn that into a
learner and so alone oh you just pass in
the model and it turns it into a real
owner in this case we have overridden
learner and the only thing we've done is
to say I want the default loss function
to be across entropy okay so this you
know entire set of
model customer model data custom learner
or fits on a single screen and they
always basically look like this right so
that's a kind of little dig inside this
pretty boring part of the code this so
the interesting part of this code base
is getting out now because that language
model is actually the thing that gives
us our AWD lsdm and it actually contains
the big idea that the big incredibly
simple idea that everybody else here
thinks is really obvious that everybody
in the NLP community I spoke to thought
was insane which is basically every
model can be thought of pretty much
every model can be thought of as a
backbone plus a head and if you pre
train the backbone and stick on a random
head you can do fine tuning and that's a
good idea all right and so here's these
two bits of the code literally right
next to each other this is kind of all
there is inside this bit of faster I've
dot LM RNN here's gate language model
here's gate classifier that language
model creates an R and n encoder and
then creates a sequential model that
sticks on top of that a linear decoder
classifier creates an R Ln encoder and
then a sequential model that sticks on
top of that appalling linear classifier
well see these what these differences
are in a moment but you get the basic
idea right they're basically doing
pretty much the same thing they've got
this it's head linear layer on top so
that's worth digging in a little bit
deeper and seeing what's going on here
yes Rachel there was a question earlier
about whether that any of this
translates to other languages yeah this
whole thing works in any language you
like obviously would you have to retrain
your language model on a corpus from
that language yeah yeah so the wiki text
103 pre-trained language model knows
English right
you could use it maybe as a pre train
start for like a French short German
model start by retraining the embedding
layer from scratch might be helpful
Chinese maybe not so much but like given
that a language model can be trained
from any and labeled documents at all
you'll never have to do that right
because every every almost every
language in the world has you know
plenty of documents you can grab
newspapers web pages you know
parliamentary records whatever you know
as long as you've got a few thousand
documents showing somewhat normal usage
of that language you can create a
language model and so I know some of our
students you know one of our students is
a bill collector in a week very
embarrassing tried this approach for
Thai and he said like the first model he
built easily beat the previous Dennis
the anti classifier like it's yeah like
for those of you that are international
fellows this is an easy way for you to
kind of to whip out a paper in which you
you know either create the first ever
classifier in your language or beat
everybody else's classifier in your
language and then you can tell them that
you've been a student of deep moaning
for six months and piss off all the
academics in your country okay so here's
our edit encoder
it's just a standard inin module most of
the text in it is actually just
documentation as you can see it it looks
like there's more going on in it then
there actually is but really all there
is is we create an embedding layer we
create an LST M for each layer that's
been asked for that's it everything else
in it is dropped out right basically all
of the interesting stuff just about in
the AWA DL STM paper is all of the
places you can put drop out and then the
forward is basically the same thing
right
it's call the embedding layer add some
dropout go through each layer call that
are a ten liya append it to our list of
our ports add dropout that's about it
okay so it's it's it's really pretty
straightforward and the the paper you
want to be reading as I've mentioned is
the AWD lsdm paper which is this one
here regularizing and optimizing lsdm
language models and it's it's
well-written and pretty accessible right
and entirely implemented inside fast AI
as well right so you can see all of the
code for that paper and like a lot of
the code actually is I'm shamelessly
plagiarized with Stephens permission
from his excellent github repo WBLS TM
and the process of which I picked some
of his bugs as well I even told him
about them so yeah so I talked you know
I'm talking and increasingly about
please read the papers so here's the
paper please read this paper and it
refers to other papers so for things
like why is it that the encoder wait and
the decoder wait are the same right well
it's because there's this thing called
tie weights this is inside this is
inside that gate language model there's
a thing called tie weights the defaults
to true and if it's true then the we
actually tie we literally use the same
weight matrix for the encoder and the
decoder so like they're literally
pointing at the same block of memory if
you like and so why is that what's the
result of it that's one of the citations
and Stephens paper
is also a well-written paper you can go
and look up and learn about wait time so
there's a lot of cool stuff in there
okay so we have basically a standard
iron in the only reason where it's not
standard is it's just got lots more
types of dropout in it and then a
sequential model on top of that we stick
a linear decoder which is literally half
the screen of code it's got a single
linear layer we initialize the weights
to some range we add some dropout and
that's it so it's a linear layer okay so
we've got an iron N on top of that
mystic linear layer with dropout and we
finished okay so that's the language
model so um what dropout you choose
matters a lot and through a lot of
experimentation I found a bunch of
dropouts you can see here we've got like
each of these corresponds to a
particular accurate a bunch of dropouts
that tend to work pretty well for
language models but if you have less
data for your language model you'll need
more dropout if you have more data you
can benefit from less dropout you don't
want to regularize more than you have to
make sense right rather than having to
tune every one of these five things
right my claim is they're already pretty
good ratios to each other so just tune
this number I just multiply it all by
something okay
so there's really just one number you
have to choose so if you're overfitting
then you'll need to increase this number
if you're underfitting you'll need to
decrease this number because other than
that these ratio is actually seem pretty
good so one important idea which may
seem pretty minor but again it's
incredibly controversial is that we
should measure accuracy
when we look at a language model so
normally language models we look at this
this lost value which is just cross
entropy loss but specifically where you
nearly always take e to the power of
that which the NLP community calls
perplexity
okay so perplexity is just a ^ cross
entropy there's a lot of problems with
comparing things based on cross entropy
loss I'm not sure I've got time to go
into it in detail now but the basic
problem is that it's kind of like that
thing we learned about focal loss cross
entropy loss if you're right yet wants
you to be really confident that you're
right you know so it really penalized as
a model that doesn't kind of say like
I'm so sure this is wrong it's wrong
whereas accuracy doesn't care at all
about how confident you are this cop
cares about whether you're right and
this is much more often than the thing
which you care about in real life so
this accuracy is what how many how often
do we guess the next word correctly and
I just find that a much more stable
number to keep track of so so that's a
simple little thing that I do okay so so
we train for a while
and we get down to a 3.9 frost entropy
loss and if you go e ^ that
and to kind of give you a sense of like
what's happened with language models if
you look at academic papers from about
18 months ago you'll see them talking
about perplexities stayed at the our
complexities of like over a hundred okay
like the the the rate at which our
ability to kind of understand language
and I think like measuring language
model accuracy or perplexity is not a
terrible proxy for understanding
language if I can guess what you're
going to say next
it's you know I pretty much need to
understand language pretty well and also
the kind of things you might talk about
pretty well
so this numbers just come down so much
it's been amazing
NLP in the last 12 to 18 months
and it's going to come down a lot more
it really feels like 2011-2012 computer
vision you know we're just starting to
understand transfer learning and fine
tuning and these basic models are
getting so much so much better so
everything you thought about like what
NLP can and can't do it's very rapidly
going out of that like there's - lots of
stuff NLP is not good at to be clear
right just like in 2012 there was what's
the stuff computer vision wasn't good at
but it's changing incredibly rapidly and
now is a very very good time to be
getting very very good at NLP or
starting startups based on NLP because
there's a whole bunch of stuff which
computers would absolutely at two
years ago and now like not quite as good
of people and then next year they'll be
much better than people yeah two
questions one what is your ratio of
paper reading versus coding in a week
gosh what do you think Rachel you say me
I mean it's a lot more coding right it's
a lot more coding I feel like it also
really varies from week to week like I
feel like they're like with that
bounding box stuff you know that like
with that bounding box stuff there was
all these papers and no man through
and so I didn't even know which one to
read first and then I'd read the
citations and didn't understand any of
them and so there was a few weeks of
just kind of reading papers before I
even know what to start coding
that's unusual though like most of the
time I'm yeah I don't know
anytime I start reading a paper I'm
always convinced that I'm not smart
enough to understand it always
regardless of the paper and somehow
eventually I do but yeah I try to spend
as much time as I can
coding and then the second question is
your dropout rate the same through the
training or do you adjust it and the
weights accordingly I just say one more
thing about the last bit which is very
often like the vast majority nearly
always I after I've read a paper even
after I've read the bit that says this
is the problem I'm trying to solve I'll
kind of stop there and try to implement
something but I think might solve that
problem and then I'll go back and read
the paper and I read little bits about
like all these are how I solve these
problem bits and I'll be like oh that's
a good idea and then I'll try to
implement those and so like that's why
for example I didn't actually implement
SSD you know like my custom here is not
the same it's because I kind of read the
gist of it and then I tried to create
something best as I cord and then go
back to the papers and try to see why
and so so by the time I got to the focal
most paper Rachael will tell you I was
like driving myself crazy with like how
come I can't find small objects how come
it's always predicting background you
know I read the focal loss paper and I
was like that's why you know so like
it's so much better when you deeply
understand the problem they're trying to
solve and I do find the vast majority of
the time by the time I read that bit of
the paper which is like solving a
problem I'm then like yeah but these
three ideas I came up with they didn't
try you know and he suddenly realized
that you've got new ideas or else if you
just implement the paper you know
mindlessly it's you know you tend not to
have these insights about better ways to
do it
yeah um varying drop out is really
interesting and there are some recent
papers actually that suggest gradually
changing drop out and it was either a
good idea to gradually make it smaller
or gradually make it bigger I'm not sure
which let's try maybe one of us can try
and find it during the week I haven't
seen it widely used I tried it a little
bit with the most recent paper I wrote
and it I had some good results I think I
was graduating like you get smaller yeah
and then the next question is am I
correct in thinking that this language
model is built on word embeddings would
it be valuable to try this with phrase
or sentence embeddings I ask that I ask
this because I saw from Google the other
day universal sentence encoder yeah no
this is like this is much better than
that you like to shoot I mean like it
this is this is not just an embedding of
a sentence this is an entire model right
so an embedding by definition is like a
fixed thing oh I think they're asking
they're saying that this language well i
the first question is is this language
model built on word embedded yes but but
it's not saying it's a sentence or a
phrase embedding is always a model that
creates that right and we've got a model
that's like trying to understand
language it's not just as phrase it's
not just a sentence you know it's a it's
a document in the end and it's not just
an embedding that's we're training
through the whole thing so like this has
been a huge problem with NLP for years
now is this attachment they have to
embeddings and so even the the paper
that the community's been most excited
about recently from the from AI to the
Allen Institute called Elmo yo mo and
they found much better results across
lots of models but again it was an
embedding they took a fixed model and
created a fixed set of numbers which
they then fed into a model but in in
computer vision we've known for
is that that approach of having a fixed
fixed set of features
they're called hyper columns in in
computer vision people stopped using
them like three or four years ago
because fine-tuning the entire model
works much better right so for those of
you that have spent quite a lot of time
with NLP and not much time with computer
vision you're going to have to start
relearning right all that stuff you have
been told about this idea that there are
these things called embeddings and that
you learn them ahead of time and then
you apply these things whether it be
word level or phrase level or whatever
level don't do that all right you want
to actually create a pre trained model
and fine-tune it and to it then you'll
see some you'll see some specific
results all right so as you answer the
existing lines for using accuracy
instead of perplexity as a metric for
the model could we work that into the
loss function rather than just use it as
a metric no you never want to do that
whether it be computer vision or NLP or
whatever it's too bumpy right so first
have to be spying is a loss function and
other thing instead of I use it in
addition to you know I think it's good
to look at the accuracy and to look at
the cross entropy but for your loss
function you need something nice and
smooth accuracy doesn't work very well
you'll see there's two different
versions of save is save and save
encoder save saves the whole model as
per usual save encoder saves just that
bit right in other words in the
sequential model it saves just that bit
and not that bit in other words you know
this bit which is the bit that actually
makes it into a language model we don't
care about the classifier we just care
about that bit okay so that's why we
save two different models here
okay so let's now create the classifier
okay and I'm going to go through this
bit pretty quickly because it's the same
but like when you go back during the
week and look at the code convince
yourself it's the same right we do get
all P tiresias P again Chuck sighs again
get all again save those tokens again we
don't create a new I to s vocabulary we
obviously want to use the same
vocabulary we had in the language model
okay too because we're about to reload
the same encoder okay same default dict
same way of creating our Americanized
list which as per before we can save
okay so that's all the same later on we
can reload those rather than having to
rebuild them so all of our hacker
parameters are the same we're not all of
them sorry the construction of the modal
hyper parameters are the same we can
change the drop hat optimize a function
pick a batch size that is as big as you
can that doesn't run out of memory and
so this bits a bit interesting there's
some fun stuff going on here the basic
idea here is that for the classifier we
do really want to look at one you know
our document right we need to say is
this document positive or negative and
so we do want to shuffle the documents
right that's because we we like to
shuffle things but those documents are
different lengths and so if we stick
them all into one batch and this is a
handy thing that last AI does for you
you can stick things of different
lengths into a batch and it will
automatically pet them so you don't have
to worry about that okay but if they're
wildly different lengths then you're
going to be wasting a lot of computation
times then what you one thing there
that's 2,000 words long and everything
else 250 words long and that means you
end up with a 2005 tensor all right
that's pretty annoying
so James Bradbury who's actually one of
Stephen Rarity's colleagues and the guy
who came up with torch text
came up with a neat idea which was let's
sort the data set by length ish right so
kind of make it so the first things in
the list on the whole shorter and the
things at the end but a little bit
random as well okay and so I'll show you
how I implemented that so the first
thing we need is a data set right and so
we have a data set passing in the the
documents and their labels and so here's
a text data set and it inherits from
data data set here is data set from
torch from PI torch and actually data
set doesn't do anything at all it says
you need to get item and if you don't
have one you're gonna get an error
you need a length if you don't have one
you're gonna get an error okay so this
is an abstract class so we're going to
pass in our X we're going to pass in our
Y and get item is going to grab the X
and grab the Y and return them it
couldn't be much simpler right
optionally they could reverse it
optionally it could stick an end or
stream at the end optionally it started
beginning we're not doing any of those
things so literally all we're doing is
we're putting in an X putting in a way
and that grab an item we're returning
the X and the y as a couple
okay and the length is X yes so that
that's that's all the data sets right
something with a length that you can in
days so to turn it into a data loader
you simply pass the data set to the data
loader constructor and it's now going to
go ahead and give you a batch of that at
a time normally you can say shuffle
equals true or shuffle equals false
it'll decide whether to randomize it for
you in this case though we're actually
going to pass in a sample up perimeter
and the sampler is a class we're going
to define that tells the data loader
shuffle okay so for the validation set
we're going to define something that
actually just sorts right it just
deterministically sorts it so the that
all the shortest documents will be at
the start or the longest documents will
be at the end and that's going to
minimize the amount of padding okay for
the training sampler we're going to
create this thing I called a sort H
sampler which also sorts ish right so
this is where like I really like hi
torch is that they came up with this
idea for an API for their data loader
where we can like hook in new classes to
make it behave in different ways right
so here's a sort sampler but is simply
something which again it has a length
which is the length of the data source
and it has an iterator
which is simply an iterator which goes
through the data source sorted by length
well the key and I pass in as the key a
lambda function which returns the links
okay and so for the sort ish sampler I
won't go through the details but it
basically does the same thing with a
little bit of randomness okay so it's a
really beautiful you know just another
of these beautiful little design things
in pi torch that I discovered I could
take James Bradbury's ideas which he had
like written a whole new set of classes
around and I could actually just use the
inbuilt hooks inside Python you will
notice data loader it's not actually PI
tortoise data loader it's actually
faster ice data loader but it's
basically almost entirely plagiarized
from PI torch but customized in some
ways to make it faster mainly by using
multi-threading instead of multi
processing that's Rachel does the
pre-trained LS TM depth it'd be bt te to
match with the new one we're training no
no that the be PTT doesn't need to match
that's just like how many things do we
look at at a time it's about nothing to
do with the architecture okay so well
now we can call that function we just
wore before get our inane classifier
it's going to create exactly the same
encoder more or less okay and we're
going to pass in the same architectural
details as before but this time we can
the head that we add on you've got a few
more things you can do one is you can
you can add more than one hidden layer
so this layers here says this is what
the input to my classifier section my
head is going to be this is the output
of the first layer this is the output of
the second layer and you can add as many
as you like so you can basically create
a little multi-layer neural net
classifier at the end and so did oh
these are the dropouts to go after each
of these layers okay and then here are
all of the AWD lsdm dropouts which we're
going to basically plagiarize that idea
for our classifier we're going to use
the errand in learn oh just like before
we're going to use discriminative
learning rates different layers actually
this is a separate here you can try
using wait okay or not I've been
fiddling around a bit with that to see
what happens and so we start out just
training the last layer and we get
ninety two point nine percent accuracy
then we freeze one more layer unfreeze
one more layer get ninety three point
three accuracy and then we fine-tune the
whole thing and after three epochs
okay so this was so here is the famous
James pepperi we're talking about this
was kind of the main attempt before our
paper came along at using a pre train
model
and what they did is they used a pre
trained translation model but they
didn't fine tune the whole thing they
just took the the activations of the
translation model and when they tried
IMDB they got they got 91.8% which we
beat easily after only fine-tuning one
layer okay
they weren't state-of-the-art they're
the state of the art is 94.1 which we
beat after fine-tuning the whole thing
for three epochs and so by the end we're
at ninety four point eight which is
obviously a huge difference because like
in terms of error rate that's gone down
from from five point nine and then I'll
tell you a simple little trick is go
back to the start of this notebook and
reverse the order of all of the
documents and then rerun the whole thing
right and when you get to the bit that
says WT 103 replace this FWD before word
with PWD for backward
that's a backward english-language model
that learns to read English backwards so
if you redo this whole thing put all the
documents in Reverse and change this to
backward you now have a second
classifier which classifiers things by
positive or negative sentiment based on
the reverse document if you then take
the two predictions and take the average
of them
you basically have like a
directional model if you've trained each
bit separately that gets you to
ninety-five point four percent accuracy
okay so we can replace eclis load up
from five point nine to four point six
so this kind of like twenty percent
change in the state-of-the-art is it's
like it's almost unheard of you know
it's like you have to go back to like
Jeffrey Hinton's imagenet computer
vision thing where they drop like thirty
percent off the state-of-the-art like it
doesn't happen very often and so you can
see this idea of like just use transfer
learning it's ridiculously powerful that
every new feel thinks their new field is
too special and you can't do it right so
it's a big opportunity for all of us so
we turn this into a paper and when I say
we I did it with this guy Sebastian
Trudeau now you might remember his name
because in lesson five I told you that I
actually had shared lesson four with
Sebastian because I think he's a an
awesome researcher who I thought might
like it I didn't know him personally at
all and much to my surprise he actually
watched the damn video I was like what
you know what an LP research is gonna
watch some beginners video but he
watched the whole video he was like
that's actually quite fantastic that's
like fun thank you very much that's
awesome coming from you and he said hey
we should turn this into a paper and I
said I don't write papers I don't care
about papers are not interested in
papers that sounds really boring and he
said okay how about I write the paper
for you and I said you can't really
write a paper about this yet because
you'd have to do like studies to compare
it to other things they're called
oblation studies to see which if it's
actually work like there's no rigor here
I just put in everything that came in my
head and checked it all together and it
happened to work it's like okay what if
I write all the paper and all the
oblation studies then can we read the
paper and I said well
it's like a whole library that like I
haven't documented and like you know I'm
not going to yet and like you don't know
how it all works he said okay if I wrote
the paper and do the ablation studies
and figure out from scratch how the code
works without bothering you then can we
write the paper I was like yeah if you
did a whole thing the paper I was like
okay and so then two days later he comes
back he says okay I've done a draft with
a paper so I share this story to say
like if you're some you know student in
Ireland and you want to like do good
work don't did anybody stop you right I
did not encourage him at least right but
in the end it's like look I want to do
this work I think it's going to be good
and I'll figure it out and you know he
wrote a fantastic paper and he did the
ablation studies and he figured out how
fast I works and now we're planning to
write another paper together and so like
there's some you've got to be a bit
careful right cuz sometimes I get
messages from random people saying like
I've got lots of good ideas can we have
coffee I don't want to I don't you know
I can have coffee in my office any time
thank you
but it's very different to say like hey
I took your ideas and I wrote a paper
and I did a bunch of experiments and I
figured out how your code works they
added documentation to it you know sure
we could all submit this to a conference
you sort of mean like there's nothing to
stop you doing amazing work and if you
do amazing work that like helps somebody
else like in this case okay I'm happy
that we have a paper I don't care about
papers but I think it's cool that you
know these ideas now have this rigorous
study like let me show you what he did
so he took all my code right so I'd
already done all the faster I got text
and stuff like that and as you've seen
it lets us work with large corpuses so
you know Sebastian is fantastic
we well-read and he said here's a paper
that young lakorn some guys just came
out with where they tried lots of
different classification datasets so I'm
gonna try running your code on all these
data sets and so these are the data sets
right and so some of them had you know
many many hundreds of thousands of
documents and they were far bigger than
and I think I had tried but I thought it
should work okay and so you know he had
a few good little ideas as we went along
and so you should like totally make sure
you you read the paper write this paper
and he said well this thing that you
called in the lessons differential
learning rates differential kind of
means something else like maybe we
should rename it so it's now called
discriminative learning rate so this
idea that we had from part one where we
use different learning rates for
different layers after doing some
literature research it does seem like
that hasn't been done before so it's now
officially I think discriminative
learning rates and so all these ideas
like this is something we learnt in
Lesson one but it now has an equation
with Greek and everything okay so when
you see an equation with Greek and
everything that doesn't necessarily mean
it's more complex than anything we did
in Lesson one because this one isn't
again that idea of like I'm freezing a
layer at a time also it seems to never
do number four so it's now a thing and
it's got the very clever name gradual
I'm freezing so then one promised what
we're going to look at this slanted
triangular learning rates so this
actually was not my idea
Leslie Smith my favorite researchers who
you all now know about emailed me a
while ago and said I'm so over so
learning rates I don't do that anymore I
now do it's like a different version
where I have one cycle which goes up
quickly at the start and then slowly
down afterwards and he said I often find
it works better I've tried going back
over all of my old data sets and it
works better for all of them everyone
so this is what the learning rate looks
like right you can use it in fast AI
just by adding use CLR equals to your
fit this first number is the ratio
between the highest learning rate and
the lowest learning rate so here this is
1/32 of that the second number is the
ratio between the first peak and the
last peak and so the basic idea is if
you're doing a cycle length 10 that you
want the first cycle sorry the first
epoch to be the upward bit and the other
nine epochs to be the downward bit then
you would use 10 and I find that works
pretty well that was also Leslie
suggestion is make about a tenth of it
the upward bit and about my intense the
down would be since he told me about it
actually it was just maybe two days ago
he wrote this amazing paper a
disciplined approach to neural network
hyper parameters in which he describes
something very slightly different to
this again but the same basic idea this
is a must-read paper you know it's got
all the kinds of ideas that fast AI
talks about a lot in great depth and
nobody else is talking about this stuff
it's it's kind of a slog unfortunately
Leslie had to go away on a trip before
he really had time to edit it properly
so it's a little bit slow reading but
it's don't let that stop you it's
amazing so this triangle this is the
equation from my paper was the best year
and Sebastian was like Jeremy can you
send me the math equation behind that
poetry rotation if I just wrote the code
I could not get it into math so he
figured out the math for it so you might
have noticed the first layer of our
classifier was equal to embedding size x
3y times 3 times 3 because and again
this seems to be something which people
haven't done before so new idea concat
pooling
which is that we take the average pool
the average pooling over the sequence of
the activations the max pooling of the
sequence over the activations and the
final set of activations and just
concatenate them all together again this
is something which we talked about in
part one but doesn't seem to be in the
literature before so it's now called
Combe kept pulling and again it's now
got an equation and everything but this
is the entirety of the implementation
pull with average pull with max
concatenate those two along with the
final sequence so you know you can go
through this paper and see how the
faster I code implements each piece so
then to me one of the kind of
interesting pieces is the difference
between RNN and coda which you've
already seen and multi batch are in an
encoder so what's the difference there
okay so the key difference is that the
the normal RN an encoder for the
language model we could just do V PTT
chunk at a time right no problem and
predict the next book but for the
classifier we need to do the whole
document we need to do the whole movie
review before we decide if it's positive
or negative and the whole movie review
can easily be 2,000 words long and I
can't fit 2,000 words worth of you know
gradients in my GPU memory for every
single one of my activations well sorry
for every one of my weights so what do I
do
and so the idea was very simple which is
I go through my whole sequence length
one batch of BPT be PTT at a time right
and I call super dot forward so in other
words the eridan encoder all right so
just couldn't call the usual iron in
encoder to grab its outputs and then
I've got this maximum sequence length
parameter where it says okay
if you've as long as you're doing no
more than that sequence length then
start appending it to my list of outputs
okay so in other words the thing that it
sends back to this pooling is is only as
much there's only as many activations as
we've asked it to keep right and so that
way you can basically just figure out
how much
what's max SEC do you can your
particular GPU handle that so it's still
using the whole document but let's say
max SEC is a thousand thousand words and
your longest document length is two
thousand words right that it's still
going through the I am creating state
for those first thousand words right but
it's not actually going to store the
activations for the backdrop the first
thousand is only going to keep the last
thousand right so that means that it
can't back propagate the loss back to
any decisions that any state that was
created in the first thousand words you
know basically that's that's now gone so
it's a really simple piece of code you
know and honestly when I wrote it it was
like I didn't spend much time thinking
about it it seems so obviously the only
way that this could possibly work but
again it's it seems to be a new thing so
we now have back prop through time for
text classification yes I think so you
can see there's lots of little pieces in
this paper so what was the result right
and so the result was on every single
data set we tried we got a better result
than any previous academic for text
classification so IMDB trekked 6aj News
dbpedia Yelp all different types and
honestly IMDB was the only one I spent
any time trying to optimize the model so
like most of them
we just did it like whatever came out
first so if we actually spent time with
it I think this would be a lot better
that and the things that these are
comparing to most of them are like
you'll see like they're different on
each table because like they're
optimized you know these like customized
algorithms on the whole so this is
saying like one simple fine-tuning
algorithm can beat these really
customized algorithms and so here's the
like one of the really cool things that
Sebastian did was his ablation studies
all right which is I was really keen
that if you're going to publish a paper
we had to say why does it work right so
Sebastian went through and tried you
know removing all of those different
contributions I mentioned right so what
if we don't use gradual freezing what if
we don't use discriminative learning
rates what if instead of discriminating
rates we use cosign annealing what if we
don't do any pre training with Wikipedia
what if we don't do any fine tuning and
then the really interesting one to me
was what's the validation error rate on
IMDB if we only use a hundred training
examples this is 200 business 500 and
you can see you know very interestingly
the the full version of this approach is
nearly as accurate on just a hundred
training examples like it's still very
accurate versus for 20,000 training
examples we also if your training from
scratch on 100 it's like almost random
all right so kind of like it's what I
expected you know I've kind of said to
Sebastian I really think that this this
is most beneficial when you don't have
much data and this is like where fast a
is most interested in contributing right
there's like small data regimes small
compute regimes and so forth and so he
did these studies to check so I want to
show you a couple of tricks as to how
you can run these kinds
the first trick is is something which I
know you're all gonna find really handy
I know you're hoping annoyed when you're
running something in a Jeep and a
notebook and you lose your internet
connection for long enough that it
decides you've gone away and then your
session disappears and you have to start
it again from Spanish ok so what do you
do there's a very simple cool thing
called VNC where basically you can
install on your AWS instance or paper
space or whatever X Windows a
lightweight window manager a VNC server
firefox a terminal and some fonts chuck
these lines at the end of your VNC x
startup configuration file and then run
this command it's now running a server
where if you now run for it's now
running a server where you can then run
the type VNC viewer or any VNC viewer on
your computer and you point it at your
server right but specifically what you
do as you go you use SSH port forwarding
to port forward port five nine one three
to localhost five nine one three right
and so then you connect to port five
nine one three on on localhost
it will send it off to port five nine
one three on your server which is the
VNC port because you said : thirteen
here and it will display an X Windows
desktop and then you can click on the
Linux start like button and click on
Firefox and you now have Firefox and so
you can now run and you'll see here in
Firefox it says localhost because this
Firefox is running on my AWS server
right and so you now run Firefox you
start your thing running and then you
close your VNC viewer
remembering that Firefox is like
displaying on this virtual VNC display
not in the real display and so then
later on that day you log back into VNC
viewer and it flops up again so it's
like you're persistent desktop and it's
shockingly fast it works really well
okay so there's trick number one and
there's lots of different VNC servers
and clients and whatever but this one
works fine for me so there you go so you
can see here I connect to localhost five
nine one three trick number two is to
create Python scripts but this is what
we ended up doing so I ended up creating
like a little Python script for
Sebastian to kind of say this is the
basic steps you need to do and now you
need to create like different versions
certain thing else and I suggested to
him that he tried using this thing
called Google fire what Google fire does
is you create a function with shitloads
of parameters right and so these are all
the things that Sebastian wanted to try
doing different drop out amounts
different learning rates do I use pre
training or not do I use CLR or not do I
use discriminative learning rate or not
do I go backwards or not blah blah blah
right so you create a function and then
you add something saying if 9 equals
main fire dot fire
and the function name you do nothing
else at all you don't have to add any
metadata any docstrings anything at all
and you then call that script and
automatically you now have a command
that's it right so that's a super
fantastic easy way to run lots of
different variations in a terminal and
this is like this is ends up being
easier if you want to do lots of
variations than using a notebook because
you can just like have a bash script
that tries all of them and spits them
all out you're fine inside the dl2
course directory there's now something
called IMDB scripts and I've put there
all of the scripts that Sebastian and I
used so you'll see because we needed to
like tokenize every
or data set we had to turn every dataset
numerical eyes every data set we had to
train a language model on every data set
we had to train a classifier every data
set we have to do all of those things in
a variety of different ways to compare
them we have a script for all those
things so you can check out and see all
of the scripts that we used when you're
doing a lot of scripts and stuff they've
got different code all over the place
eventually it might get frustrating that
you want to you know you don't want a
symlink
you're faster yo library again and again
but you probably don't want to pip
install it because that version tends to
be a little bit old we move so fast you
want to use the current version in get
if you say pip install - a dot from the
fast AI repos base it does something
quite neat which is basically creates a
symlink - the faster a library to get
you know in your get installation right
here inside your site packages directory
your site packages directory is like
your main you know Python library and so
if you do this you can then access fast
AI from anywhere but every time you do
get pull you've got the most recent
version one downside of this is that it
installs any updated versions of
packages from Kipp which can kind of
confuse Condor a little bit so another
alternative here is just to Simla --nk
the FASTA a library to your site
packages library like that works just as
well and then you can use faster i'll
again from anywhere and it's quite handy
when you want to kind of run scripts
that use past AI from different
directories under system okay so one
more thing before we which is something
you can try if you like
you don't have to tokenize words instead
of tokenizing words you can tokenize
what are called sub word units and so
for example unsupervised
for example unsupervised quickly
tokenized his on supervised tokenizer
could be tokenized as token either right
and then you could do the same thing the
language model that works on sub units a
classifier that works on sub word units
etc so how well does that work I started
playing with it and with not too much
playing I was getting classification
results that were nearly as good as
using word level tokenization not quite
as good but nearly as good I suspect
with more careful thinking and playing
around maybe I could have got as good or
better but even if I couldn't if you
create a a sub word unit wikitext model
then IMDB model language model and then
classifier forwards and backwards force
upward units and then ensemble it with
the forwards and backwards word level
ones you should be able to beat us right
so here's an approach you may be able to
beat our state if ya was on Google has
as Sebastian told me about this
particular project is great Google has a
project called sentence peace which
actually uses a neural net to figure out
the optimal splitting up of words and so
you end up with a vocabulary of sub word
units in my planning around I found that
creating a vocabulary of about 30,000
sub word units seems to be about optimal
so if you're interested there's
something you can try
it's a bit of a pain to install it's C++
it doesn't have great error messages but
it will work
- like before it and if anybody tries to
so I'm happy to drop them get it working
there's been little if any experiments
with ensemble abroad and word level
stuff classification and I do think it
should be the best approach alright
thanks everybody
have a great week and see you next
Monday
[Applause]