welcome to the last lesson lesson 14
we're going to be looking at image
segmentation today amongst other things
but before we do a bit of show-and-tell
from last week
Elena Ali did something really
interesting which was she tried finding
out what would happen if you did cycle
gain on just three or 400 images and I
really like these projects where people
just go to Google Image Search you know
using the the API you're one of the
libraries out there some of our students
have created some very good libraries
for interacting with Google images API
download a bunch of stuff that they're
interested in in this case some photos
and some stained glass windows and yeah
with three or four hundred photos of
that she trained a model she trained
actually a few different models this is
what I particularly liked and as you can
see with quite a small number of images
you know she gets some very nice
stained-glass effects so I thought that
was a interesting example of yeah using
pretty small amounts of data that was
readily available that she was able to
download pretty quickly and there's more
information about that on the forum if
you're interested yeah it's it's
interesting to wonder about what kinds
of things people will come up with with
this kind of generative model it's
clearly a great artistic medium it's
clearly a great medium for forgeries and
bakeries I wonder what other kinds of
things before will realize they can do
with these kind of generative models I
think audio is going to be the next big
area and also very like interactive type
stuff that Nvidia I just released a
paper showing a interactive kind of
photo repair tour where you just like
brush over an object and it replaces it
with you know a deep learning generated
replacement very nicely those kinds of
interactive tools I think would be very
interesting too so before we talk about
segmentation we've got some stuff to
finish up from last time which is that
we look
at doing style transfer they actually
directly optimizing pixels and you know
like with most of the things in part two
it's not so much that I'm wanting you to
understand style transfer per se but the
kind of idea of optimizing your input
directly and using activations as part
of a loss function is really the key
kind of takeaway here so it's
interesting then to kind of see the
photos effectively the follow-up paper
you know not from the same people but
the paper that kind of came next in the
in the sequence of these kind of vision
generative models with this one from
Justin Johnson and folks at Stanford and
it it actually does the same thing style
transfer but it does it in a different
way rather than optimizing the pixels
we're going to go back to something much
more familiar and optimize some weights
and so specifically we're going to train
a model which learns to take a photo and
translate it into a photo on this in the
style of a particular artwork
so each ComNet will learn to produce one
kind of style now it turns out that
getting to that point there's an
intermediate point which is I actually
think kind of more more useful and Texas
halfway there which is something called
super resolution so we're actually going
to start with super resolution because
then we'll build on top of super
resolution to finish off the style
transfer ComNet based I'll transfer and
so super resolution is where we take a
low res image we're going to take 72 by
72 and upscale up to a larger image 288
by 288 in our case trying to create you
know a higher res image that looks as
real as possible and so this is a pretty
challenging thing to do because at 72
by 72 there's not that much information
about a lot of the details and the cool
thing is that we're going to do it in a
way as we tend to do with vision models
which is not tied to the input size so
you could totally then take this model
that and apply it to a 288 by 288 image
and get something that's four times
bigger on each side so 16 times bigger
than that and and often it even kind of
works better at that level because
you're really introducing a lot of a lot
of detail into the finer details and you
could really print out a high resolution
print of something which earlier on was
pretty big so later so this is the
notebook or enhance and it is a lot like
that kind of CSI style enhancement where
we're going to take something that
appears like the information is just not
there and we kind of invent it but the
confidence going to learn to invent it
in a way that's consistent with the
information that is there so hopefully
you know it's kind of inventing the
right information one of the really nice
things about this kind of problem is
that we can create our own data set as
big as we like without any labeling
requirements because we can easily
create a low res image from a high-res
image just by down sampling our images
so something I would love some of you to
try doing the week would be to through
other types of imaged image translation
where you can invent kind of late labels
invent your dependent variable for
example D skewing you know so either
recognize things that have been rotated
by 90 degrees or better still that have
been rotated by five degrees and
straighten them colorization so turn
make a bunch of images into
black-and-white and learn to put the
color back again noise reduction you
know maybe do a really low quality JPEG
save and learn to put it back to how it
should have been
and so forth or yeah maybe taking
something that's like in a 16 color
palette and put it back to a higher
color palette I think these things are
all interesting because they can like be
used to take you know pictures that you
may have taken back on crappy old
digital cameras before there are high
resolution or you may have scanned in
some old photos that kind of faded or
whatever you know I think it's really
useful thing to go to do and also it's
but it's a good project because it's
like really similar to what we're doing
here but different enough that you'll
come come across some interesting
challenges on the way I'm sure so I'm
going to use some imagenet again again
you don't need to use all of image net
at all I just happened to have it lying
around you can download the one percent
sample of image net from faster faster
they are you can use any set of pictures
you have lying around honestly and in
this case as I say we don't really have
labels per se so I just got a give
everything a label of zero just so we
can use it with our existing
infrastructure more easily now because
I'm in this case pointing at a folder
that contains all of image net I
certainly don't want to wait for all of
image net to finish to run an epoch so
here I'm just most of the time I would
set keep percent to like one or two
percent and then I just generate a bunch
of random numbers and then I just grab
those keeps those which are less than
0.02 and so that lets be quickly
subsample my rows all right so we're
going to use vgg 16 and vgg 16 is
something that we haven't really looked
at in this class but it's a very simple
very simple model where we take and
normal as you apply three-channel input
and we basically run it through a number
of 3x3 convolutions
and then from time to time we put it
through a 2x2 Maps pool and then we do a
few more 3x3 convolutions max Paul so on
so forth and then this is kind of our
backbone I guess and then we we don't do
an average pooling layer in a deputy of
average pooling layer after a few of
these we end up with this you know 7x7
grid as usual I think it's about 7 by 7
by 512 something like that and so rather
than average polling we do something
different which is reflect the whole
thing so that spits out a very long
vector of activations of size 7 times 7
times 512 memory says correctly and then
that gets fed into two fully connected
layers each one of which has 409 6
activations and then one more fully
connected layer which has however many
classes so if you think about it the
weight matrix here is huge it's you know
7 by 7 by 512 by 409 6 and it's because
of that weight matrix really that V gge
went out of favor pretty quickly because
it takes a lot of memory and takes a lot
of computation and it's really slow and
there's a lot of redundant stuff going
on here because really those 512
activations are not that specific to
which of those 7x7 grid cells they're in
right but when you have this entire
weight matrix here of every possible
combination it treats all of them
uniquely right and so that'll can also
lead to generalization core ones because
there's just a lot of weights and so
forth
my view is that there's you know that
the approach that's used in every modern
Network which is here we do an adaptive
average pulling care ask that we be
known as a global average calling for in
fast AI we didn't really do a concat
adaptive concat pooling which spits it
straight down to a 512 long activation
I think that's throwing away too much
geometry so to me probably the correct
answer is somewhere in between and will
involve some kind of um factored
convolution or some kind of tensor
decomposition which yeah maybe some of
us can think about in the coming months
so for now anyway we've gone from one
extreme which is the adaptive average
pulling to the other extreme which is
this huge flattened collocation player
so a couple of things which are
interesting about vgg that make it still
useful today the first one is that
there's there's more interesting layers
going on here with with most modern
networks including the resident family
we the very first layer generally is a
seven by seven pawns or something
similar which means we and that's tried
to right which means we throw away half
the grid size straight away and so this
little opportunity to use the the fine
detail because we never do any
computation with it and so that's a bit
of a problem for things like
segmentation or super resolution models
because the fine detail matters right we
actually want to restore it and then the
second problem is that the adaptive
average polling layer entirely throws
away the geometry in the last few
sections which means that the rest of
the moral doesn't really have as much
interesting kind of learning that
geometry is it otherwise might and so
therefore for things which dependent on
position any kind of localization based
approach tor anything that requires
generative model
is going to be less effective so one of
the things I'm hoping you're hearing is
I describe this is that probably none of
the existing architectures are actually
ideal we can invent a new one then
actually I just tried inventing a new
one over the week which was to take the
the vgg head and attach it to a resonate
that one and interestingly I found I
actually got a slightly better
classifier than a normal ResNet but it
also was something with a little bit
more useful information you know it took
I don't know five or ten percent longer
to Train but nothing worth worrying
about yeah I think you know maybe we
couldn't in Resident replace this as
we've talked about briefly before this
very early convolution with something
more like an inceptions dam which has a
bit more computation I think there's
definitely room for some nice little
tweaks to these architectures so that we
can build some models which are maybe
more versatile you know at the moment
people tend to build architectures that
just do one thing they don't really
think you know what am i throwing away
in terms of opportunity because that's
that's how publishing works you know you
published like they've got the state of
the art and this one thing rather than
you have created something that's good
at lots of things so um so for these
reasons we're going to use vgg today
even though it's it's ancient and it's
missing lots of great stuff one thing we
are going to do though is use a slightly
more modern version which is a version
of vgg where batch norm has been added
after all the convolutions and so in
fast AI actually when you ask for a vgg
Network you always get the best norm one
because that's basically always what you
want so this is actually very Gigi with
batch mode and there's a 16 in the 19
the 19 is way bigger and heavier and
doesn't really is really any better so
we no one really uses it okay so we're
going to go from 72 by 72 LR is low
resolution input size low resolution
we're going to initially scale it up by
x 2 we're the batch size of 60
or to get a two times 72 so one by 44 by
144 output so that's gonna be our stage
stage one we'll create our own data set
for this and the data set it's very
worthwhile looking inside the faster I
dot data set module and seeing what's
there because just about anything you'd
want we probably have something that's
almost what you want so in this case I
want a data set where my X's are images
and my y's also images so there's
already a files data set we can inherit
from where the x's are images and then i
just inherit from that and i just copied
and pasted the get x and turn that into
get y so i just opens an image so now
I've got something where that X is an
image and the y is an image and in both
cases what we're passing in is an array
of flower names I'm going to do some
data augmentation obviously with all of
image net we don't really need it but
this is mainly here for you know anybody
who's using smaller data sets to make
the most of it
random dihedral is referring to every
possible 90-degree rotation and plus
optional left/right flipping so though
the dihedral group of eight symmetries
normally we don't use this
transformation for image net pictures
because like you don't normally flip
blobs upside down but in this case we're
not trying to classify whether it's a
dog or a cat we're just trying to keep
the general structure of it
so actually you know every possible flip
is a reasonably sensible thing to do for
this problem so a creative validation
set in the usual way
and you can see I'm kind of like using a
few more slightly lower level functions
generally speaking I just copy and paste
them out of the faster source code to
you know find the bits I want so here's
the bit which takes an array of
validation set indexes and one or more
arrays of variables and simply splits so
in this case the
into a training and a validation set and
this into a training novella bit sorry
it yeah the training validation set you
give us our X's and our whites now in
this case the Train are the X and the y
at the same import image and our output
image of the same we're going to use
transformations to make one of them
lower resolution so that's why these are
the same the same thing okay so the next
thing that we need to do is to create
our transformations as per usual and
we're going to use this transform Y
parameter like we did for bounding boxes
but rather than use transform type dot
coordinate we're going to use transform
type pixel and so that tells our
transformations framework that your Y
values are images with normal pixels in
them and so anything you do the X you
also need to do so the way do the same
thing okay
and you need to make sure any data
augmentation transforms you use have the
same parameter as well okay so you can
see the possible transform types you
basically you've got classification
which we're about to use the
segmentation in the second half of today
coordinates no transformation at all or
pixel alright so once we've got a
dataset class and some X&amp;Y training and
validation sets there's a handy little
method called get datasets which
basically runs that constructor over all
the different things that you have to
return all the datasets you need in
exactly the right format to pass pass to
a model data constructor as a
constructor in this case the image data
constructor so we're kind of like going
back under the covers of fast AI a
little bit and building it up from
scratch and you know in the next few
weeks this will all be wrapped up and
refactored into something that you can
do in a single step in fast AI but the
point of this
is to learn you know a bit about going
under the covers
so something we've briefly seen before
is that when we take images in we
transform them not just the data
augmentation that we also move the
channels dimension up to the start we
subtract the mean divided by the
standard deviation whatever so if we
want to be able to display those
pictures that have come out of our data
sets or data loaders we need to
denormalize them and so the model data
objects data set has ad norm function
that knows how to do that so I'm just
going to give that a short name for
convenience so now I'm going to create a
function that can show an image from a
data set and if you pass in something
saying this is a normalized image then
won'ting on it okay so we can go ahead
and have a look at that you'll see here
we've passed in size low-res as our size
for the transforms and size high-res as
this is something new the size Y
parameter okay so the two bits are going
to get different sizes and so here you
can see the two different resolutions of
our X and our Y for a whole bunch of
fish okay as you know as per usual plot
subplots to create our two plots and
then we can just use the different axes
that came back to the stuff next to each
other so we can then have a look at a
few different versions of the data
transformation and there you can see
them being clicked in all different
directions okay
so let's create our model so we're going
to have an image coming in small image
coming in and we want to have a big
image coming out and so we need to do
some computation
between those two to calculate what the
big image would look like and so
essentially there's kind of two ways of
doing that computation we could first of
all do some up sampling and then do a
few straight one kind of layers to do
lots of computation or we could first do
lots of straight one layers to do other
computation and then at the end do some
up sampling we've got to pick the second
approach because we want to do lots of
computation on something smaller because
it's much faster to do it that way and
also like all that computation we get to
kind of leverage during the up sampling
process so that's sampling we know a
couple of possible ways to do that we
can use transposed or fractionally
straited convolutions or we can use
nearest neighbor up sampling followed by
a one by one conf and then in in the
kind of do lots of computation section
we could just have a whole bunch of 3x3
coms right but in this case particular
it seems likely that ResNet blocks are
going to be better because really the
output and the input are very very
similar right so we really want a kind
of a flow through path that allows as
little fussing around as possible except
kind of a minimal amount necessary to do
our super resolution and so if we use
ResNet blocks then they have an identity
path already right so like you can
imagine the most simple version where it
does like a you know bilinear sampling
kind of approach or something it could
basically just go through identity box
all the way through and then in the up
sampling blocks just learn to take the
averages of the inputs and get something
that's like not too terrible so that's
what we're going to do we're going to
create something with five ResNet blocks
and then
for each 2x scale-up we have to do we'll
have 1/2 sampling look so they're all
going to consist of obviously as per
usual convolution layers possibly with
activation functions after many of them
so I kind of like to put my standard
convolution block into a function so I
can refactor it more easily as per usual
I just won't worry about passing in
padding and just calculate it directly
as kernel size over two so one
interesting thing about a little comic
block here is that there's no that's not
which is pretty unusual for ResNet type
models and the reason there's no batch
norm it because I'm stealing ideas from
this fantastic recent paper which
actually won a recent competition in
super resolution performance and to see
how good this paper is here's kind of a
previous state of the art there's SR
ResNet right and what they've done here
is they've zoomed way in to a an up
sampled kind of natural or fence this is
the original and you can see in the kind
of previous best approach there's a
whole lot of distortion and blurring
going on right or else in their approach
it's it's nearly perfect alright so like
it was a really big step up this paper
they call their model EDS are enhanced
deep residual networks and they did two
things differently to the kind of
previous standard approaches one was to
take the ResNet blocks this is a regular
resident block and throw away the better
not so why would they throw away the
veteran or well the reason they would
throw away the batch norm is because
batch norm changes stuff and we want a
nice straight through path that doesn't
change stuff okay so the idea basically
here is like hey if you don't want to
fit all with the input more than you
have to then don't force it to have to
calculate things like batching on
parameters so throw away the
and the second trick we'll see shortly
alright so here's a con with no batch
norm and so then we're going to create a
residual block containing as per usual
two convolutions and as you see in their
approach they'd even they don't even
have a rail you after their second conf
okay so that's why I've only got
activation on the first one so a couple
of interesting things here one is that
this idea of like having some kind of
main ResNet path like conv relia cons
and then turning that into a rail you
block by adding it back to the identity
it's something we do so often I kind of
factored it out into a tiny little
module called res sequential which
simply takes a bunch of layers that you
want to put into your residual path
turns that into a sequential model runs
it and then adds it back to the input
right so with this tat all module we can
now turn anything like conf activation
cons into a resonate lock just by
wrapping it in res sequential okay but
that's not quite all I'm doing because
like normally a res block just has that
and it's forward but I've also got that
what's risco Briscoe is the number zero
point one why is it there I'm not sure
anybody quite notice but the short
answer is that the guy who invented
batch norm also somewhat more recently
did a paper in which he showed for I
think the first time the ability to
Train imagenet in under an hour
and the way he did it was fire up lots
and lots of machines and have them work
in parallel to create really large batch
sizes now generally when you increase
the batch size by order n
you also increase the learning rate by
order n to go with it so generally a
very large batch size training means
very high learning rate training as well
and he found that with these very large
batch sizes of like 8,000 plus or even
up to 32,000 that at the start of
training his activations would basically
go straight to infinity and a lot of
other people have found that we actually
found that when we were competing in
dawn bench both on the sofa and the
imagenet competitions that you know we
really struggled to make the most of
even the eight GPUs that we were trying
to take advantage of because of these
kind of challenges with these larger
batch sizes and taking advantage of them
so something that a Christian found this
research was that if he in the ResNet
blocks if he multiplied them by some
number smaller than one something like
point one or point two it really helped
stabilize training start and that's kind
of weird because let mathematically it's
kind of identical right because
obviously whatever I'm multiplying it by
here you know I could just scale the
weights by the opposite amount here and
have the same number okay so but it's
kind of like we're not dealing with
abstract math you know we're dealing
with like you know real optimization
problems and different initializations
and learning rates and whatever else and
so the problem of kind of whites
disappearing off into infinity
I guess generally is really about that
they're kind of the discrete and finite
nature of computers in in practice
partly and so often
yeah these kind of little tricks can can
make the difference alright so in this
case we're just kind of toning things
down based at least based on our initial
initialization and so there probably
other ways to do this for example one
approach from some folks at Nvidia
called Lars le RS which I briefly
mentioned last week is an approach which
uses discriminative learning rates
calculated in real time basically
looking at the ratio between the
gradients and the activations to scale
all learning rates by layer and so they
found that they didn't need this trick
to scale it scale up the batch sizes a
lot maybe a different initialization
which would be all that's necessary the
reason I mentioned this is not so much
because I think a lot of you are likely
to want to train on massive clusters of
computers but rather that I think a lot
of you want to train models quickly and
that means using high learning rates and
ideally getting super convergence and I
think these kinds of tricks are the
tricks that we'll need to be able to get
super convergence across more different
architectures and so forth
and you know other than Leslie Smith no
one else is really working on super
convergence other than some fast AI
students nowadays so these kind of
things about how do we train at very
very high learning rates we're going to
be have to be the ones who figure it out
because as far as I can tell nobody else
cares yet so so I think you know looking
at the literature around you know
training imagenet in one hour or more
recently there's now a train image net
in 15 minutes these papers actually tell
I think have some of the tricks to allow
us to train things at home learning
rates and so here's one of them and so
interestingly other than the train image
net1 our paper the only other place I've
seen this mentioned was in this PDS our
paper and it's really cool because like
I know people who win competitions I
just find them to be very pragmatic and
well-read you know lucky they actually
have to get things to work and so this
paper describes an approach which
actually worked better than anybody
else's approach and they did these
pathetic things like throw away batch
norm and use this little scaling factor
which almost nobody seems to know about
and stuff like that ok
so that's where the point one comes from
so basically our super-resolution ResNet
is down and do a convolution to go from
our three channels to 64 channels just
to rich nut the space a little bit then
also we've got actually a cannot 5h lots
of these res blocks and we're just going
to keep remember every one of these res
blocks is strike one so the grid size
doesn't change the number of filters
doesn't change it's just 64 all the way
through well do one more convolution and
then we'll do our app sampling by
however much scale we asked for and then
something I've added which is a little
idea is just one batch norm here because
it kind of felt like it might be helpful
just to scale the last layer and then
finally a comb to go back to the three
channels we want so you can see that's
basically here's lots and lots of
computation and then a little bit of our
sampling just like we kind of described
so the only other piece here then is and
I also just dimension you know as you
can see as I'm tending to do now this
whole thing is done by creating just a
list with layers and then at the end
turning that into a sequential model and
so my forward function is as simple as
can be so here's our app sampling and up
sampling is a bit interesting because it
is not doing either of these two things
so let's talk a bit about up sampling
here is a picture from the paper from
not from the competition winning paper
but from this original paper and so
they're saying hey our approach is so
much better but look at their approach
it's got goddamn artifacts in it alright
these just pop up everywhere and so one
of the reasons for this is that they use
transposed convolutions and we all know
don't use transposed convolutions okay
so here are transposed convolutions this
is from this fantastic convolutional
arithmetic paper that was shown also in
the Theano Docs if we're going from the
blue is the original image so 3x3 image
up to a 5x5 image right or a 6x6 if we
added a layer of padding then all a
transpose convolution does is it uses a
regular 3x3 cons but it sticks white you
know zero pixels between every pair of
pixels alright so that makes the input
image bigger and when we run this
convolution life over it therefore gives
us a larger output okay but I mean
that's obviously stupid because when we
get here for example of the nine pixels
coming in eight of them a zero so like
we're just wasting a whole lot of
computation and then on the other hand
if we're slightly off over here then
four of our nine and on zero but yet we
only have one filter like one kernel to
use so it can't like change depending on
how many zeros are coming in so it has
to kind of be suitable for both and it's
just not possible right so we end up
with these artifacts so one approach
we've learnt to make it a bit better is
to not put white things here but instead
to copy this pixels value to each of
these three locations alright so that's
a just a nearest neighbor up sampling
that's certainly a bit better all right
but it's still pretty crappy because now
still when we get to these nine here
four of them are exactly the same number
all right and when we move across one
then now we've got you know a different
situation entirely right and so to
on where we are so in particular if
we're here you know there's going to be
a lot less repetition so again we have
this problem where there's like wasted
computation and too much structure in
the data and it's going to lead to RFS
again so up sampling is better than
transposed convolutions it's you know
better to copy them rather than replace
them with zeros but it's still not quite
good enough so instead we're gonna do
the pixel shuffle so the pixel shuffle
is an operation in this sub pixel
convolutional neural network and it's a
little bit mind-bending but it's kind of
fascinating and so we start with our
input we go through some convolutions to
create some feature Maps for a while
until eventually we get to layer and I
we go to this layer I minus one which
has n I minus one feature Maps we're
going to do another 3x3 cons and our
goal here is to go from a 7x7 grid cell
we're going to go a 3x3 up scaling so
we're going to go up to a 21 by 21 grid
cell so how do we what's another way we
could do that to make it simpler let's
just pick one face just one filter so
we'll just take the topmost filter and
just do a convolution over that just to
see what happens and what we're going to
do is we're going to use a convolution
where the kernel size is is the number
of filters is nine times bigger than we
strictly speaking need so if we needed
64 filters
we're actually going to do 64 times nine
filters why is that right and so uh here
are is the scale effect uh so three
right so a squared 3 squared is 9 so
here are the nine filters to cover one
of these input layers one of these input
slices
but what we can do is we started with
seven by seven and we turn it into seven
by seven by nine right well the output
that we want is equal to 7 times 3 by 7
times 3 so in other words there's an
equal number of pixels here activations
here as there are our activations here
so we can literally reshuffle these
seven by seven by nine activations to
create this 7 by 3 by 7 by 3 Matt and so
what we're going to do is we're going to
take one little kind of tube here on the
top left hand of each grid and we're
going to put the purple one up in the
top left and then the blue one one to
the right and then the light blue one
one to the right of that and then the
slightly darker blue one and the middle
of the far left the green one in the
middle and so forth so each of these
nine cells in the top left are going to
end up in this little 3x3 section of our
grid and then we're going to take you
know 2 comma 1 and take all of those 9
and move them to these 3 by 3 part of
the grid and so on and so forth right
and so we're going to end up having
every one of these 7 by 7 by 9
activations inside this 7 by 3 by 7 by 3
image so the first thing to realize is
yes of course this works under some
definition of works because we have a
learn herbal convolution here and it's
going to get some gradients which is
going to do the best job it can of
filling in the correct activation such
that this output is the thing we want
alright so the first step is to realize
there's nothing particularly magical
here you know we can we can create any
architecture we like we can move things
around any how we want to and you know
our wipes in the convolution will do
their best to do all we asked the real
question is is it
good idea you know is this an easier
thing for it to do you know and a more
flexible thing for it to do then the
transposed convolution or the up
sampling followed by one by one month
and the short answer is yes it is and
the reason it's better in short is that
the convolution here is happening in the
low resolution seven by seven space
which is quite efficient where else if
we first of all up sampled and then did
our cons then our con would be happening
in the 21 by 21 space which is a lot of
computation right and furthermore as we
discuss there's a lot of replication in
redundancy in the nearest neighbor
sample version so they actually show in
this paper they actually in fact I think
they have a follow-up technical note
where they kind of provide some more
mathematical details as to exactly what
work is being done and show that the
work really is more efficient this way
okay so that's what we're going to do
all right so we're going to have for our
app sampling we have two steps the first
will be a three by three cons with R
squared times more channels than we
originally wanted and then a pixel
shuffle operation which moves everything
in each grid cell into the little by our
grids that are located throughout here
okay so here it is it's one line of code
right and so here's the cons from number
of in to number of filters out times
four because we're doing a scale to that
sample all right so two squared is four
so that's our convolution and then here
is our pixel shuffle it's built into
high touch pixel shuffle is the thing
that moves each thing into its right
spot so that will increase will up
sample by a scale factor of two and so
we need to do that log base two scale
time
so if scale is for two times to go two
times two you go okay so that's what
this up sample here does great guess
what that does not get rid of the
checkerboard patterns we still have
checkerboard patterns so I'm sure in
great fury and frustration this same
team from Twitter I think this is back
when they used to be at a startup called
magic Pony that Twitter thought came
back again with another paper saying
okay this time we've got rid of the
checkerboard okay so so why do we still
have as you can see here you still have
a checkerboard right and so the reason
we still have a checkerboard even after
doing this is that when we randomly
initialize this convolutional kernel at
the start it means that each of these
nine pixels in this little 3x3 grid over
here are going to be totally randomly
different but then the next set of three
pixels will be randomly different to
each other but will be very similar to
their corresponding pixel in the
previous 3x3 section so we're going to
have repeating 3x3 things all the way
across and so then as we try to learn
something better it's starting from this
like repeating 3x3 starting point which
is not what we want right what we
actually would want is for these three
by three pixels to be the same to start
with so to make these three by three
pixels the same we would need to make
these nine channels the same here right
for each filter and so the solution and
his paper is very simple it's that when
we initialize this convolution that
start when we randomly initialize it we
don't totally randomly initialize it we
randomly initialize one of the
the r-squared sets of channels and then
we copy that to the other R squared so
they're all the same and that way
initially each of these three by threes
will be the same and so that is called I
CNN okay and that's what we're going to
use in a moment so before we do let's
take a quick look so we've got this
super resolution resinate which just
does lots of computation you know with
lots of ResNet blocks and then it does
some up sampling and gets our final
three channels out and then to make life
faster we're going to run this in
parallel one reason we want to run it in
parallel is because Jurado told us that
he has six GPUs and this is what his
computer looks like right now and so I'm
sure anybody who has more than one GPU
has had this experience before so how do
we get how do we get these men working
in together all you need to do is to
take your PI torch module and wrap it
with N n data parallel okay and once
you've done that it copies it to each of
your GPUs and will automatically run it
in parallel it scales pretty well done
to two GPUs okay to three GPUs better
than nothing to four GPUs and beyond
that performance does two go backwards
the by default it will copy it to all of
your GPUs you can add an array of GPUs
otherwise if you want to avoid getting
in trouble for example I have to share
our box with you net and if I didn't put
this here then she would be yelling at
me right now well maybe you know or
according my plus so this is how you
avoid getting into trouble with you net
so one thing to be aware of here is that
once you do this it actually modifies
your module so if you now print out your
module let's say previously it was
just an endless sequential now you'll
find it's an N in dots as Crenshaw
embedded inside a module called module
right and so in other words if you save
something which you had n end updated
paralleled and then tried and load it
back into something that you hadn't and
end up beta paralleled it'll say it
doesn't match up because one of them is
embedded inside this module attribute
and the other one isn't it may also
depend even on which GPU IDs you have
had a coffee too
so two possible solutions one is don't
save the module M but instead save the
module attribute m dot module because
that's actually the the non data
parallel bit or always put it on the
same GPU IDs and then use data parallel
and load and save that every time that's
what I was using this will be an easy
thing for me to fix automatically in
fast AI and I'll do it pretty soon so
it'll look for that module attribution
and deal with it automatically but for
now we have to do it manually it's
probably useful to know what's going on
behind the scenes anyway alright so
we've got our module you know I find it
overrun like 50 or 60 percent faster on
a 1080 TI if you're running on voltar it
actually paralyzes a bit better there's
a there much faster ways to parallel
parallel lives but this is like a super
super easy way all right so we created
our learner in the usual way we could
use MSA loss here so that's just going
to compare the pixels of the output to
the pixels you know that we expected and
we can run our learning rate finder and
we can train it for awhile and here's
our input and here's our output and you
can see that what we've managed to do is
to train a very advanced residual
convolutional net work that's learnt to
blur things why is that well because
it's what we asked for we said to
minimize MSE loss right an MSA lost
between pixels really the best way to
that is just average the pixels I eat a
blur so that's why pixel lusts no good
so we want to use our perceptual loss so
let's try perceptual us right
so with perceptual loss we're basically
going to take our vgg network and just
like we did last week we're going to
find the block index just before we get
a max ball okay so here are the ends of
each kind of block of the same grid size
and if we just print them out as we'd
expect every one of those is a value
module and so in this case these last
two blocks are less interesting to us
they're kind of the grid size there is
small enough you know kind of coarse
enough that it's not as useful for super
resolution so we're just going to use
the first three and so just to save
unnecessary computation we're just going
to use those first 23 layers or vgg
we'll throw a way to look at the rest
we'll stick it on the GPU we're not
going to be training this speech EG
model at all we're just using it to
compare activations so we'll stick it in
eval mode and we will set it to not
trainable okay just like last week we
will use a save features class to
through a forward hook which saves the
output activations at each of those
layers and so now we've got everything
we need to create our perceptual loss so
as I call it here feature loss plus
right and so we're going to pass in a
list of layer IDs
you know the layers where we want the
content loss to be calculated and array
of weights a list of weights for each of
those layers so we can just go through
each of those layer IDs and create an
object which is going to store which is
you know I've got the book function
forward hook function to store the
activations and so in our forward then
we can just go ahead and call the
forward pass of our model with the
target so the target is the hi
whereas image we're trying to create
okay and so the reason we do that is
because that's going to then call that
book function and store in soft
save features the activations we want
right now we're going to need to do that
for our confident output as well right
so we need to clone these because
otherwise the confident output is going
to go ahead and just plop up what I
already had
okay so now we can do the same thing for
the confident output which is the input
to the loss function and so now we've
got those two things we can zip them all
together along with the weights so we've
got inputs targets and weights and then
we can do the l1 loss between the inputs
and the targets and multiply by the
layer weights the only other thing I do
is I also grab the pixel loss right but
I weight it down quite a bit okay and
most people don't do this I haven't seen
papers that do this but in my opinion
it's maybe a little bit better because
you've got you know the perceptual
content lost activation stuff but you
know the really finest level it also
cares about the individual pixels okay
so that's our last function we create
our super resolution ResNet telling it
how much to scale up by and then we're
going to do our I see in our
initialization of that pixel shuffle
convolution right so there's really like
it's this is very very boring code I
actually stole it from from somebody
else like literally all it does is just
say okay you've got some weight tensor X
that you want to initialize so we're
going to treat it as if it had shape
divided by so number of features divided
by scale squared features in practice so
like you know this might be 2 squared
before because we actually want to copy
you know we want to just keep
set with them and then copy them four
times so we divide it by four and we
create something of that size and we
initialize that with by default timing
normal initialization and then we just
make scale squared copies of it okay and
the rest of its just kind of moving axes
around a little bit all right so that's
kind of return a new weight matrix where
each each initialized sub kernel is
repeated R squared or scale squared
times so that details don't matter very
much all that matters here is that I
just looked through to find what was the
actual layer the cone flower just before
the pixel shuffle and stored it away and
then I called I see an R on its weight
matrix to get my new weight matrix and
then I copied that new weight matrix
back into that layer ok so as you can
see I went to quite a lot of trouble in
this exercise to really try to implement
all the best practices right and I kind
of tend to do things a bit one extreme
or the other I show you like a really
happy version that only slightly works
or I go to the enth degree to make it
work really well right and so this is a
version where I'm claiming that this is
pretty much a state of the art
implementation it's a competition
winning or at least my reimplementation
of a competition winning approach and
the reason I'm doing that is because I
think like this is one of those rare
papers where they actually get a lot of
the details right and I kind of want you
to get a feel of what does it feel like
to get all the details right and you
know remember getting the details right
is the difference between this hideous
blurry mess you know and this really
pretty exquisite result okay so so we're
gonna have a to do potato parallel on
that again we're going to set our
criterion to be feature loss using our
vgg model grab the first few blocks and
these are assets of layer weights that I
found worked pretty
well do a learning rate finder fit it
for a while and I fiddled around for a
little while trying to kind of get some
of these details right but here's the my
favorite part if the paper is what
happens next now that we've done it for
scale equals to progressive resizing
right so progressive resizing is the
trick that let us get the best single
computer result for image net training
on one bench it's this idea of starting
small gradually making bigger I only
know of two papers that have used this
idea one is the progressive resizing of
gans paper which allows training a very
high resolution gains and the other one
is the ideas are and the cool thing
about progressive resizing is not only
are your earlier epochs assuming you've
got two by two smaller four times faster
you can also make the batch size maybe
three or four times bigger but more
importantly they're going to generalize
better because you're feeding your model
different sized images during training
right so we were able to Train like half
as many epochs for imagenet as most
people so our epochs were faster and
they were fewer of them so progressive
resizing is something that you know
particularly if your training from
scratch I'm not so sure if it's useful
for fine-tuning transfer learning but if
you're training from scratch you
probably want to do nearly all the time
so the next step is to go all the way
back to the top right and change to full
scale thirty-two batch size right like
restart so I saved the model before I do
that go back and that's why there's a
little bit of fussing around in here
with reloading because what I needed to
do now is I needed to load my saved
model back in but there's a slight issue
which is I now have one more up sampling
layer than I used to
have to go from two by two to four by
four my little my little loop here is
now looping through twice not once
and therefore it's added an extra
convent an extra pixel shuffle so how am
I going to load in weights for a
different network and the answer is that
I use a very handy thing in pi torch
which is if I call that this is what
this is basically what learned load
calls behind the scenes load state
kicked if I pass this parameter strict
equals false if I pass in this parameter
strict equals false that it says okay if
you can't fill in all of the layers just
fill in the lay as you can so after
loading the model back in this way we're
going to end up with something where
it's loaded in all the layers that it
can and that one comp layer that's new
is going to be randomly initialized all
right and so then I freeze all my layers
and then unfreeze that upsampling part
right and then use I CNR on my newly
added extra layer right and then I can
go ahead and wear again and so then the
rest is the same so if you're trying to
replicate this don't just run this top
to bottom
okay realize it involves a bit of
jumping around okay yeah the longer you
train the better it gets
I ended up training it for about 10
hours but you'll still get very good
results much more quickly if you're less
patient and so we can try it out and
here is the result here is my pixelated
bird and look here it's like totally
random e pixels and here's the upsampled
version it's like it's literally
invented color it coloration but it
figured out what kind of bird it is
right and it knows what the
feathers are metal look like and so it
has imagined a set of feathers which are
compatible with these exact pixels which
is like genius like saying here at
there's no way you can tell what these
blue dots are meant to represent but if
you know that this kind of bird has an
array of feathers here you know that's
what they must be right and then you can
figure out where the feathers would have
to be such that when they were pixelated
they'd end up in these pots all right so
it's like literally reverse engineered
like given its knowledge of this exact
species of bird how it would have to
have looked to create this output and so
this is like so amazing it also knows
from all the kind of signs around it
that this area here was was almost
certainly blurred out so it's actually
reconstructed blurred vegetation and you
know if it if it hadn't have done all of
those things it wouldn't have got such a
good loss function right because in the
end it had to match you know the
activations saying like oh there's a
feather over here and it's kind of
fluffy looking and it's you know in this
direction and all that all right well
that brings us to the end of super
resolution don't forget to check out the
ask Jeremy anything's threaded and we
will do some Astro me anything after the
break but see you back here a quarter to
eight
okay so we are going to do ask Jeremy
anything
Rachel will tell me the most voted up of
your questions yes Rachel what are the
future plans for fast AI in this course
will there be a part three if there is a
part three I would really love to take
it oh I'm not quite sure I always had to
guess I hope there'll be some kind of
follow-up last year after part two one
of the students started up a weekly book
club going through the Ian Goodfellow
deep learning book and Ian actually came
in and presented quite a few of the
chapters and other people like there's
somebody an expert who presented every
chapter that was really that was like a
really cool part three and four that
extended will depend on I'm you the
community to come up with ideas and help
make them happen and yeah and I'm
definitely keen to to help I've got a
bunch of ideas but I'm nervous about
saying them because I'm not sure which
ones will happen and which ones won't
but the more support I have in making
things happen that you want to happen
from you the more likely they are what
was your experience like starting down
the path of entrepreneurship have you
always been an entrepreneur or did you
start at it start out at a big company
in transition to a startup did you go
from academia to startups or startup
stack edenia no I was definitely not an
academia I'm totally a fake academic I I
I started at McKinsey and company which
is a strategy firm when I was 18 which
meant I couldn't really go to university
so I didn't really turn up and then yeah
spent eight years in business helping
really big companies on strategic
questions
I always wanted to be an entrepreneur
planter on you spend two years in
McKinsey only thing I really regret in
my life was not sticking to that plan
and wasting eight years instead so two
years would have been perfect but yeah
then I went into burner ship started two
companies in Australia and the best part
about that was that I didn't get any
funding so all the money that I made was
mine or the decisions were mine and my
you know and my partner's you know I
focused entirely on on profit and
product and customer and service whereas
I find in San Francisco I'm glad you
know I'm glad I came here and so the two
of us from you know came here for cable
and EMI and raised you know ridiculous
amount of money eleven million dollars
for this really new company that was
really interesting but it's also really
distracting you know trying to worry
about scaling and VC's wanting to see
what your business development plans are
and also just not having any real need
to actually make a profit and yeah so I
had a bit of the same problem at
analytic where I again raised a lot of
money fifteen million dollars pretty
quickly and yeah a lot of distractions
so yeah I think you know trying to
bootstrap your own company and focus on
making money by selling something at a
better profit and then you know plowing
that back into the company it worked
really well right because within like
five years you know we were making a
profit from three months in and within
five years we're making you know enough
for profit not just to pay all of us in
their own wages but also to see my bank
account growing and after ten years sold
it for a big chunk of money not enough
that a VC would be excited but enough
that I didn't have to worry that money
again you know so I think yeah
bootstrapping a company
something which people in the Bay Area's
don't seem to appreciate how good our
idea that is if you were 25 years old
today and still know what you know where
which of you looking to use AI what are
you working on right now are looking to
work on in the next two years
you should ignore the last part of that
I won't even answer it doesn't matter
where I'm looking like what you should
do is leverage your knowledge about your
domain so like one of the main reasons
we do this is to get people who have
backgrounds in whatever recruiting you
know oil field surveys journalism
activism whatever right and solve your
problems
it'll be really obvious to you what real
problems are and it'll be really obvious
to you what data you have and where to
find it those are all the bits that for
everybody else that's really hard so
people who start out with like oh I know
deep learning now I'll go and find
something to apply it to basically never
succeed where else people who are like
oh I've been spending 25 years doing
specialized recruiting for legal firms
and I know that the key issue is this
thing and I know that this piece of data
totally solves it and so I'm just going
to do that now and I already know who to
call who actually start selling it to
you know they're the ones who who tend
to win so yeah and and and you know if
you if you've done nothing but like
academic stuff that it's more maybe
about your your hobbies and interests
you know so everybody has hobbies the
main thing I would say is please don't
focus on building tools for data
scientists to use or for software
engineers to use because every data
scientist knows about the market of data
scientists whereas only you know about
the market for you know analyzing oil
survey world walks or you know
understanding audiology studies or
whatever it is that
you do given what you've shown us about
applying transfer learning from image
recognition to NLP there looks to be a
lot of value in paying attention to all
of the developments that happen across
the whole machine learning field and
that if you were to focus in one area
you might miss out on some great
advances in other concentrations
how do you stay aware of all the
advancements across the field while
still having time to dig in deep to your
specific domains yes awesome I mean
that's kind of the message of this
course one of the key messages this
course yeah it's like lots of good works
being done in different places and
people are so specialized most people
don't know about it like if I can get
stated that results in an LP within six
months of starting to look at NLP and I
think that says more about NLP than it
does about me
thankfully so yeah it's kind of like the
Entrepreneurship thing it's like you
pick that the areas you see that you
know about and kind of transfer stuff
like oh we could use deep learning to
solve this problem or in this case like
we could use you know this idea can
compute a vision to solve that problem
so things like trendier may transfer
learning i'm sure there's like a
thousand things opportunities for you to
do in other fields to do what Sebastian
and I did in NLP with NLP classification
so the short answer to your question is
the way to stay ahead of what's going on
would be to follow my feed of Twitter
favorites and my approach is to and
follow lots and lots of people on
Twitter and put them into the Twitter
favorites for you like literally I every
time I come across something interesting
I click favorite and there are two
reasons I do it the first is that when
the next course comes along I go through
my favorites to find which things I want
to study the second is so that you know
you can do the same thing and then you
know which do you go deep into it almost
doesn't matter like I find every time I
look at something it turns out to be
super interesting and important so tiss
like pick something which is like you
feel like solving that problem would be
actually useful to some reason and it
doesn't seem to be
popular which is kind of the opposite
with what everybody else does everybody
else works on the problems which
everybody else is already working on
because they're the ones that seem
popular and I don't know I can't quite
understand this chain of thinking but it
seems to be very common is deep learning
and overkill to use on tabular data when
is it better to use deep learning
instead of machine learning on tabular
data is that a real question or did you
just put that there so that I would
point out that Rachel Thomas just wrote
an article so yes so Rachel's just
written about this and and original and
I spent a long time talking about it and
the short answer is we think it's great
to use deep learning on tabular data
actually of all the rich complex
important and interesting things that
appear in Rachel's Twitter stream
covering everything from the genocide of
the Inga through to latest ethics
violations in AI companies the one by
far that got the most attention and
engagement from the community was their
question about is it called tabular data
or structured data so ya ask computer
Pires people how to name things and
you'll get plenty of interest yeah and
there's some really good links here to
stuff from instacart and pinterest and
other folks in this area any of you that
went to the data institute conference
will have seen Jeremy Stanley's
presentation about the really cool work
they did and instacart yes we're sure so
I relied heavily on lessons 3 and 4 from
part one and writing this post so yes
much of that may be familiar to you yeah
Rachel asked me during the post like how
to tell whether you should use the
decision tree ensemble like GBM or
random forest or or a neural net and my
answer is I still don't know nobody to
my nobody I'm aware of has done that
research and any particularly meaningful
way so there's
a question to be answered there I guess
my approach has been to try to make both
of those things as accessible as
possible through the faster your library
so you can try them both both and see
what works yes that's what I do and that
is it for the top voted questions thank
you okay so just quickly to go from
super resolution to style transfer it's
kind of oh I think I miss the one on
reinforcement learning and reinforcement
learning popularity has been on a
gradual rise in the recent past what's
your take on reinforcement learning
which fast day I consider covering some
ground and popular RL techniques in the
future I'm still not a believer in
reinforcement learning I think it's a an
interesting problem to solve but it's
not at all clear that we have a good way
of solving this problem so the problem
it really is the delayed credit problem
so you know I want to learn to play pong
I've moved up or down and three minutes
later I find out whether I won the game
of pong which actions I took were
actually useful and so to me the idea of
calculating the gradients of those
inputs with respect you know the app so
the gradient of the output with respect
to those inputs the credit is so delayed
that those derivatives don't seem very
interesting and there's been you know
kind of been I get this question quite
regularly in every one of these four
courses so far I've always it the same
thing I'm rather pleased but finally
recently there's been some results
showing that actually basically random
search often does better than
reinforcement learning so basically
what's happened is very well-funded
companies with vast amounts of
computational power throw all of it at
reinforcement learning problems and get
good results and people then say oh it's
because of the reinforcement learning
rather than the vast amounts of compute
power
or they use extremely thoughtful and
clever algorithms like a combination of
convolutional neural nets and Monte
Carlo tree search like they did with the
alpha girl stuff to get great results
and people incorrectly say oh that's
because of reinforcement learning when
it wasn't really reinforcement learning
at all so I'm very interested like in
solving these kind of more generic
optimization type problems rather than
just prediction problems and that's what
these delay to credit problems tend to
look like but I don't think we've yet
got good enough best practices that I
have anything on ready to teach and say
like I've got to teach you this thing
because I think it's still going to be
useful next year so we'll keep watching
and yeah see see what happens ok so
we're going to now turn the super
resolution Network basically into a
style transfer network and what do this
pretty quickly we basically already have
something so here's my input image and
I'm going to have some loss function and
I've got some neural net again so
instead of a neural net that does a
whole lot of compute and then does up
sampling at the end our input this time
is just as big as our output so we're
going to do some down sampling first and
then our compute and then our settlement
okay so that's the first change we're
going to make is going to add some down
sampling so since tried to convolution
layers to the front of our network the
second is rather than just comparing YC
and X to the same thing here right so
we're going to basically say our input
image should look like itself by the end
and so specifically we're going to
compare it by checking it through vgg
and comparing it at one of the content
at one of the activation layers and then
its style should look like some painting
which brought to it just like we did
with the gaddy's approach by looking at
the grand Matrix correspondence at a
number of layers
so that's basically it and so that that
ought to be super straightforward it's
really just combining two things we've
already done and so all this code starts
identical except we don't have high res
and low res we just have one size 256
well this is the same my model is the
same one thing I did here is I I made I
did not do any kind of fancy best
practices for this one at all
partly because there doesn't seem to be
any like there's been very little follow
up in this approach compared to the
super resolution stuff and we'll talk
about why in a moment so you'll see this
is like much more normal looking you
know I've got batch norm layers I don't
have the scaling factor here you know I
don't have a pixel shuffle that's just
using a normal up sampling followed by
one by one cons so it's kind of it's
just more normal
one thing they mentioned in the paper is
they had a lot of problems with zero
padding creating artifacts and the way
they solve that was by adding 40 pixels
of reflection padding at the start so I
did the same thing and then they used
zero padding in there convolutions in
there red blocks now if you've got zero
padding in your convolution in your red
blocks then that means that you're the
two parts of your resin it won't add up
anymore because you've lost a pixel from
each side on each of your two
convolutions so my my red sequential has
become res sequential Center and I've
removed the last two pixels on each side
of those good sus okay so other than
that this is basically the same as what
we had thought so then we can bring in
our starry night picture we can resize
it we can throw it through our
transformations just to make the method
a little bit easier for my brain to
handle
I took my transformation image which
after transfer our transform style in
after transformations of three by 256 by
256 and I made a mini batch my batch
size is 24 24 copies of it now it just
makes it a little bit easier to do the
kind of batch arithmetic without
worrying about some of the broadcasting
they're not really 24 copies are used MP
dot broadcast to to basically fake 24
piece okay so just like before we create
a V Gigi grab the last block this time
we're going to use all of these layers
so we keep everything up to the
forty-third layer and so now our
combined lasts is going to add together
a content loss for the third block plus
the gramm loss for all of our blocks
with different weights and so the gram
loss against that kind of going back to
everything being is like normal as
possible I've gone back to using MSA
here basically what happened as I had a
lot of trouble getting this to train
properly so I gradually removed trick
after trick and eventually just went ok
that's good I believe make it as as
bland as possible
last week's Graham matrix was wrong by
the way it only worked for a batch size
of one and we only had a batch size of
one so that was fine I was using matrix
multiply which meant that every batch
was being compared to every other batch
you actually need to use batch matrix
multiply which does a matrix multiply
per batch ok so that's something to be
aware of there ok so so I've got my
grand matrices I do my MSE loss between
the gram matrices I weight them my style
weights so I create that ResNet so
create my style my combined loss passing
in the vgg Network passing in the block
IDs passing in the transformed starry
night image and so you'll see the very
start here I do a forward pass through
both vtg model with that starry night
image in order that I can
the features for it right now notice
it's really important now that I don't
do any data augmentation because I've
saved the style features for a
particular you know non Augmented
version and so if I augmented it it
might make some minor problems but
that's fine because I've got all of
imagenet to deal with I don't really
need to do data augmentation anyway okay
so I've got my loss function and I can
go ahead and fit and there's really
nothing flavor here at all at the end I
have my some layers equals false so I
can see what each part looks like and
see that there is some we balanced and I
can finally pop it out so I mentioned
that should be pretty easy and yet it
took me about 4 days because it just I
just found this incredibly fiddly to
actually get it to work so like when I
finally got up in the morning I said to
Rachel guess what they're trained
correctly Rachel was like I never
thought that was going to happen it just
it just looked awful all the time and
it's really about getting the exact
right mix of content lossless a style
loss of the mix of the layers of the
style loss and that the worst part was
it takes a really long time to train the
damn CNN and I don't didn't really know
how long to train it before before I
decided it wasn't doing well like should
I just train it for longer or what and I
don't know all the little details didn't
seem to like slightly change it but just
like it would totally fall apart all the
time so I kind of mentioned this partly
to say like just remember the final
answer you see here is after me driving
myself crazy or weak over nearly always
not working until finally the last
minute it finally does for even for
things which just seemed like they
couldn't pass
be difficult because that is combining
two things we already have working the
other is like to be careful about how we
interpret what authors claim yeah so it
was so fiddly getting this style
transfer to work and like after doing it
it left me thinking why did I bother
because now I've got something that
takes hours to create a network that can
turn any kind of photo into one specific
style it just seems very unlikely I
would want that for anything like about
the only reason I could think that being
useful would be to like do some art and
stuff on a video rather to turn every
frame into some style like it's
incredibly interesting to what to do but
you know when I looked at the paper that
you know their tables saying like oh
we're a thousand times faster than the
Gattis approach which is like it's just
such an obviously meaningless thing to
say in such an incredibly kind of
misleading thing to say because it
ignores all the hours of training for
each individual style and I don't know I
find this frustrating because like a
groups like this Stanford group clearly
know better or ought to know better but
still I guess the academic community he
kind of encourages people to make these
ridiculously grand plans and it also
completely ignores this incredibly
sensitive fiddly training process so you
know this paper was just so well
accepted when it came out you know I
remember everybody getting on Twitter
and being like wow you know these
Stanford people have found this way of
doing style transfer a thousand times
faster and clearly you know the people
saying this would like all like top
researchers in the field clearly like
none of them actually understood because
nobody said you know I don't
see why this is remotely useful and also
I tried it and it was incredibly fiddly
to get it all to work and so it's not
until like what is this they're like
eighteen months later or something that
I finally coming back to it and kind of
thinking like wait a minute this is kind
of stupid and so so this is the answer I
think to the question of like well why
haven't people don't follow ups on this
to like create really amazing best
practices and better approaches like
with a super resolution part of the
paper and they I think the answer is
because it's done so I think this part
of the paper is clearly not fun you know
and it's been improved and improved and
improved and now we have great super
resolution and I think we can derive
from that great noise reduction great
colorization great you know slant
removal great interactive and effective
or whatever so I think there's a lot of
really cool techniques here and it's
also delivering a lot of stuff that
we've been learning and getting better
and better at okay so then finally let's
talk about segmentation this is from the
famous some cam vid data set which is a
classic example of an academic
segmentation data set and basically you
can see what we do is we start with a
picture they're actually video frames in
this data set like here and we construct
we have some labels where they're not
actually colors that each one has an ID
and the IDS of math two colors so like
red might be one purple might be two
like pink might be three and so all the
buildings you know one class or the cars
or another class or the people or
another class or the road is another
class and so what we're actually doing
here is multi-class classification for
every pixel okay and so you can see
sometimes that model class specification
really is quite tricky there's you know
like like these branches well though
sometimes the labels are really not that
great you know this is very coarse
as you can see so here at traffic lights
so forth so but that's what we're going
to do we're going to do this is
segmentation and so it's a look like
bounding boxes okay but you know rather
than just finding you know a box around
each thing we're actually going to label
every single pixel with its plus and
really that's actually a lot easier
because it fits our CNN style so nicely
that we've basically we can create any
CNN where the output is an N by M grid
containing the integers from 0 to C
where there are C categories and then we
can use cross-entropy loss with a
softmax activation and we're done right
so like I could actually stop the class
there and you can go and use exactly the
approaches you've learnt in like lessons
1 &amp; 2 and you'll get a perfectly okay
result ok
so the first thing to say is like this
is not actually a terribly hard thing to
do but we're going to try and do it
really well and so let's start by doing
it the really simple way and we're going
to use the CAG or carvanha competition
so you could go cable car Varner to find
it you can download it with the caracal
api as per usual
now basically there's a train folder
containing a bunch of images which is
the independent variable and a train
masks folder there's the dependent
variable and they look like this here's
the here's one of the independent
variable and here's one of the dependent
variable okay so in this case just like
cats and dogs we're going simple rather
than doing multi-class classification
we're going to do binary classification
but of course multi-class is just the
more general version you know
categorical cross-entropy your binary
cross-entropy okay so there's no
differences conceptually so we've got
this is just you know zeros and ones
where else this is a regular image so in
order to do this well it would really
help to know what cars look like right
because you know really
we just what to do is figure out this is
a car and its orientation and then color
you know put white pixels where we
expect the part of e based on the
picture and their understanding of what
cars will plug the original data set
came with these CSV files as well I
don't really use them for very much
other than getting the list of images
from them each each image after the car
ID has a 0 1 0 2 etc of which I've
printed out all 16 of them for one car
and as you can see if basically those
numbers are the 16 orientations of one
car that is and I don't think anybody in
this competition actually used this
orientation information I believe they
all kick the cars images just treated
them separately these images are pretty
big like over a thousand by thousand in
size and just opening the JPEGs and
resizing them is slow so I processed
them all also OpenCV can't handle gif
files so I converted them yes Rachel the
question how would somebody get these
masks for training initially Mechanical
Turk or something yeah yeah just a lot
of boring work you know probably some
tools that help you with a bit of edge
snapping and stuff so that the human can
kind of do it roughly and then just find
you in the bits it gets wrong yeah these
kinds of labels are expensive you know
and so one of the things I really want
to work on is deep learning enhanced
interactive labeling tools because you
know yeah so I've got a little section
here that you can run if you want to you
probably want to which converts the
gifts into pngs so just open it up with
PIL and then save it as PNG because open
CV doesn't have give support and as per
usual for this
stuff I do it with a thread pool so I
can take advantage of parallel
processing and then also create a
separate directory train - 128 and train
masks 128 which contains the 128 by 128
resized versions of them and this is the
kind of stuff that keeps you sane if you
do it early in the process so anytime
you get a new data set you know
seriously think about creating a you
know smaller version to make life fast
anytime you find yourself waiting on
your computer you know try and think of
a way to create a smaller version so
yeah after you grab it from cowboy you
probably want to run this stuff by way
to have lunch come back and when you're
done you'll have these smaller
directories which we're going to use
here 128 by 128 pixel versions to start
with so here's a cool trick if you use
the same access object to plot an image
twice and the second time you use alpha
which as you might know means
transparency in the computer vision
world then you can actually plot the
mask over the top of the photo and so
there here's a nice way to see all the
masks on top of the photos for all of
the cars in one group this is the same
match files data set we've seen twice
already this is all the same code we
used - and here's something important
though if we had something that was in
the training set go to this image and
then the validation had that image that
would kind of be cheating because it's
the same Cup so we use a contiguous set
of car IDs and since each set is a set
of 16 we make sure that's evenly
divisible by 16 so we make sure that our
validation set contains different car
IDs to our training set this is the kind
of stuff but you've got to be careful of
on Kaggle it's not so bad you'll know
about it because you'll submit your
result and you'll get a very different
result on your leaderboard compared to
your validation set but in the real
world you won't know until you put it in
production and send your company
bankrupt and lose your job
so you might want to think carefully
about your validation set in that case
so here we're going to use transform
type classification it's basically the
same as transform type dot pixel but if
you think about it we with a pixel
version if we rotate a little bit then
we probably want to like average the
pixels in between the two but the
classification obviously we we don't we
use nearest neighbor so the slight
difference there also for classification
you know lighting doesn't kick in
normalization to the dependent variable
okay they're already square images so we
don't have to do any cropping so here
you can see different versions of the
Augmented you know move around a bit
when they're rotating a bit and so forth
yeah I get a lot of questions kind of
like during our study group and stuff
about like how do I debug things and fix
things that aren't working and like a I
never have a great answer other than
like every time I fix a problem is
because of stuff like this that I do all
the time you know I just always print
out everything as I go and then the one
thing that I screw up always turns out
to be the one thing that I forgot to
check along the way so yeah the more of
this kind of thing you can do the better
if you're not looking at all of your
intermediate results I mean I have
troubles okay so given that we want
something that knows what cars look like
we probably want to start with a pre
trained imagenet network so we're going
to start with ResNet 34 and so with
confident builder we can grab our resin
at 34 and we can add a custom head and
so the custom head is going to be
something that up samples a bunch of
plants and we're going to do things
really done for now which is we're just
going to do a commons pose to addy batch
norm value okay
and so here's like this is what I'm
saying you could any of you could have
built this without looking at any of
this
or at least like you have the
information from previous classes
there's nothing new at all
okay and so at the very end we have a
single filter okay and now that's going
to give us something which is batch size
by 1 by 128 by 128 but we want something
which is batch sized by 128 by 128 so we
have to remove that unit axis so I've
got a lambda layer here lambda layers
are incredibly helpful right because
without the lambda layer here which is
simply removing that unit axis by just
indexing into it at 0 without the lambda
layer I would have to have created a
custom class with a custom forward
method and so forth but by creating a
lambda layer that does like the one
custom bit I can notice chocolate from
the sequential and so that just makes
life easier so the PI torch people are
kind of snooty
about this approach lambda is actually
something that's part of the first day I
library not part of the pad torch
library and like literally people on the
pad watch discussion board like yes we
could give people this yes it is only a
single line of code but they never like
encourage them to use sequential too
often so there you go okay so so this is
that custom head right so we're gonna
have a rest at 34 that goes down sample
and then a really simple custom here
that very quickly up samples and that
hopefully will do something and we're
going to use accuracy with a threshold
of 0.5 to print out metrics and so after
a few a pops we've got 96 percent
accurate okay
so is that good is 96 percent accurate
good and hopefully the answer to your
question that question is it depends
what's it for right and the answer is
qivana wanted this because they wanted
to be able to take their car images and
cut them out and paste them on you know
exotic monte-carlo backgrounds or
whatever that's multicolor the place
the simulation so to do that you need a
really good mask but you don't want to
like leave the rearview mirrors behind
or like you know kind of have one wheel
missing or include a little bit of
background or something that would look
stupid so you would beat something very
good
so only having 96 percent of the pixels
correct doesn't sound great but we won't
really know until we look at it so let's
look at it so there's the correct
version that we want to cut out
that's the 96% expert version okay so
like where do you look at it you guys oh
yeah
getting 90% 96% of the pixels accurate
is actually easy because like all the
outside bits not care at all the inside
bit is car and really really interesting
bit is the edge okay so we need to do
better
so let's unfreeze because what we've
done so far is trained the customer here
okay let's do more and so after a bit
more we've got 99.1 percent okay so is
that good I don't know let's take a look
and so actually no it's totally missed
the rearview vision mirror here and
missed a lot of it here and it's clearly
got an edge wrong here and these things
are totally going to matter when we try
to cut it out so it's still not good
enough so let's try upscaling and the
nice thing is that when we upscale to
512 by 512 make sure you decrease the
batch size because you'll run out of
memory you know here's the true ones
it's quite a lot more this is all
identical it's quite a lot more
information Everett go on so our
accuracy increases to 99.4% and things
keep getting better but we've still got
quite a few little black blocky bits so
let's go to 124 by 124 down to batch
size of four this is pretty high res now
and train a bit more ninety nine point
six ninety-nine point eight and so now
if we look at the masks they're actually
looking not bad
okay that's looking pretty good right so
can we do better and the answer is yes
we can so we're moving from the carbonyl
nut book to the carbonyl unit notebook
now and the unit Network is quite
magnificent right you see with that
previous approach our pre-trained
imagenet network was being squished down
all the way down to seven by seven and
then expand it out all the way back up
to you know well it's two to four go to
seven by seven but one or two four is
going quite a bit bigger and then
expanded out again or this way which
means it has to somehow store all the
information about the much bigger
version in the small version right and
actually most of the information about
the bigger version was really in the
original picture anyway so it doesn't
seem like a great approach this
squishing and I'm squishing so the unit
idea comes from this fantastic paper
where like it was literally invented in
this you know very domain-specific area
of biomedical image segmentation but in
fact basically every cattle winner in in
anything even vaguely related to
segmentation has ended up using unit as
one of these things that like everybody
in Carroll knows is the best practice
but in more of an academic circles like
even now this has been around for a
couple of years at least a lot of people
still don't realize it's like this is by
far the best approach and here's the
basic idea here's the downward path
right where we basically start start at
five 72 by 5 3 2 in this case and then
kind of half the grid size half the grid
size half the grid size half the grid
size right and then here's the upward
path where we double the grid size
double double double double no but the
thing that we also do is we take you
know at every point where we've half the
grid size we actually copy those
activations over to the upward path and
and concatenate the
together and so you can see here these
red blobs of maps polling operations the
green blobs are upward sampling and then
these gray bits here are copying right
and so we copy and can cat so basically
in other words the input image after a
couple of poems is copied over to the
output concatenated together and so now
we get to use all of the informations
gone through all the down and all the
app plus also a slightly modified
version of the input pixels right and a
slightly modified version of one thing
down from the input pixels because they
came out through yes right so we have
like all of the richness of going all
the way down and up but also like a
slightly less coarse version and a
slightly less cost version and then this
really kind of simple version and they
can all be combined together okay and so
that's unit it's such a cool idea so
here we are in the in the carvanha unit
notebook all this is the same code as
before and at the start I've got a
simple up sample version just to kind of
show you again the the non unit version
this time I'm going to add in something
called the dice metric dice is very
similar as you see to jacquard or I over
you it's just a minor difference it's
basically intersection over Union with a
minor tweak and the reason we're going
to use dice is that's the metric that
the caracal competition used and it's
kind of it's a little bit harder to get
a high score than a high accuracy
because it's really looking at like what
the overlap of the correct pixels are
with with your pixels but it's pretty
similar so in the Carroll competition
people that we're doing okay we're
getting about ninety nine point six dice
and the winners for about nine nine
point seven days so here's our standard
up sample this is all as before and so
now we can check our dice metric
and so you can see on dice metric we're
getting like nine six eight at 128 by
128 and so that's not great
okay so so let's try unit and I'm
calling it unit ish because that's per
usual I'm creating my own someone hacky
version right kind of trying to keep
things as similar to what you're used to
as possible and doing things that I
think makes sense and so there should be
plenty of opportunity for you to at
least make this more authentically unit
by looking at the exact kind of grid
sizes and like see how here the size is
going down a little bit so they're
obviously not adding any padding and
then they're doing here they've got some
cropping going on there's a few
differences right but one of the things
is because I want to take advantage of
transfer learning that means I can't
quite use unit so here's another big
opportunity is what if you create the
unit down path and then add a classifier
on the end and then train that on
imagenet and you've now got an image net
trained classifier which is specifically
designed to be a good backbone for unit
right and then you should be able to now
come back and get pretty close to
winning this old competition is actually
not that old it's fairly recent
competition because you know that pre
train network didn't exist before but if
you think about like what Yolo v3 did
it's basically that right they create a
darknet they pre trained it on image net
and then they used it as the basis for
their bounding boxes so again this kind
of idea of free training things which
are designed not just for classification
but to find for other things is just
something that nobody's nobody's done
yet and let's weave but as we've
shown you know you can train image net
for 25 bucks in three hours now so
and if people in the community are
interested in doing this you know
hopefully I'll have credits I can help
you with as well so if you do you know
the work to get it set up and give me a
script I can probably run it for you so
for now though we don't have that so
we're going to use resonate so so we're
basically going to start with this let's
see with get base and so base is our
base network and that was defined back
up for this first section right so get
base is going to be something that calls
whatever this is and this is resna 34 so
we're going to grab our ResNet 34 and
cut model is the first thing that our
confident builder does it basically
removes everything from the adaptive
pulling onwards and so that gives us
back the backbone of resna 34 okay so
get base is going to give us okay and
then we're going to take that rest at 30
for backbone and turn it into a I call
it a unit 34 so what that's going to do
is it's going to save that ResNet that
we passed in and then we're going to use
a forward hook just like before to save
the results at the second fourth fifth
and sixth blocks which as before is the
basically before each straight to
convolution then we're going to create a
bunch of these things we're calling unit
blocks and the unit block basically says
so these unit blocks are these things
these are unit blocks so the the unit
block tells us you know we have to tell
it how many things are coming from the
from the kind of previous layer that
we're up sampling how many are coming
across and then how many do we want to
come out right and so the amount coming
across is entirely defined by whatever
the base network was right it's like
whatever whatever the downward path was
we need that many layers and so this is
a little bit awkward
actually one of our master students here
kerim has actually created something
called dynamic unit that you'll find in
fast AI unit dynamic unit and it
actually calculates this all for you
and automatically creates the whole unit
from your base model it's got some minor
quirks still that I want to fix by the
time the videos out it'll definitely be
working and I will at least have a
notebook showing how to use it and
possibly add additional video but for
now you know you'll just have to go
through and do it yourself you can
easily see it just by once you've got a
reson it you can just go you know just
type in its name and it'll print out all
the layers and you can see how big how
many activations there are in each block
or you can even have a printed out for
you for each for each block
automatically anyway I just did this
manually
and so the unit block is works like this
so you said okay right this penny coming
up from the previous layer I've got this
penny coming across this X I'm using
across across from the the downward path
this is the amount I want coming out now
what I do is they then say okay we're
going to create a certain amount of
convolutions from the upward path in a
certain amount from the cross path and
so I'm going to be concatenated them
together so let's divide the number we
want out by two right and so we're going
to have our cross convolution take our
cross path and create number out / - and
then the upward path is going to be a
common transpose to D right because we
want to increase up sample and again
here we've got the number n divided by
two and then at the end I just
concatenate those together alright so
I've got an upward sample I've got a
cross convolution I can catenate the two
together yeah and so that's all a unit
block is and so that's actually a pretty
easy module to create and so then in my
forward path I need
to pass to the forward of the of the
unit block the upward path and the cross
plus so the upward path is just wherever
I'm up to so far right but then the
cross path is whatever the value is of
whatever the activations are that I
stored on the way down right so as I
come up it's the last set of saved
features that I need first and in as I
gradually keep going up further and
further and further eventually it's the
first set of features okay and so there
are some more tricks we can do to make
this a little bit better but this is
this is a good stuff right so if we try
this so the simple up sampling approach
looked horrible right and had a dice of
nine six eight now you net with
everything else identical except we've
been out got these unit blocks has a
dice of nine eight five right sir that's
like we've kind of halved the error with
with everything else exactly the same
and more the point you can look at it
this is actually looking somewhat
car-like compared to our non unit
equivalent which is just a block now
because you know try to do this through
down and up paths just it's just asking
too much you know where else when we
actually provide the downward path
pixels at every point it can actually
start to create something karush so at
the end of that we'll go dot close to
again remove those s FS features taking
up GPU memory go to a smaller batch size
a higher size and you can see the dice
coefficients really going up this is
just so notice here I'm learning I'm
loading in right the 128 by 128 version
of the network okay so we're doing this
progressive resizing trick again so that
gets us 99 3 and then unfreeze to get to
99 4 and you can see it's now looking
pretty good okay go down to a batch size
of 4 so
102 for load-in what we just did with
the 512 Texas 299 5 unfreeze takes us to
99 we'll call that 99 six five nine nine
and as you can see that actually looks
good right in accuracy terms ninety-nine
point eight two you know you can see
this is looking like something you could
just about used to cut out I think too
you know at this point there's a couple
of minor tweaks we can do to get up to
ninety-nine point seven but really the
key thing then I think is just maybe to
do a you know a few bit of smoothing
maybe or a little bit of post-processing
you can go and have a look at the
carvanha winners blogs and see some of
these tricks but as I say the difference
between where we are at ninety nine
point six and what the winners got of
99.7 you know is it's not heaps and so
really that just the you net on its own
pretty much pretty much solves our
problem okay so that's it so the last
thing I wanted to mention is now to come
all the way back to bounding boxes
because you might remember I said out
our bounding box model was still not
doing very well on small objects so
hopefully you might be able to guess
where I'm going to go with this which is
that for the bounding box model remember
how we we had at different grid cells we
spat out outputs of their model and it
was those earlier ones with the small
grits sizes that weren't very good for
how do we fix it you net it right let's
have an upward path with cross
connections right and so then we're just
going to do a unit and then spit them
out of that the
now does those finer grid cells have all
of the information of that path and that
path and that path and that path for
leverage now of course this is deep
learning so that means you can't write a
paper saying we just used you net for
bounding boxes you have to invent a new
word so this is called feature pyramid
networks or fbms okay and like that
literally the paper this is part of the
retina net paper which is actually a
it's used in the retina net paper it was
you it was created an earlier paper
specifically of Olympians and like if
memory serves correctly they did briefly
cite the unit paper but they kind of
made it sound like it was this vaguely
slightly connected thing that maybe some
people could consider slightly useful
but it really F P ends as units okay I
don't have an implementation of it to
show you but you know it'll be a fun
thing maybe for some of us to try and
some of us have already some I haven't
yet but I know some of the students have
been trying so to get it working well on
the forums so yeah interesting thing to
try so I think a couple of couple of
things to look at after this class as
well as the other things I mentioned
would be playing around with FP ends and
also maybe trying caroms dynamic unit
they would both be interesting things to
look at all right so so you guys have
all been through fourteen lessons of me
talking at you now
so I'm sorry about that thanks for
putting up with me you know I think it's
it it's you're gonna find it hard to
find people who actually as know them as
much about training neural networks and
practice as you do it'll be really easy
for you to overestimate how capable all
these other people are an underestimate
how poor you are and so like the main
thing I'd say is like please practice
please just because you don't have this
constant thing getting you to come back
here every Monday night now it's very
easy to kind of lose that momentum so
find ways to keep it you know you know
organize a study group you know or a
book a reading group or get together
some friends and work on a project or
you know do something more than just
deciding I want to keep working on X
like it's gonna need to involve problem
unless you're the kind of person who's
super motivated and you know that
whenever you decide to do something it
happens that's not me right it's like I
know something to happen I have to like
say yes David in October I will
absolutely teach that course and then
it's like okay if it actually writes a
material let's see only way I can get
stuff to happen so we've got a great
community there on the forums if people
have ideas for ways to make it better
please tell me you know if you think you
can help with you know if you want to
create some new forum or moderated in
some different way or whatever it is let
me know right you can always PM me and
there's a lot of projects going on
through github as well
lots of stuff so yeah I hope to see you
all back here at something else and
thanks so much for joining me on this
journey
[Applause]