okay so today we're going to continue
working on object detection which means
that for every object in a photo with
one of 20 classes we're going to try and
figure out what the object is and what
its bounding box is hi that model to a
new data set of unlabeled data and add
those medals to the general approach
we're going to use this to start simple
and gradually make it more complicated
so we started last week with a simple
classifier the three month of classifier
we then made it slightly more complex to
turn it into a bounding box without a
classifier today we're going to put
those two pieces together to make a
classifier plus a bounding box all of
these are just for a single object the
largest object and then from there we'll
roll it up to something which is closer
to final goal you should go back and
make sure that you're understanding all
of these concepts from last week before
you move on if you don't go back and
really go through the locals carefully I
won't read them all to you because you
can see in the video needs to be enough
that practice is the most important
knowing how to jump around source code
in whatever but the lambda functions
lambda function is also particularly
important they come up everywhere and
this idea of a custom head is also gonna
come up in pretty much every lesson I've
also added here a a reminder of what you
should know from part one of the course
because quite often I see questions on
the forum asking basically why isn't my
model working like why doesn't it start
training or having trained why doesn't
it seem to be any use and nearly always
the answer to the question is did you
print out the inputs to it from a data
loader did you print out the outputs
from a after evaluating and normally the
answer is no and I try printing it and
it turns out all the inputs 0
or all of the appellants negative
reports when it was really obvious so
that's just part of something wanted to
remind you about this you need to know
how to do these two things if you can't
do that that's gonna be very hard to
debug models and B if you can do that if
you're not doing it then it's going to
be very happy to debug models you could
have debug models by staring at a source
code hoping your error pops out your
debug models by checking all the
intermediate steps looking in the data
printing it out plotting its histogram
making sure it says okay so we were
working through Pascal notebook and we
just quickly zipped through the bounding
box of the largest object without a
classifier and there was one bit that I
skipped over and said I've come back to
so let's do that now which is to talk
about augmentations data augmentations
of the the Y of the dependent variable
before I do I just mention something
pretty awkward in all this which is I've
got here image classifier data
continuous equals true this makes no
sense whatsoever a classifier is
anything where the dependent variable is
categorical or binomial as opposed to
regression which is anything with the
pen and variable is continuous and yet
this parameter here continuously was
true says that the dependent variable is
continuous so this claims to be creating
data for a classifier where the
dependent is continuous this is the kind
of awkward rough edge that you see when
we're kind of at this like you know at
the edge of the pasta our code is not
quite solidified yes so probably by the
time you watch this in the MOOC this
will be sorted out this is before even
you regress it
or something like that but you know I
just wanted to kind of point out this
this issue and also because sometimes
people were getting confused between
regression business classification and
this is okay so let's create some data
augmentations right there normally when
we create data augmentations we tend to
type in like transform sidon or
transform spa gym but if you look inside
that fast they are transforms module
you'll see that they are simply defined
as a list so this one called transforms
basic which is 10 degree rotations plus
0.05 brightness and contrast and then
sidon adds to that and random horizontal
flips or else top down as to that random
dihedral group of symmetry flips which
basically means if we possible 90 degree
rotation optionally so like these are
just a little shortcuts that I added
because time but you can always create
your own list of augmentations right and
if you're not sure what augmentations
are there you can often see check the
past AI source or if you just start
typing random they all start with so you
can see so let's take a look at what
happens if we create some data
augmentations create a model data object
and let's just go through and rerun the
iterator a bunch of times and we all do
two things we'll print out the bounding
boxes and so you can see the value box
is the same time and we will also draw
the pictures so you'll see this lady is
as we would expect flipping around and
spinning around getting darker and
lighter but the bounding box a is not
moving and B is in the wrong spot so
this is the problem with data
augmentation when your dependent
variable you
is pixel values or is in some way
connected to your independent variable
its who need to be augmented together
and in fact you can see that from the
printout these numbers are bigger than
two to four but these images are of size
two to four that what we requested in
this in this transpose and so it's not
even being like scaled or cropped or
anything right so you can see that how
the pendant variable needs to go through
all of the same geometric
transformations without independent
variable so to do that every
transformation has an optional transform
Y parameter it takes a transform type-in
um the transform type-in um has a few
options all of which we'll cover in this
course the co ward up ssin says that the
Y values represent coordinates in this
case bounding box coordinates okay and
so therefore if you flip you need to
change the coordinate derivative
represent that flip or if you rotate you
to change the coordinate represent a
rotation so I can add transform type a
chord to all of my augmentations I also
have to add the exact same thing to my
transforms from model function because
that's the thing that does the cropping
and/or zooming and or padding and or
resizing and all of those things need to
happen to the dependent variable so if
we add all of those together and rerun
this you'll see the bounding box changes
each time and you'll see us in the right
spot now you'll see sometimes it looks a
little odd like here why is that
bounding box there and the problem is
this is just a constraint that the
information we have right the bounding
box does not tell us that actually her
head isn't way over here in the top left
corner alright but actually if you do a
thirty degree rotation in her head was
over here the top left corner then the
new bounding box would need would go
really high right so this is actually
the correct bounding box based on the
information and has available which is
to say this is this is how higher
Mobe so basically you've got to be
careful of not doing to higher rotations
with bounding boxes because there's not
enough information for them to stay
totally accurate just fundamental
limitation of the information we're
given if we were doing like polygons or
segmentations or whatever we wouldn't
have this problem okay so I'm gonna do a
maximum of three degree rotations I'm
also going to only rotate half the time
my random flip my brightness/contrast
changing and so there's my set of
transformations that I can use
so we briefly looked at this custom head
idea but basically if you look at dot
summary dot summary does something
pretty cool which is it basically runs a
small batch of data through a model and
prints out how big it is
at every every layer and we can see that
at the end of the convolutional section
before we get the flatten it's 512 by 7
by 7
okay and so 512 by 7 5 7 10 serve
breakfast reach answer at that size if
we flatten it out into a single rank one
tensor into a vector it's going to be
225 thousand a ninety eight long right
so then that's why we had this linear
layout to 500 for the bosses right so
stick that on top of a pre-trained
ResNet and trade it for a while okay so
that's where we got to last time so
let's now put those two pieces together
so that we can get something that
classifies and does bounding boxes and
there are there are three things that we
need to do basically to train a neural
network ever right we need to provide
data
we need to pick some kind of
architecture and we did a loss function
okay so the loss function says you know
something anything that gives a lower
number here is a better network using
this data in this architecture so we're
going to need to create those three
things for our classification plus
bounding box regression so that means we
need a model data object which has as
the independence the images and as the
dependence I want to have a tupple the
first time one of the tuples should be
the bounding box coordinates and the
second element as a couple should be
there class okay
there's lots of different ways you could
do this the particularly lazy and
convenient way I came up with was to
create two mobile data objects
representing the two different dependent
variables I want so one with the
bounding box coordinates one of the
classes just using the CSVs we go over
four and now I'm going to merge them
together so I create a new data set
class and a data set class is anything
which has a length and an index service
or something that lets you use it as
like lists and so in this case I can
have a constructor which takes an
existing data set and the second
dependent that I want the length then is
just obviously the length of the data
set the first data set and then getitem
is grab the X and the y from the data
set that I passed in and return that X
and that Y and the ayth of the second so
there's a data set that basically adds
in a second
as I said there's lots of ways you could
do this it's kind of convenient because
now what I could do is I can create
training data set in the validation data
set based on that so here's an example
you can see it's got a couple of the
bounding box coordinates in the class we
can then take the existing training and
validation data loaders now so you
replace their data sets with these and
unknown okay so we can now test it by
grabbing a mini batch of data and
checking it says okay so there's one way
to customize data set so what we're
going to do this time now is we've got
the data so now we need an architecture
so the architecture is going to be the
same as the architectures that were used
for the classifier and for the bounding
box aggression but we're just going to
combine them so in other words if there
are C classes then the number of
activations we need in the final layer
is 4 plus C for panama's coordinates and
the C probabilities one per class so
this is the final layer a linear layer
that has four plus men of categories
divisions the first player is before is
a flattened we could just join those up
together but in general I want my my
custom head to like hopefully be capable
of solving the problem that I give it on
its own if the pre-trained backbone is
connected to is you know is appropriate
and so in this case I'm thinking okay
I'm trying to do quite a bit here two
different things there classifier and
balanced regression so just a single
linear layer doesn't sound like enough
so I put in a second millionaire okay
and so you can see we basically go over
Al you drop out
Lydia rarely veteran or dropout yeah if
you're wondering why there's no better
on that here at
the resonant backbone it already has a
match norm as it's finally out okay so
this is basically nearly the same custom
headers before it's just it's got two
linear layers one and nonlinearities
okay so that's piece to but data we've
got architecture now we need a loss
function so the loss function needs to
look at these four plus C activations
and aside are they good
right are these numbers accurately
reflecting the position and class of the
largest object in this image we we know
how to do that for the last for the
first four we use l1 loss just like we
did in the bounding box regression
before remember l1 loss is like mean
squared error rather than sum of squares
is some of our values and then for the
rest of the activations we can use
cross-entropy loss so let's go ahead and
do that so we're going to create
something called detection loss and loss
functions always take an input and a
target that's what PI torch always calls
them so this is the activations this is
the ground truth so remember that our
our date custom data set returns a tuple
containing the bounding box coordinates
in the classes so we can D structure
that use D structuring assignment to
grab the bounding boxes and the classes
of the target and then the bounding
boxes and the classes of the input are
simply the first four elements of the
input and the four onwards elements of
the universe and remember we've also got
a batch dimension so that's it we've now
got the bounding box target bounding box
import class target plus input further
bounding
boxes we know that they're going to be
between 0 &amp; 2 to 4 the coordinates
because that's how they got images okay
so let's grab a sigmoid to force it
between 0 &amp; 1 multiply it by 2 to 4 and
that's just helping our neural net you
know get close to what we you know be in
the range we know it has to be as a
general rule is it better to put bash
norm before or after RL you I would
suggest that you should put it after a
value because batch norm is meant to
move towards a computer one random
variable and if you put value after it
then you're truncating it 0 so there's
no way to create negative numbers about
a huge port value Lembeck norm
having said that and I think that that
way of doing it gives slightly better
results
having said that it's not too big a deal
either way and you'll see during this
part of the course most of the time I go
well you and then vet norm but sometimes
they go vetch moment in value if I'm
consistent so I think originally the
batch normal is put it off to the
activation so okay so so this is kind of
to help our data or force our data into
the right range which you know if you
can do stuff like that it makes it
easier to Train yes Rachel one more
question
what's the intuition behind using
dropout with P equals 0.5 after a batch
norm does a batch alarm already do a
good job of regularizing fessional
doesn't okay Java vaporizing and if you
think that to part one we have had that
list of things we do to avoid
overfitting and adding batch long as one
of them is david augmentation but it's
perfectly possible that you'll still be
okay
so one nice thing about dropout is that
it has a parameter to say how much to
drop out and so that like parameters are
great like well specifically parameters
that decide how much to regularize
because it lets you build a I speak over
priced model and then decide on
interiorize it so yeah I tend to always
drop out and then if it turns out I'm
you know I'll start with P equals zero
and then as you know I can just change
my grammar without worrying about you
know if I saved a model I'm gonna be
able to load it back but if I have
dropout ladies and one and not in
another or load me more this way it
stays consistent okay so now that I've
got my inputs and targets I can just go
hey calculate the l1 loss and add to it
the cross-entropy
okay so that's our that's our loss
function it's a surprisingly easy brass
now of course the cross entropy and the
l1 lost maybe of wildly different scales
in which case in the loss function the
larger one is going to dominate and so I
just ran this in a debugger checked what
you don't you just use print check how
big each of the two things were and
found if they multiply by 20 that makes
them about the same about the same scale
as your training it's nice to print out
information as you go so I also grabbed
the l1 part of this and put it in our in
a function and I also created a function
for accuracy so that I could make the
metrics and so they're down alright so
we can how about something which is
printing out our object detection loss
detection accuracy and detection l1 and
so chain it for a while and it's looking
good a detection accuracy is in the low
80s which is the same as what it was
before that doesn't surprise me because
like ResNet was designed to do
classification so
I wouldn't expect us to be able to
improve things in such a simple way but
it certainly wasn't designed to do
bounding box regression it was
explicitly actually designed in such a
way is to be as to kind of not care
about geometry rather it takes that last
seven most seven creative activations
and averages them all together and
throws away all of the information that
is going wrong so so you can see that
the when we only train the last layer
the detection l1 is pretty bad running
poor and it really improves a lot but
where else the accuracy doesn't improve
it stays exactly the same
interestingly the l1 when we do accuracy
and bowing boss at the same time 8.5
seems like it's a little bit better than
when we just do bounding box regression
and if that's counterintuitive to you
then this would be one of the main
things to think about after this lessons
it's a really important idea and the
idea is this figuring out figuring out
what the main object in an image is is
kind of the the eye part and then
figuring out like exactly where the
bounding box is and what class it is is
kind of the easy part in a way and so
when you've got a single network that's
about saying what is the object and
where is the object it's going to share
all of the computation about like
finding the object and so all that
shared information all that shared
computation is very efficient and so
when we vet propagate the errors in you
know the class and in the place that's
all information that's going to help the
computation around like finding the
biggest object so anytime you've got
multiple tasks which kind of share some
some concept of what those tasks would
need to do to complete their work it's
very likely they should share at least
some layers of
were together and we'll look later today
a place where most of the layers are
shared but are just the last one isn't
okay so you can see this is some doing a
good job as before of anytime there is
just a single major object sometimes
it's getting a little confused it thinks
the main object here is the dog and it's
kind of served with the dog although
it's kind of recognize that actually the
main object is us so far and so the
classifier is doing the right thing with
the bounding boxes labeling the wrong
thing which is yours when there are two
birds you can only pick one so it's just
kind of hitching in the middle get over
these lots of cows and so forth doing
good job with this car all right so
that's so that's that
all right there's not much new there
although in that last bit we did learn
about you know some simple custom data
sets and simple custom Lots functions
hopefully you can see now how easy that
is to do so next stage for me would be
to do multi-label classification so this
is this idea that I just want to keep
building models that are slightly more
complex than the last model but
hopefully don't require too much extra
concepts so I can kind of keep seeing
things working and if something stops
working I know that wherever I find
building everything at the same time so
model label classification is so easy is
there's not much to mention so we've
moved to a Pascal multi now that's what
we're going to do the multi object stuff
so for the multi object stuff I've just
copied and pasted the functions from the
previous notebook that we used so
they're all at the top so we can create
now a multi class a multi class CSV file
using the same basic approach that we
did last time and I'll mention by the
way one of our students actually who's
visiting from India funny
pointed out to me
that all this stuff we're doing with
default dicks and stuff like that he
actually showed her a way of doing that
which was much simpler using pandas and
he shared that on the forum so I totally
bow to his much better approach simpler
and more concise approach yeah it's
definitely true like the more you get to
know handers the more often you realize
is a good way to solve lots of different
problems so definitely check that out
when you're building out the smaller
models and you're iterating do you reuse
those models as pre-trained waits for
this link larger one or do you just toss
it all away and then retrain from
scratch with when I'm kind of like
figuring stuff out as I go like this I
would generally towards tossing away
because they're kind of reusing
pre-trained weights introduces
complexities that are not really to
think about however if I'm trying to get
to a point where I can run something on
really big images doing these much
smaller ones and often I don't reuse
those ways
okay so in this case what we're doing is
we are just joining up all of the
classes with a space which gives us a
CSV in the normal format and once we've
got the CSV in a normal format it's the
usual three lines of code and we train
it and we've checked the results so
there's literally nothing to show you
yeah and as you can see it's done a
great job the only mistake I think it
made was it called this dog for us it
should have been dog and so far
okay so Maury class classification is is
pretty straightforward one minor tweak
here is to note that I used a set here
because I don't want to list all of the
objects I only want each object type
type here once and so the set plus is a
way of deem cute locating so that's why
I don't have person person person person
person just appears so yeah these sum
these object classification pre-trained
networks we have a really pretty good at
recognizing multiple objects as long as
you only have to mention each one once
so that works pretty well
all right so we've got this idea that
we've got an input image that goes
through a con
ComNet you know which was kind of
treated the black box and it spits out
a tensor vector of size 4 plus C right C
is the number of classes and so that's
what we've got and that gives us a an
object detector for a single object the
largest object Americus
so let's now create one which doesn't
find a single object but that finds 16
objects okay so an obvious way to do
that would be to take this last this is
just a n n dot minion right which has
got however many inputs and 4 plus C
outputs we could take that linear layer
and rather than having 4 plus C outputs
we could have 16 times 4 plus C outputs
so it's now spitting out enough things
to give us 16 sets of class
probabilities and 16 sets of bounding
box coordinates and then we would just
need a loss function that will check
whether those 16 sets of bounding boxes
correctly represented the up to 16
objects that were represented in the
image now there's a lot of hand waving
about the loss function we're going to
it later as to what that is but let's
pretend we have one okay assuming we had
a reasonable loss function that's
totally going to work right that that is
an architecture which has the necessary
output activations but with the correct
loss function we should be at a trainer
to do what we wanted to do okay but
that's just one way to do it there's a
second way we could do it rather than
having a n n dot linear what if instead
we took from our
ResNet convolutional background backbone
not in linear but instead we added a an
end come to D with stride to right so
the final layer of resin app is gets you
a seven by seven by 512 as all right so
this would give us a four by four by
whatever number of filters result maybe
for the number of filters that say we
picked 256 okay so it would be four four
four by four by 256 has well actually
look let's change that let's not make it
four by four by 256 better still let's
do it all in one step let's make it four
by four by four plus C because now we've
got a tensor where the number of
elements is exactly equal to the number
of elements we wanted so in other words
we could we could now this would well to
if we created a loss function that took
a four by four by four plus c tensor and
mapped it to sixteen objects in the
image and checked whether each one was
correctly represented by those four plus
c activations that would work like these
are two exactly equivalent sets of
activations because they've got the same
number of elements they're just reshaped
yeah so it turns out that both of these
approaches are actually used the
approach where you basically just spit
out one big long vector from
fully connected linear layer is used by
a class of models known as yellow where
else the approach of the convolutional
activations is used by models which
started with something called SSD single
what I will say is that since these
things came out of very similar times in
late 2015
things are very much moved towards here
so the point where this morning
Yolo version 3 came out and is now doing
it the SSD ok so that's what we're going
to do right we're gonna do this and
we're gonna learn about why this makes
more sense as well and so the basic idea
is this let's imagine that on top of
underneath this we had another another
come to D stripe 2
and we'd have something which was to buy
to buy again less sales for plus C
alright that's nice and simple and so
basically it's creating a grid that
looks something like this one two three
four okay so that would be like how the
activations are you know the geometry of
the activations of that second extra
convolutional straight - laughs remember
it's fair to convolution does the same
thing to the geometry of the activations
as a stripe one convolution below
biomass pulling okay so let's talk about
what we might do here because the basic
idea is like we want to kind of say
alright this top left grid cell is
responsible for identifying any object
that's in the top of left this one in
the top right is responsible for
identifying something in the top right
this one bottom left this one at the
bottom right okay so in this case you
can actually see it started it said okay
this one is going to try and find the
chair this one that's actually made a
mistake introducing a table but there
are actually one two three chairs here
as well right so basically each of these
grid cells it's going to be told in the
loss function your job is to find the
object you know the big object is in
that part of the image so what so for a
multi-label classification i saw you had
a threshold on there which i guess we're
getting your relative let's let's work
through it okay right so why do we care
about the idea that we would like this
convolutional grid cell to be
responsible for finding things that were
in this part of the image and the reason
is because of something called the
receptive field of that car
and the basic idea is that through
actual convolutional layers every every
piece of those tensors has a receptive
field which means which part of the
input image was responsible for
calculating that cell right and like all
things in life the easiest way to see
this is with Microsoft Excel so do you
remember our convolutional neural net
and this was emilis and we had the
number 7 and it went through a a two
channel filter channel 1 channel 2 which
therefore created a 2 channel output
okay and then the next layer was another
convolution so this tensor is now a 3d
tensor okay which then creates saved
again to channel output and then after
that we had our max pooling layer okay
so let's look at this part of this
output and the fact this is common
followed by max pool let's just pretend
as a stripe to come that's basically the
same so let's see where this number 27
came from so if you've got Excel you can
go formulas trace precedents right and
so you can see this came from these 4
okay now where did those 4 come from
those 4 came from obviously the
convolutional filter Colonel kernels and
from these 4 parts of time one right
because we've got four things here each
one of which has a 3 by 3 filter and so
we have 3 3 3 3 the other boy oh where
did this four come from
those four came from obviously our
filter and this entire part of the input
image okay and what's more you can see
and it also comes through this whole
duration as well and you can see that
these bits in the middle have lots of
weights coming out batgirls these bits
on the outside only have one weight
coming out so we call this here the
receptive field of this activation right
but note that the receptive field is not
just saying it's this here box but also
that the center of the box has more
dependencies so this is a critically
important concept when it comes to kind
of understanding architectures and
understanding why confidence work yeah
of the receptive field and there are
some great articles if you just Google
for convolution receptive field you can
find lots of through the articles I'm
sure some of you will write much better
ones during the week as well so that's
the basic idea there right is that the
receptive field of this convolutional
activation is generally centered around
this part of the input image so it
should be responsible for finding
objects that here so that's the
architecture the architecture is that
we're going to have a resonant backbone
followed by one or more 2d convolutions
and for now we're just going to do one
right which is going to give us a four
by four grid so let's take a look at
that
so here it is we start with our Lu and
drop out we then do at the start at the
output well I just go through and see
what we've got here this one is not
being used we start with a straight one
convolution and the reason we start with
a straight one convolution is because
that doesn't change the geometry at all
it just lets us add an extra layer of
calculations right let's create you know
not just a linear layer but now we have
like a little mini neural network in our
custom here all right so we start with
this dr1 convolution and standard
college is just something i defined up
here which does convolution value
vaginal like most research code you see
won't define a class like this instead
they'll write the entire thing again and
again and again convolution don't be
like that right like that kind of
typical code leads to errors and leads
to poor understanding and I mentioned
that also because this week I released
the first draft of the FASTA a style
guide and the faster I style guide is
very heavily Orion towards the idea of
expository programming which is the idea
that programming code should be
something that you can use to explain an
idea ideally as readily as mathematical
notation to somebody that understands
your your coding method and so the idea
actually goes back a very long way but
it was best described in the Turing
award like Genesis like the Nobel in
computer science the cheering award
lecture of 1979 by probably my greatest
computer science hero can I was he had
been working on a since well well before
in 1964 but 1964 was the first
example of this approach to programming
he released something called APL and
then 25 years later he won the Turing
award he then passed on the baton to his
son Eric Iverson and there's been
basically 50 or 60 years now of
continuous development of this idea of
like what does programming look like
when it's designed to to be a notation
notation as a tool for thought for
expository programming and so I've made
a very shoddy attempt at taking some of
these ideas and thinking about how can
they be applied to - programming with
all the limitations by comparison that
python has anyway so but you know here's
a very simple example is that if you
write all of these things again and
again and again then it really hides the
fact that you've got you know two
convolutional layers one of this dried
one one of this dried - so my default
for standard canvas tried to as a
straight one this is a straight two and
then at the end so this the output of
this is going to be four by four okay
I've got a outcomes and an outcome vis
interesting you can see it's got two
separate convolutional layers each of
which is straight one so it's not
changing the geometry of the input okay
one of them is of length of the number
of classes just ignore K for now K is
equal to K is equal to 1 at this point
in the code so it's not doing anything
so what is equal to the length of the
number of classes one is equal to four
and so this is this idea of rather than
having a single comp layer that outputs
4 plus C let's have two complex one of
which outputs for one of which outputs C
and then I will just return them as a
list of two items that's nearly the same
thing it's nearly the same thing as
having a single column player that
outputs 4 + C but let's
it lets these layers specialize just a
little bit alright so like we talked
about this idea that when you've got
kind of multiple tasks they can share
layers but they don't have to share all
the layers so in this case our two tasks
which is fine create a classifier and
create down paths regression share every
single layer is set the very last one
okay and so this is going to spit out
two separate tensors and activations one
of the classes and one of the
coordinates why am i adding one that's
because I'm going to have one more class
for background right so if there aren't
actually sixteen objects to detect or if
there is an object in this corner
represented by this population or grid
cell then I want you to predict
background so that's the entirety that's
the entirety of our architecture it's
incredibly simple right but the point is
now that we you know we have this
convolutional air at the end one thing I
do do is that I at the very end I
flatten out the convolution basically
because I wrote the loss function to
expect flattened out tensor but I could
totally try doing that during the week
and see which one was easier to
understand okay so we've got our data
we've got our architecture so now all we
need is a loss function okay so the loss
function needs to look at each of these
16 sets of activations each of which
you're going to have four bounding box
coordinates and C plus one class
probabilities and aside are those
activations
close or far away from the object which
is kind of closest to this this this
grid cell in the image and if nothing's
there then you know are you predicting
background correctly so that turns out
to be very hard to do because let's go
back to the 2x2 example to keep it
simple the loss function actually needs
to take each of the objects in the image
and match them to one of these
convolutional grid cells to say like
this grid cell is responsible for this
particular object this grid cell is
responsible for this particular object
so then it can go ahead and say like
okay how close are the four coordinates
and how close are the master
probabilities right so this is called
the matching problem and in order to
explain it I'm going to show it to you
but what I'm going to do first is I'm
going to take a break okay and we're
going to come back and understand the
maxing map the matching problem so
during the break have a think about how
would you design a loss function here
how would you design a function which
has a lower value if these 16 times 4
plus K activations you know somehow
better reflect the up to 16 objects
which are actually in the ground truth
image and we'll come back at 7:40
so here's our goal our dependent
variable basically looks like that
and those are just an extract from our
CSV file trapped in dependence and our
final convolutional layer is going to be
a bunch of numbers which initially is a
four by four I in this case I think C is
equal to twenty plus we've got one for
background right so four plus 21 equals
26 all right four by four okay and then
we we flatten that out into vector we
flatten that out into a vector and so
basically our goal then is to say to
some particular set of activations that
ended up coming out of this model for
some let's let's pick some particular
dependent variable we need some function
that takes in that and that right and
where if it feeds back a higher number
if these activations aren't a good
reflection of the ground truth bounding
boxes or a lower number if it is a good
reflection of the ground through the
bounding boxes that's how cool we need
to create that much and so the general
approach to creating that function will
be to first of all to simplify it down
with the two-by-two version will be the
first of all well actually I'll show you
here's a model I trained earlier okay
and let's run through I've taken the
loss function and I've split it line by
line so that you can see every line that
goes into menu okay so so let's grab our
validation set data loader grab a batch
from it turn them into variables so we
can stick them into a model put the
model in evaluation mode stick that data
into we don't stick that data into our
model to grab a batch of activations and
remember that the final output
convolution returned two items that the
classes and the bounding boxes so we can
do destructuring assignment to grab the
two pieces the batch of classes and
outputs and the batch of bounding box
okay
and so as expected the batch of class
outputs is batch size 64 by 16 grid
cells by 21 classes and then 64 by
sixteen by four through the bounding box
coordinates okay hopefully that all
makes sense and after class go back into
spec sure it's not obvious why these are
the shapes make sure you get to the
point where you understand where they
are let's now go back and look at the
ground truth so the ground truth is is
in this Y variable so let's grab the
bounding box part and the plas part and
put them into these two Python variables
and print them out and so there's our
ground truth bounding boxes and there's
our ground truth classes so this this
image apparently has three objects you
know so let's draw a picture of the
three objects and there they are okay we
already have a show ground truth
function the torch ground truth function
simply converts the tensors into numpy
and passes them on so that we can print
them out so here we've got the bounding
box coordinates you'll notice that
they've all been scaled to zero to what
between 0 and 1 okay so basically we're
treating the image as being like 1 by 1
so these are all relative to the size of
the image there's our three classes and
so here they are chair is 0 dining table
is 1 and 2 is so far this is not a model
this is the ground truth great
here is our 4 by 4 grid cells from our
final convolutional letter so each of
these square boxes different papers call
them different things the three terms
you're here are anchor boxes prior boxes
or default boxes okay and through this
explanation you'll get a sense of what
they are but for now think of them as
just these 16 squares I'm going to stick
with the term anchor boxes ok these 16
squares on our end devices so what we're
going to do for this loss function is
we're going to go through a matching
problem where we're going to take every
one of these 16 boxes and we're going to
see which one of these three round truth
objects has the highest amount of
overlap with this square okay so to do
that we're going to need to know we
really have to have some way of
measuring amount of overload and there's
a standard function for this which is
called the jacquard in this and the
jacquard index is very simple I'll do it
through example let's take this sofa
okay so if we take this sofa and let's
take the jacquard index of this sofa
with this grid cell here all right what
we do is we find the area of their
intersection so
here is the area of their intersection
okay and then we find the area of their
union so here is the area of their unit
smart phone here's the area of their
union okay and then we say take the
intersection divided by the union okay
and so that's jacquard index also known
as iou intersection over all right so of
two things overlap by more compared to
their total sizes together they have a
higher jacquard alright so we're going
to go through and find the jacquard
overlap for each one of these three
objects versus each of these 16 anchor
boxes and so that's going to give us a 3
by 16 matrix but for every ground truth
object and above every anchor box how
much overlap is there so here are the
coordinates of all of our anchor boxes
in this case they're printed as Center
and height width and so here is the
amount of overlap between and as you can
see it's 3 by 16 right so for each of
the three ground truth objects each of
these 16 anchor boxes how much do they
overlap right so you can see here 0 1 2
3 4 5 6 7 8 the 8 anchor box overlaps a
little bit with the second ground truth
object okay so what we could do now is
we could take the max of dimension 1
right so the max of each row and that
will tell us for each ground truth
object what's the maximum amount that
overlaps with some grit zone and it also
tells us remember PI torch when you say
Mets
two things it says what is the max and
what is the index both amass so for each
of these things the 14th grid cell is
the largest is the largest overlap for
the first round truth thirteen for the
second and 11 okay so that tells us you
know a pretty good way of assigning each
of these ground truth objects to a grid
cell what what the matches is which one
is the highest overlap but we're going
to do a second thing we're also going to
look at max over dimensions zero and Max
over dimension zero is going to tell us
what's the maximum amount of overlap for
each grid cell so across all of the
ground truth objects right and so
particularly interesting here tells us
for every grid cell of sixteen what's
the index of the ground truth object
which overlaps with it the most zero is
a bit overloaded here zero could either
mean the amount of overlap was zero or
it could mean its largest overlap is
with object index zero it's going to
turn out not to matter so there's a
function called map to ground truth
which I'm not going to worry about for
now it's it's super simple code but it's
slightly awkward to to think about but
basically what it does is it combines
these two sets of overlaps in a way
described in the SSD paper to assign
every anchor box to a ground truth
object and basically the way of the
signs that is each of these ones each of
these three gets assigned in this way
right so this one this object is
assigned to bound to anchor box 14 this
one to 13 and this one through 11 and
then of the rest of the anchor boxes
they get assigned to anything which they
have an overlap of at least point 5
with if anything that doesn't which
isn't in either of those criteria ie
either isn't a maximum or doesn't have a
greater than 0.5 overlap is considered
to be a cell which contains background
okay so that's all the map to ground
truth motion does and so after we go
through it you can see now a list of all
of the assignments and you can also see
anywhere that there's a zero here it
means it was assigned a background in
fact anywhere it's less than point five
here give us a sign in the background so
you can see those three which kind of
forced assignments that puts a high
number in just to make sure all of their
assigned all right so we can now go
ahead and convert those two classes and
then we can make sure we just grab those
which are at least point five in size
and so finally that allows us to spit
out the three pluses that are being
predicted we can then put that back into
the bounding boxes and so here are what
each of those bounding boxes is sorry
what each of those anchor boxes is meant
to be predicting okay so you can see
sofa dining room table chair which makes
perfect sense if we go back to here this
is meant to be predicting so far this is
over this is meant to be predicting
dining room table this has been to be
predicting chair and everything else has
been to be predicting background so
that's the matching stage
so once we've done the matching stage
we're basically done we can take the
activations just grab those which which
matched that's what this positive
indexes are subtract from those the
ground truth bounding boxes just for
those which matched positive ones take
the absolute value of the difference
take the mean of that and that's not one
loss and then for the classifications we
can just do a cross entropy and then
before we can add them together okay so
that's the basic idea there's a few and
so this is this is what's going to
happen right we're going to end up with
16 recommended you know predicted
bounding boxes coming out most of them
will be background see all these ones
that say BG but from time to time
they'll say this is a cow this is potted
plant this is par okay if you're
wondering like what does it predict in
terms of the bounding box of background
the answer is a totally ignores it right
that's why we had this only positive
indexes thing here right so if it's
background there's no you know sense of
like where's the correct bounding box in
background that's totally meaningless so
the only ones where the bounding box
makes sense out of all these are the
ones that there are some important
literal tweets what is that the how do
we interpret the activations and so the
way we interpret the activations is
defined here in activation two bounding
box and so basically we grab the
activations we stick them throughthe an
and so remember fan is the same as
sigmoid shape except it's scaled to be
between negative 1 and 1
but read zero okay so it's basically a
sigmoid function that goes between
negative one and one and so that forces
it to be within that range and we then
say okay let's grab the the actual
position of the anchor boxes and we will
move them around according to the value
of the activations divided by two so in
other words each each each activate each
edge as predicted bounding box can be
moved by up to fifty percent of a grid
size from where its default position is
and ditto for its height and width it
can be up to twice as being all half as
big as its default size so so that's one
thing is we have to convert the
activations into some kind of way of
scaling those default length of box
positions another thing is we don't
actually use cross entropy we actually
use binary cross entropy loss okay so
remember binary cross entropy loss is
what we normally use for multi-label
classification like in the planet amazon
satellite competition each satellite
image you could have multiple things in
it okay so if it's got multiple things
in it you can't use soft max because
soft max kind of really encourages just
one thing to have in our case each
anchor box can only have one object
associated with it so it's it's not for
that reason that we're avoiding song max
it's something else which is it's
possible for an anchor box to have
nothing associated with it so there'd be
two ways to handle that is this either
at background one would be to say you
know what backgrounds just a class right
so let's use soft max right and just
treat background as one of the classes
that the soft max could could predict a
lot of people have done it this way I
don't like that though right because
that's a really hard thing to ask of
your network do
it's basically to say can you tell
whether this grid cell doesn't have any
of the 20 objects that I'm interested
with a jacquard overlap of more than 0.5
now that's a really hard thing to put
into a single computation on the other
hand what if we just had for each class
you know is it a motorbike is it a bus
is it a person it's the bird is it a
dining room table right and then it can
check each of those would be no no no no
and it snowed all of them and it's like
oh it's background all right so that's
that's the way I'm doing it is it's not
that we could have multiple true labels
but we can have 0 and so that's what's
going on here we take our target and we
do a one hot embedding with number of
classes plus 1 so this stage we do have
the idea of background but then we
remove the last problem so the Batman
columns now gone right and so now this
vectors either of all zeros basically
meaning there's nothing here or it has
at most one one and so then we can use
binary cross-entropy
predictions with that that is a minor
tweak right but like it's the kind of
minor tweak that I I want you to think
about and understand because it's a
really like it makes a it makes a really
big difference in practice to your
training and it's the kind of thing that
you'll see a lot of papers talk about
like often when there's some increment
over some previous paper it'll be
something like this that we somebody to
realize this like Oh trying to predict a
background category using a soft mass is
really hard to do what if we use the
binary cross-entropy instead you know
and so it's kind of like if you
understand what this is doing and more
importantly why
yeah that's a really good test of your
understanding of the material and if you
don't that's fine Brad just shows you
this is something that you need to let
me go back and re-watch this part of the
video and talk to some of your
classmates and if necessary ask for the
forum and sure you understand what are
we doing okay so that's what this that's
what this binary cross entropy loss loss
function is doing so basically in this
part of the code we've got this custom
loss function we've got the thing that
calculates the declared index we've got
the thing that converts activations to
bounding balls we've got the thing that
does map to ground truth okay and that's
it all that's left is the SSD loss
function so the SSD loss function this
is actually what we set yeah as they are
crit as our criterion is SSD
so what SSD lost class is it it loops
through each image in the minivan and it
calls SSD one loss so Assisting loss for
one image so this function is really
where it's all happening this is
calculating the SSD loss for one image
so we D structure our bounding box in
class and basically there's a what is
this doing here actually this is worth
mentioning a lot of code you find out
there on the Internet
doesn't work with mini-batches you know
it only does like one thing at a time
so in this case we you know all this
stuff is working it's not exactly a mini
batch at a time it's on a whole bunch of
ground truth objects at a time and the
data loader is being fed a mini batch at
a time to do or the convolutional layers
because we could have different numbers
of ground truth objects in each image
but a tensor has to be the strict
rectangular shape fast AI automatically
with zeros anything that's not the same
life thing I fairly recently added but
it's super handy almost no other
libraries do that but that does mean
that you then have to make sure that you
get rid of those zeros right so you can
see here I'm checking to find all of the
all of the non zeros and I'm only
keeping those this is just getting rid
of any of the bounding boxes that are
actually I'm just padding yeah okay so
get rid of the padding turn the
activations bounding boxes do the
jacquard doing about this is all the
stuff we just went through it's on line
by line underneath right check that
there's an overlap greater than
something around 0.4 0.5 different
papers use different values for this
find the things that match but the class
put the background class for those and
then finally get the l1 loss for the
localization part get the binary
cross-entropy boss for the
classification part turn those two
pieces and then finally add them
together so that's a lot going on and it
might take a few watches of the video to
in the code to fully understand it but
the basic idea now is that we now have
the things we need we have the data we
have the architecture and we have the
loss function so now we've got those
three things we can train my finder and
train for a bit and we get down to 25
and the end we can see how we went
so obviously this isn't quite what we
want when we do practice we'd kind of
remove the background ones or some
threshold but it's like it's on the
right track there's a dog in the middle
let's go to 0.34 there's a bird here in
the middle of 0.94
you know something's working okay yeah
I've got a few concerns I don't think
it's
I don't see anything saying motorcycle
here it says bicycle which is in great
there's nothing for the potted plant
that's big enough but that's not
surprising because all of our anchor
boxes were small they were 4x4 grid so
to go from here to something that's
going to be more accurate what we're
gonna do is to create way more and the
buses okay so there's a couple of ways
we can create quick question and I'm
just getting lost in the fact that the
anchor boxes in the bounding boxes are
how are they not the same I must be
missing something
anchor boxes are the square the fixed
square grid cells these are the anchor
boxes they're in an exact specific
unmoving location the bounding boxes are
these are three things the bounding
boxes these 16 things at anchor boxes
okay so we're going to create lots more
anchor bosses so there's three ways to
do that and I've kind of drawn some of
them printed some of them here one is to
create anchor boxes of different sizes
and orientations so here you can see you
know there's a upright rectangle there's
a line down rectangle and there's a
square it's a question for the
multi-label classification why aren't we
multiplying the categorical loss by a
constant like we did before that's a
great question because later on it'll
turn out we don't need to
so yeah so you can see here like this
square and so I don't know if you can
see this blue shield up you basically
got one two three squares of different
sizes and for each of those three
squares you've also got a line down
rectangle and up rectangle that's we've
got three aspect ratios at three zoom
levels
that's why don't you do we can do this
and this is for the one by one grid so
in other words if we added two more
strata convolutional layers you
eventually get to a one by one grid and
so this is for the one by one include
another thing we could do is to use more
compositional layers as sources of
anchor boxes so as well as our and I've
I've randomly gated these a little bit
so it's easy to see right so as well as
our 16 by 16 grid cells these cells
we've also got two by two grid cells and
we've also got the one by one itself
alright so in other words if we add
three straight hours prior to
convolutions to the to the end we'll
have 4 by 4 2 by 2 and 1 by 1 sets of
grid cells all of which have anchor
boxes and then for every one of those we
can have all of these different shapes
and sizes okay so obviously those two
combined with each other to create lots
of anchor boxes and if I try to print
that on the screen is just one big toss
so that's what this code is right it
says all right what are all the grid
cell sizes I have for the anchor boxes
what are all the zoom levels I have for
the anchor boxes and what are all the
aspect ratios I have for the anchor
boxes and the rest of this code then
just goes away and creates the top left
and bottom right corners inside anchor
corner and the middle and height width
in mecca's so that's all this does and
you can go through it and print out the
anchor
in a corner so the key the key is to
remember this basic idea that we have a
vector of ground truth stuff right where
that stuff is like sets of four bounding
boxes this is what we were given it was
in the JSON files that it's the ground
truth it's the dependent variable sets
of four bounding boxes and for each one
also a class right so this is a person
in this location this is a dog in this
location that's the ground truth that
we've given yes yeah exactly left X Y
bottom right X Y so that's what we
printed here right we print it out this
is what we call the ground truth there's
no model this is what we're told is what
we this is what the answer is meant to
be and so remember any time we train an
ear on that we have a dependent variable
and then we have a neuro nap from
blackbox neural net that takes some
input and spits out some output
activations and we take those
activations and we compare them to the
ground truth we calculate a loss we find
the derivative of that and adjust the
weights according to the derivative
times a learning rate okay
so the loss is calculated using a must
function something I wanted to say is I
think them one of the challenges with
this problem is part of what's going on
here is we're having to come up with an
architecture that's letting us predict
this ground truth like it's not because
you can have you know any number of
objects in your picture it's not an you
know immediately obvious like oh what's
the correct architecture that's gonna
let us predict that sort of ground truth
that's so I'm gonna kind of make this
plain as we saw when we looked at the
kind of Yolo versus SSD that like there
are only two possible architectures the
last layer is fully connected or the
last layer is convolutional and both of
them work perfectly well I'm sorry I
meant in terms of by creating this idea
of anchor boxes and anchor boxes with
different locations locations and sizes
that's giving you a format that kind of
lets you get to the activations you're
right like high level is that you see
okay so that's that's really entirely in
the loss function not in the
architecture like and if we use the Yolo
architecture where we had a fully
connected layer like literally there
would be no concept of geometry at all
right so I would suggest like kind of
forgetting the architecture and just
like treated as just a given it's a
theme that is spitting out 16 times 4
plus C activations right and then I
would say our job is to figure out how
to take those 16 times 4 plus C
activations and compare them to our
ground truth which is like 4 plus it's 4
plus 1 but if it was one hot encoded it
would be C and I think that's easier to
think about so call it 4 plus C times
however many ground truth objects there
are for that particular image all right
so let's pour that
right so we need a loss function that
can take these two things and spit out a
number that says how good are these
activations that that's that's what
we're trying to do so to do it we need
to take each one of these M ground truth
objects and decide which set of 4 plus C
activations is responsible for that
object which one should we could be
comparing and saying like yes the right
class will not and yeah it's false or
not and so the way we do that is
basically to say okay let's decide the
first for the first 4 plus C activations
are going to be responsible for
predicting the bounding box of the thing
that's closest to the top left and the
last 4 plus C you'll be predicting those
the furthest to the bottom right and
kind of everything in between so this is
this matching and then of course we're
not using the yellow approach where we
have a single vector we're using the SSD
approach where we spit out a
convolutional output which means that
it's it's not arbitrary as to which we
mash up but actually we want to match up
the set of activations whose receptive
field most closely reflects you know as
the maximum density from where this real
object is but that's a that's a minor
tweak you know I guess like that it
that's the easy way to have taught this
but if we just start with the Yolo
approach where it's just like an
arbitrary vector and we can decide which
activations correspond to which agree on
trees object as long as it's consistent
it's going to be a consistent rule
because like if in the first image the
top left
object corresponds with the first four
plus C activations and then the second
image we threw things around and
suddenly it's now going with the last
four plus the activations the neural net
doesn't know what to learn about that
the neural net needs to like a loss
function needs to be like some
consistent task right which in this case
the consistent task is try to make these
activations reflect the bounding box in
this general area that's basically what
this loss function is trying to do is it
purely coincident that you know the 4x4
in the kong-kong 2d is the same thing as
no you're 16 not at all coincidence it's
it's because though that 4x4 comp is
going to give us activations whose
receptive field corresponds to those
locations in the infinite so it's it's
carefully designed now remember I told
you before part two that like the stuff
we learn in part two is going to assume
that you are extremely comfortable with
everything you learnt in part one and
for a lot of you you might be realizing
now maybe I wasn't quite as familiar
with the starting part one as I first
thought and that's fun right but just
realize you might just have to go back
and really think deeply it's there more
with understanding with life what are
the inputs and outputs to each layer and
a convolutional Network how big are they
one of their rank is that V how are they
calculated so that you really fully
understand the idea receptive field
what's a loss function really how does
back propagation work exactly like these
things all need to be like deeply felt
intuitions but you only get through to
practice and once they're all deeply
felt intuitions then you can we watch
this video and you'll be like oh I see
okay
see that you know these activations just
need some way of understanding what task
they're being given that is being done
by the loss function and the loss
function is encoding a task and so the
task of the SSD loss function is
basically two parts part one is figure
out which ground truth object is closest
to which grid cell which anchor boss
when we where we started doing this the
grid cells of the convolution and the
anchor boxes were the same right but now
we're starting to introduce the idea
that we can have multiple anchor boxes
per grid cell okay a little bit more
complicated so every ground truth object
we have to figure out which anchor boxes
are closest to every anchor box we have
to decide which ground truth object
isn't responsible for if any and once
we've done that matching it's trivial
now we just basically go through and
going back to the single object
detection it now is just this it's once
we've got every ground truth object mesh
to anchor box to a set of activations we
can basically didn't say okay what's the
cross entropy loss of the categorical
part
what's the r-1 loss so really it's the
matching part which is kind of I don't
know kind of slightly surprising bit and
then this idea of picking those in a way
that the convolutional Network gives it
the best opportunity to calculate that
part of the space is then the final
cherry on top
and this um I'll tell you something else
this class is by is by far I think going
to be the most conceptually challenging
and part of the reason for that is that
after this we're going to go and do some
different stuff and we're going to come
back to it in lesson 14 and do it again
with some tweaks alright we're gonna add
in some of the new stuff we learned
afterwards so you're gonna get like a
whole second round for this material
once we add some some extra stuff at the
end so we kind of dinner revise it as we
normally do remember in part 1 we kind
of went through computer vision and RP
structured data back to NLP back to
computer vision you know so we revised
everything from this at the end it'll be
kind of similar yeah so yeah so don't
worry if it's a bit challenging in fist
you'll get there
okay so so for every grid cell there can
be different sizes we can have different
orientations and zooms representing
different different anchor boxes which
are just like conceptual ideas that
basically every one of these is
associated with one set of four plus e
activations in a model right so however
many of these ground truth boxes we have
we need to have that x 4 plus C
activations in the model now that does
not mean that each convolutional layer
needs that many filters right because
remember the 4x4 convolutional layer
already has 16 sets of filters the 2x2
accomplished layer already has four sets
activations and then finally the one by
one has one set
so we basically get 1 plus 4 plus 16 for
free just because that's how convolution
works it that relates things at
different locations so we actually only
need to know K where K is the number of
zooms by the number of aspect ratios
where else the grids we're gonna get for
free through our architecture so let's
check out that architecture so the model
is nearly identical to what we had
before all right that we're gonna go
we're going to have a number of strive
to convolutions which is going to take
us through to 4 by 4 2 by 2 1 by 1 you
straight to convolution perhaps our grid
sizes okay and then after we do our
first convolution to get to 4 by 4 we're
going to grab a set of outputs from that
because we want to save away the 4 by 4
which anchors and then once we get to 2
by 2 we grab another set now two by two
anchors and then finally we get to 1 by
1 and we saw we get another set of the
Ovilus right so you can see we've got
like a whole bunch of these outcome this
first one we actually not easy so at the
end of that we can then concatenate
torque at concatenate them all together
so we've got the four by four
activations the two by two activations
the one by one and visions so that's
going to give us the correct number of
activations to give us one activation
for every for every bounding a periphery
anchor boss
so then we just set our criterion as
before to SSD loss and we go ahead and
train right and the way we go so in this
case I'm just printing out those things
with at least probability of point one
and you can see we've got some things
booked okay some things don't our big
objects like bird we've got a box here
with a point nine three probability it's
looking to be in about the rest but our
person is looking pretty hopeful but our
motorbike has nothing at all a lot of
plants looking pretty horrible that bus
is all the wrong size what's going on so
but what's going on here will tell us a
lot about the kind of history of object
detection and so these five papers are
key steps in the history recent modern
history of our vegetation and so they go
back to a balance of maybe 2013 this
paper called scalable object detection
using deep neural networks this is what
basically set everything up and when
people refer to the multi box method
they're talking about this paper and
this was the basic one that came up with
this idea that we can have a loss
function that has this matching process
and then you can kind of use that to do
object addition so everything since that
time has been trying to figure out
basically how to make this better so in
parallel as a guy quarter Oscar shik who
was going down a totally different
direction which was he had these
two-stage processes where the first
stage used like classical computer
vision approaches to like fine kind of
edges and changes of gradients and stuff
to kind of guess which parts of the
image may represent us
objects and then fit each of those into
a convolutional neural network which was
basically designed to figure out is that
actually the kind of object I'm
interested in and so this was the kind
of our CNN and fast
I see a hybrid of traditional computer
vision and so what Russ and his team
then did was they basically took this
multi box IDE the air and replaced the
traditional non deep learning computer
vision part of their two-stage process
with a confident so they now have two
conquers one comp net that basically
sped out something like this which we
call these region proposals you know all
of the things that might be objects and
then the second part was the same as his
earlier work because basically something
the top each of those fitted into a
separate part net which was designed to
classify whether or not that particular
thing really isn't interesting at a
similar time these two papers came out
Yolo and SSD now both of these did
something pretty cool which is they got
the same kind of performance is faster a
CNN but with once - okay and so they
basically took the multi boss idea and
they tried to figure out how to deal
with this mess it's done and the basic
ideas were to use for example called
hard-
mining where they would like go through
and find all of the matches that didn't
look that good and further away has some
very tricky and complex data
augmentation methods all kinds of
hackery
basically but they got it to work pretty
pretty well but then through really cool
happened late last year which is this
thing called focal versus paper
philosophy dense object attention the
network object is called written written
where they actually realized why this
messy crap wasn't working and I'll
describe why dismissive fat loss by
trying to describe why it is that we
can't find the motive a so here's the
thing when we look at this we have three
different granularities of convolutional
route four by four two by two one by one
the one by one it's quite likely to have
a reasonable overlap with some object
because most photos have sometimes main
so - okay on the other hand in the four
by four those sixteen grid cells
unlikely most of them are not going to
have a much of an overlap with anything
like in this motor pipe cases guys so if
somebody was to say to you like you know
20-buck bet what do you reckon this
little quick is you know and you're not
sure you're gonna say background because
most of the time in this background
right and so here's the thing
okay I understand why we have a four by
four grid of receptive fields with one
anchor box each to coarsely localize
objects in the image but I think I'm
missing is why we need multiple
receptive fields at different sizes
the first version already included 16
receptive fields each with a single
anchor box associated with the addition
there are now many more anger boxes to
consider is this because you constrain
how much a receptive field could move or
scale from its original size or is there
another reason it's kind of backwards
the reason I did the constraining was
because I knew I was going to be adding
more boxes later but really the reason
is that
the jacquard overlap between one of
those 4x4 grid cells and you know a
picture a single object that takes out
most of the image is never going to be
0.5 because like the intersections much
smaller than the Union because the
object is too big so for this general
idea to work where we're saying like
you're responsible for something that
you've got a better than 50% overlap
with we need anchor boxes which which
will on a regular basis have a 50% or
higher overlap which means we need to
have a variety of sizes and shapes and
scales yeah so this is this this this
all happens this all happens in the last
match basically the vast majority of the
interesting stuff in all of the object
detection stuff is the loss function
because there is only three things last
function architecture so the this is the
focal most paper for kalasa dense object
detection from August 2017 his Ross
Perik still doing this stuff coming her
you might recognize as being the the
rezneck guy a bit of an all-star cast
here and this the key thing is this very
first picture the blue line is a picture
of binary cross-entropy loss the x-axis
is what is the probability or what is
the activation what is the probability
of the ground truth class so it's
actually a motorbike I said with point
six chance
it's a motorbike or it's actually not a
motorbike and I said with plot point six
chance so this blue line represents the
level of the value of cross-entropy loss
so you can draw this in Excel or Python
or whatever
a simple plot of cross-entropy loss so
the point is if the answer is because
remember we do in binary custom to be
lost if the answer is not a motorbike
and I said yeah I think it's not a
motorbike I'm point six sure it's not a
motorbike this blue line is still it
like a loss at about 0.5 it's it's it's
it's there's a lot of it's still pretty
bad right so I actually have to keep
getting more and more confident that
it's not a motorbike so if I want to get
my loss down then for all of these
things which are actually background I
have to be saying like I am sure that
background you know or I'm sure it's not
a motorbike or a bus or a person or a
diagram there because if I don't say I'm
sure it's not any of these things then I
still get plus so that's why this
doesn't work all right this doesn't work
because even when it gets to here and it
wants to say I think it's a motorbike
there's no payoff for it to say so
because if it's wrong right and it kick
it it gets killed and the vast majority
of the time it's not anything the vast
majority of time its background and even
if it's not background it's not enough
just to say it's not background you're
gonna say which of the 20 things it is
right so for the really big things it's
fine because that's the one by one grid
you know so it's it generally is a thing
and you just have to figure out which
thing it is where else for these small
ones and generally it's not anything so
generally small ones we just prefer to
be like I've got nothing to say no
comment okay so that's why this is empty
and that's why even when we do have a
bus right it's using a really big grid
cell to say it's a bus because these are
the only ones where it's like confident
enough to make a call that something
right because the small grid cells it
very rarely is something so the trick is
to try and find a different loss
function instead of binary cross which
we lost it doesn't look like the blue
line but it looks more like the green or
purple line and they actually end up
suggesting the purple line and so it
turns out this is cross-entropy loss
negative log PT focal loss is simply 1
minus PT to the gamma where gamma is
some parameter right and they recommend
using 2 times the cross entropy loss
that's it's literally just a scaling and
so that takes you to if you use camera
that's true that takes you to this
purple line so now if we say yeah I'm
point 6 sure that it's not a motorbike
than the loss function is way good for
you no worries
ok so that's what we want to do we want
to replace cross entropy loss with
vocalist and I mentioned a couple of
things about this fantastic paper the
first is like the actually contour the
actual contribution of this paper is to
add Y minus P to the gamma to the start
of this equation which sounds like
nothing right but actually people have
been trying to figure out this down
problem for years that and I'm not even
sure that realize it's a problem there's
just this assumption that you know
object detection is really hard and you
have to do all of these complex data
augmentations and have- mining and blah
blah blah to get the damn thing to work
so a it's like this recognition of like
but why are we doing all those things
and then this realization is I'm like oh
if I do that it goes away it's fixed
alright so when you come across a paper
like this which is like game-changing
you shouldn't assume you're gonna have
to write 100 thousand lines of code very
often is one line of code or the change
of a single constant or adding log to a
single class
so let's go down to the bit where it all
happens where they describe personal
loss and I just wanted to point out a
couple of terrific things about this
paper the first is here is their
definition of cross-entropy and if
you're not able to write cross-entropy
on a piece of paper right now then you
need to go back and study it because
we're going to be assuming that you know
what it is what it means why it's that
what the shape of it looks like
cross-entropy appears everywhere binary
cross-entropy
and kind of variable cross entropy and
the softmax that most people most of the
time we'll see cross entropy written as
like an indicator on y Times log K plus
an indicator on Y minus y times y minus
PE this is like kind of awkward notation
often people we use that Dirac Delta
functions like that or else this this
paper just says you know what it's just
a conditional the cross yet repeat
simply is a lot negative luck P of Y is
1 negative 1 1 minus P of us so this is
y is 1 if it's a motorbike 0 or not in
this paper they say what if it's about
by 4 negative 1 and then they do
something which mathematicians never do
they refactor all right check us out hey
what if we replace what if we define a
new term called PT which is equal to the
probability if Y is 1 or 1 minus P
otherwise if we did that we could now
redefined seee as that we're just super
cool like it's such an obvious thing to
do but as soon as you do it all of the
other equations get simpler as well
because later on straight at the
variants paragraph they say hey one way
to deal with class in balance ie lots of
stuff is background would just be to
have a different weighting factor the
background this is not so like
for class one you know we'll have some
number alpha + 4 + 0 will have 1 minus
alpha but then they're like hey let's
define alpha to you the same way and so
now our cross entropy well you know with
a weighting factor like this and so then
they can wrap their focal loss with the
same concept and then eventually they
say hey let's take focal loss and
combine it with class waiting like so
yeah so often when you see in a paper
huge big equations it's just because
mathematicians don't know how to be back
though and you'll see like the same
pieces are kind of repeated all over the
place right very very very often and by
the time you've turned it into non pile
code suddenly is super simple so this is
a million times better than so great
paper to read to understand how papers
should be a terrible paper to read to
understand what most his long rap okay
so let's try this we're going to use
this yeah now remember negative log P is
the cross entropy loss so therefore this
is just equal to some number times the
cross entropy loss and when I defined
the binomial cross entropy loss if you
remember or if you noticed I had a
weight which by default was none right
and when you call binary cross entropy
Swaggart's pipe torch thing you can
optionally pass in the web this is
nothing that's more applied by
everything and if it's none then there's
no work so since we're just going to
multiply across entropy by something we
can just define get away
so here's the entirety this is the thing
that like suddenly made object detection
business okay so this was late last year
suddenly it got rid of all of the
complex messy pattern right and so
sigmoid is that PT is W and here you can
see 1 minus P 2 e to the power of gamma
right so we're gonna hammer of to our
first point 2 5 if you're wondering why
this paper because they tried lots of
different values of gamma and alpha and
they found that 2 and 0.25 work well
okay so there's our new loss function it
derives from our BC loss adding a weight
to it focal loss other than that there's
nothing else to do we could just train
our model again okay and so this time
things are looking quite a bit better
you know we now have motor bike bicycle
person motorbike like it's it's actually
having a go at finding something yeah
it's still doing a good job with big
ones in fact it's looking quite a lot
better it's finding quite a few people
it's finding a couple of different birds
it's looking pretty good right so our
last step is for now is to basically
figure out how to pull out just the
interesting stuff like let's take this
barking this sofa right how do we pick
out a dog and a sofa and the answer is
incredibly simple all we're going to do
is we're going to be going to go through
every pair of these bounding boxes and
if they overlap by more than some amount
say 0.5 using jacquard and they both
predict in the same class we're going to
assume that the same thing
and we're just got to pick the one with
the higher p-value and we just keep
doing that repeatedly that's really
boring code I actually didn't write it
myself I copied it on somebody else's
code non maximum suppression yes no
reason particularly to go through it but
that's one of us okay
so we can now show the results of the
non maximum suppression and yeah here's
the sofa here's the dog yeah yes the
bird is the person this person cigarette
looks like it's firework this one it's
like it's okay but not great like it's
found a person and his bicycle of a
person and his bicycle with his bicycle
in the wrong place place you know you
can also see that like some of these
smaller things that lower p-values the
top button where the back of just point
one sticks this is same time of bus so
there's something still two things here
right and the trick will be to use
something called featured here and
that's what we're going to do in less
than 14 what I wanted to do in the last
few minutes of class was to talk a
little bit more about the papers and
specifically to go back to the SSD paper
okay so this is single-shot multipass
detector and when this came out I was
very excited because it was kind of you
know it and Yolo were like you know the
first kind of single pass good quality
object detection methods that come along
and so I kind of ignored object
detection until this time or this to
pass stuff with
and then fast our CNN and faster us you
know because there's been as kind of
continuous repetition of history and the
deep learning world which is things that
involve multiple passes of multiple
different pieces over time you know
particularly where they involve some
long deep learning pieces like over time
they basically always get turned into a
single end-to-end deep learning model so
I tend to kind of like ignore them until
that happens because that's the point
where it's like okay now people have
figured out how to show this as a deep
learning problem as soon as people do
that they generally end up something
it's much faster and much more accurate
and so SSD and Yolo were really
important so here's the SSD paper let's
go down to the key piece which is where
they describe the model and let's try
and understand it so the model is
basically one two three four paragraphs
right so tape is a really concise mat
which means that you kind of need to
read them pretty carefully partly though
you need to know which bits to read
carefully so the bits where they say
here we're going to prove the error
bounds on this model you could ignore
that right because you don't care about
proving the intervals but the bit which
says here is what the model is careful
so here's the bit called model and so
hopefully you'll find we can now read
this together and understand it so SSD
is a feed-forward content and it creates
a fixed size collection of bounding
boxes and scores for the presence of
object class instances in those boxes so
fixed size that ie the the convolutional
great time
okay you know different aspect ratios
and stuff and each one of those has 4
plus C activations followed by a non
maximum suppression step to take that
massive gump and turn it into you know
just a couple of novel adding different
objects the early layer is based on the
standard architecture so we just use
rest man this is pretty standard as you
know you can kind of see this consistent
theme particularly in kind of how the
pasta you know library tries to do
things which is like grab a pre trade
network that already does something pull
off the envious decant a new enemy all
right so early network players we use
the standard classifier truncate the
classification layers as we've always do
that automatically when we use Carmona
and we call this the base Network some
campers call that the backbone and we
then add an auxilary structure okay so
the auxiliary structure which we call
the custom head has multi scale feature
nests so we add compositional layers to
the end of this base Network and they
decrease in size progressively so a
bunch of side to convice so that allows
predictions of detections and multiple
scales the grid cells are different size
it is the model is different for each
feature layer compared to Yolo that
operate on a single feature so you're
low as we discussed dispenser is one
vector for us we have different harmless
H added feature layer gives you a fixed
set of predictions using a bunch of
filters for a filter layer where the
grid size is n by n 4x4 with pay
channels where in fact let's take the
pick as well seven by seven with 512
panels the basic element is going to be
a three by three by P cone which in our
case is a three by three
by four for the shape offset bit or
three by three by C for the score for
category vision that's so those are
those three those are those two pieces
at each of those grid cell locations
it's going to produce an output value
and the bounding box offsets measured
relative to that default cost position
which we've been calling an anchor box
position relative to the feature mount
location what we've been calling the
grid cell okay as opposed to Yolo right
which has a fully connected layer and
then they go on to describe the default
boxes what they are for each feature now
cell organs in grid cell they Tyrell the
picture map in a convolutional manner so
the position of each box relative to its
grid cell is best so hopefully you can
see you know we end up with C plus 4
times K filters if there are K boxes at
each location okay so these are similar
to the anchor bosses so like if you jump
straight in and read a paper like this
without knowing like only solving and
Maya solving yet when what's the kind of
man acted shirt circle those four
paragraphs would probably make almost no
sense but now that we've gone through it
you read those four paragraphs and
hopefully you're thinking oh that's just
what Jeremy said only they said it
better than Jerry and less words okay so
so I have the same problem when I
started reading the SST paper and I read
those four paragraphs and I didn't have
before this time much of a background in
object notation because I decided to
wait until she passed me more and so I
read this and I was like what the hell
right and so the trick is to then start
reading back over the citation
right so for example and you should go
back and read this paper now look here's
the matching strategy but and that all
matching strategy that I somehow spent
like it now we're talking about that's
just a paragraph but it really is right
for each ground truth we select from
default boxes based on location aspect
ratio and scale we match each ground
truth to the default box with the best
jacquard overlap and then we met two
default boxes - anything with jacquard
over that I own printer that's it that's
the one sentence version and then we've
got the loss function which is basically
to say take the average of the last
based on classes plus the lost based on
localization with some weighting factor
now with focal loss I found I didn't
really need the weighting factor anymore
they both but in this case as I started
reading this I didn't really understand
exactly what LMG and all this stuff was
but it says well this is derived from
the more t-bar subjective so then I went
back to the paper that defined Modi bas
and I found in their proposed approach
they've also got a section called
training objective also known as loss
function and here I can see it's the
same notation l GE and so this is where
I can go back and see the detail and
after you read a bunch of papers you'll
start to see things very quickly for
example when you see these double bars -
- you'll realize every time there's mean
squared error that's how you're right
mean square error right this is actually
called the two norm the two long is just
the sum of squared differences right and
then there's two up here means normally
they take the square root so we just
don't do this so this is just M SC all
right anytime you see like oh yes a lot
of C and his
see you know that's basically a binary
cross-entropy
right so it's like you you're not
actually gonna have to read every day at
every equation right you are kind of a
bit at first
right but after a while your brain just
like immediately knows basically what's
going on and then I say oh I've got a
Luxio panel of 1 minus C and as expected
I should have my X and here's my 1 minus
X okay there's all the pieces there that
I would expect to see
so then having done that that then kind
of allowed me okay and then they get
combined with the two pieces and oh
there's the multiplier that I expected
and so now I can kind of come back here
understand what's going on okay so we're
going to be looking at a lot more papers
right but maybe this week go through the
code and go through the paper all right
and be like what's what's going on and
remember what I did to make it easier
for you was I took that loss function I
copied it into a cell and it has lit it
up so that each bit was in a separate
cell and then after every cell I other
printed or plotted that value that so if
I hadn't have done that for you you
should do it yourself right like if
there's no way you can understand these
functions without trying putting things
in single time yeah okay so hopefully
this is kind of a good good start okay
well thanks everybody have a great week
see you next Monday