what a start pointing out a couple of
the many cool things that happen this
week one thing that I'm really excited
about is we briefly talked about how
Leslie Smith has a new paper out and it
basically the paper goes text is
previous to key papers are cyclic or
learning rates and super convergence and
built on them with a number of
experiments to show how how you can
achieve super convergence and so super
convergence lets you train models five
times faster than previous like kind of
stepwise approaches it's not 5 times
faster than CLR but it's faster than CLR
as well and the key is that super
convergence lets you get up to like
massively high learning rates by
somewhere between 1 and 3 which is quite
amazing and so the interesting thing
about super convergence is that it you
actually train at those very high
learning rates for quite a large
percentage of your ybox and during that
time the loss doesn't really improve
very much but the trick is like it's
doing a lot of searching through the
space to find really generalizable areas
it seems so those we kind of had a lot
of what we needed in fast AI to achieve
this but we're missing a couple of bits
and so silver Google has done an amazing
job of fleshing out the pieces that
we're missing and then confirming that
he has actually achieved super
convergence on training on say 5 10 so I
think this is the first time that this
has been done that I've heard of outside
of Leslie Smith himself and so he's got
a great blog post up now on one cycle
which is what Leslie Smith called this
approach and this is actually it turns
out what one cycle looks like it's a
single cyclic or learning rate but the
key difference here is that the the
going up be it is the same length as
they're going down
right so you go up like really slowly
and then at the end for like a tenth of
the time you you then have this little
bit where you go down even further and
it's interesting obviously this is a
very easy thing to show very easy thing
to explain Sylvia has added at a fast AI
under the temporarily it's it's called
use CLR beta by the time you watch this
on the video it'll probably be called
one cycle something like that but you
can use this right now so that's one key
piece to getting these massively high
learning rates and he shows a number of
experiments when you do that a second
key piece is that as you do this to the
learning rate you do this to the
momentum right so when the loading rates
low it's fine to have a high momentum
but then when the learning rate gets up
really high your momentum needs to be
quite a bit lower so this is also part
of our what he's added to the library is
this cyclic all momentum and so with
with with these two things you can train
for about the fifth of the number of
epochs with stepwise learning rate
schedule then you can drop your weight
decay down by about two orders of
magnitude
you can often remove most or all of your
drop out and so you end up with
something that's trained
faster and generalizes better and it
actually turns out that silver got quite
a bit better accuracy than Leslie
Smith's paper his guess I was pleased to
see is because our data augmentation
defaults are better than less visas I
hope that's true
so check that out another cool thing I
just as I say there's been so many cool
things this week I'm just going to pick
two Hamill who seen who's a works at
github I just really like this there's a
fairly new project called our cube flow
which is basically 10250 for kubernetes
Hamill wrote a very nice article about
magical sequence to sequence models
building data products on that
and using kubernetes to kind of put that
in production and so forth he said that
the Google cou flow team created a demo
based on what he wrote earlier this year
directly based on the skills on moon
fast AI and I will be presenting this
technique at KD DK t DS one of the top
academic conferences so I wanted to
share this as a motivation for folks to
blog which i think is a great point you
know I don't nobody who goes out and
writes a blog things that you know
probably you know none of us really
think our blog is actually going to be
very good probably nobody's gonna read
it you know and then when people
actually do like it and read it it's
like with great surprise you just got
over that's actually something people
were interested to read so here is the
the tool where you can summarize github
issues using this tool which is now
hosted by Google on their Cooper org
domain so I think that's a great story
of getting you know if Emeril didn't put
his work out there none of this would
have happened and yeah you can check out
his post that made it all happen as well
so talking of the magic of sequence to
sequence models let's build one so we're
going to be specifically working on
machine translation so machine
translation is a something that's been
around for a long time but specifically
we're going to look at an approach
called neural translation which is using
neural networks for translation and they
didn't know that wasn't really a thing
in any kind of meaningful way until a
couple of years ago and so thanks to
Chris Manning from Stanford for the next
three slides 2015 Chris pointed out that
neural machine translation kind of first
appeared properly and it was pretty
crappy compared to the statistical
machine translation approaches that use
kind of classic like feature engineering
and standard MLP kind of approaches of
lots of
stemming and fiddling around this work
frequencies and engrams and lots of
stuff by a year later it was better than
everything else this is on a metric
called blue we're not going to discuss
the metric because it's not a very good
metric and it's not very interesting but
it's what everybody uses so that was
blue as of when Chris did this slide as
of now it's about up here it's about 30
so we're kind of seeing machine
translation starting down the path that
we saw starting computer vision object
classification in 2012 I guess which is
you know we kind of just surpassed the
state of the art and now we're zipping
past it at a great rate it's very
unlikely that anybody watching this is
actually gonna build a machine
translation model because you can go to
translate Google calm and use theirs and
it works quite well so why are we
learning about machine translation well
the reason we're learning about machine
translation is that the general idea of
taking some kind of input like a
sentence in french and transforming it
into some other kind of output with
arbitrary length such as a sentence in
english is a really useful thing to do
for example the thing that we just saw
that ham all that github did tex github
issues and turns them into summaries
other examples is taking videos and
turning them into descriptions or taking
a well I don't know I mean like you know
basically anything where you're spitting
out kind of an arbitrary sized output
very often that's a sentence so maybe
taking a CT scan and spitting out a
radiology report you know this is where
you can use sequence to sequence
learning
so the important thing about a neural
machine translation these are more
slides from Chris and and generally six
a sequence of sequence models is that
you know there's no fussing around with
heuristics and Haacke you know feature
engineering whatever it's end-to-end
training we're able to build these
distributed representations which are
shared by lots of kind of concepts
within a single network we're able to
use long term State in the air and ENSO
use a lot more context than kind of
Engram type approaches and in the end
the text we're generating uses an iron
in as well so we can build something
that's more fluid we're going to use a
bi-directional LS TM with attention well
actually were going to use a
bi-directional giu
with attention but basically the same
thing so you already know about
bi-directional recurrent neural networks
and attention we're going to add on top
today these general ideas you can use or
lots of other things as well as Chris
points out on this slide so let's jump
into the code which is in the translate
notebook funnily enough and so we're
going to try to translate French into
English and so the basic idea is that
we're going to try and make this look as
much like a standard neural network
approach as possible so we're going to
need three things you will remember the
three things data a suitable
architecture and a suitable loss
function once you've got these three
things you run fit and all things going
well you end up with something that
solves your problem okay so data you
know we generally need XY pairs okay
because we
need something which we can feed it into
the loss function and say I took my
x-value which was my French sentence and
the loss function says it was meant to
generate this English sentence and then
you had your predictions which you would
then compare and see how good it is okay
so therefore we need lots of these
tuples of french sentences with their
equivalent English sentence that's
called a parallel corpus obviously this
is harder to find than a corpus for a
language model because for a language
model we just need text in some language
which you can basically all for any
living language of which the people that
use that language like use computers
there will be a few gigabytes at least
of text floating around the internet for
you to grab okay so building a language
model is only challenging corpus wise or
you know ancient languages one of our
students is trying to do a Sanskrit one
for example at the moment but that's
very rarely a problem for translation
there are actually some pretty good
parallel corpus is available for
European languages the European
Parliament basically has every sentence
in every European language anything that
goes through the UN is translated to
lots of languages for French to English
we have a particularly nice thing which
is pretty much any semi official
Canadian web site I will have a French
version and an English version and so
this chap kursk Ellison birch did a cool
thing which is basically to try to
transform French URLs into English URLs
by like replacing - if I am and hoping
that that retrieves the equivalent
document and then did that for lots and
lots of web sites and into that creating
a huge corpus based on millions of web
pages so a French to English we have
this particularly nice resource so we're
going to start out by talking about how
to create the data then we'll look at
the architecture and then we'll look at
the loss function and so for
bounding boxes all of the interesting
stuff was in the loss function but for
New York translation all of the
interesting stuff is going to be in the
architecture okay so let's zip through
this pretty quickly and one of the
things I want you to think about
particularly is what are the
relationships the similarities in terms
of the tasks we're doing and how we do
it between language modeling versus euro
translation okay
so the basic approach here is that we're
going to take a sentence so this case
this example is English to German and
this slides through Mon Steven emeriti
we steal everything we can from Steven
we start with some sentence in English
and the first step is to do basically
the exact same thing we do in a language
model which is to chuck it through an R
in it now with our language model
actually that's not even think that
language model let's start even easier
the classification model okay so
something that turns some this sentence
into positive or negative sentiment we
had a a decoder you know something which
basically took the RNN output and from
our paper we grabbed three things we
took a max pull over all of the time
steps we took a mean port over there all
the time steps and we took the value of
the iron in at the last time step stack
all those together and put it through a
linear layer most people don't do that
in most NLP stuff this is a like I think
it's something we invented people pretty
much always use the last time step so
all the stuff we'll be talking about
today uses the last time step so we
start out by chucking this sentence
through an R and N and out of it comes
some state right so some state meaning
some hidden state some vector that
represents the output of an hour
that is encoded that sentence you'll see
the word that Steven used here was
encoder we've tended to use the word
backbone right so like when we've talked
about like adding a custom head to an
existing model like you know the
existing pre-trained imagenet model for
example we kind of say that's our
backbone and then we stick on top of it
some-some head that does the task we
want in sequence to sequence learning
they use the word encoder but it
basically it's the same thing it's some
piece of a neural network architecture
that takes the input and turns it into
you know some representation which we
can then stick a few more layers on top
of to grab something out of it such as
we did for the classifier where we stuck
a linear layer on top over to turn it
into a sentiment positive or negative so
this time though we have something
that's a little bit harder than just
kiding sentiment which is I want to turn
this state not into a positive or
negative sentiment but into a sequence
of tokens where that sequence of tokens
is the German in this case the German
sentence that we want so this is
sounding more like the language model
than the classifier because the language
model had multiple tokens for every
input word there was an output word but
the language model was also much easier
because the the number of tokens in the
language model output was the same
length as the number of tokens in the
language model input and not only were
there the same length they exactly
matched up it's like after word one
comes word two afterward two comes word
three and so forth right
but for translating language you don't
necessarily know that the word he will
be translated as the first word in the
output and that love will be the second
word in the output I mean in this
particular case unfortunately they are
the same but very often you know the
subject object order will be
differential there will be some extra
words inserted or some pronouns we'll
need to add some gendered article
or whatever okay so this is the key
issue we're gonna have to deal with is
the fact that we have an arbitrary
length output where the tokens in the
output do not correspond to the same
order you know specific tokens in the
input okay but the general idea is the
same here's an RNN to encode the input
turns it into some hidden state and then
this is the new thing we're going to
learn is generating a sequence output so
we already know sequence two plus that's
IMDB classifier we already know sequence
two equal length sequence where
corresponds to the same items that's the
language model for example but we don't
know yet how to do a general-purpose
sequence to sequence so that's the new
thing today very little of this will
make sense unless you really understand
lesson six how an RNN works okay so if
some of this lesson doesn't make sense
to you and you find yourself wondering
what does he mean by hidden state
exactly how's that working go back and
re-watch lesson six to give you a very
quick review we learnt that and are an N
at its heart is a standard fully
connected Network so here's one with one
two three four layers right takes an
input and puts it through four layers
but then at the second layer it can just
concatenate in the second important
third layer concatenate in a third input
but we actually wrote this in Python as
just literally a four layer neural
network okay there's nothing else we
used other than linear layers and values
we used the same weight matrix every
time an input came in we used the same
matrix every time we went from one of
these states to the next and that's why
there's errors of the same color and so
we can redraw that previous thing like
this yeah
and so we not only did we redraw it but
we took the you know four lines of
linear linear linear linear code
in pi torch and we replaced it with a
for loop okay so remember we had
something that did exactly the same
thing as this but it just had four lines
of code saying linear linear linear
layer and we really literally replaced
it with a for loop because that's nice
to refactor so like literally that
refactoring which doesn't change any of
the math any of the ideas and if the
outputs that refactoring is entirely
okay turning a bunch of separate lines
in the code into a Python corner okay
and so that's how we can draw it we
could take the output so that it's not
outside the loop and put it inside the
loop like so right and if we do that
we're now going to generate a separate
output for every input so in this case
this particular one here the hidden
state gets replaced each time and we end
up just spitting out the final hidden
State
so this one is this example okay but if
instead we had something that said you
know h's dot append h and returned H's
at the end that would be this picture
yeah and so go back and relook at that
notebook if this is unclear I think the
main thing to remember is when we say
hidden state we're referring to a vector
okay see you
here's the vector right H equals torch
zeroes okay and hidden now of course
it's a vector for each thing in the mini
bash so it's it's a matrix but I'm
generally when I speak about these
things I ignore them in each piece and
treat it for just a single item okay so
it's just a vector of this length we
also learned that you can stack these
layers on top of each other so rather
than this first errand ends bidding our
output there could just spit out inputs
into a second area and
if you're thinking at this point I think
I understand this but I'm not quite sure
if you're anything like that me that
means you don't understand this right
and the only way you know and that you
actually understand it is to go and
write this in from scratch in PI torch
or an umpire okay and if you can't do
that then you know okay you don't
understand it and you can go back and
re-watch the lesson 6 and check out the
notebook and copy some of the ideas
until you can it's really important that
you can write that from scratch it's
less than a screen of code okay
so you want to make sure you can create
a two layer iron okay and this is what
it looks like if you unroll it okay so
that's the goal is to get to a point
that we first of all have these XY pairs
of sentences and we're going to do
French to English so we're going to
start by downloading this data set and
training a translation model takes a
long time
Google's translation model has eight
layers of RNN stacked on top of each
other there's no conceptual difference
between eight layers and two layers it's
just like if you're google and you have
more GPUs GPUs and you know what to do
with then you're fine doing that where
else in our case it's pretty likely that
the kind of sequence to sequence models
we're building are not going to require
that level of computation so to keep
things simple let's do a cut-down thing
where rather than learning how to
translate French into English for any
sentence let's learn to translate French
questions into English questions okay
and specifically questions that start
with what where which when okay so you
can see here I've got a regex it looks
for things at start of WH and in with a
question mark so I just go through the
corpus open up each of the two files
each line is one parallel text written
together I grab the English question the
French question and check whether they
match the regular submissions okay dump
that out was the pickle and so they
don't have to do it again and so we now
have 52,000 sentences and here are some
examples with us well sentence pairs and
here are some examples of those
one nice thing about this is that what
who where clap questions tend to be
fairly short which is nice but I would
say the idea that we could learn from
scratch with no previous understanding
of the idea of language let alone of
English or a French that we could create
something that can translate one to the
other for any arbitrary question with
only 50,000 sentences
it sounds like a ludus cursory difficult
thing to ask us to do right so I will be
impressed if we can make any progress
whatsoever this is very little data to
do a very complex exercise correct so
this contains the tuples of French and
English you can use this handy idiom
just pick them apart into a list of
English questions and list of french
questions and then we tokenize the
English question questions and we
tokenize the French questions okay so
remember that just means splitting them
up into separate words or word like
things
by default the tokenizer that we have
here and remember this is a wrapper
around the Spacey tokenizer which is a
fantastic tokenizer
this wrapper by default assumes English
okay so to ask for French you just add
an extra parameter the first time you do
this you'll get an error saying that you
don't have the space you French model
installed and you can Google to get the
command something Python - MS BAE see
download French or something like that
to grab the French model okay I don't
think any of your going to have RAM
problems here because this is not
particularly big corpus but I know that
some of you we're trying to train new
language models during the week and
we're having RAM problems if you do it's
worth knowing what these functions are
actually doing so for example these ones
here is processing every sentence across
multiple processes as well the NP means
and remember you know Farsi our code is
designed to be pretty easy to read so
you know three or four lines of code so
here's the three lines of code to
process or MP find out how many CPUs you
have divided by two because normally
with hyper-threading they don't actually
all work in parallel then in in parallel
run this process function so that's
going to spit out a whole separate
Python process for every CPU you have if
you have a lot of cause that's a lot of
Python processes everyone's going to
load the whole you know all this data in
and that can potentially use up all your
ramped so you could replace that with
just proc all rather than pro or MP to
use less RAM or you could just pros use
less cause so but you know at the moment
we were calling this function partition
by cause which calls partition on a list
and asks to split it into a number of
equal length things according to how
many CPUs you have so you could replace
that you're not splitting it into a
smaller list and read it on less things
yes Rachel was an intention layer tried
in the language model do you think it
would be a good idea to try and add one
we haven't had learned about attention
yet so let's ask about things that we
have cut to not things we haven't the
short answer is no I haven't tried it
properly yes you should try it because
it might help okay and you know in
general there's going to be a lot of
things that we covered a day which if
you've done some sequence to sequence
stuff before you're want to know about
something we haven't covered yet I'm
going to cover all the sequence of
sequence things ok so at the end of this
if I haven't covered the thing you
wanted to know about please ask me then
if you ask me before I'll be answering
something based on something that I'm
about to teach you ok so having
tokenized
the english and french you can see how
it gets bit out and you can see the
tokenization for french is quite
different looking because french loves
their apostrophes and their hi friends
and stuff right so if you try to use in
english tokenizer for a french sentence
you're going to get it pretty crappy ok
so like I don't find you need to know
heaps of NLP ideas to use deep learning
for NLP but just some basic stuff like
you know use the right tokenize of your
language is important and so some of the
students this week in our study group
have been trying to work build language
models for Chinese instance which of
course doesn't really have the concept
of a tokenizer in the same way so we've
been starting to look at it briefly
mentioned last week this google thing
called sentence peace which basically
splits things into arbitrary sub word
units and so when I say tokenize if
you're using a language that doesn't
have spaces in you should probably be
checking out sentence peace or some
other similar sub word unit thing
instead and hopefully in the next week
or two we'll be able to report back with
some early results of these experiments
with Chinese okay
so have you tokenized to it will save
that disk and then remember the next
step after we create tokens is to turn
them into numbers and turn them into
numbers we have two steps the first is
to get a list of all of the words that
appear and then we turn every word into
the index into that list right if there
are more than 40,000 words that appear
then let's cut it off there so it
doesn't go too crazy and we insert a few
extra tokens for beginning of stream
padding end of stream and okay so if we
try to look up something that wasn't in
the 40,000 most common then we use a
default dicked to return three which is
unknown so now we can go ahead and turn
every token into an ID by putting it
through the string to integer dictionary
we just created and then at the end of
that let's add the number two which is
industry and you'll see like this kind
the code you see here is the code I
write when I'm iterating in
experimenting right because like 99% of
the code I write when I'm either writing
experimenting it turns out to be totally
wrong or stupid or embarrass
seeing and you don't get to see it right
but like there's no point you know
refactoring that and making it beautiful
when I'm riding it's kind of wanting you
to see all the little shortcuts I have
so like rather than doing this properly
and actually find you know having some
constant or something for end of stream
marker and using it when I'm prototyping
I just do the easy stuff you know I mean
not not so much that I end up with
broken code you know but I I don't you
know try to find I try to find some
middle ground between beautiful code and
you know code that was just heard him
mention that we divide number of CPUs by
two because with hyper-threading we
don't get a speed-up using all the hyper
threaded cores is this based on
practical experience or is there some
underlying reason why we wouldn't get
additional speed-up yeah it's just
practical experience and it's like a lot
of things kind of seem like this but I
definitely noticed with tokenization
hyper threading seem to slow things down
a little bit also if I use all the cause
you know like often I want to do
something else at the same time like
generally run some interactive notebook
and I don't have any spare room to do
that it's a minor issue yeah okay so now
for our English and our French we can
grab our list of IDs and when we do that
of course we need to make sure that we
also store the vocabulary there's no
point having IDs if we don't know like
what the number five represents there's
no point having a number five so that's
our vocabulary it's a string and the
reverse mapping string to int that we
can use to convert more courses in the
future okay so just to confirm it's
working we can go through each ID
convert the into a string and spit that
out and there we have our thing back now
with an industry marker at the end
English vocab is 17,000 our French vocab
is 25,000 so you know there's not too
big you know there's not too complex a
vocab that we're dealing with which is
nice to know
okay so we spent a lot of time on the
forums during the week discussing how
pointless what vectors are and how you
should stop getting so excited about
them and we're now going to use them why
is that basically all the stuff we've
been learning about using language
models and pre-trained proper models
rather than pre-trained you know linear
single layers which is what word vectors
are I think applies equally well to
sequence to sequence but I haven't tried
it yet yet so Sebastian and I are you
know starting to look at that and
slightly distracted by preparing this
class at the moment but after this class
is done so there's a whole thing for
anybody interested in creating some
genuinely new like highly publishable
results the entire area of sequence to
sequence with pre-trained language
models hasn't been touched yet and I
strongly believe is going to be just as
good as as classification style and if
you you know work on this and you get to
the point where you have something
that's looking exciting and you want
help publishing it you know I'm very
happy to help co-author papers you know
that on stuff that's looking good you
know so feel free to reach out if and
when you have some interesting results
so at this stage we don't have any of
that so we're going to use you know very
little fast I I actually and very little
in terms of kind of fast AI ideas so we
you know all we've got is word vectors
anyway so let's at least use decent word
vectors so word Tyvek is very old where
vectors there are better word vectors
now and fast text is a pretty good
source of word vectors
there's hundreds of languages available
for them your language is likely to be
represented so to grab them you can
click on this link download word vectors
for a language that you're interested in
install install the fast text Python
library it's not available on pi PI but
here's a handy trick if there is a
github
repo that has like a setup PI inert and
a requirements text in it you can just
chuck get Plus at the start and then
stick that in your pip install and it
works like hardly anybody seems to know
this and like it never even like if you
go to the fast text repo they won't tell
you this they'll say you have to
download it and CD into it and blah blah
blah but you're done you can just run
that ok which you can also use for the
first AI library by the way if you want
to pip install the latest version of
past pay I even totally do this so you
grab the library import it load the
model so here's my English model and
here's my French you'll see there's a
text version and a binary version the
binary versions a bit faster we're going
to use that the text version is also a
bit buggy and then I'm going to convert
it into a standard Python dictionary to
make it a bit easier to work with so
this is just going to grow through each
word with a dictionary comprehension and
save it as a pickle dictionary ok so now
we've got our pickle dictionary we can
go ahead and look up a word for example
come up and that will return a vector
the length of that vector is the
dimensionality of this set of word
vectors so in this case we've got three
hundred dimensional English and French
words okay
[Music]
for reasons that you'll see in a moment
I also want to find out what the mean of
my vectors are and the standard
deviation of my vectors are so the means
about 0 and the standard deviation is
about point three so remember that often
corpuses have a pretty long tailed
distribution of sequence length and it's
the longest sequences that kind of tend
to overwhelm how long things take and
you know how much memory is used and
stuff like that
so I'm going to grab you know in this
case the 99th to 97th percentile of the
English and French and truncate them to
that amount originally I was using the
90th percentile so these are poorly
named variable
so apologies for that okay so that's
just truncating them so we're nearly
there we've got our tokenized numeric
alized English and French data set we've
got some word vectors so now we need to
get it ready for play torch so app a
torch expects a data set object and
hopefully by now you all can tell me
that a data set object requires two
things a length and an indexer so I
started route writing this now it's like
okay I need a sector sector dataset and
I started out writing it and I thought
okay we're going to have to pass it out
X's now wise and store them away and
then my indexer is going to need to
return a numpy array of the X's at that
point in an umpire row of the Y's at
that point and oh that's it
so then after I wrote this I realized I
haven't really written a sector sector
dataset I've just written a totally
generic data set so here's like the
simplest possible data set that works
for any pair of arrays so it's now
poorly named it's much more general than
a sector sick data set but that's what I
needed it for this a function remember
we've got V variables teeth tensors a4
arrays so this basically goes through
each of the things you pass it if it's
not already in numpy array it converts
it into a numpy array and returns back
at a pool of all of the things that you
passed it which are now guaranteed to be
mud pirates so that's a VT 3 very handy
little functions ok so that's it that's
our data set so now we need to grab our
English and French IDs and get a
training set and a validation set and so
one of the things which is pretty
disappointing about a lot of code out
there on the Internet is that they don't
follow us and simple best practices for
example if you go to the Play Torche
website they have an example section for
sequence a sequence translation there
example does not have a separate
validation set
I tried it training according to their
settings and I tested it with their
validation set it turned out that it
overfit massively so this is not just a
theoretical problem the actual pipe
torch repo has the actual official
sequence the sequence translation
example which does not check for
overfitting and overfits horribly also
it fails to use mini batches so it
actually fails to utilize any of the
efficiency of Pi torch whatsoever so
there's a lot of like even if you find
code in the official pipe torch repo
don't assume it's any good at all right
the other thing you'll notice is that
everybody were when they like pretty
much every other sequence the sequence
model I've found in Peyer torch anywhere
on the internet has clearly copied from
that shitty pipe or epoch isn't all the
same variable names it has the same
problems it has the same mistakes like
another example nearly every PI torch
convolutional neural network I found
does not use an adaptive pooling layer
so in other words the final layer is
always like average paul 7 comma 7 right
so they assume that the previous layer
is 7 by 7 and if you use any other size
input you get an exception and therefore
nearly everybody i've spoken to that
uses Piatt torch thinks that there is a
fundamental limitation of CN NS that
they are tied to the input size and that
has not been true since vgg right so
every time we grab a new model and stick
it in the first day i repo i have to go
in search for paul and add adaptive to
the start and replace the 7 with a 1 and
now it works on any sized object all
right so just be careful you know it's
still early days and and believe it or
not even though most of you have only
started in the last year your deep
learning journey you know quite a lot
more about a lot of the more important
practical aspects and the vast majority
of people that are like publishing and
writing stuff in official repos and
stuff so you kind of need to have a
little more self-confidence than you
might expect when it comes to reading
other people's code if you find yourself
thinking that looks odd it's not
necessarily you it might well be then
okay
so yeah I would say like at least 90% of
deep learning code that I start looking
at turns out to have like you know like
deathly serious problems that make it
completely unusable for anything and so
I kind of been telling people that I've
been working with recently you know if
if the repo you're looking at doesn't
have a section on it saying here's the
test we did where we got the same
results as the paper that suspend to be
implementing that almost certainly means
they haven't got the same results in the
paper they're implementing they probably
haven't even checked okay and if you run
it it definitely won't get those results
because it's it's hard to get things
right the first time it takes me 12 goes
you know probably takes the normal
smarter people than me six goes but if
they haven't tested it once it's almost
certainly won't work okay so there's our
sequence sequence data set let's get the
training and validation sets here's an
easy way to do that we have a bunch of
random numbers one feature of your data
see if they're bigger than 0.1 or not
that gives you a list of balls index
into your array with that list of balls
to grab a training set index into that
array with the opposite of that list of
balls to get your validation set there's
a nice easy way there's lots of ways of
doing it I just like to do different
ways to you can see a few approaches
okay so now we can create our data set
with our X's in our Y's French and
English if you want to translate instead
English to French switch these two
around and you're done okay now we need
to create data loaders we can just grab
our data loader and pass in our data set
and match size we actually have to
transpose the arrays I'm not going to go
into the details about why we can talk
about it during the week if you're
interested but have a think about why we
might need to transpose their
orientation but there's a few more
things I want to do one is that since
we've already done all the
pre-processing there's no point spawning
off multiple workers to do like
augmentation or whatever because there
know what to do so making them workers
equals one will save you some time
we have to tell it what our padding
index is that's actually pretty
important because what's going to happen
is that we've got different length
sentences and faster I I think it's
pretty much the only baby that does this
past day I will just automatically stick
them together and pad the shorter ones
to be so that they're all in that equal
length because remember a tense has to
be rectangular okay
in the decoder in particularly I
actually want my padding to be at the
end not at the start like for a
classifier I want the padding at the
start because I want that final token to
represent the last word of the movie
review but in the decoder as you'll see
it actually is going to work out a bit
better to have the padding at the end so
I say prepaired equals false and then
finally since we've got sentences of
different lengths coming in and they all
have to be put together in a mini batch
to be the same size by padding we would
much prefer that the sentence in a mini
batch are of similar sizes already
because otherwise that it's going to be
as long as the longest sentence and
that's going to end up wasting time and
memory okay so therefore I'm going to
use the sample of tricks that we learnt
last time which is the validation set
we're going to ask it to sort everything
by length first okay and then for the
training set we're going to ask it to
randomize the order of things but to
roughly make it so that things of
similar length are about in the same
spot okay that's how we got our sort
sample and a sort assembler
okay and then at that point we can
create a model data object remember a
model data object really does one thing
which is it says I have a trading set
and a validation set and an optional
test set and sticks them into a single
object we also have a path so that it
has somewhere to store temporary files
models stuff like that right so you know
we're doing we're not using fast AI for
very much at all in this example just
kind of a minimal set to show you like
you know
how to you know kind of get your model
data objects in the end once you've got
a model data object you can then create
a learner and you can then call fit okay
so that's kind of like minimal amount of
faster faster I stuff here this is a
standard height watch compatible data
set this is a standard plate or
compatible data loader behind the scenes
it's actually using the class AI version
because I do need to do this automatic
padding for convenience so there's a few
tweaks in our version that are a bit
faster a bit more convenient the faster
ice samplers we're using but you know
there's not too much going on here so
now we've got our model data object we
can basically tick off number one okay
so as I said most of the work is in the
architecture and so the architecture is
going to take our sequence of tokens
okay it's going to spit them in to a
encoder or you know in kind of computer
vision turns what we've been calling a
backbone you know something that's going
to try and turn this into some kind of
representation so that's just going to
be an iron in okay that's going to spit
out the final hidden state which for
each sentence it's just a vector single
okay and so that's all going to take
that's none of this is going to be do
that's all going to be using very direct
simple techniques that we've already
learnt and then we're going to take that
and we're going to spread it into a
different era tan which is a decoder and
that's going to have some new stuff
because we need something that can go
through one word at a time okay and it's
got to keep going until it thinks it's
finished the sentence it doesn't know
how long the sentence is going to be
ahead of time keeps going until it
thinks it's finished the sentence and
then it stops and returns a sentence
okay so let's start with the with the
end coder so in terms of variable naming
here there's basically identical
variable
for encoder and decoder buttes for
encoder and decoder the encoder versions
have Inc the decoder versions have dead
okay so for the N coder here's our
embeddings and so like I always try to
mention like what the mnemonics are you
know rather than writing things out you
know so in turn longhand so you know
just remember anchors and encoder
deckers of decoder and visit embedding
the final thing that comes out is out
the r and n in this case is a gr u not
an LST M
they're nearly the same thing so don't
worry about the difference you could
replace it with an LST m and you'll get
basically the same results to replace it
with an LST M simply type OST M okay so
we need to create an embedding layer to
take because remember what we're being
passed is the index of the words into a
vocabulary and we want to grab there
fast text embedding and then over time
we might want to also fine tune to train
that embedding n to it so to create an
embedding we'll call create embedding up
here so we'll just say n n dot embedding
so it's important that you know now how
to set the rows and columns for your
embedding so the number of rows has to
be equal to your vocabulary size
so each vocab riordan has a word vector
and the how big is your embedding well
in this case it was determined by fast
text and the first text embedding size
300 so we have to use size 300 as well
otherwise we can't start out by using
their betting's okay now so what we want
to do is this is initially going to give
us a random set of embeddings and so
we're going to now go through each one
of these and if we find it in fast text
we'll replace it with the first text
admitting okay so again something that
you should already know is that a PI
torch module that is learn about has a
weight attribute and the weight
attribute is a variable and that
variables have a data attribute and the
data attribute is a tensor now your
notice very often today I'm saying here
is something you should know not so that
you think oh I don't know that I'm a bad
person right but so that you think okay
this is a concept that you know I
haven't learnt yet and Jeremy thinks I
ought to know about and so I've got to
write that down and I'm gonna go home
and I'm gonna like Google because like
this is a normal pie Torche
attribute in every single learning
platform module this is a normal plate
or attribute in every single pipe torch
variable and so if you don't know how to
graph the weights out of a module or you
don't know how to grab the tensor out of
a variable it's gonna be hard for you to
build new things or to debug things or
maintain things or whatever yes so if I
say you ought to know this and you're
thinking I don't know this don't run
away and hide go home and learn the
thing and if you're having trouble
learning the thing because you can't
find documentation about it or you don't
understand that documentation or you
don't know why Jeremy thought it was
important you know it jump on the forum
and say like please explain this thing
here's my best understanding of that
thing as I have it at the moment here's
the resources I grew up that helped film
you okay
and normally if I respond it's very
likely I will not tell you the answer
but I will instead give you something a
problem that you could solve that if you
solver will solve it for you because I
know that that that way it'll be
something you remember okay so again
don't be put off if I'm like okay you
like go read this link try and summarize
that thing tell us what you think like
I'm trying to be helpful not unhelpful
and if you're still not following just
come back and say like I had to look
honestly that link you sent I don't know
what I knew that means I wouldn't know
where to start whatever like I'll keep
trying to help you until you fully
understand it okay
so so now that we've got our weight
tensor we can just go through our
vocabulary and we can look at the word
in our pre-trained vectors and if we
find it we will replace the random
weights with that pre-trade vector
the random weights have a standard
deviation of 1 our pre-trained vectors
it turned out how to standard deviation
of about 0.3 so again this is the kind
of hacky thing I do when I'm prototyping
stuff I just multiply two by three okay
obviously by the time you you know see
the video of this mean way we'll have
put all this sequence to sequence stuff
into the faster library you won't find
horrible paths like that and there sure
hope but hack away when you're
prototyping some things won't be in fast
text in which case we'll just keep track
of it and I've just added this print
statement here just so that I can kind
of see what's going like why am I
missing stuff basically when you know
I'll probably comment it out when I
actually commit this to github that's
why that's there okay so we create those
embeddings and so when we actually
create the sequence to sequence RNN
it'll print out how many or missed and
so remember we had like about 30,000
words so we're not missing too many and
interesting the things that are missing
well there's our special toque there's a
special token for uppercase not
surprising that's missing also remember
it's not token Tyvek it's not token text
it's you know it does words so L
apostrophe and D apostrophe and
apostrophe s they're not appearing
either so that's interesting that does
suggest that maybe we could have
slightly better embeddings if we try to
find some which would being tokenized
the same way we tokenize that's okay
Rachel do we just keep embedding vectors
from training why don't we keep all word
embeddings in case you have new words in
the test set oh I mean we're gonna be
fine-tuning them you know and so yeah I
don't know I mean it's an interesting
idea maybe that would work I haven't
tried it I mean obviously you wouldn't
so can you use that
I asked the question so you can also add
random embedding to those and the
beginning just keep them random on but
you're gonna have bigs gonna make it an
effect in the sense that you are going
to be using those words yeah yep I think
it's an interesting line of inquiry but
I will say this the vast majority of the
time when you're kind of doing this in
the real world your vocabulary will be
bigger than 40-thousand and once your
vocab areas bigger than 40-thousand
using the standard techniques you the
embedding layers gets so big that it
takes up all your memory it takes up all
of the time and the backdrop there are
tricks to dealing with very large vocab
Riis I don't think we'll have time to
handle them in this session but you
definitely would not want to have all
three and a half million fast text
vectors in a in an embedding layer so I
I wonder so if you're not touching a
word it's not gonna change right like
you and we are fine-tuning right you are
not it's in GPU Ram and you're gonna
remember three and a half million times
three hundred times the size of a single
precision floating point vector plus all
of the gradients for them even if it's
not touched like they're without being
very careful and adding a lot more code
and stuff it is slow and hard and when
we wouldn't touch it for now but as I
say I think there's an interesting path
of inquiry but it's the kind of path of
inquiry that leads to like multiple
academic papers not you know something
that you do on a weekend but I think
would be very interesting for ya maybe
we can look at at some time you know and
as I say I have actually started doing
some stuff around incorporating large
for cavalry handing handling into fast
AI it's not finished but hopefully by
the time we get here this kind of stuff
would be possible ok so we create our
encoder embedding add a bit of drop out
ok and then we create our an end
this input to the RNN obviously is the
size of the embedding by Bodie by
definition number of hidden is whatever
we watch so we set up to 256 for now
however many layers we want hands and
drop out inside the arent as well okay
so this is all standard height watch
stuff you could use ur LS TM here as
well and then finally we need to turn
that into some output that we're going
to feed to the decoder so let's use a
linear layer to convert the number of
hidden into the decoder embedding sites
okay so in the forward pass here's how
that's used we first of all initialize
our hidden state to a bunch of zeros
okay so we've now had a vector of zeros
which we and then we're going to take
our input and put it through our
embedding we're going to put that
through drop out we then pass our
currently zeros hidden state and our
embeddings into our R and N and it's
going to spit out the usual stuff that I
ran in spit up which includes the final
hidden state we're then going to take
that final hidden stake and stick it
through that linear layer so we now have
something of the right size to feature
our decoder okay so that's that's it and
again this is like ought to be very
familiar and very comfortable it's like
the most simple possible iron n so if
it's not go back check out lesson six
make sure you can write it from scratch
and that you understand what it does but
the key thing to know is that it takes
our inputs and spits out a hidden vector
that hopefully will learn to contain all
of the information about what that
sentence says and how it says it because
if it can't do that
all right if we can't do that then we
can't feed it into a decoder and hope it
to spit out our sentence in a different
language so that's what we want it to
learn to do
and we're not going to do anything
special to make it learn to do that
we're just gonna do you know the three
things and cross our fingers because
that's what we do all right so that's H
is is that yes all right so it's a
hidden stick
I guess Stephen used s for state I used
HB hidden but there you go you would
think the two Australians could agree on
something like that but apparently not
so how do we now do the new bit right
and so the basic idea of the new bit is
the same we're going to do exactly the
same thing but we're going to write our
own forward okay and so the full loop is
going to do exactly what the for loop
inside pi torch does here but we're
going to do it manually right so we've
got to go through the forward and how
big is the for loop
it's a output sequence length well what
is output sequence length that's
something that passed to the constructor
and it is equal to the length of the
largest English sentence okay
so we're going to do this for loop as
long as the largest English sentence
because we're translating into English
right so we can't possibly be longer
than that
at least not in this corpus if we then
used it on some different corpus that
was longer this is going to fail so but
you could make this you know you could
always pass in a different parameter of
course all right so the basic idea is
the same we're going to go through and
put it through the in the embedding
we're going to stick it through the R
and n we're going to stick it through
drop out and we're going to stick it
through a linear layer all right so the
basic four steps are the same and once
we've done that we're then going to
append that output to a list fat and
then when we're going to finish we're
going to stack that list up into a
single tensor and return it okay that's
the basic idea
normally a recurrent neural network
here is our decoder current neural
network recurrent neural network works
on a whole sequence at a time but we've
got a for loop to go through each part
of the sequence separately so we have to
add a leading unit access to the start
to basically say this is a sequence of
length 1 okay so we're not really taking
advantage of the recurrent net much at
all we could easily rewrite this with a
linear layer actually that would be an
interesting experiment if you wanted to
try it so we basically take our input
and we feed it into our embedding and we
add something to the front saying treat
this as a sequence of length 1 and then
we pass that to our M we then get the
output of that RNN feed it into our
dropout and 15:20 me a layer so there's
two extra things to know that be aware
of well I guess it's really one thing
the one thing is what's this what is the
input to that embedding okay and the
answer is it's the previous word that we
translated see how the input here is the
previous word here the input here is the
previous word here so the basic idea is
if you're trying to translate if you're
about to translate you know tell me the
fourth word of the new sentence but you
don't know what the third word you just
said was that's going to be really hard
all right so we're gonna feed that in at
each time step let's make it as easy as
possible okay and so what was the
previous word at the start for the Rawls
month
okay so specifically we're gonna start
out with a beginning of stream took it
okay so the beginning of stream token is
a zero so let's start out our decoder
with a beginning of stream token which
is zero okay
and of course we're doing a mini batch
so we need batch size number of them but
let's just think about one part
- so we've got we start out with a zero
we look at that zero in our in our
embedding matrix to find out what the
vector for the beginning a stream token
is we stick a unit axis on the front to
say we have a single sequence length of
beginning of stream token we stick that
through our RM which gets not only the
fact that there's a zero is beginning of
stream but also the hidden state which
at this point is whatever came out of
our encoder okay so this now its job is
to try and figure out what it's the
first word okay what's the first word to
translate the sentence pop through some
drop out go through one linear layer in
order to convert that into the correct
size for our decoder embedding matrix
okay append that to our list of
translated words and now we need to
figure out what word that was because we
need to feed it to the next time step we
need to feed it to the next time step
okay so remember what we actually output
here and and look at use a debugger
right pdb dot set trace put it here
what is at P now P is a tensor how big
is the tensor so before you look it up
in the debugger try and figure it out
from first principles and check you're
right so our P is a tensor whose length
is equal to the number of words in our
English vocabulary and it contains the
probability for every one of those words
that it is that word makes sense right
so then if we now say at P dot max that
looks in its tensor to find out which
word has the highest probability okay
and max imply Torche returns two things
the first thing is what is that max
probability and the second is what is
the index into the array of that mass
probability and so we want that second
item index number one which is the word
index with the largest thing okay so now
that contains the word well the word
index into a VOC a pre of the word if
it's a one right
you might remember one was padding then
that means we're done right that means
we've reached the end because we
finished with a bunch of padding okay if
it's not one let's go back and continue
but now Dec M is whatever the highest
probability word was but so we keep
looping through either until we get to
the largest length of a sentence or
until everything in our mini batch is
padding and each time we've appended our
outputs each time not not the word with
the probabilities okay to this list
which we stack up into a tensor and we
can now go ahead and feed that to a loss
function so before we go to a break
since we've done one and two let's do
three which is the last function the
last function is categorical
cross-entropy loss okay we've got a list
of probabilities for each of our classes
that the classes are all the words in
our English vocab and we have a target
which is which is the correct class ie
which is the correct word at this
location there's two tweaks which is why
we need to write our own little loss
function but you can see basically it's
going to be cross interview that's right
and the tweaks are as follows tweak
number one is we might have stopped a
little bit early right and so the
sequence length that we generated may be
different to the sequence length of the
target in which case we need to add some
padding right height or padding function
is weird if you have a rank three cancer
which we do we have batch size by sorry
we have sequence length by batch size by
number of words in the vocab Iraq three
tensor requires a six tupple each pair
and things in that topple is the padding
before and
the padding after that that dimension
all right so in this case the first
dimension has no padding the second
dimension has no padding the third
dimension has no padding on the left and
as much padding is required on the right
okay so it's good to know how to use
that function now that we've added any
padding that's necessary the only other
thing we need to do is cross entropy
loss expects a rank two tensor I
mentioned matrix but we've got sequence
length by batch size so let's just
flatten out the sequence length and
batch size into a that's what that minus
one in view does okay so flatten out
that for both of them and now we can go
ahead and call cross-entropy
that's it so now we can just use the
standard approach here's our sequence of
sequence R and n that's this one yeah so
that is a standard pipe watch module
stick it on the GPU hopefully by now
you've noticed you you can call CUDA but
if you call to GPU then it doesn't put
it on the GPU if you don't have one you
can also set faster I don't use GPU to
false to force it to not use the GPU and
that can be super handy for debugging
we then need something that tells it how
to handle learning rates learning rate
groups so there's a thing called single
model that you can pass it to which
treats the whole thing as a single
learning rate group so this is like this
easiest way to turn a height watch
module into a fast AI model here's the
model data object we created before we
could then just call lerner to turn that
into a learner but if we call our NN
learner our NN learner is a learner it
defines cross-entropy as the default
criteria this case we're overriding that
anyway so that's not what we care about
but it does add in these save encoder
and load encoder things that can be any
sometimes so we could have in this case
we're really pretty to set learner but
Aaron Lerner also works ok so here's how
we turn our height watch module into a
fast AO model into a and once we have a
learner give it our new loss function
and then we can call LR find and we can
call Fitch and it runs through awhile
and we can save it you know the normal
learn stuff now works the remember the
model attribute of a learner is a
standard piped watch model so we can
pass that sum X which we can grab out of
our validation set or you could use lo
not predict array or whatever you like
if you get some predictions and then we
can convert those predictions into words
by grabbing going dot max 1 to grab the
index of the highest probability words
to get some predictions and then we can
go through a few examples and print out
the French the correct English and the
predicted English for things that are
not padding and here we go alright so
amazingly enough this kind of like
simplest possible written largely from
scratch PI torch module and only fifty
thousand sentences is sometimes capable
on a validation set of giving you
exactly the right answer
sometimes the right answer in slightly
different wording and sometimes
sentences that really are grammatically
sensible or even have too many question
marks so we're we're well on the right
track I think you would agree so you
know even the simplest possible sector
SiC trained for a very small number of
epochs without any you know pre-training
other than the use of word embeddings
surprisingly good so I think you know
the message here and we're going to
improve this for the moment after the
break but I think the message here is
even sequence to sequence models you
think as simple of them to possibly work
even with less data than you think you
could learn from can be surprisingly
and in certain situations this main even
you know be enough for your needs
so we're going to learn a few tricks
after the break which will make this
much better
so let's come back at 750 so one
question that came up during the break
is that some of the tokens that are
missing in fast text like had a a curly
quote rather than a straight quote for
example and the question was would it
help to normalize punctuation and the
answer for this particular case is
probably yes the difference between
curly quotes and straight quotes is
rarely semantics you do have to be very
careful though because like it may turn
out that people using beautiful curly
quotes like using more formal language
and they're actually writing in a
different way so I generally you know if
you're going to do some kind of
pre-processing like punctuation
normalization you should definitely
check your results with and without
because like nearly always that kind of
pre-processing makes things worse even
when I'm sure it won't
hello what would be some ways over what
I seen these sequence of sequence
besides through power and weight again
let me think about that during the week
yeah it's like you know a wdl STM which
we've been relying on a lot has so many
great I mean it's it's all drop out well
not all drop out those drop out of many
different kinds there's and then there's
the we haven't talked about it much but
there's also a kind of a regularization
based on activations and stuff like that
as well
and on changes and whatever I just
haven't seen anybody put in a
thing like that amount of work into
regularization of sequence to sequence
models and I think there's a huge
opportunity for somebody to do like the
AWD LS TM of sectors ik which might be
as simple as dealing all the ideas from
a top UDS VLS TM and using them directly
in Sector SEC that would be pretty easy
to try I think and there's been an
interesting paper that actually Steven
Rarity's added in the last couple of
weeks where he used an idea which I
don't know if he stole it from me but it
was certainly something I had also
recently done and talked about on
Twitter
either way I'm thrilled that he's done
it which was to take all of those
different AWD LS TM hyper parameters and
train a bunch of different models and
then I use a random forest to find out
with feature importance which ones
actually met at the most and then figure
out like how to set them yeah so I think
you could totally you know use this
approach to figure out you know for
sequence the sequence regularization
approaches which one's the best and
optimize them and that would be amazing
yeah but at the moment I think you know
I I don't know that there are additional
ideas to sequence the sequence
regularization that I can think of
beyond what's in that paper for regular
language models stuff and probably all
those same approaches would would work
okay so tricks trick number one go
bi-directional okay so for
classification
my approach to bi-directional that I
suggested you use is take all of your
token sequences spin them around and
train a new language model and train a
new traffic classifier and I also
mentioned the wiki text pre train model
if you replace FWD with vwd in the name
you'll get the pre-trained backward
model I created for you okay so you can
use that get a set of predictions and
then average the predictions just like a
normal ensemble okay and that's kind of
how we do Baidu for that kind of
classification there
maybe ways to do it end to end but I
haven't quite figured them out yet
they're not in first AI yet and I don't
think anybody's written a paper about
them yet so if you figure it out
that's an interesting line of research
but because we're not doing you know
massive documents where we have to kind
of chunk it into separate bits and then
pall over them and whatever we can do by
do very easily in this case which is
literally as simple as adding
bidirectional equals true to our encoder
people tend not to do bi-directional for
the decoder I think partly because it's
kind of considered cheating but I don't
know like I was just talking to somebody
to break about it there you know maybe
it can work in some situations although
it might need to be more of a ensemble
approach in the decoder because you kind
of it's a bit less obvious anyway and
the ink into the encoder it's very very
simple
bi-directional equals true and we now
have with bi-directional equals true
rather than just having an RNN which is
going this direction we have a second
RNN that's going in this direction and
so that second RNN literally is visiting
them each token in the opposing order so
when we get the final here in state it's
here rather than here right but the
hidden state is of the same size so the
final result is that we end up with a
tensor that's got an extra to long axis
right and you know depending on what
library you use often that will be then
combined with the number of layers
things so if you've got two layers and
bi-directional that tensor dimension is
now length four with PI torch it kind of
depends which bit of the process you're
looking at as to whether you get a
separate result for each layer and offer
each bi-directional bit and so forth you
have to
cut the docs and it will tell you
inputs/outputs cancer sizes appropriate
for the number of layers and whether you
have bi-directional equals true in this
particular case you'll basically see all
the changes I've had to make so for
example you'll see when I added
bi-directional it was true my linear
layer now needs number of hidden times
to to reflect the fact that we have that
second direction in our hidden state now
you'll see in in it hidden it's now self
dot number of layers times two here okay
so you'll see there's a few places where
there's been an extra two that has to be
thrown in yes your net um why making any
color by the original is considered
cheating well it's it's not just this
cheating it's like we have this loop
going on you know it's not as simple as
just kind of having two tenses and then
like how do you turn those two separate
loops into a final result hey you know
after talking about it during the break
I've kind of gone from like hey
everybody knows it doesn't work to like
oh maybe it kind of could work but it
requires more thought it's quite
possible during the week I realize it's
a dumb idea and I was being stupid but
well think about it another question
people had why do you need to have an
into that look why do I have a watch of
the loop why do you need to like have a
an end to that look you have like a
range if your range yeah oh I mean it's
because when I start training
everything's random so this will
probably never be true so later on it'll
pretty much always break out eventually
but yeah it's basically like we're going
to go for it it's really important to
remember like when you're designing an
architecture that when you start the
model knows nothing about anything right
so you kind of want to make sure it's
doing
something at least vaguely sensible okay
so bi-directional means we had you know
let's see how we go here we got out to
358 cross entropy loss okay with a
single direction with fire direction
gets down to 351 yeah so that improved
it a bit that's good and as I say the
only you know it shouldn't really slow
things down too much
you know bidirectional does mean there's
a little bit more sequential processing
have to happen but you know it's
generally a good win in the Google
Translation model of the eight layers
only the first layer is bi-directional
because it allows it to do more in
parallel so if you create really deep
models you may need to think about which
ones are bi-directional otherwise we
have performance issues okay and so 351
now let's talk about teacher for C so
teacher forcing is I'm going to come
back to this idea that when the model
starts learning it knows nothing about
nothing so when the fertile starts
learning it is not going to spit out ah
at this point it's going to spit out
some random meaningless work acts it
doesn't know anything about German or
about English or about the idea of
language or anything and then it's going
to feed it down here as an input and be
totally unhelpful yeah and so that means
that early learning is going to be very
very difficult because it's feeding in
an input that's stupid into a model that
knows nothing and somehow it says get
better right so that's it's not asking
too much eventually it gets there but
it's definitely not as helpful as we can
be so what if instead of feeding in what
if instead of feeding in the thing I
predicted just now right what if instead
we see it in the actual correct word it
was meant to be right now we can't do
that at inference time because by
definition we don't know the correct
word it has to translate it
we can't require the correct translation
in order to do translation right so the
way I've set this up is I've got this
thing called PR force which is
probability of forcing and if some
random number is less than that
probability then I'm going to replace my
decoder input with the actual correct
thing right and if we've already gone
too far and if it's already longer than
the target sentence I'm just going to
stop well obviously I can't give it the
correct thing so you can see how
beautiful pi torches for this right
because like if you try to do this with
some static grafting like like classic
tensorflow
well I tried right like one of the key
reasons that we switched to PI torch at
this exact point in last year's class
was because Jeremy tried to implement it
you're forcing in chaos intensive flow
and went even more insane and he started
right and I was like it was weeks of
getting nowhere and then I literally on
Twitter I think it was Andre capaci
eyesore announced say it's something
about oh there's this thing called PI
torch just came out and it's really cool
and I've tried it that day by the next
day I had teacher flossing would and so
like I was like oh my gosh you know and
like all the stuff of trying to debug
things it was suddenly so much easier
and this kind of you know dynamic stuff
is so much easier so this is a great
example of like hey I get to use random
numbers and if statements and stuff so
yeah so here's the basic idea is at the
start of training let's set P our force
really high right so that nearly always
that gets the actual correct you know
previous word and so it has a useful
input right and then as I train a bit
more let's decrease PR force so that by
the end PF force is zero and it has to
learn properly which is fine because
it's now actually feeding in sensible
inputs most of the time anyway so let's
now write something such that in the
training loop it gradually decreases
pyaare force so how do you do that well
one approach would be to write our own
training loop okay but let's not do that
because we already have a training loop
that has progress bars and uses
exponential weighted averages to smooth
out the losses and keeps track of
metrics and you know it does a bunch of
things which they're not rocket science
but they're kind of convenient and they
also kind of keep track of you know
calling the reset hour and ends at the
start of an epoch to make sure that the
hidden states set to zeros and you know
little things like that we'd rather not
have to write that in scratch so what
we've tended to find is that as I start
to kind of write some new thing and I'm
like oh I need to kind of replace some
part of the code I then kind of add some
little hook so that we can all use that
book to make things easier in this
particular case there's a book that I've
ended up using all the damn time now
which is the hook called the stepper and
so if you look at our code model dot pi
is where our fit function lives right
and so the fit function and model dot pi
is kind of we've seen it before I think
it's like the lowest level thing that
doesn't require and learner it doesn't
really require anything much at all this
requires a standard PI torch model and a
model data object you just need to know
how many epochs are standard pipe torch
optimizer and the standard page watch
boss function all right so you can call
I don't we've hardly ever used it in the
class we normally call learn but fit but
learn dot fit calls this so this is our
lowest level thing but we filtered the
source code here sometimes we've seen
how it loops through each epoch and that
lives through each thing in our batch
and calls step or dot step right and so
step or dot step is the thing that's
responsible for calling the model
getting the last finding the last
function and calling the optimizer and
so by default step or dot step uses a
particular class called stepper which
there's a few things you don't know
where basically it calls the model all
right so the model winds up inside M
Zero's the gradients cause the loss
function calls backwards does gradient
flipping if necessary and then calls the
optimizer alright so you know they're
the basic steps that back when we looked
at kind of pi torch from scratch we had
to do so the nice thing is we can
replace that with something else rather
than replacing the training loop right
so if you inherit from step up and then
write your own version of step right you
can just copy and paste the contents of
step and add whatever you like right or
if it's something that you're going to
do before or afterwards your could even
call super dot step in this case I
rather suspect
I've been unnecessarily complicated here
I probably could have replaced commented
about all of that and just said super
darts DEP X's comma Y comma epoch
because I think this is an exact copy of
everything right but you know as I say
when I'm prototyping I don't think
carefully about how to minimize my code
I copied and pasted the contents of the
code from step and I added a single line
to the top which was to replace PR force
in my module with something that
gradually decreased linearly for the
first 10 a box and after 10 B box it was
zero okay so total hack but good enough
to try it out and so the nice thing what
is that I can now you know everything
else is the same
I've replaced I've added these three
lines of code to my module and the only
thing I need to do other that's
differently is when I call fit is I pass
in my customized step a class okay and
so that's going to do teacher forcing
and so we don't have bi-directional so
we're just changing one thing at a time
so we should compare this to our
unidirectional results
which was three point five eight and
this is three point four nine okay so
that was an improvement so that's great
needed to make sure at least two ten
epochs because before that it was
cheating by using the teacher forcing so
yeah okay
so that's good that's an improvement so
we've got another trick and this next
trick is a it's a bigger trick it's a
it's a pretty cool trick and it's it's
called attention and the basic idea of
attention is this which is expecting the
entirety of the sentence to be
summarized into this single hidden
vector is asking a lot you know it has
to know what was said and how it was
said and everything necessary to create
the sentence in general and so the idea
of attention is basically like maybe
we're asking too much all right
particularly because we could use this
form of model where we output every step
of the loop to not just have a hidden
state at the end but to hit a hidden
state after every single word and like
why not try and use that information
it's it's like it's already there but so
far we've just been throwing it away and
not only that but by directional we've
got every step we've got to you know
vectors of state that we can use so how
could we use this piece of state this
piece of state this piece of state this
piece of state and this piece of state
rather than just the final state and so
the basic idea is well let's say I'm
doing this word translating this word
right now which of these five pieces of
state do I want and of course the answer
is if I'm doing well actually that's
bigger more interesting would
pick this one so if I'm trying to do
loved then clearly the hidden state I
want is this one right because this is
the word okay and then for for this
preposition of little preposition
whatever this little word here no it's
not a preposition I guess it's part of
the boat so for this part of the verb I
probably would need like this and this
and this to kind of make sure that I've
got kind of the tense right and know
that I actually need this part of the
verb and so forth so depending on which
bit I'm translating I'm going to need
one or more bits of this of these
various hidden States and in fact you
know like I probably want some weighting
of them so like what I'm doing here I
probably mainly want this state right
but I maybe run a little bit of that one
and a little bit of that one right so in
other words for these five pieces of
hidden state we want to wait an average
right and we wanted waited by something
that can figure out which bits of the
sentence the most important right now so
how do we figure out something like
which bits are the symptoms are
important right now we created a neural
net and we train the neural net to
figure it out
when do we train that you're on it and
to end
so let's now train to neural nets well
we've actually already kinda got a bunch
right we've got an hour and an encoder
we got an RNN decoder we've got a couple
of linear layers what the hell let's add
another neural net into the mix okay and
this neural net is going to spit out a
wait for every one of these things and
we got to take the weighted average at
every step and it's just another set of
parameters that we learn all at the same
time okay and so that's called attention
so the idea is that once that attentions
been learned we can see this terrific
demo from Chris Olerud roncada each
different word is going to take a
weighted average see how they're
weighted the weights are different
depending on which word is being
later all right and you can see how it's
kind of figuring out the color the
deepness of the blue is how much weight
it's using you can see that each word is
basically or here at which word are we
transferring from so when we say
European we need to know that both of
these two parts you only influenced
ordering economic both these three parts
are very influenced including the gender
of the the definite article and so forth
right so check out this distill the pub
article are these things are all like
little Hospital interactive diagrams
basically shows you how weights how
attention works and what the actual
attention looks like and a trained
translation model okay so let's try and
implement attention so with attention
it's basically this is all identical
right and the encoder is identical and
all of this bit of the decoder is
identical there's one difference which
is that we see where this happens here
we go we basically are going to take a
weighted average and the way that we're
going to do the weighted average is we
create a little neural net which we're
going to see here and here and then we
use softmax because of course the last
thing about softmax is that we want to
ensure that all of the weights that
we're using add up to 1 and we also kind
of expect that one of those weights
should probably be quite a bit higher
than the other ones right and so soft
mattes gives us the guarantee that they
add up to 1 and because it's that aid of
that unit it tends to encourage one of
the weights to be higher than the other
ones all right so let's see how this
works so what's going to happen is we're
going to take the last layers hidden
state
and we're going to stick it into a
linearlayout and then we're going to
stick it into a nonlinear activation and
then we're going to do matrix multiply
and so if you think about it linear
layer nonlinear activation matrix
multiply that's a neural net it's a
neural net with one hidden layer okay
stick it into a softmax okay and then we
can use that to weight our air encoder
outputs okay so now rather than just
taking the last encoder output we've got
this is going to be the whole tensor of
all of the encoder outputs which I just
weight by this little neural net that I
created and that's basically it right so
[Music]
okay so what I'll do is I'll put on the
wiki thread couple of papers to check
out there was there was basically one
amazing paper that really originally
introduced this idea of attention and I
say amazing because it actually
introduced a couple of key things which
have really changed how people work in
this field they say area of attention
has been used not just for text but for
you know things like reading text out of
pictures or kind of doing various stuff
with computer vision and stuff like that
and then there's a second paper which
actually Geoffrey Hinton was involved in
called grammar as a foreign language
which used this idea of Iranians with
attention to basically try to replace
rules based grammar with an R and n
which automatically basically tagged the
grammatical you know each word based on
this grammar and turned out to do it
better than any rules based system which
today like actually kind of seems
obvious I think we're now used to the
idea that
neural nets do lots of this stuff better
than rules-based systems but at the time
I was considered really surprising
anyway one nice thing is that they're
kind of summary of how attention works
is really nice and concise you know can
you please explain a thing again sure
so here's the idea I like that nice
crisp request that's very easy to
understand okay let's go back and look
at our original encoder so an eridan
spits out two things it spits out a list
of the the state after every time step
and it also tells you the state at the
last time step and we used the state at
the last time step to create the input
state for our decoder okay which is what
we see you won but we know that it's
actually creating a vector at every time
step so wouldn't it be nice to use them
all right but wouldn't it be likes to
use the one or ones that's most relevant
to translating the word I'm translating
now so wouldn't it be nice to be able to
take a weighted average of the hidden
state at each time step weight it by
whatever is the appropriate weight right
now which for example in this case
litter would definitely be time step
number two here's what it's all about
because that's the word I'm translating
so how do we get how do we get a list of
weights that is suitable for the word
we're training right now well the answer
is by training a neural net to figure
out the list of weights and so anytime
we want to figure out how to train a
little neuron that that does and
tasks the easiest way normally always to
do that is to include it in your module
and train it in line with everything
else the minimal possible neural net is
something that contains two layers and
one nonlinear activation function so
here is one linear layer okay and in
fact you know instead of a linear layer
we can even just grab a random matrix if
we don't care about bias right and so
here's a random matrix it's just a
random tensor wrapped up in a parameter
a parameter remember is a is just a PI
torch variable it's like identical to a
variable that it just tells PI torch I
want you to learn the weights for this
place alright so here we've got a linear
layer here we've got a random matrix and
so here at this point where we start out
our decoder let's take that final let's
take the current hidden state of the
tked of the decoder right put that into
a linear layer right because like how
what's the information we use to decide
what words we should focus on next well
we the only information we have to go on
is what the decoders hidden state is now
all right so let's grab that put it into
the linear layer put it through a
[Music]
non-linearity put it through one more
nonlinear layer this one actually
doesn't have a bias in it so it's
actually just a matrix multiply put that
into a soft Max and that's it right
that's a little neural net it doesn't do
anything we could it's just a neuron
that no neuron it's do anything they're
just linear layers with nonlinear
activations with random weights right
but it starts to do something if we give
it a job to do right and in this case
the job we give it to do is to say don't
just take the final state but now let's
use all of the encoder states and let's
take all of them and multiply them by
the output of that little neuron it
right and so given that the things in
this little neural net are learnable
weights hopefully it's going to learn to
wait
those encoder outputs those encoder
hidden States by something useful all
right that's all in neural net ever does
is is we give it some random weights to
start with and a job to do and hope that
it learns to do the job and the ants and
it turns out that it does all right so
everything else in here is identical to
what it was before
we've got teacher forcing it's not
bi-directional so we can see how this
goes right you can see actually I am
oh yes here yeah using bi-directional
that's are using teacher forcing so
teacher foreseeing had three point four
nine and so now we've got nearly exactly
the same thing but we've got this little
minimal neural net figuring out what
weightings to give our inputs oh wow
now it's now down to three point three
seven all right remember these things
are logs right so e ^ this is quite a
significant change so three point three
seven let's try it out
not bad right where are they located
what are their skills what'd you do
it's still not perfect why or why not
but it's quite a few of them are correct
and again considering that we're asking
it to learn about the very idea of
language for two different languages and
how to translate them between the two
and grammar and vocabulary and we only
have 50,000 sentences and a lot of the
words only appear once I would say this
is actually pretty amazing
yes Annette why do we use tongue H you
still free Lu for attention minute I
don't quite remember it's been a while
since I looked at it you should totally
try using value and see how it goes
obviously then the key difference is
that it kind of go in each direction and
it's as limited both at the top and the
bottom I know very often like in it like
for the gates inside our own ends and
Ellice Tian Xin Jie I use fan often
works out better but it's been about a
year since I actually doctored that
specific question so I look at it during
the week but the short answer is you
know you should try a different
activation function and see if you can
get a better result be interested to
hear what you find out so what we can do
also is we can actually grab the
attentions out of the model right so I
actually added this return attention
equals true here look see here in my
forward like forward you can put
anything you like in forward so I added
a return attention parameter false by
default because obviously the the
training loop it doesn't know anything
about it but then I just had something
here saying if returned attention then
stick the attentions on as well right
and the attentions is simply that value
a just check it in a list okay so we can
now call the model with returned
attention equals true and get back the
probabilities and the attentions
betweens as well as printing out these
here we can draw pictures at each time
step of the attention and so you can see
at the start the attentions on the first
word second word third word a couple of
different words and this is just for one
particular sentence right but so you can
kind of see this is
equivalent this is like you know when
you're Chris solar and and and and Sean
kata you make things that look like this
when you Jeremy Howard the exact same
information looks like this but it's the
same thing okay just pretend that it's
beautiful bit so you can see basically
at each different time step we've got a
different a different attention and it's
really important when you try to build
something like this like you don't
really know if it's not working right
because if it's not working and you know
as per usual my first twelve attempts
that this were broken and and they were
broken in the sense that it wasn't
really learning anything useful
and so therefore was basically giving
equal attention to everything and
therefore it wasn't worse it just wasn't
better whenever it wasn't much better
and so I'm sure you actually find ways
to visualize the thing in a way that you
know what it ought to look like ahead of
time you don't really know if it's
working so it's really important that
you try to find ways to kind of check
your intermediate steps in your outputs
yes you know so we won't ask you what is
the last function for the attention on
your network no no no loss function to
determine your network right it's
trained in to end so it's just like it's
just sitting here inside out decoder
look right so the loss function for the
decoder loop is that this result
contains it's exactly the same as before
just the outputs the probabilities of
the words right so like the loss
function it's it's the same loss
function right so so how come the how
come the little little mini neural nets
learning something well because in order
to make the outputs better and better it
it would be great if it made the weights
of these little weighted-average better
and better right so part of creating our
output is to please do a good job of
finding a good set of weights and if it
doesn't do a good job of finding good
set of weights then the loss function
won't improve from that bit so like
end-to-end learning means like you throw
in
you know everything that you can into
one loss function and the gradients of
these of all the different parameters
point in a direction that says basically
hey you know if you had put more weight
over there it would have been better and
thanks to the magic of the train rule it
then no it's like oh well it would have
put more weight over there if you would
like change the parameter in this matrix
multiply a little bit over there all
right and so that's that's the magic of
end-to-end learning so it's a very
understandable question of like how did
this little mini in your network but
you've got to realize there's nothing
particularly about this code that says
hey this particular bits a separate
little mini neural network anymore than
the grooc is a separate little neural
network or this linear layers is a
little function like it's all ends up
pushed into one output which is a bunch
of probabilities which ends up in one
lost function that returns a single
number that says this either was or
wasn't a good translation right and so
thanks to the magic of the chain rule we
then back propagate little updates to
all the parameters to make them a little
bit better okay so this is a a big weird
counterintuitive idea and it's totally
ok if it's a bit mind-bending right and
it's the bit where even back to lesson 1
you know it's like how did this how did
we make it find dogs versus cats so we
didn't you know all we did was we said
this is our data this is our
architecture this is our loss function
please back propagate into the weights
to make them better and after you've
made them better a while it'll start
finding cats from dogs right that's just
in this case we haven't used somebody
else's like convolutional network
architecture we have said here's like a
custom architecture which we hope is
going to be particularly good at this
problem right and even without this
custom architecture it was - ok all
right
but then when we kind of made it in a
way that made more sense short we think
it ought to do it worked even better but
at no point did we kind of do anything
different other than say here's a data
here's an architecture here's a loss
function go and find the parameters
please pay ins and it did it because
that's what your net to do okay so that
is sequence the sequence planning and
you know if you want to encode an image
into you know using CNN backbone of some
kind and then pass that into a decoder
which is like a our an N with attention
and you make your y-values the actual
correct caption speech of those images
you will end up with an image caption
generator if you do the same thing with
videos and captions you'll end up with a
video caption generator if you do the
same thing with 3d CT scans and
radiology reports you'll end up with a
radiology report generator if you do the
same thing with github issues and you
know people's chosen summaries of them
you'll get a github issue summary
generator which you know it sector sick
I agree you know they're magical but
they they work you know and I don't feel
like people have begun to scratch the
surface of how to use sector SEC models
in their own domains so that's like not
being a github person it would never
have occurred to me that like oh it
would be kind of cool to start with some
you know issue and automatically create
a summary but now I'm like huh of course
next time I go to github I want to see a
summary written there for me I don't
want to write my own damn commit message
through that you know why should I write
my own like summary of the code review
when I finished adding comments just
lots of lines it should do that for me
as well now I'm thinking like Oh github
so behind it could be doing this stuff
so what are the things in your industry
you know that you could like start with
a sequence in
generate something from it I can't begin
to imagine right so again it's kind of
like it's a fairly new area the tools
for it are not easy to use they're not
even built into fast AI yet as you can
see hopefully there will be you know
soon and like you know I don't think
anybody knows what the opportunities are
okay so I've got good news bad news the
bad news is we have 20 minutes to cover
a topic which in last year's course took
a whole lesson the good news is that
when I went to rewrite this using fast
AI Empire torch I ended up with almost
no code so all of the stuff that made it
hard last year is basically gone now so
we're going to do something
bringing together for the first time our
two little worlds we focused on text and
images and we're going to try and bring
them together and so this idea came up
really in a paper by this extraordinary
deep learning practitioner and
researcher named Andrea Framm and Andrea
was Google at the time and her basic
crazy idea was to say like you know
words can have a distributed
representation a space which
particularly at that time was you know
really was just word vectors right and
images can be represented in a space I
mean like in the end if we have like a
fully connected layer they kind of ended
up as like a vector representation could
we merge the two could we either it
could be somehow encourage the vector
space that the images end up with be the
same vector space that the words are in
and if we could do that what would that
mean what could we do with that
right so though what could we do with
that covers things like well what if I'm
wrong you know what if I'm predicting
that this image
is a beagle and I predict jumbo jacked
you know and you nets model predicts
Corgi the normal loss function says that
your net and Jeremy's models are equally
good ie they're both wrong right but
what if we could somehow actually say
though you know what like Corky's closer
to beagle than it is to jumbo jets so
units models better than Jeremy's and we
should be able to do that right because
in in in in word vector space vehicle
and Corgi are pretty close together but
jumbo jet not so much okay so it would
give us a nice situation where hopefully
our inferences would be like wrong
insane aways if they're wrong it would
also allow us to search for things that
aren't in our you know an image net
since set ID you know like a category in
image net like like dog and cat why did
I have to train a whole new model to
find dog vs. cats when we already have
something that found Corky's and Paddy's
right why can't I just say find me dogs
well if I had trained it in in word
vector space I totally could right
because like that there there's our word
vector I can find things with the right
image vector and so forth so we'll look
at some cool things we can do with it in
a moment but first of all let's train a
model where this model is not learning a
category a one hotted coded ID where
every category is equally far from every
other category let's instead trainer
model where we're finding the dependent
variable which is a word vector so what
word vector well obviously the word
vector for the word you want right so if
it's Corgi let's train it to create a
word vector that's that's the Corgi work
that don't if it's a jumbo jet let's
train it with a dependent variable that
says this is the word vector for a jumbo
jet okay so as I said it's now
shockingly easy
okay so let's grab the fart the fasttech
word vectors again load the men we only
need English this time right and so
here's an example of the word vector for
King but it's just a 300 numbers so for
example you know little J Jeremy and big
J Jeremy have a correlation to point six
I don't like bananas at all this is good
banana and Jeremy point one four right
so like words that you would expect to
be correlated are correlated in words
that should be as far away from each
other as possible unfortunately they're
still slightly correlated but not so
much right
so let's now grab all of the imagenet
classes because we actually want to know
you know which one's Corgi and which
ones jumbo jet so we've got we've got a
list of all of those up on files doc
bastard AI we can grab them and that's
also grab a list of all of the nouns in
English which I've made available here
as well okay so here are the names of
each of the thousand imagenet classes
and here are all of the nouns in English
according to work net which is a popular
thing for kind of representing what
words are or not so we can now go ahead
and load that list of nouns and sorry
load the list of imagenet classes turn
that into a dictionary so these are the
class IDs for the 1000 images that are
in the competition data set they're at a
thousand okay so here's an example and
0-100 Allah is attentively is a kind of
fish let's do the same thing for all
those word net nouns and you can see
actually it turns out that image net is
using word net class names so that makes
it nice and easy to map between the two
and word net you know most basic thing
is an entity and then that if it's an
abstraction and a physical entity could
be an object and so forth right so these
are our two worlds we've got the image
net thousand
and we got the 80 mm which are in
wordnet so we want to map the two
together and which is as simple as
creating a couple of dictionaries to map
them based on the on the scene set ID or
the web net ID and it turns out that 49
thousand four hundred and sixty nine
let's see since set - oh okay so what I
need to do now is grab the 80 mm nouns
in word net and try and look them up in
fast text okay and so I've managed to
look up 49 thousand of them in fast text
all right so I've now got a dictionary
that goes from sin set ID which is what
wordnet calls them to word vectors okay
so that's what this dictionary yes sin -
sin set to work vector and I've also got
the same thing specifically for the 1000
word net classes so save them away
that's fine now I grab all of the image
net which you can actually download from
cable now if you look at the cackle
image net localization competition that
contains the entirety of the image net
classifications as well it's got a
validation set of 28,650 items in it and
so i can basically just grab for every
image in image net I can grab using that
sin set to work vector grab it's its
word net sorry it's a fast text word
vector and I can now stick that into
this image vectors array stack that all
up into a single matrix and save that
away and so now what I've got is
something for every image net image
they've also got the
fast text word vector that it's
associated with like just by looking up
you know the the sin set ID going to
word net then going to first text and
grabbing though the the word vector okay
and so here's a cool trick I can now
create a model data object which is
specifically it's an image classifier
data object and I've got this in court
from names an array I'm not sure if
we've used it before but we can pass it
a list of file names and so these are
all of the file names in an image net
and we can just pass it an array of our
dependent variables and so this is all
of the fast text word vectors right and
then I can pass in the validation
indexes which in this case is just all
of the last IDs I need to make sure that
they're the same as image net users
otherwise I'll be cheating okay and then
I pass in continuous equals true which
means this puts a lie again to this
image classifier data is now really an
image regressive data so continuous
equals true means don't one-hot encode
my outputs but treat them just as
continuous values so now I've got a
model data object that contains all of
my file names and for every file name a
continuous array representing the word
vector for that so I have an X I have a
Y so I have data now I need an
architecture and the last function that
once I've got that I should be done so
let's create an architecture and so we
can roll revise this next week but
basically we can use the tricks we've
learnt so far but it's actually
incredibly simple fast AI has a ComNet
builder which is what when you say you
know come flow no dot pre-trained it
calls this and you basically say okay
what architecture do you want so we're
going to use ResNet 50 how many classes
do you want in this case it's not really
classes it's how many outputs do you
want which is the length of the fast
text word vector that's 300
obviously it's not model class
classification it's not classification
at all
is it regression yes it is regression
okay and then you can just say all right
what fully connected layers do you want
so I'm just going to add one fully
connected layer hidden layer of length a
thousand and twenty four why a thousand
and twenty four well I've got the the
last layer of resin 850 is I think it's
a thousand twenty four long the final
output I need is three hundred long I
obviously need my penultimate layer to
be longer than three hundred otherwise
it's not enough information so I kind of
just picked something a bit bigger maybe
different numbers would be better but
this worked for me
how much dropout do you want I found
that the default dropout I was
consistently under fitting so I just
decreased the dropout from 0.5 to 0.2
and so this is now a convolutional
neural network that does does not have
any softmax or anything like that
because it's regression it's just a
linear layer at the end and yeah that's
basically it that that's that's my model
so I can create a common floater from
that model give it an optimization
function so now all I need I've got data
I've got an architecture right so the
architecture because I said I've got
this many three hundred outputs it knows
that there are three hundred outputs
because that's the size of this array
right so now all I need is a loss
function now the default loss function
for regression is l1 loss so the
absolute differences that's not bad
right but unfortunately in really high
dimensional spaces anybody whose could
have studied the bit of machine learning
probably knows this in really high
dimensional spaces in this case it's
three hundred dimensional and basically
everything is on the outside okay and
when everything's on the outside
distance is it's not meaningless but
it's it's a little bit awkward like
things you know things can things tend
to be close together or fire
doesn't really mean much in these really
high dimensional spaces but everything's
on the edge right what does mean
something though is that if one things
on the edge over here and one things on
the edge over here you can form an angle
between those vectors and the angle is
meaningful right and so that's why we
use a cosine similarity when we're
basically looking for like how close or
far apart are things in high dimensional
spaces right and if you haven't seen
cosine similarity before it's basically
the same as you're fitting in distance
but it's normalized to be basically a
unit norm that's so it basically divided
by the length so we don't care about the
length of the vector we only care about
its angle okay so there's a there's a
bunch of like stuff that you could
easily learn in a couple of hours but
but if you haven't seen it before it's a
bit mysterious for now just know that
loss functions in high dimensional
spaces where you're trying to find
similarity you you care about angle and
you don't care about distance okay if
you didn't use this custom loss function
it would still work I tried it it's just
a little bit less good okay so we've got
an architecture we've got data we've got
a loss function therefore we're done
okay
so we can go ahead and fit now I'm
training on all of imagenet right that's
going to take a long time so pre-compute
equals true as your friend okay you
remember precompute equals true that's
that thing we learnt ages ago that
caches the output with the final
convolutional layer that and just trains
the fully connected bit yeah and like
even with pre compute equals true it
takes like three minutes to train an
epoch on all of imagenet so I trained it
for a while I trained it for a while
longer so it's like an hour's worth of
training right but it's pretty cool that
you know with fast AI we can train you
know a new custom head basically on all
of imagenet for 48 bucks you know in an
arrow so okay and so at the end of all
that we can now say all right
grab the 1000 images all right and let's
predict on our whole validation set
right and let's just take a look at a
few pictures okay so here's a look at
you know a few pictures and because the
validation set is ordered you know
they're all all the stuff is the same
type as in the same place I don't know
what this thing is and what we can now
do is we can now use nearest neighbors
search all right so nearest neighbors
search means you know here's one 300
dimensional vector here's a whole lot of
other three-dimensional vectors which
things is it closest to Wow and normally
that takes a very long time because you
have to look through every 300
dimensional vector caplets at distance
and find out how far away it is okay but
there's an amazing almost unknown
library quote NMS Lib that that does
that incredibly fast like almost
nobody's heard of it some of you may
have tried other nearest neighbors
libraries I guarantee this is faster
than what you're using I can tell you
that because it's been benched much like
by people who do this stuff for a living
this is by far the fastest on every
possible dimension right so this is
basically a super fast way we basically
look here this is angular distance right
so we want to create an index on angular
distance and we're going to do it on all
of our imagenet word vectors right
adding a whole batch create the index
and now I can query a bunch of vectors
all at once get there ten nearest
neighbors users Bodi threading it's it's
absolutely fantastic
this library okay you can install it
from pip it just works
and it tells you how far away they are
and their indexes right and so we can
now go through and print out the top
three so it turns out that bird actually
is a limpkin okay so here are there this
is the top three for each one
interestingly this one doesn't say it's
a limpkin and I looked it up it's the
fourth one I don't know much about birds
but like everything else here is brown
with white spots that's not so I don't
know if that's actually a limb tune or
if there's the mislabel but I
sure as hell doesn't look like the other
birds so you know I thought that was
pretty interesting that yeah it's kind
of saying like I don't think it's that
now this is not a particularly hard
thing to do because it's only a thousand
imagenet classes it is not doing
anything new right but what if we now
bring in the entirety of wordnet and we
now say which of those forty-five
thousand things as a closest to exactly
the same right so it's now searching all
of wordnet right so now like let's do
something a bit different which is take
all of our predictions right so
basically take our whole validation set
of images and create a KNN index of the
image representations because remember
it's predicting things that are meant to
be word vectors and now let's grab the
fast text vector for boat and boat is
not an image net concept right and yet I
can now find all of the images in my
predicted word vectors in my validation
set that are closest to the word boat
and it works even though though it's not
something that was ever trained on what
if we now take engine's vector and boats
vector and take their average and what
if we now look in our nearest neighbors
for that these are boats with engines I
mean yes this is this is actually a boat
with an engine it just happens to have
wings on as well right
by the way sail is not an image net
thing boat is not an image net thing
here's the average of two things that
are not image net things and yet with
one exception it's bound me to sailboats
well okay let's do something else crazy
let's open up an image in the validation
set here it is hey I don't know what it
is
let's call predict array on that image
to get you know it's kind of like word
victor like thing and let's do a nearest
neighbors search on all the other images
and here's all the other images of
whatever
that is that so you can see this is like
crazy we've trained a thing on all of
imagenet in an hour using like a custom
head that required basically like two
lines of code and these things like run
in like 300 milliseconds to do these
searches like I I actually taught this
basic idea last year as well but it was
in chaos
and it was just like pages and pages and
pages of code and everything took a long
time and it's complicated
and back then I kind of said yeah I
can't begin to think all the stuff you
could do with this as I don't think
anybody's really thought deeply about
this yet but I think it's fascinating
and so go back and read the devise paper
because like Andrea had a whole bunch of
other thoughts and now that it's so easy
to do hopefully people will will dig
into this now because I think it's crazy
and amazing all right thanks everybody
see you next week
[Applause]